<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Apple’s reign as world’s most valuable stock by market value in jeopardy from bumpy 2024 start</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247501/apples-reign-worlds-most-valuable-stock-market-value-jeopardy-bumpy-2024-start</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Apple's stock price fell by 0.4% on Friday due to news that the US Justice Department is nearing an antitrust case against the company. This marks the fifth consecutive day of losses for Apple, its longest losing streak since October. Apple has lost about $177 billion in market value so far this year, despite previously holding the title of the world's most valuable company by market value. The antitrust case, if filed, could target Apple's business model of tightly integrating its devices and services.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's stock declines on news of a potential antitrust case by the US Justice Department.</li>    <li>Theme: Challenges faced by Apple, including declining iPhone sales, patent issues, and an antitrust lawsuit.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of an antitrust case on Apple's business model and market position.</li>    <li>Main information: Apple's stock performance, declining market value, ratings downgrades, and the potential impact of the antitrust case.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果公司股票在周五下跌0.4%，原因是美国司法部即将对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。这标志着苹果连续第五个交易日下跌，也是自去年10月以来持续时间最长的下跌。今年以来，苹果市值已蒸发约1770亿美元，尽管该公司此前一直保有全球市值最高的公司称号。如果反垄断诉讼提交，可能会针对苹果紧密整合其设备和服务的商业模式。  <ul>    <li>摘要：美国司法部潜在的反垄断诉讼消息导致苹果股价下跌。</li>    <li>主题：苹果面临的挑战，包括iPhone销量下降、专利问题和反垄断诉讼。</li>    <li>观点：反垄断诉讼对苹果商业模式和市场地位的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果股票表现、市值下降、评级下调以及反垄断诉讼的潜在影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>notch (v.) - /nɒtʃ/ 切割，刻痕。    <p>原文例句：The decline notched the fifth consecutive negative day for Apple, its longest losing streak since October. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古英语“nocche”，意为“刻痕，凹陷”。在这个例句中，它表示“刻痕”，指苹果股票连续第五个交易日下跌，是自去年10月以来持续时间最长的下跌。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rout (n.) - /raʊt/ 溃败，大败。    <p>原文例句：Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古法语“route”，意为“溃败，大败”。在这个例句中，它表示“溃败”，指苹果引领了科技股的溃败，与该集团在2023年的反弹形成鲜明对比。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in jeopardy - 面临危险，处于危险之中。    <P>原文例句：putting its long-standing status as the world’s most valuable stock by market value in jeopardy. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由介词in、形容词jeopardy（危险）和名词stock组成，表示“面临危险，处于危险之中”。在这个例句中，它表示苹果作为全球市值最高股票的长期地位正面临危险。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Cupertino, California-based company has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022, but has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. - 总部位于加州库比蒂诺的公司自 2022 年 7 月以来一直是全球市值最高的上市公司，但彭博社汇编的数据显示，今年迄今已蒸发了约 1770 亿美元的市值。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022，其中主语是The company，谓语是has been。but has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year是一个现在完成时态的句子，其中主语是The company，谓语是has seen，宾语是US$177 billion in market value erased。这个句子的意思是说，总部位于加州库比蒂诺的公司自 2022 年 7 月以来一直是全球市值最高的上市公司，但今年迄今已蒸发了约 1770 亿美元的市值。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>非限定性定语从句 - 提供补充信息，具有解释说明的作用，用逗号分隔。    <p>原文例句：Wall Street has rewarded Microsoft, which is benefiting from the artificial intelligence trade that has mesmerized investors over the past year, more recently than Apple. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个非限定性定语从句，它对Microsoft进行了补充说明，解释了微软受益于人工智能交易的原因。这个从句用逗号分隔，表示它不是微软的必要信息，而是补充信息。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>宾语从句 - 在复合句中充当宾语的作用。    <p>原文例句：Investors realise how rare it is to have two people go negative.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个宾语从句，它在复合句中充当宾语，解释了投资者意识到什么。这个从句由how rare it is to have two people go negative组成，其中how rare it is是主语，to have two people go negative是谓语。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Shares of Apple fell 0.4 per cent on Friday after a report that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company</li>
<li>The tech giant has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/0bab1060-0f68-4b59-b625-ee8f62b7b778_cec54c59.jpg" /><figcaption>People walk past an Apple Store in the Glendale Galleria shopping mall in California on December 26, 2023. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> just had its worst start to the year by one measure, as investors react to mounting pressures on the company, putting its long-standing status as the world’s most valuable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/stocks" target="_self" title="">stock</a> by market value in jeopardy.</p><p>Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.</p><p>The decline notched the fifth consecutive negative day for Apple, its longest losing streak since October.</p><p>The potential antitrust case against Apple “would add to the plethora of problems it faces, from slowing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> sales to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246452/apple-resumes-sale-watches-after-appeals-court-lifts-us-ban" target="_self" title="">Apple Watch patent issues</a>”, Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Anurag Rana wrote in a note. “The suit could attack Apple’s business model of tightly integrating its devices and services.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/bdba7b4d-2eef-4fae-a196-1d3cd943fe89_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Cupertino, California-based company has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022, but has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.</p><p>While the stock has suffered bigger percentage declines in the first week of January, the losses are the biggest market value destruction at the start of any year on record.</p><p>The downturn began earlier in the week after the technology giant was hit by two <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" target="_self" title="">ratings downgrades</a>, with analysts flagging a weak macro environment in China pressuring demand for iPhones.</p><p>That has shrunk its lead over fellow technology juggernaut <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft Corp</a> – whose shares have seen a less pronounced decline to begin the year – to less than US$100 billion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247211/apple-leads-us383-billion-tech-rout-reversal-groups-2023-rally" title="">Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</a></h3><p>“Investors realise how rare it is to have two people go negative,” said Gene Munster, managing partner of Deepwater Asset Management. “I’ve been covering this company for a long time and I’ve never seen two downgrades before an earnings report.”</p><p>Apple is also likely under pressure as investors rotate their portfolios at the start of the year.</p><p>“Everybody’s selling their winners and buying losers,” said Brian Mulberry, client portfolio manager at Zacks Investment Management. “There’s a big rebalance going on.”</p><p>The losses have pushed Apple’s market value down to about US$2.8 trillion, nearing Microsoft’s US$2.7 trillion. Shares of Microsoft fell less than 0.1 per cent Friday to close at about US$368.</p><p>The Windows software maker has benefited from the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> trade that has mesmerised Wall Street over the past year. The company is <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content" target="_self" title="">OpenAI</a>’s largest shareholder and has invested about US$13 billion into the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> parent.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech trade group representing TikTok, Snapchat and Meta sues Ohio over state’s new law limiting children’s use of social media apps</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247497/tech-trade-group-representing-tiktok-snapchat-and-meta-sues-ohio-over-states-new-law-limiting</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In July 2023, Ohio Governor Mike DeWine signed a state budget bill into law, part of which requires social media companies to obtain parental consent for children under 16 to use their platforms. </li>    <li>The NetChoice trade group, representing major tech companies like TikTok, is suing Ohio, arguing that the law violates free speech, and is overly broad and vague.</li>    <li>The law's goal is to protect children's mental health, but the tech companies believe parents are capable of determining online services and privacy protections for their children.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>2023年7月，俄亥俄州州长迈克·德温签署了一项州预算法案，其中一部分要求社交媒体公司获得16岁以下儿童使用其平台的父母同意。</li>    <li>代表TikTok等主要科技公司的NetChoice贸易集团正在起诉俄亥俄州，认为该法律侵犯了言论自由，并且过于广泛且模糊。</li>    <li>该法律的目的是保护儿童的心理健康，但科技公司认为家长能够为子女确定在线服务和隐私保护。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unconstitutional (adj.) - /ˌʌnkɒnstɪˈtjuːʃən(ə)l/ 违反宪法的。    <p>原文例句：The NetChoice trade group argues that Ohio’s law unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p>    <p>例句讲解：unconstitutional这个单词由un-（不）和constitutional（合乎宪法的）组成，表示“违反宪法的”。在这个例句中，它表示NetChoice贸易集团认为俄亥俄州的法律违反了言论自由，而且过于广泛和模糊。</p></li>    <li>implicate (v.) - /ɪmˈplɪkeɪt/ 牵连，把……牵连进来。    <p>原文例句：The litigation argues that Ohio’s law impedes free speech.</p>    <p>例句讲解：implicate这个单词来源于Latin，由in-（进入）和plicare（折叠）组成，表示“把…卷入，牵连”。在这个例句中，它表示诉讼认为俄亥俄州的法律侵犯了言论自由。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take effect - 生效。    <p>原文例句：The law is set to take effect on January 15.</p>    <p>例句讲解：take effect是由take（拿）和effect（效果）组成的短语动词，意为“生效”。在这个例句中，它表示法律将于1月15日生效。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The NetChoice trade group filed its lawsuit against Republican Attorney General Dave Yost in US District Court for the Southern district of Ohio. It seeks to block the law from taking effect. - NetChoice贸易集团在美国俄亥俄州南区地方法院对共和党总检察长戴夫·约斯特提起诉讼。该诉讼旨在阻止该法律生效。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The NetChoice trade group filed its lawsuit，其中主语是The NetChoice trade group，谓语是filed its lawsuit，宾语是lawsuit。against Republican Attorney General Dave Yost in US District Court for the Southern district of Ohio是一个介词短语作状语，表示诉讼的被告是共和党总检察长戴夫·约斯特，诉讼的地点是美国俄亥俄州南区地方法院。It seeks to block the law from taking effect是一个主语从句作目的语，表示诉讼的目的或结果，即阻止该法律生效。这个句子的意思是说，NetChoice贸易集团在美国俄亥俄州南区地方法院对共和党总检察长戴夫·约斯特提起诉讼，该诉讼旨在阻止该法律生效。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>of-phrase - 名词性词组。    <p>原文例句：The litigation argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps - impedes free speech.</p>    <p>语法讲解：of-phrase是一种名词性词组，由介词of和一个名词性结构组成。在这个例句中，of-phrase是of a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps，其中介词of表示属于或关于，名词性结构是a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps。of-phrase在这个句中作定语，修饰law，表示法律的内容或特征，即要求社交媒体公司获得父母的许可才能让16岁以下的儿童注册社交媒体和视频游戏应用程序。</p></li>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示动作或状态在某个时间之前已经完成，并且一直持续到现在。    <p>原文例句：The group has won lawsuits against similar restrictions in California and Arkansas.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是英语中一种重要的时态，用于表示动作或状态在某个时间之前已经完成，并且一直持续到现在。其结构为：have/has + 过去分词。在这个例句中，现在完成时态是has won，其中has是have的第三人称单数形式，won是win的过去分词。has won表示该组织之前已经赢得了一些类似的限制，而且这个结果一直持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The law forms part of a state budget bill that Ohio Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July and set to take effect on January 15</li>
<li>The NetChoice trade group argues that Ohio’s law unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/0827334f-9aca-4109-b4e2-813fa20ac5b8_06ce695b.jpg" /><figcaption>Ohio’s new law requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps. Photo: TNS</figcaption></figure><p>A trade group representing major tech companies including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/snapchat" target="_self" title="">Snapchat</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/facebook" target="_self" title="">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/instagram" target="_self" title="">Instagram</a> operator <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226704/meta-takes-aim-twitter-launch-rival-app-threads" target="_self" title="">Meta Platforms</a> sued Ohio on Friday over the state’s pending law that requires children to get parental consent to use <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">apps</a>.</p><p>The law was part of an US$86.1 billion state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July. It is set to take effect on January 15.</p><p>The administration pushed the measure as a way to protect children’s mental health, with Republican Lieutenant Governor Jon Husted saying at the time that social media was “intentionally addictive” and harmful to kids.</p><p>The NetChoice trade group filed its lawsuit against Republican Attorney General Dave Yost in US District Court for the Southern district of Ohio. It seeks to block the law from taking effect.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP" class="image-inline caption" height="1410" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/8d380f8f-5e87-4f75-add2-ca49bea0915b_3ad8b242.jpg" title="A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP" width="2000" /><figcaption>A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The litigation argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> apps – unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p><p>The law also requires social media companies to provide parents with their privacy guidelines, so that families can know what content will be censored or moderated on their child’s profile.</p><p>“We at NetChoice believe families equipped with educational resources are capable of determining the best approach to online services and privacy protections for themselves,” Chris Marchese, director of the organisation’s litigation centre, said in a statement.</p><p>“With NetChoice v Yost, we will fight to ensure all Ohioans can embrace digital tools without their privacy, security and rights being thwarted.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247089/montana-appealing-ruling-blocked-state-barring-tiktok-use" title="">Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok use</a></h3><p>The group has won lawsuits against similar restrictions in California and Arkansas.</p><p>Husted, who leads Ohio’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> initiatives and championed the law, called Friday’s lawsuit “cowardly but not unexpected”.</p><p>“In filing this lawsuit, these companies are determined to go around parents to expose children to harmful content and addict them to their platforms,” Husted said in a statement.</p><p>He also alleged the tech companies know their algorithms are harming children “with catastrophic health and mental health outcomes”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China needs ‘groundbreaking’ policy changes to embrace disruptive technologies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247450/china-needs-groundbreaking-policy-changes-embrace-disruptive-technologies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China's economic success has been driven by carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies.</li>    <li>However, disruptive technologies, such as AI and quantum computing, are changing the way consumers, industries, and businesses operate, and China needs to adjust its policies to keep up.</li>    <li>Analysts suggest that China should shift from a selective industrial policy paradigm to a functional policy paradigm, which would allow for more innovation and experimentation.</li>    <li>This would involve providing more funding for industrial research and allowing small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) to play a larger role in economic development.</li>    <li>China's basic research expenditure is lower than that of other developed countries, and its enterprises' contribution to R&D is also relatively low.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国经济的成功得益于精心制定的产业政策和引进技术。</li>    <li>然而，人工智能和量子计算等颠覆性技术正在改变消费者、行业和企业运作方式，中国需要调整政策以跟上步伐。</li>    <li>分析人士建议中国应从选择性产业政策范式转向功能性政策范式，这将允许更多的创新和实验。</li>    <li>这将涉及提供更多资金用于产业研究，并允许中小型企业（SME）在经济发展中发挥更大作用。</li>    <li>中国的基础研究支出低于其他发达国家，其企业对研发的贡献也相对较低。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>disruptive (adj.) - /dɪsˈrʌptɪv/ 颠覆性的，破坏性的。    <p>原文例句：Disruptive technologies, including artificial intelligence and quantum computing, will significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate</p>    <p>例句讲解：“disruptive”的意思是“破坏性的，颠覆性的”，它描述了人工智能和量子计算等技术具有颠覆性，正在改变消费者、行业和企业运作方式。</p></li>    <li>paradigm (n.) - /ˈpærədaɪm/ 范式，模式。    <p>原文例句：Huang Shaoqing said in the report that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“paradigm”的意思是“范式，模式”，它指的是一种思维方式或行为模式。在这个例句中，它指的是选择性产业政策的模式，这种模式导致了中国过去经济的成功，但未来可能会导致失败和成为陷阱。</p></li>    <li>crucial (adj.) - /ˈkruːʃəl/ 重要的，关键的。    <p>原文例句：Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, said China needs to plan areas where matured technologies can be applied, including sectors influenced by US export bans, and that involve more markets.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“crucial”的意思是“重要的，关键的”，它强调了某事的重要性或关键性。在这个例句中，它指的是中国需要规划成熟技术可以应用的领域，包括受到美国出口禁令影响的行业，以及涉及更多市场的领域。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>economic miracle - 经济奇迹。    <p>原文例句：China’s economic miracle over the past four decades has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“economic miracle”的意思是“经济奇迹”，它指的是经济快速增长的阶段或时期。在这个例句中，它指的是中国在过去四十年的经济奇迹，其基础是精心制定的产业政策和引进技术，以实现规模经济并降低生产成本。</p></li>    <li>industrial policy - 产业政策。    <p>原文例句：China’s economic miracle over the past four decades has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“industrial policy”的意思是“产业政策”，它指的是政府对特定产业的干预和支持政策。在这个例句中，它指的是中国过去四十年的产业政策，其基础是精心制定的产业政策和引进技术，以实现规模经济并降低生产成本。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China’s economic miracle over the past four decades has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs. - 中国在过去四十年的经济奇迹是基于精心制定的产业政策和引进技术，以实现规模经济并降低生产成本。    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是China’s economic miracle has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies，其中主语是China’s economic miracle，谓语是has been based on，宾语是carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies。over the past four decades是一个时间状语，表示“在过去的四十年里”。to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs是一个目的状语，表示“为了实现规模经济并降低生产成本”。这个句子的意思是说，中国在过去四十年的经济奇迹是基于精心制定的产业政策和引进技术，以实现规模经济并降低生产成本。</p></li>    <li>Huang Shaoqing said in the report that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”. - 黄少卿在报告中说，导致中国过去经济成功的选择性产业政策制度“甚至可能导致失败并成为未来的陷阱”。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huang Shaoqing said in the report that，其中主语是Huang Shaoqing，谓语是said，宾语是that。the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past是一个定语从句，修饰名词selective industrial policy regime，表示“选择性产业政策制度，导致了中国过去经济的成功”。“may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”是一个结果状语，表示“甚至可能导致失败并成为未来的陷阱”。这个句子的意思是说，黄少卿在报告中说，导致中国过去经济成功的选择性产业政策制度“甚至可能导致失败并成为未来的陷阱”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 被动语态表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：China’s economy has been propelled by disruptive technologies, and potentially revolutionary industrial changes are set to alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，propelled和alter都是被动语态的动词。propelled by disruptive technologies表示“被颠覆性技术推动”，alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate表示“改变消费者、行业和企业运作的方式”。被动语态可以使句子更加简洁和正式，并且可以使句子的重点放在动作或状态的承受者上。</p></li>    <li>条件状语从句 - 条件状语从句表示一个条件，如果这个条件满足，那么主句中的动作或状态就会发生。    <p>原文例句：If more companies can generate groundbreaking technologies, China is set to achieve further economic success.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，If more companies can generate groundbreaking technologies是一个条件状语从句，表示“如果更多的公司能够产生突破性技术”。China is set to achieve further economic success是一个主句，表示“中国将取得进一步的经济成功”。条件状语从句可以使句子更加复杂和精确，并且可以使句子的重点放在动作或状态的条件上。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Disruptive technologies, including artificial intelligence and quantum computing, will significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate</li>
<li>China should make ‘groundbreaking changes’ to its industrial policymaking amid its push to become a global technological and economic leader, analysts said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/df3b6f4b-498c-4140-80f2-8b42e0ebe9ed_9f02ea50.jpg" /><figcaption>China’s HL-2M reactor in Sichuan could provide a long-term solution to the world’s energy needs by generating power without producing nuclear waste. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China needs to adjust its industrial policymaking to brace for possible revolutionary changes to its economy by disruptive technologies, analysts said.</p><p>From artificial intelligence (AI) to quantum computing, and from room-temperature superconductivity to controllable nuclear fusion, disruptive technologies are set to significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate.</p><p>China’s economic miracle over the past four decades has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs.</p><p>This model has been adopted by other economies in East Asia during their development in the second half of 20th century.</p><blockquote>How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgentHuang Shaoqing</blockquote><p>“As frontier technologies, no one knows what technology truly has promising prospects, which could ultimately be screened out by the market through competition,” Huang Shaoqing, a professor of economics at the Antai College of Economics and Management at Shanghai Jiao Tong University, said in a report.</p><p>“Therefore, in the early development stage of disruptive technologies, economies of scale are not important and even dangerous.”</p><p>Huang said in the report published by the English-language Asian Review of Political Economy in October 2022 that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”.</p><p>“How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgent,” he wrote in the report, which had earlier been published in Mandarin by the Journal of Comparative Studies in February 2022.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>The urgency has become more prominent for Beijing, which views innovation and technological advancement as key to countering the heightened containment efforts by the United States, and also crucial for its ambition to become an economic and tech superpower by the middle of the century.</p><p>Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, said China needs to plan areas where matured technologies can be applied, including sectors influenced by US export bans, and that involve more markets.</p><p>“China needs to make groundbreaking changes to its industrial policymaking, otherwise, it will never be a global technological and economic leader,” Peng said.</p><p>“Decision makers need to listen more to private companies, give them enough funding for industrial research, and place them at the front role of disruptive industrial exploration.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies" title="">‘More, better’: premier urges China to focus on application of core technologies</a></h3><p>But as it is impossible to determine in advance which technology would prevail, a country can gain an advantage only if it develops enough small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) to offer sufficient diversified technological routes, Huang added.</p><p>“Only by promoting innovation and entrepreneurship, relaxing market access, improving the business environment, and allowing as many as SMEs as possible to grow rapidly can these SMEs play an important role in economic development driven by innovation,” he said.</p><p>In 2016 when mapping out a national scientific and technology plan, Beijing vowed to improve tracking revolutionary industrial development to be capable of prejudging “the turning point” of possible replacements for traditional industries.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>At the time it added that it would make a timely plan for research into disruptive technologies, such as AI, quantum information, genome editing, unmanned driving, hydrogen power and nanotechnology.</p><p>Li Yangwei, a technical consultant in the computing sector in Shenzhen, said disruptive technologies may lead to bigger tech and economic gaps among regions within China, but when there are more participants, the cost of any potential failures can be lowered.</p><p>He also said small market players can offer advice to the central government about industrial policies, but amid hefty external pressure and geopolitical complications, Beijing may still allocate resources to big companies or state-owned enterprises.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3243101/chinas-ai-aspirations-will-fuel-economy-drive-investment-trillions-dollars-mckinsey" title="">China’s AI gains will fuel economy as windfall swells into trillions: McKinsey</a></h3><p>“It also requires technocrats to be socially, economically and politically insightful, as well as having strong communication skills and being given central decision-making power,” Li said.</p><p>China’s basic research accounted for more than 6 per cent of its total research and development (R&amp;D) expenditure in the last four years, lower than the 16 to 18 per cent in the US and 22 per cent in France over the last 10 years.</p><p>Basic research from enterprises only accounted for 0.78 per cent of China’s overall R&amp;D expenditure, behind over 6 per cent in developed countries, according to a report in February by the Science and Technology Daily, a newspaper backed by the Ministry of Science and Technology.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s ‘king of software’, Wang Wenjing, steps down as president of enterprise management systems firm Yonyou amid mounting losses</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247446/chinas-king-software-wang-wenjing-steps-down-president-enterprise-management-systems-firm-yonyou</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Tech billionaire Wang Wenjing, known for being China’s “king of software,” resigned as president of Yonyou Network Technology, a company he founded in 1988. The resignation comes amid sluggish sales and mounting losses for Yonyou. Yonyou's board expressed gratitude for Wang's contributions, and the 60-year-old Wang will retain his roles as chairman and chief executive. Veteran Yonyou executive Chen Qiangbin will take over as president, focusing on operations and management. Yonyou has shifted its focus from selling software licenses to providing cloud-based services. The changes aim to address stagnant revenue growth and widening losses. While the digital economy push presents fresh opportunities, Yonyou reported positive revenue growth across all segments in the third quarter of last year. Despite this, the company experienced a 91% increase in losses year-on-year. Yonyou has expanded globally, with branch offices worldwide.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tech billionaire Wang Wenjing steps down as president of Yonyou Network Technology, as the company faces challenges.</li>    <li>Theme: Yonyou Network Technology's struggles, leadership changes, and strategic shifts to improve performance.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of weak economic recovery on Yonyou's business; the potential of China's digitalisation drive for Yonyou.</li>    <li>Main information: Wang's resignation, Chen's appointment as president, Yonyou's move towards cloud-based services, positive revenue growth in Q3 2022, and the company's global presence.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  科技亿万富翁王文京，曾被称为中国的“软件大王”，辞去亲手创办于1988年的用友网络科技的总裁职务。用友陷于销售不振和亏损加剧中王的辞职也因此而起。用友董事会对王文京的贡献表示感谢，年已60的王文京仍将担任公司董事长和首席执行官。用友老员工陈强斌接任总裁职务，专注于运营和管理。用友将重点从销售软件许可证转移到提供云计算服务。这些变化旨在扭转持续两年左右的营收停滞增长和亏损扩大的趋势。虽然数字经济推动为用友带来了新的机遇，但该公司在去年第三季度报告称各板块营收环比增长。尽管如此，公司去年亏损同比扩大91%。用友的业务已扩展至全球，在世界各地设有分支机构。  <ul>    <li>摘要：科技亿万富翁王文京辞去用友网络科技总裁职务，该公司面临着挑战。</li>    <li>主题：用友网络科技的困境、领导层更迭以及为改善业绩而进行的战略调整。</li>    <li>观点：经济复苏疲软对用友业务的影响；中国数字化转型推动对用友的潜在影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：王文京辞任，陈强斌被任命为总裁，用友向云计算服务转型，2022年第三季度营收增长，以及公司在全球业务的存在。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>shuffle (v.) - /ˈʃʌfəl/ 洗牌，随机变更（人事）。    <p>原文例句：The senior management shuffle at Yonyou reflects the firm’s effort to turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语“scufan”，意思是“推”，有“洗牌，随机变更（人事）”之意。在这个例句中，它指的是用友的高层管理层变更，反映了公司在收入增长停滞约两年后为扭转局面所做的努力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sluggish (adj.) - /ˈslʌɡɪʃ/ 迟缓的，缓慢的。    <p>原文例句：Yonyou Network Technology founder Wang Wenjing retains his roles as chairman and chief executive at the Beijing-based enterprise management systems company. Photo: Weibo</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于中古英语“slou”，意思是“懒惰”，有“迟缓的，缓慢的。倦怠的”的意思。在这个例句中，它描述了用友网络科技的销售缓慢和亏损不断增加的状态，反映了公司面临的挑战。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make its operations - 进行运营，开展业务。    <P>原文例句：The move was expected to make its operations more focused on vertical industries, instead of regional markets. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由make（使，制作），its（它的），operations（运营），和more（更）等单词构成。意思是开展业务，进行运营。在这个例句中，它表示改组将使用友的业务更加专注于垂直行业，而不是区域市场。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The resignation comes amid sluggish sales and mounting losses for Yonyou. - 而在用友销售不振和亏损不断加剧的情况下，他的辞职也因此而起。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The resignation comes，其中主语是The resignation，谓语是comes。amid sluggish sales and mounting losses for Yonyou是一个介词短语作状语，表示辞职的原因或背景，即在用友销售不振和亏损不断加剧的情况下。这个句子的意思是说，王文京的辞职发生在用友销售不振和亏损不断加剧的情况下。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 用于修饰名词或代词。    <p>原文例句：Former Yonyou veteran Chen Qiangbin, 48, takes over as company president, with a focus on operations and management. </p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语是一种非谓语动词结构，由一个分词和一个或多个修饰成分组成，用于修饰名词或代词。分词短语可以起到形容词或副词的作用。在这个例句中，分词短语Former Yonyou veteran Chen Qiangbin, 48, takes over as company president, with a focus on operations and management作主语，修饰名词president，起到形容词的作用，表示原用友老员工陈强斌，现年48岁，担任公司总裁，专注于运营和管理。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>介词短语 - 用来修饰动词、形容词或其他副词。    <p>原文例句：After joining Yonyou in 2000, Chen was involved in software development, sales and then served as general manager at the firm’s branch offices in Beijing, northern Hebei province and southwestern Sichuan province. </p>    <p>语法讲解：介词短语是一种由介词和一个名词或代词组成的结构，用来修饰动词、形容词或其他副词。介词短语可以表示时间、地点、方式、原因、目的等。在这个例句中，介词短语After joining Yonyou in 2000,作状语，修饰谓语动词was involved，表示在2000年加入用友之后。介词短语in software development, sales作状语，修饰谓语动词was involved，表示在软件开发、销售方面。介词短语at the firm’s branch offices in Beijing, northern Hebei province and southwestern Sichuan province作状语，修饰谓语动词served，表示在公司位于北京、河北北部和四川西南的分公司。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Tech billionaire Wang, 60, will remain in his roles as Yonyou chairman and chief executive, overseeing corporate strategy and product development</li>
<li>The senior management shuffle at Yonyou reflects the firm’s effort to turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/6c7f31d3-f7f3-4577-a795-008077b768f9_4bcd59c9.jpg" /><figcaption>Yonyou Network Technology founder Wang Wenjing retains his roles as chairman and chief executive at the Beijing-based enterprise management systems company. Photo: Weibo</figcaption></figure><p>Tech billionaire <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/347601/ufsoft-creates-fast-fortune-and-billion-dollar-goal" target="_self" title="">Wang Wenjing</a>, who was once known as China’s “king of software”, has stepped down as president of enterprise management systems provider Yonyou Network Technology, as the company he founded in 1988 continues to struggle with sluggish sales and mounting losses amid the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3241783/chinas-2023-gdp-forecasts-twisted-and-turned-prognosticators-puzzled-over-countrys-future" target="_self" title="">weak post-pandemic economic recovery</a>.</p><p>Wang had tendered his resignation with immediate effect, according to Yonyou’s filing with the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai-stock-index" target="_self" title="">Shanghai Stock Exchange</a> on Wednesday. “The company’s board expresses its sincere gratitude to Wang for his contribution,” the Beijing-based firm said.</p><p>The 60-year-old Wang – with a net worth of US$3.1 billion as of January 5, according to Forbes – will remain in his roles as Yonyou chairman and chief executive, overseeing corporate strategy and product development, according to a separate statement released by the firm.</p><p>Veteran Yonyou executive Chen Qiangbin, 48, takes over as company president, with a focus on operations and management, according to the company. After joining Yonyou in 2000, Chen was involved in software development, sales and then served as general manager at the firm’s branch offices in Beijing, northern Hebei province and southwestern Sichuan province.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/9f56e087-6a3a-4e69-b9a6-4ca4b123727b_b201e52d.jpg" title="Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Yonyou, ranked by research firm Gartner as one of the world’s top 10 enterprise resource planning (ERP) software providers, saw its shares close down 2.48 per cent to 16.49 yuan (US$2.32) on Friday.</p><p>ERP refers to software designed to automate business processes, as well as provide insights and internal controls, often in real time. It manages operations including accounting and finance, procurement, supply chain, manufacturing, human resources and collaboration.</p><p>In recent years, Yonyou changed its focus from selling licences of its ERP and other enterprise management software to collecting service fees by providing these systems via a software-as-a-service model called Yonyou BIP. By 2022, cloud-based services accounted for nearly 70 per cent of the firm’s revenue.</p><p>Still, the senior management shuffle at Yonyou reflects the company’s effort to try and turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth and widening losses, as fresh opportunities beckon from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" target="_self" title="">Beijing’s digitalisation drive</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" title="">China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms</a></h3><p>Yonyou initiated one of its largest organisational changes last year, when it set up 23 industry client and solution business units to cover a range of industries including manufacturing, consumer products, energy, logistics and the public sector. The move was expected to make its operations more focused on vertical industries, instead of regional markets.</p><p>Even as China’s weak macroeconomic environment has driven a round of poor earnings from cybersecurity and finance software stocks, Yonyou’s third-quarter results last year – with “positive revenue growth across all segments” – “indicate that ERP demand has been resilient”, according to a November research note by Jefferies.</p><p>While it reported 2 per cent revenue growth in the first three quarters of last year, Yonyou saw its losses widen 91 per cent year on year to 1 billion yuan.</p><p>Wang, who was 24 when he founded Yonyou <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/242891/software-rewards-u-turn-decision" target="_self" title="">after leaving a job in government</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/496999/software-firm-hopes-name-will-score-goal" target="_self" title="">initially provided accounting software</a> to businesses and quickly became a dominant player in that market. When Yonyou – first known as Ufsoft and then Ufida – expanded into ERP and other enterprise management systems, it surpassed the performance of major foreign ERP players like Oracle and SAP in the Chinese market.</p><p>Yonyou currently has more than 230 branch offices worldwide – including in the mainland, Hong Kong, Macau, Australia, New Zealand and a number of countries in Southeast Asia.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>McDonald’s China and Cainiao partner on RFID chips to improve supply chain efficiencies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247447/mcdonalds-china-and-cainiao-partner-rfid-chips-improve-supply-chain-efficiencies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: McDonald's China partners with Cainiao to utilize RFID technology in supply chain.</li>    <li>Theme: Adoption of RFID technology by McDonald's China enhances supply chain efficiency.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Advancement in logistics and digitization as key factors in optimizing supply chains.</li>    <li>Main information: RFID implementation reduces stocktaking time, improves inventory accuracy, and allows tracking of products throughout the supply chain. </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>摘要：麦当劳中国与菜鸟合作，在供应链中运用射频识别（RFID）技术。</li>    <li>主题：麦当劳中国采用RFID技术，提高供应链效率。</li>    <li>观点：物流和数字化进步是优化供应链的关键因素。</li>    <li>主要信息：RFID的实施减少了盘点时间，提高了库存的准确性，并允许跟踪整个供应链中的产品。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>accuracy (n.) - /ˈæk.jʊ.rə.si/ 准确性。    <p>原文例句：A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants while improving the accuracy of inventory data by 30 per cent, according to the statement.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“accuracy”意为“准确性”，指测量或计算结果与真实值接近的程度。在这个例句中，“accuracy of inventory data”意为“库存数据的准确性”，指库存数据与实际库存情况的接近程度。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>digitisation (n.) - /ˌdɪdʒ.ɪ.tʌɪˈzeɪ.ʃən/数字化。    <p>原文例句：Apart from deploying RFID technology to improve efficiency in inventory and logistics, McDonald’s and Cainiao will also explore digitisation and automation technologies in the supply chain, Cainiao said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“digitisation”意为“数字化”，指将模拟信息转换为数字形式的过程。在这个例句中，“digitisation and automation technologies”意为“数字化和自动化技术”，指将供应链中的模拟信息转换为数字形式，并利用自动化技术进行管理和控制。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>reduce the time (for something) - 减少（做某事）的时间。    <P>原文例句：A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由reduce（减少），the time（时间）和for something（做某事）组成，表示“减少做某事的时间”。在这个例句中，它表示RFID技术的试点项目帮助餐馆将每天盘点所需的时间从1小时减少到15分钟。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>track products - 追踪产品。    <P>原文例句：Under a deal signed on Thursday, McDonald’s China will deploy Cainiao’s RFID technology in its supply chain with built-in tags on food packages, allowing the company to track products from factories to restaurants. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由track（追踪）和products（产品）组成，表示“追踪产品”。在这个例句中，它表示麦当劳中国将部署菜鸟的RFID技术在其供应链中，在食品包装上内置标签，允许公司从工厂到餐馆追踪产品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>McDonald’s China has a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year. - 麦当劳中国拥有5500多家餐厅和超过20万名员工，每年为超过10亿的顾客提供服务。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是McDonald’s China，谓语是has，宾语是a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year.其中a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year是一个复合名词作宾语，表示麦当劳中国拥有一个包含5500多家餐厅和超过20万名员工的网络，每年为超过10亿的顾客提供服务。这个句子的意思是说，麦当劳中国拥有5500多家餐厅和超过20万名员工，每年为超过10亿的顾客提供服务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Cainiao moved into the RFID field with the launch of its own tags in 2021, which it said could achieve 99.9 per cent recognition accuracy.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，但强调动作或状态已经完成。结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词。在这个例句中，它表示菜鸟在2021年推出自己的标签，进入RFID领域，并表示该标签可以实现99.9%的识别准确率。这个句子的意思是说，菜鸟在2021年推出自己的标签，进入RFID领域，并表示该标签可以实现99.9%的识别准确率。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apart from deploying RFID technology to improve efficiency in inventory and logistics, McDonald’s and Cainiao will also explore digitisation and automation technologies in the supply chain, Cainiao said.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，表示动作或状态正在进行。结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。在这个例句中，它表示除了部署RFID技术来提高库存和物流的效率之外，麦当劳和菜鸟还将探索供应链中的数字化和自动化技术。这个句子的意思是说，除了部署RFID技术来提高库存和物流的效率之外，麦当劳和菜鸟还将探索供应链中的数字化和自动化技术。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants</li>
<li>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/d5e1a0a3-a5e3-492f-b311-a67d3c5f12ec_d1186b0d.jpg" /><figcaption>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong. Photo: Reuters </figcaption></figure><p>McDonald’s China unit has partnered with Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics business, to improve supply chain efficiency using radio frequency identification (RFID) chips and other technologies.</p><p>Under a deal signed on Thursday, McDonald’s China will deploy Cainiao’s RFID technology in its supply chain with built-in tags on food packages, allowing the company to track products from factories to restaurants, according to a statement by the Hangzhou-based logistics firm.</p><p>A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants while improving the accuracy of inventory data by 30 per cent, according to the statement.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240676/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-will-enhance-its-overseas-presence-proposed-buyout-local-rival-best" title="">Alibaba logistics spin-off Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout</a></h3><p>RFID is a third-generation identification technology, after bar codes and QR codes, and has been widely adopted in supply chain tracking. With a built-in microchip, data is transmitted through radio frequency signals.</p><p>Apart from deploying RFID technology to improve efficiency in inventory and logistics, McDonald’s and Cainiao will also explore digitisation and automation technologies in the supply chain, Cainiao said.</p><p>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3235860/alibabas-cainiao-files-us1-billion-ipo-helping-hong-kong-land-worlds-second-biggest-listing-2023" target="_self" title="">an initial public offering (IPO) in Hong Kong</a> after submitting its A1 filing to the city’s stock exchange last September.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month. The listing is part of a group-wide restructuring of Alibaba as the e-commerce titan seeks to free up decision- making amid increased competition across its businesses. Alibaba also owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Established in 2013, Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s huge e-commerce empire, handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023. Alibaba announced it would spin Cainiao off in the restructuring announced in March.</p><p>Cainiao moved into the RFID field with the launch of its own tags in 2021, which it said could achieve 99.9 per cent recognition accuracy. The company announced in April last year that it had produced and sold over 100 million RFID tags in just two years.</p><p>McDonald’s China has a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year. It has also been stepping up efforts to digitise its operations in the country, which is the fast-food giant’s second-largest market globally.</p><p>Last month, McDonald’s China said it would work with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> to build a native app based on the next iteration of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3136017/will-huaweis-harmony-operating-system-end-global-duopoly-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS</a>, the Chinese telecommunications equipment and smartphone giant’s self-developed mobile platform.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China unveils 3-year ‘data action plan’ as Beijing seeks to boost growth through tech</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247423/china-unveils-3-year-data-action-plan-beijing-seeks-boost-growth-through-tech</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  China's National Data Administration (NDA) has released a three-year plan to bolster the country's data industry and economy. The plan aims to build over 300 representative application scenarios, expand the data industry by 20% annually, and enhance data trading. It seeks to tap into China's vast data resources and market advantages, addressing challenges like low data quality and limited application potential. The NDA aims to develop AI large language models and industry databases, while fostering investment in the data sector. The plan targets 12 industries, including manufacturing, finance, and transportation, to leverage data for growth. This initiative is part of China's broader drive to achieve digital economy-led common prosperity and catch up with global AI advancements.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: China unveils a three-year plan to transform its data resources into an economic driving force.</li>    <li>Theme: China's data administration outlines strategies to enhance data utilization, industry growth, and application development.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of data as a production factor in China's economic development; addressing challenges in data quality and application potential; promoting data security and privacy.</li>    <li>Main information: Building representative application scenarios; expanding the data industry; mobilizing data resources for AI development; improving data quality and circulation; supporting data brokers and private capital investment; targeting 12 industries for data-driven growth.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国国家数据管理局发布三年计划，以提振该国数据产业和经济。该计划旨在构建 300 多个代表性的应用场景，每年将数据产业扩大 20%，并加大数据交易量。它旨在利用中国庞大的数据资源和市场优势，解决数据质量低、应用潜力有限的挑战。国家数据管理局旨在开发人工智能大型语言模型和行业数据库，同时促进对数据部门的投资。该计划以制造、金融和交通运输等 12 个行业为目标，利用数据促进增长。这一举措是中国实现数字经济引领的共同繁荣和赶上全球人工智能进步的更广泛推动力的一部分。    <ul>    <li>摘要：中国公布三年计划，将其数据资源转变为经济驱动力。</li>    <li>主题：中国数据管理局概述了加强数据利用、行业增长和应用开发的战略。</li>    <li>观点：数据作为中国经济发展生产要素的重要性；解决数据质量和应用潜力挑战；促进数据安全和隐私。</li>    <li>主要信息：构建代表性应用场景；扩大数据产业；调动数据资源发展人工智能；提高数据质量和流通；支持数据经纪人和民间资本投资；以 12 个行业为目标，实现数据驱动增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>representative (adj.) - /ˌrepɹɪˈzentətɪv/ 有代表性的。    <p>原文例句：China aims to build more than 300 “representative” application scenarios by 2026. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由re-（重新）和presentative（表示，呈现）构成，表示“代表性的，具有代表性的”。在这个例句中，它形容application scenarios，指这些应用场景具有代表性，可以代表中国数据产业的整体发展水平。</p>    </li>    <li>circulation (n.) - /ˌsɜːkjʊˈleɪʃən/ 流通，循环。    <p>原文例句：The digital economy still faces challenges including low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped applications potential.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自拉丁语circulus（圆圈），表示“流通，循环”。在这个例句中，它指的是数据的流通和循环，即数据在不同主体之间流动和转移的过程。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unleash economic value - 释放经济价值。    <p>原文例句：The goal was to unleash economic value while ensuring security and privacy.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由unleash（释放）和economic value（经济价值）构成，表示“释放经济价值”。在这个例句中，它指的目标是释放数据的经济价值，即通过数据的流通和利用创造经济效益。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms - 中国数字经济对 12 个行业的推动将目光投向金融、科技、农业。<p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是China’s digital economy push，谓语是sets sights on，宾语是finance, tech, farms。其中，sets sights on是一个习语，表示“将目光投向，瞄准”。在这个例句中，它表示中国数字经济的推动将把目光投向金融、科技和农业等12个行业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级和最高级 - 比较不同事物或事物的程度。    <p>原文例句：It will also increase efforts to have research institutions and leading enterprises build industry databases to create high quality datasets for training AI models. </p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级和最高级是形容词或副词的屈折变化形式，用于比较两个或多个事物或事物的程度。比较级用以比较两个事物或事物，最高级用以比较三个或三个以上事物或事物。在这个例句中，high quality是high（高）的比较级，表示“高质量的”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China aims to build more than 300 ‘representative’ application scenarios by 2026, and grow its data industry by 20 per cent every year</li>
<li>The digital economy still faces challenges including low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped applications potential</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/7195ef42-b909-415f-a96d-069d4c81cfa9_a08669f1.jpg" /><figcaption>A visitor shakes hands with a humanoid robot during the China International Digital Economy Expo 2023 in Hebei Province. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China’s newly established data administration, an agency created by Beijing to make data an effective production factor, has unveiled a three-year action plan to use the country’s massive troves of information to boost its economy.</p><p>According to the plan published by the National Data Administration (NDA) on Thursday, China aims to build more than 300 “representative” application scenarios by 2026, grow its data industry by 20 per cent every year, and multiply data trading volume.</p><p>The initiative is aimed at “cultivating” a new driving force for China’s economic development, leveraging the country’s advantages including a sizeable market, and abundant data resources and use cases, the NDA said.</p><p>The agency’s plan involves mobilising data resources to support development of China’s own artificial intelligence (AI) large language models - the technology used to train AI applications like ChatGPT. It will also increase efforts to have research institutions and leading enterprises build industry databases to create high quality datasets for training AI models.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" title="">China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms</a></h3><p>The blueprint comes at a time when China’s digital economy, having developed rapidly in recent years, still faces challenges including the low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped potential for applications, it said.</p><p>The NDA was announced in March last year as Beijing ramped up efforts in managing the country’s growing pool of data that is fragmented across different sectors and industries. The goal was to unleash economic value while ensuring security and privacy.</p><p>While the country’s internet watchdog, the Cyberspace Administration of China, has put in place laws and regulations governing data security, Beijing did not have a government body overseeing development policies for data until the establishment of the NDA.</p><p>The new administration, which officially began operations in October, is tasked with “coordinating and promoting the construction of data infrastructure, coordinating the integration, sharing, development and utilisation of data resources” across China’s economy and society, it said in March 2023.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246289/china-turns-spotlight-digital-economy-quest-common-prosperity-under-president-xi-jinping" title="">China’s focuses on digital economy to drive ‘common prosperity’ under Xi</a></h3><p>The agency, established under China’s top economic planner, the National Development and Reform Commission, is headed by information technology (IT) veteran Liu Liehong, former chairman of state-owned telecommunications network operator China Unicom.</p><p>The three-year plan will “guide and encourage” different types of private capital to invest in the data industry, and support data brokers in raising capital by going public.</p><p>The NDA also singled out 12 industries that should make better use of data, including manufacturing, agriculture, commerce, transport, finance and IT.</p><p>China’s new data strategies come as it seeks to catch up with the US in the development of AI, despite facing a host of challenges including restricted access to advanced chips.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong-listed Chinese miner CMOC takes Glencore’s cobalt crown as output jumps 170% in 2023</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247376/hong-kong-listed-chinese-miner-cmoc-takes-glencores-cobalt-crown-output-jumps-170-2023</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In 2023, CMOC Group became the largest cobalt producer globally, surpassing Glencore, with an output of 55,526 tonnes. The company's Kisanfu mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo played a significant role in achieving this increase, which contributed to a decline in global cobalt prices. The soaring production of cobalt, along with rising output in Indonesia and increased exports from CMOC's Tenke-Fungurume operation in Congo, led to a 30% drop in prices over the year. CMOC's copper production also witnessed a notable surge of 51%, solidifying its position among the top producers. The growing demand for cobalt in the production of electric vehicle batteries, fueled by the increasing popularity of EVs, particularly in China, is driving the expansion of the cobalt market. However, analysts predict a slowdown in EV sales growth in China from 30% in 2023 to 20% in 2024, though EVs are expected to make up a significant portion of global vehicle sales in the coming years.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: CMOC Group's increased cobalt and copper production impacts global markets.</li>    <li>Theme: CMOC's role as the world's leading cobalt producer and the impact of its Kisanfu mine on the cobalt market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of cobalt in electric vehicle batteries and the shifting dynamics of the global cobalt market.</li>    <li>Main information: CMOC's cobalt output surpasses Glencore's; Kisanfu mine's contribution to cobalt price decline; CMOC's strong copper production; growing demand for cobalt in EV batteries; projected slowdown in EV sales growth in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023年，CMOC集团以55,526吨的钴产量成为全球最大的钴生产商，超越了嘉能可。该公司位于刚果民主共和国的Kisanfu矿发挥了重要作用，帮助实现了这一增长，并导致全球钴价格下滑。钴产量飙升，加上印尼产量的增加以及CMOC在刚果的Tenke-Fungurume业务出口增加，导致全年价格下跌30%。CMOC的铜产量也大幅增长51%，巩固了其作为顶级生产商之一的地位。对钴的需求不断增长，用于生产电动汽车电池，而电动汽车的流行，尤其是在中国，正在推动钴市场不断扩张。然而，分析人士预测中国电动汽车销量增长会从2023年的30%放缓至2024年的20%，尽管预计电动汽车将在未来几年占全球汽车销量的很大一部分。    <ul>    <li>摘要：CMOC集团提高钴和铜产量影响全球市场。</li>    <li>主题：CMOC作为全球领先的钴生产商的作用及其Kisanfu矿对钴市场的影响。</li>    <li>观点：钴对电动汽车电池的重要性以及全球钴市场动态的变化。</li>    <li>主要信息：CMOC的钴产量超过嘉能可；Kisanfu矿对钴价下跌的贡献；CMOC强劲的铜产量；电动汽车电池对钴的需求增长；预计中国电动汽车销量增长放缓。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>surge (v.) - /sɜːdʒ/ 猛增，激增，飙升。    <p>原文例句：Soaring output at CMOC’s US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词表示“突然增加，猛增”。在这个例句中，它指的是Kisanfu矿的产量急剧增加，导致去年钴价大幅下跌。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>slump (n.) - /slʌmp/ 暴跌，突然下跌。    <p>原文例句：Soaring output at CMOC’s US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词表示“突然下降，暴跌”。在这个例句中，它指的是由于Kisanfu矿的产量激增，导致去年钴价大幅下跌。</p></li>  </ul>    </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>leapfrog (v.) - /ˈliːpfrɔːg/ 跳过，超越。    <p>原文例句：with surging production at a new mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo helping the company leapfrog Glencore as the world’s top producer of the key battery metal.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词表示“跳过，超越”。在这个例句中，它指的是CMOC集团通过在刚果民主共和国新矿山的产量激增，超越了嘉能可，成为全球最大的电池金属生产商。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>play a significant role - 发挥重大作用。    <p>原文例句：The company’s Kisanfu mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo played a significant role in achieving this increase</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“发挥重要的作用”。在这个例句中，它表示公司位于刚果民主共和国的Kisanfu矿在实现这一增长方面发挥了重要作用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>make up - 构成，组成。    <p>原文例句：China, the EV penetration rate exceeded 40 per cent in 2023 amid motorists’ rising penchant for environmentally friendly cars featuring autonomous driving technology and digital cockpits.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“构成，组成”。在这个例句中，它表示在2023年，随着车主对具有自动驾驶技术和数字座舱的环境友好汽车的偏好不断上升，中国的电动汽车渗透率超过了40%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>CMOC’s copper output also jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes, establishing it as one of the world’s top producers at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output. - CMOC的铜产量也增长了51%，达到419,539吨，使其成为全球顶级生产商之一，而此时许多矿商都在努力提高产量。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是CMOC’s copper output，谓语是jumped，宾语是by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes。at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output是一个时间状语，表示在许多矿商都在努力提高产量的时候。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去式 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Soaring output at CMOC’s US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去式的句子，表示飙升的产量在去年引发了钴价格的急剧下跌。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：CMOC Group boosted its cobalt output by more than 170 per cent last year</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时的句子，表示CMOC集团去年将钴产量提高了170%以上，现在仍在继续。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The company’s output of the key metal in EV batteries exceeded its own guidance by more than 20 per cent</li>
<li>Soaring output at CMOC’s US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/978ac785-70c2-47f2-8569-299b57f5feb3_f7bc69b7.jpg" /><figcaption>Excavators and drillers work in an open pit at Tenke Fungurume, a copper and cobalt mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>China’s CMOC Group boosted its cobalt output by more than 170 per cent last year, with surging production at a new mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo helping the company leapfrog Glencore as the world’s top producer of the key battery metal.</p><p>Hong Kong-listed CMOC produced 55,526 tonnes of cobalt in 2023, it said in a filing on Thursday. In October, Glencore forecast output of as much as 42,000 tonnes. While investors and traders had been expecting a large increase at CMOC’s massive Kisanfu mine – which came online in the second quarter – the full-year result exceeded the company’s own production guidance by more than 20 per cent.</p><p>Soaring output at the US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year, alongside rising production in Indonesia and a rebound in exports from CMOC’s other operation in Congo, Tenke-Fungurume. The market was already in one of its biggest ever surpluses as 2023 began, and the additional output helped drive a 30 per cent slump in prices over the year.</p><p>The mismatch between supply and demand became so acute that by midyear Glencore had started to stockpile surplus at its operations in Congo in a bid to bring the market back into balance. Glencore is set to announce its full production results next month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/bc0491e6-2aee-4541-8141-aa5c1fb6228a_1126e908.jpg" title="An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>CMOC’s copper output also jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes, establishing it as one of the world’s top producers at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output.</p><p>Cobalt is a material used in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3234469/global-ev-transition-accelerates-falling-battery-costs-hasten-purchase-price-parity-further-blow" target="_self" title="">NCM (lithium, nickel, cobalt and manganese) batteries</a> powering electric cars, which offer vehicles a longer driving range than nickel-based LFP (lithium, iron and phosphate) counterparts.</p><p>Global consultancy AlixPartners forecast in a research report in July that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicles (EVs)</a> would account for 34 per cent of global sales by 2028 and make up 61 per cent of sales in 2035, compared to 14 per cent in 2022.</p><p>In China, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243806/li-auto-xpeng-pace-chinese-ev-makers-race-towards-2023-sales-record-amid-all-time-high-monthly" target="_self" title="">EV penetration rate</a> exceeded 40 per cent in 2023 amid motorists’ rising penchant for environmentally friendly cars featuring autonomous driving technology and digital cockpits.</p><p>Mainland China is now the world’s largest automotive and EV market, with sales of battery-powered cars accounting for about 60 per cent of the global total.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246699/chinese-battery-maker-gotion-starts-making-energy-storage-packs-fremont-plant-kicking-made-america" title="">Chinese EV battery maker Gotion starts making energy storage packs in US</a></h3><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3237220/chinese-ev-makers-course-smashing-85-million-2023-sales-target-mainland-industry-players-and" target="_self" title="">Electric vehicle (EV) sales on the mainland</a>, however, are seen growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from the projected 30 per cent increase in 2023.</p><p>Seoul-based consultancy SNE Research said in a report last February that electric cars with a driving range of more than 300 kilometres were sold at about US$30,000, on par with prices of petrol-powered vehicles, which helped EVs gain popularity around the globe.</p><p><em>Additional reporting by</em> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/author/daniel-ren" target="_self" title=""><em>Daniel Ren</em></a></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Qualcomm unveils chip for mixed reality to compete with Apple’s Vision Pro</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247367/qualcomm-unveils-chip-mixed-reality-compete-apples-vision-pro</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Qualcomm has unveiled its Snapdragon XR2+ chip specifically designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets, aiming to compete with Apple's upcoming Vision Pro. Qualcomm's newest chip can support 12 or more high-definition cameras and will be utilized by Samsung and Google. The XR2+ features improved processors and graphics components, promising better image quality and reduced eye fatigue. It also has enhanced perception and eye tracking capabilities. Qualcomm anticipates announcements regarding the chip's integration from partners like Samsung and Google at CES next week, with products potentially available later this year.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Qualcomm unveils the Snapdragon XR2+ chip for VR/MR headsets, competing with Apple's Vision Pro.</li>    <li>Theme: The introduction of Qualcomm's XR2+ chip and its applications in virtual and mixed-reality devices.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Qualcomm's commitment to advancing VR/MR technology and its focus on improving user experience through enhanced chip capabilities.</li>    <li>Main information: The XR2+'s compatibility with multiple high-definition cameras, its integration in products by Samsung and Google, and its potential in addressing eye fatigue and motion sickness in VR/MR devices.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  高通公司发布了专为虚拟现实和混合现实头显设计的骁龙 XR2+ 芯片，旨在与苹果即将推出的 Vision Pro 竞争。高通最新的这款芯片支持多达 12 个或更多的高清摄像头，并将由三星和谷歌采用。XR2+ 具有升级的处理器和图形组件，保证更好的图像质量及缓解眼部疲劳。它还增强了感知和眼球追踪能力。高通预计将在下周的 CES 展会上与三星和谷歌等合作伙伴发布关于该款芯片集成的公告，搭载这款芯片的产品可能会在今年晚些时候上市。  <ul>    <li>摘要：高通发布骁龙 XR2+ 芯片用于 VR/MR 头显，对抗苹果的 Vision Pro。</li>    <li>主题：高通 XR2+ 芯片的推出及其在虚拟现实和混合现实设备中的应用。</li>    <li>观点：高通致力于推进 VR/MR 技术并专注于通过改进的芯片功能来提升用户体验。</li>    <li>主要信息：XR2+ 可兼容多种高清摄像头，集成在三星和谷歌的产品中，并且有可能解决 VR/MR 设备中的眼部疲劳和晕动症问题。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>headset (n.) - /ˈhɛdsɛt/ 头戴式耳机。    <p>原文例句：The Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：headset 是由 head（头部）和 set（集合）组成的复合词，意为“头戴的设备”。在本例中，它指的是虚拟现实和混合现实头戴式耳机。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>resolution (n.) - /ˌrɛzəˈluːʃən/ 分辨率，解析度。    <p>原文例句：Headsets with the XR2+ will use processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors to project 4K-resolution images on each lens.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：resolution 是由 re-（再次）和 solution（解决）组成的复合词，意为“解决，解析”。在本例中，它指的是图像的分辨率，即图像中的像素密度。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>as much as - 最多，高达。    <P>原文例句：Headsets with the XR2+ will use processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors.     </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由 as（像，如同）和 much as（一样）组成的，表示“最多，高达”。在这个例句中，它表示 XR2+ 头戴式耳机使用的处理器和图形组件比其前代产品最多提高了 20%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors, announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro.- 高通公司是最大的手机处理器制造商，该公司宣布推出专为虚拟现实和混合现实头戴式耳机设计的 Snapdragon XR2+ 芯片，它将与苹果即将推出的 Vision Pro 展开竞争。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是 Qualcomm announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip，其中主语是 Qualcomm，谓语是 announced，宾语是 the Snapdragon XR2+ chip。designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets 是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰 the Snapdragon XR2+ chip，表示这款芯片专为虚拟现实和混合现实头戴式耳机设计。that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro 是一个定语从句，修饰 Snapdragon XR2+ chip，表示这款芯片将与苹果即将推出的 Vision Pro 展开竞争。这个句子的意思是说，高通公司宣布推出专为虚拟现实和混合现实头戴式耳机设计的 Snapdragon XR2+ 芯片，它将与苹果即将推出的 Vision Pro 展开竞争。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示高通的芯片一直处于其他许多公司吸引消费者进入该类别的核心。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由主语以外的人或事物执行或造成的。    <p>原文例句：Headsets with the XR2+ will use processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个语态，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词。被动语态表示动作或状态是由主语以外的人或事物执行或造成的，强调动作或状态的接受者。在这个例句中，it表示带有 XR2+ 的头戴式耳机将使用比其前代产品多达 20% 的处理器和图形组件。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The chip design firm said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung and Google</li>
<li>Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off</li>
</ul><p>Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors, announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro.</p><p>The San Diego, California-based chip design firm said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung Electronics and Alphabet’s Google on products under development.</p><p>The market for devices that project information onto the user’s view of the physical world was fired up last year by Apple’s announcement that it would sell a mixed-reality headset. Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off.</p><p>Augmented reality imposes graphics and written content on top of a person’s view of the world. Virtual reality places a consumer in a closed digital world. Apple’s coming Vision Pro and Meta Platforms' most-recent Quest 3 headset mix the technologies. Previous versions of Qualcomm’s XR chip have been featured in devices from Microsoft and Meta.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3240824/can-virtual-reality-ease-surgery-fears-patients-hong-kong-study-may-have-answer" title="">Virtual reality could be key to easing fears in surgical patients: study</a></h3><p>Headsets with the XR2+ will use processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors to project 4K-resolution images on each lens, according to Qualcomm’s Said Bakadir, a senior director of product management.</p><p>That improvement in quality will ease eye fatigue from reading text, reduce the potential for motion sickness and let device makers implement new features, he said. The chip’s ability to handle more cameras will aid in-depth perception and the eye tracking required to orient the user in the real world and recognise items.</p><p>“A lot of people want more juice to do more things,” Bakadir said. “People want to push the platform even higher.”</p><p>Qualcomm is working with a number of partners in addition to Google and Samsung, and announcements from customers may come as soon as next week’s CES show with products available as early as this year, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>OpenAI in talks with dozens of publishers to license content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>OpenAI signs a multi-year licensing agreement for articles from Politico’s parent company, Axel Springer, as it seeks content to train its artificial intelligence (AI) models.</li>    <li>The company seeks to balance the need for updated data with concerns about data sourcing and copyright issues.</li>    <li>A lawsuit by The New York Times against OpenAI and Microsoft for using its articles without permission poses legal challenges and complicates OpenAI’s relationships with media companies.</li>    <li>OpenAI argues that its use of content for model training differs from traditional reproduction or replacement of content, while The New York Times insists on its right to control the use of its copyrighted material.</li>    <li>The outcome of the lawsuit could have significant implications for OpenAI's business model, its access to data, and its relationships with media organizations.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>OpenAI 与 Politico 的母公司 Axel Springer 签署了一项多年的授权协议，以获取文章，以用于培训其人工智能 (AI) 模型。</li>    <li>该公司寻求在对更新数据需求与对数据来源和版权问题关注之间取得平衡。</li>    <li>纽约时报对 OpenAI 和微软使用其文章未经许可提起诉讼，这让 OpenAI 面临法律挑战并让其与媒体公司的关系变得复杂。</li>    <li>OpenAI 认为其在模型训练中使用内容的方式与传统的内容复制或替换不同，而纽约时报坚持认为自己有权控制其受版权保护材料的使用。</li>    <li>诉讼的结果可能对 OpenAI 的商业模式、其获取数据的方式以及其与媒体组织的关系产生重大影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>license (n.) - /ˈlaɪsəns/ 许可证，执照。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自拉丁文licentia，意为“自由，允许”。在这个例句中，它指的是OpenAI 与 Politico 的母公司 Axel Springer 签署的一项多年的授权协议，以获取文章，以用于培训其人工智能 (AI) 模型。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>content (n.) - /ˈkɑːntent/ 内容，资料。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI is looking for content to train its artificial intelligence (AI) models.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自拉丁文contentus，意为“满足的，满足的东西”。在这个例句中，它指的是 OpenAI 正在寻找的内容，以用于培训其人工智能 (AI) 模型。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>artificial intelligence (n.) - /ˌɑːrtɪˈfɪʃəl ˌɪntɛlɪdʒəns/ 人工智能。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI is looking for content to train its artificial intelligence (AI) models.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是artificial（人工的）和intelligence（智能）的组合，意为“人工产生的智能”。在这个例句中，它指的是OpenAI 正在开发的人工智能系统或程序。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>strike a deal - 达成协议，达成交易。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI said it is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由strike（打击，罢工）和deal（交易，协议）组成，意为“达成协议，达成交易”。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI 正在与数十家出版商谈判，以达成授权其文章的协议。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>source data - 源数据，原始数据。    <p>原文例句：as it is balancing the need for updated, accurate data to build its models with growing scrutiny about where that data is sourced from.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由source（源，来源）和data（数据）组成，意为“源数据，原始数据”。在这个例句中，it 指 OpenAI，data 指 OpenAI 用于构建其模型的数据。这个词组表示 OpenAI 在努力平衡对更新、准确数据的需求与对数据来源的日益严格的审查之间。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars. - OpenAI 近期与 Politico 的母公司 Axel Springer 签订了一项多年授权协议，金额高达数千万美元。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是 OpenAI，谓语是 inked，宾语是 a multi-year licensing deal。with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer 是介词短语，作地点状语，表示与 Politico 的母公司 Axel Springer 签订协议。for tens of millions of dollars 是介词短语，作原因状语，表示花费数千万美元签订协议。这个句子的意思是说，OpenAI 近期与 Politico 的母公司 Axel Springer 签订了一项多年授权协议，金额高达数千万美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI has been making significant progress towards building a safe and beneficial AGI.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示OpenAI，been making significant progress towards building a safe and beneficial AGI表示OpenAI一直在取得重大进展，以构建一个安全且有益的通用人工智能。这个句子的意思是说，OpenAI 一直在取得重大进展，以构建一个安全且有益的通用人工智能。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的主语所承受。    <p>原文例句：ChatGPT is trained on a massive dataset of text and code.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个语态，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的第三种形式。被动语态表示动作或状态是由句子中的主语所承受，强调动作或状态的接受者。在这个例句中，ChatGPT 是主语，is trained 是谓语，on a massive dataset of text and code是介词短语，作状语，表示接受训练的数据集。这个句子的意思是说，ChatGPT 接受了一个包含大量文本和代码的数据集的训练。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars</li>
<li>One of the companies it had been in talks with, The New York Times, sued OpenAI and Microsoft for using articles without permission</li>
</ul><p>OpenAI said it is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles, a broader effort than was previously known, as the start-up looks for content to train its artificial intelligence (AI) models.</p><p>“We are in the middle of many negotiations and discussions with many publishers. They are active. They are very positive. They’re progressing well,” Tom Rubin, OpenAI’s chief of intellectual property and content, told Bloomberg News. “You’ve seen deals announced, and there will be more in the future.”</p><p>OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars, a person familiar with the matter previously told Bloomberg. In July, OpenAI announced an agreement with the Associated Press for an undisclosed amount. These deals are key to OpenAI’s future, as it is balancing the need for updated, accurate data to build its models with growing scrutiny about where that data is sourced from.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246524/chinese-ai-champion-sensetime-introduces-go-playing-robot-japan-south-korea" title="">Chinese AI champion SenseTime introduces Go playing robot to Japan, South Korea</a></h3><p>But last week, one of the companies it had been in talks with, The New York Times Co, sued OpenAI and Microsoft for using the publication’s articles without permission.</p><p>The suit poses an existential challenge to OpenAI’s business. If the Times wins the case, OpenAI may not only owe billions of dollars, but could also be forced to destroy any of its training data that includes work from the Times, a costly and complicated task. More immediately, however, the lawsuit complicates OpenAI’s deal-making efforts with the media industry.</p><p>“The current situation is vastly different than the situations that publishers faced in the past with search engines and social media,” Rubin said. “Here, the content is used for training a model. It’s not used to reproduce the content. It’s not used to replace the content.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246667/chinas-cloud-market-growth-plateaus-despite-big-ai-push" title="">China’s cloud market growth plateaus despite big AI push</a></h3><p>The Times, however, disagrees with OpenAI’s stance, arguing that ChatGPT is flat out copying its journalists’ work without paying for it.</p><p>In its lawsuit, the publisher showed examples in which ChatGPT spit out entire paragraphs of nearly verbatim text from The New York Times (although some have pointed out that in certain examples, it was specifically prompting ChatGPT to reproduce Times content). The publisher argues that is proof OpenAI used New York Times data.</p><p>“If Microsoft and OpenAI want to use our work for commercial purposes, the law requires that they first obtain our permission,” The New York Times said in a statement. “They have not done so.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong-based AI-driven company sells potential breast cancer drug in deal whose value could exceed US$500 million</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247263/hong-kong-based-ai-driven-company-sells-potential-breast-cancer-drug-deal-whose-value-could-exceed</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Insilico Medicine, an AI-driven drug discovery company based in Hong Kong, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group. </li>    <li>Stemline Therapeutics, a wholly owned unit of Menarini, will make a US$12 million upfront payment to Insilico under the agreement. </li>    <li>The combined value of the deal includes all development, regulatory, and commercial milestones. </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>香港的人工智能药物发现公司Insilico Medicine将用于治疗乳腺癌的候选药物售予意大利制药公司Menarini Group。 </li>    <li>根据协议，Menarini的全资子公司Stemline Therapeutics将向Insilico支付1200万美元的预付费用。 </li>    <li>这项交易的总价值包括所有开发、监管和商业里程碑。 </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>hormone-sensitive cancer 激素敏感性癌症    <p>原文例句：Breast cancer, a hormone-sensitive cancer, is the most common cancer worldwide, and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the WHO.</p>    <p>例句解释：激素敏感性癌症是指对激素治疗敏感的癌症，例如乳腺癌、卵巢癌和前列腺癌等。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>small molecule inhibitor 小分子抑制剂    <p>原文例句：Under the exclusive licensing agreement, Insilico has granted Stemline the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule KAT6A inhibitor as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers and other oncology indications.</p>   <p>例句解释：小分子抑制剂是指能够抑制靶蛋白活性的低分子量化合物，常被用作药物或药靶。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>AI-driven 人工智能驱动的    <p>原文例句：Insilico Medicine, a Hong Kong-based AI-driven drug discovery company that intends to list in Hong Kong after it unveiled an initial public offering plan (IPO) last year, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group in a deal that could reach a value of over US$500 million.</p>    <p>例句解释：人工智能驱动的药物发现是指利用人工智能技术来加速新药的发现过程。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>develop and commercialise 开发和商业化    <p>原文例句：Under the exclusive licensing agreement, Insilico has granted Stemline the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule KAT6A inhibitor as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers and other oncology indications.</p>    <p>例句解释：开发和商业化是指将新药从实验室研究阶段推进到临床试验阶段，并最终将其推向市场。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>preclinical drug candidate 临床前候选药物    <p>原文例句：Insilico Medicine, a Hong Kong-based AI-driven drug discovery company that intends to list in Hong Kong after it unveiled an initial public offering plan (IPO) last year, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group in a deal that could reach a value of over US$500 million.</p>    <p>例句解释：临床前候选药物是指尚未进入临床试验阶段的新药候选化合物。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>compound annual growth rate (CAGR) 复合年增长率    <p>原文例句：The AI-driven drug discovery market is projected to grow at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 23.72 per cent from 2023 to 2030, reaching an estimated value of US$7.1 billion by 2030, according to US-based Vantage Market Research.</p>    <p>例句解释：复合年增长率是指在一定时期内，每年平均增长的百分比。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Breast cancer, a hormone-sensitive cancer, is the most common cancer worldwide, and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the WHO.乳腺癌是一种激素敏感性癌症，是全世界最常见的癌症，也是导致女性癌症死亡的首要原因，根据世界卫生组织的数据。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复句，主句是Breast cancer is the most common cancer worldwide，其中主语是Breast cancer，谓语是is，宾语是the most common cancer worldwide。一个定语从句是a hormone-sensitive cancer，修饰主语Breast cancer，表示乳腺癌是一种激素敏感性癌症。另一个定语从句是and the leading cause of cancer death among women，修饰主语Breast cancer，表示乳腺癌是导致女性癌症死亡的首要原因。这个句子的意思是说，乳腺癌是全世界最常见的癌症，也是导致女性癌症死亡的首要原因，根据世界卫生组织的数据。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>一般现在时 - 表示现在发生或存在的事物或状态。    <p>原文例句：Insilico Medicine, a Hong Kong-based AI-driven drug discovery company that intends to list in Hong Kong after it unveiled an initial public offering plan (IPO) last year, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group in a deal that could reach a value of over US$500 million.</p>    <p>语法讲解：一般现在时用于描述现在发生或存在的事物或状态。其结构是：主语 + be动词（am/is/are）+ 其他。在这个例句中，be动词是has，它与主语Insilico Medicine一起，表示Insilico Medicine已经出售了其用于治疗乳腺癌的临床前候选药物。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Stemline Therapeutics, a wholly owned unit of Menarini, will make a US$12 million upfront payment to Insilico under the agreement, which will be followed by sales royalties worth up to “double digits”.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时用于表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。其结构是：主语 + have/has + 过去分词。在这个例句中，主语是Stemline Therapeutics，过去分词是made，它与have一起，表示Stemline Therapeutics已经支付了1200万美元的预付款，并将继续支付销售提成。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Insilico grants Italy’s Menarini Group, the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule inhibitor, as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers</li>
<li>Breast cancer, a hormone-sensitive cancer, is the most common cancer worldwide, and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the WHO</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/0aa273cd-964f-49d2-be3b-69223d5b9a88_d8bebbd1.jpg" /><figcaption>null</figcaption></figure><p>Insilico Medicine, a Hong Kong-based AI-driven drug discovery company that intends to list in Hong Kong after it unveiled an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3225736/hong-kong-based-biotech-insilico-medicine-shifts-ipo-plan-city-new-york" target="_self" title="">initial public offering plan</a> (IPO) last year, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group in a deal that could reach a value of over US$500 million.</p><p>Stemline Therapeutics, a wholly owned unit of Menarini, will make a US$12 million upfront payment to Insilico under the agreement, which will be followed by sales royalties worth up to “double digits”. The combined value of the deal includes all development, regulatory, and commercial milestones.</p><p>The agreement comes at a time when cutting-edge technology is playing a greater role in drug discovery. AI has emerged as a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery by enhancing efficiency and accuracy while reducing the time-consuming aspects of research and development, experts say.</p><p>The AI-driven drug discovery market is projected to grow at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 23.72 per cent from 2023 to 2030, reaching an estimated value of US$7.1 billion by 2030, according to US-based Vantage Market Research.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/8d6c5116-f305-4968-8ef3-f757c1373823_34f54c2a.jpg" title="An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The technology expedites the process of identifying potential drugs, according to Insilico’s founder and co-CEO, Dr Alex Zhavoronkov.</p><p>Under the exclusive licensing agreement, Insilico has granted Stemline the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule KAT6A inhibitor as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers and other oncology indications.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3199001/sanofi-signs-research-tie-hong-kongs-insilico-medicine-accelerate-ai-powered-drug-discovery" title="">Sanofi signs with Hong Kong biotech firm Insilico to spur AI drug discovery</a></h3><p>Breast cancer is the most common cancer worldwide and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the World Health Organization.</p><p>The global breast cancer market is projected to hit around US$73.68 billion by 2032 with a registered CAGR of 9.9 per cent, according to Precedence Research.</p><p>“The partnership at the early stage preclinical trial is truly optimal when the partner is very committed,” said Zhavoronkov.</p><p>Menarini, an international pharmaceutical and diagnostics company with a turnover of more than US$4.4 billion and operations in 140 countries, sees the collaboration with Insilico as an opportunity to explore new treatment approaches and potentially unlock transformative cancer therapies, according to CEO Elcin Barker Ergun.</p><p>Insilico, founded by Zhavoronkov in 2014, has a pipeline that consists of 31 programmes for 29 drug targets in cancer, fibrosis, immunity, central nervous system and ageing-related diseases.</p><p>In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence.</p><p>Zhavoronkov declined to reveal a timeline for its IPO but said market sentiment was a concern.</p><p>Insilico has a presence in the markets of the US, Greater China, Canada and the Middle East. It launched the Generative AI and Quantum Computing Research and Development Center in Abu Dhabi in February 2023.</p><p>To date, the company has raised more than US$400 million via private markets. In 2022, it secured series D financing of US$95 million from investors such as Prosperity7, a growth venture fund of Saudi Arabia’s Aramco, and others including B Capital Group, Warburg Pincus, and Hong Kong-based Qiming Ventures.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
