<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Microsoft to show off Copilot AI key for Windows keyboards at CES, in first change to layout since 1994</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247280/microsoft-show-copilot-ai-key-windows-keyboards-ces-first-change-layout-1994</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In order to promote its AI development and application, Microsoft plans to add a dedicated Copilot key to Windows keyboards. This new key will enable users to quickly access Microsoft's AI assistant, allowing them to generate content, write emails, and summarize text with ease. Microsoft believes that 2024 will be the year of the AI PC and has spent the past year integrating AI technology into its major products.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Microsoft introduces a Copilot key to Windows keyboards for easy access to AI assistance.</li>    <li>Theme: Microsoft's commitment to integrating AI into its Windows operating system and products.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of AI technology in shaping the future of personal computing.</li>    <li>Main information: The Copilot key's position and function; Microsoft's focus on AI-powered devices; leveraging GPT-4 technology; the potential impact on hardware sales.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  为了推动其人工智能的发展和应用，微软计划在 Windows 键盘中增加一个专用的 Copilot 键。这个新按键将允许用户快速访问微软的人工智能助手，从而轻松地生成内容，撰写电子邮件并总结文本。微软认为，2024 年将成为人工智能电脑的元年，并已花费了过去一年时间在其主要产品中集成了人工智能技术。  <ul>    <li>摘要：微软在 Windows 键盘中引入 Copilot 键，以便轻松访问人工智能助手。</li>    <li>主题：微软致力于将人工智能集成到其 Windows 操作系统和产品中。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能技术在塑造个人计算未来方面的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：Copilot 键的位置和功能；微软对人工智能设备的关注；利用 GPT-4 技术；对硬件销售的潜在影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>underscore (v.) - /ˈʌndərsˌskɔːr/ 强调，强调。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft’s hardware partners will show off Windows 11 computers with the Copilot button over the coming days at the CES technology conference and, over time, it will become a required feature. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由under（在……之下）和score（划线，分数）构成的，表示“ подчеркивать, подчеркивать”。在这个例句中，它指的是微软的硬件合作伙伴将在 CES 技术大会上展示搭载 Copilot 按钮的 Windows 11 电脑，并且它将成为一项必需的功能。这个单词的使用给句子增加了一种正式感和强调感，表明微软对 Copilot 功能的重視程度。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>touts (v.) - /taʊt/ 夸耀，吹嘘。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft touts booming enterprise AI demand in Hong Kong amid cloud push.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old Norse，表示“ говорить, 吹嘘”。在这个例句中，它指的是微软吹嘘其企业人工智能在香港的需求量正在蓬勃发展。这个单词的使用表明微软对企业人工智能市场充满信心，也表明微软正在积极宣传其企业人工智能产品。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>short cut - 捷径，快速方式。    <P>原文例句：The short cut will help users create images, write emails and summarise text with the help of AI. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由short（短）和cut（剪，切）构成的，表示“捷径，快一点，快速的方式”。在这个例句中，它指的是这种快捷方式将帮助用户在人工智能的帮助下创建图像、撰写电子邮件和总结文本。这个词组的使用表明微软正在努力使 Copilot 功能易于使用和方便访问。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change.    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware”，其中主语是AI，谓语是will be woven，宾语是into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware。Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change是一个插入语，提供有关该声明的背景信息或来源。这个句子的意思是说，从系统、硅到硬件，人工智能将与 Windows 无缝集成，微软的消费者首席营销官 Yusuf Mehdi 在一篇博文中宣布了这一改变。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式短语 - 用来说明目的、原因、结果或方式。    <p>原文例句：The work heavily leverages the GPT-4 technology from OpenAI, in which Microsoft has invested US$13 billion. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个不定式短语，由不定词leverages和介词短语in which Microsoft has invested US$13 billion组成。不定词leverages表示“利用，利用”，介词短语in which Microsoft has invested US$13 billion表示“微软投资了 130 亿美元”。这个短语的使用表明微软正在利用 OpenAI 的 GPT-4 技术进行大量投资和开发，从而加强其 AI 功能。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示微软在过去的一年中一直在重新调整其最大的产品，使其围绕着可以生成新内容的人工智能技术进行。这个时态的使用表明微软正在致力于其人工智能技术的开发和应用，并且这一过程仍在持续进行中。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Start key</li>
<li>The tech giant sees 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’ and has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/e31b152f-c194-4f64-8148-b14c9b1dd6e5_1adc5e70.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft said it is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to allow users to immediately call up its artificial intelligence assistant. Photo: YouTube / Windows</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft</a> is adding a button to the Windows keyboard to activate its AI Copilot service, with the first devices to sport the new key available this month.</p><p>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Windows/Start key in 1994, underscoring the company’s commitment to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a>. Microsoft’s hardware partners will show off Windows 11 computers with the Copilot button over the coming days at the CES technology conference and, over time, it will become a required feature.</p><p>The short cut will help users create images, write emails and summarise text with the help of AI.</p><p>“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234530/microsoft-sees-booming-enterprise-ai-demand-hong-kong-amid-us-china-tech-war-threatens-cloud" title="">Microsoft touts booming enterprise AI demand in Hong Kong amid cloud push</a></h3><p>The Redmond, Washington-based company sees 2024 as “the year of the AI PC”, according to Mehdi, mirroring the budding trend among smartphone makers to tout their latest models as “AI phones”. Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves, but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets. That list now includes Windows, Office, Bing search, security software and customer and finance products. The work heavily leverages the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">GPT-4 technology</a> from OpenAI, in which Microsoft has invested US$13 billion.</p><p>For device makers, Microsoft’s push into AI services has not yet translated into a boost for sales, as the novel Copilot features are being rolled out to new and existing devices alike. Mehdi’s promise of weaving AI into hardware and silicon may signal more pressure on consumers to upgrade as Microsoft evolves and improves its AI proposition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TikTok eyes US$17.5 billion shopping business on Amazon’s turf</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247219/tiktok-eyes-us175-billion-shopping-business-amazons-turf</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  TikTok plans to grow its US e-commerce business tenfold to US$17.5 billion in 2024, challenging Amazon, Temu and Shein.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: TikTok expands its e-commerce business in the US, aims to grow tenfold.</li>    <li>Theme: TikTok's ambitious target to grow its US e-commerce business.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: TikTok's competitive advantages and challenges.</li>    <li>Main information: TikTok's target of US$17.5 billion in US sales, strategies like free shipping and subsidies, shift from promotions to revenue generation, and target audience of younger American shoppers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  TikTok 计划将其在美国的电子商务业务增长 10 倍，达到 175 亿美元，以挑战亚马逊、Temu 和希音。  <ul>    <li>摘要：TikTok 扩大其在美国的电子商务业务，目标十倍增长。</li>    <li>主题：TikTok 雄心勃勃地扩大其在美国的电子商务业务。</li>    <li>观点：TikTok 的竞争优势和面临的挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：TikTok 在美国销售额 175 亿美元的目标、免费送货和补贴等策略、从促销到创收的转变以及目标受众年轻美国购物者。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>amass (v.) - /əˈmæs/ 积累，聚集。    <p>原文例句：TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于古诺斯语，意思是“收集，聚集”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok去年有望在全球范围内积累约200亿美元的商品总价值，其中东南亚贡献了大部分销售额。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>gross merchandise value (GMV) (n.) - /ˌɡrəʊs ˈmɜːrtʃəndaɪz ˌvæljuː/ 商品总价值。    <p>原文例句：TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词是由gross（总计，全部），merchandise（商品），value（价值）组成的，表示“商品总价值”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok去年有望在全球范围内积累约200亿美元的商品总价值。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>ecommerce (n.) - /ˈiːkɑːmɜːs/ 电子商务。    <p>原文例句：According to estimates, TikTok's e-commerce operations in the US account for about 60 billion yuan.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词是由electronic（电子的）和commerce（商业）构成的，表示“电子商务”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok在美国的电子商务业务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>social media (n.) - /ˌsəʊʃəl ˈmiːdɪə/ 社交媒体。    <p>原文例句：TikTok, the global hit short-video platform owned by ByteDance, aims to grow the size of its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, according to people familiar with the matter, posing a bigger threat to Amazon.com.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词是由social（社会的）和media（媒体）组成的，表示“社交媒体”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok这个全球热门的短视频平台。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>impulse buying (n.) - 冲动购买。    <p>原文例句：The 2024 merchandise volume goal for the US version of TikTok Shop – which melds online entertainment with impulse buying – was discussed in internal meetings in recent weeks and may still change depending on how the business goes, said the people, who asked not to be named discussing private information.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词是由impulse（冲动）和buying（购买）构成的，表示“冲动购买”。在这个例句中，it指的是TikTok Shop即将于2024年在美国推出的电子商务平台的目标销售额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance’s revenue surged roughly 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing the projected growth of far more established social media rivals Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings. - 字节跳动 2023 年的收入猛增约 30%，超过 1100 亿美元，超过了更成熟的社交媒体竞争对手 Meta Platforms 和腾讯控股预计的增长。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是ByteDance’s revenue surged roughly 30 per cent，其中主语是ByteDance’s revenue，谓语是surged，宾语是roughly 30 per cent。in 2023 to more than US$110 billion是一个时间状语和目的状语，表示字节跳动 2023 年的收入猛增至超过 1100 亿美元。outpacing the projected growth of far more established social media rivals Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings是一个并列状语，表示字节跳动 2023 年的收入猛增超过了更成熟的社交媒体竞争对手 Meta Platforms 和腾讯控股预计的增长。这个句子的意思是说，字节跳动 2023 年的收入猛增约 30%，超过 1100 亿美元，超过了更成熟的社交媒体竞争对手 Meta Platforms 和腾讯控股预计的增长。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式短语作宾语 - 在句中充当宾语的不定式短语。    <p>原文例句：TikTok plans to grow its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, according to people familiar with the matter. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个结构是：to + 动词原形 + 其他。其中to是介词，动词原形是动词的基本形式，其他是宾语。这个结构可以作宾语，表示动作或状态的目的、原因或结果。在这个例句中，to grow its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year是一个不定式短语作宾语，表示TikTok计划将今年的美国电子商务业务增长十倍，达到175亿美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示TikTok Shop允许用户在滚动浏览源源不断的短视频和直播时购买商品，这一动作从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon, but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein</li>
<li>TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales</li>
</ul><p>TikTok, the global hit short-video platform owned by ByteDance, aims to grow the size of its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, according to people familiar with the matter, posing a bigger threat to Amazon.com.</p><p>The 2024 merchandise volume goal for the US version of TikTok Shop – which melds online entertainment with impulse buying – was discussed in internal meetings in recent weeks and may still change depending on how the business goes, said the people, who asked not to be named discussing private information.</p><p>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon but also fellow Chinese-owned budget retail outfits Temu and Shein, which have been making big strides among younger American shoppers.</p><p>Unlike its two rival discounters, TikTok is counting on its social media reach and the appeal of viral videos to hook buyers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales through its platform, Bloomberg News reported. The company is now seeking to expand sales across the US and Latin America, where it is planning to launch the e-commerce operation in coming months, two people familiar with the matter said.</p><p>“The speculated US merchandise sales figures represented by Bloomberg are inaccurate,” TikTok said in a statement.</p><p>ByteDance, founded more than a decade ago by Zhang Yiming and Liang Rubo, grew into an internet leader worth more than US$200 billion thanks to the virality of short-video platforms TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin. TikTok Shop is one of the fastest-growing features for the Beijing-based, closely held company, which is seeking a new growth driver beyond social-media advertising. ByteDance’s revenue surged roughly 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing the projected growth of far more established social media rivals Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings.</p><p>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams within its main social media app, hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee. That format – an effort to combine the ease of shopping on Amazon with the product discovery afforded by apps like Meta’s Instagram – has already helped Douyin snatch a significant portion of Chinese consumer spending from Alibaba Group Holding and JD.com, particularly after lockdown rules during the pandemic drove people to spend more time online. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/80b40a96-5660-44d3-a756-f6c48d3cb312_1126e908.jpg" title="TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>ByteDance is intent on exporting its e-commerce model globally. In the US, TikTok is offering free shipping and subsidies to influencers who peddle gadgets, clothes and make-up in videos and live streams. In November, boosted by Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals, more than 5 million new US customers bought something on TikTok, the company said. It has roughly 150 million users in the country.</p><p>TikTok on Wednesday announced it will increase fees imposed on merchants to 6 per cent of each sale beginning in April and to 8 per cent in July in most product categories, marking an end to promotions used to entice sellers. Those commissions are still significantly lower than Amazon seller fees, which are typically about 15 per cent, but the boost signals TikTok is quickly moving to generate revenue from its e-commerce platform.</p><p>Americans are increasingly comfortable shopping on Chinese e-commerce apps, including the popular fashion site Shein and PDD Holdings' Temu, which has exploded in popularity since airing a Super Bowl ad in February.</p><p>It is unclear what sales targets TikTok Shop has set globally or for other markets. In Indonesia, TikTok has taken control of GoTo Group’s e-commerce unit Tokopedia in a US$1.5 billion deal, which allowed the company to restart its online retail service after months of scrutiny by the local government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247211/apple-leads-us383-billion-tech-rout-reversal-groups-2023-rally</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Magnificent Seven, a group of large tech stocks including Apple, Amazon, Alphabet, Microsoft, Meta Platforms, Tesla, and Nvidia, experienced a decline in the first trading days of 2024.</li>    <li>This losing streak, spanning four days, erased US$383 billion in market value from the group.</li>    <li>Investor concerns over the sustainability of the 2023 rally and the Federal Reserve's ability to achieve a soft landing for the US economy contributed to the selloff.</li>    <li>Apple shares were particularly affected by a downgrade from Barclays analysts, who predicted weaker demand for iPhones.</li>    <li>Tesla's position as the top seller of electric vehicles was surpassed by China's BYD, despite reporting strong delivery numbers in the fourth quarter.</li>    <li>Analysts believe that the tech giants need to continue delivering profitable technology to regain investor confidence.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>由苹果、亚马逊、Alphabet、微软、Meta Platforms、特斯拉和英伟达等大型科技股组成的七大巨头，在 2024 年的第一个交易日中集体下跌。</li>    <li>这一持续四天的下跌行情，使得七大巨头的市值蒸发了 3830 亿美元。</li>    <li>投资者对于 2023 年涨势的可持续性以及美联储实现经济软着陆的能力感到担忧，是导致此次抛售的原因之一。</li>    <li>苹果股价受到巴克莱分析师降级的特别影响，他们预计 iPhone 的需求疲软。</li>    <li>尽管特斯拉报告称第四季度交付的电动汽车数量超出分析师预期，但其全球电动汽车销量第一的位置被中国比亚迪超越。</li>    <li>分析师认为，科技巨头需要持续提供盈利的技术，才能重新获得投资者的信心。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>frenzy (n.) - /ˈfrɛnzi/ - 狂热，狂躁。    <p>原文例句：Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“frenzy”意为“狂热，狂躁”，强调一种强烈的兴奋和激动。在这个语境中，“frenzy”具体指代电动汽车市场的激烈竞争和对电动汽车的热烈需求。</p></li>    <li>recoup (v.) - /rɪˈkuːp/ - 弥补，恢复。    <p>原文例句：Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier</p>    <p>例句讲解：“recoup”意为“弥补，恢复”，强调通过某些手段将先前遭受的损失或亏损弥补回来。在这个语境中，“recoup”具体指代科技股试图弥补2022年的损失。</p></li>    <li>profitability (n.) - /prɑːfɪˈtæbəlɪti/ - 盈利能力，获利性。    <p>原文例句：The companies need to continue to deliver not only solid technology, but profitable technology going forward, according to Sosnick.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“profitability”意为“盈利能力，获利性”，强调企业或项目能够产生利润的能力。在这个语境中，“profitability”具体指代科技公司持续提供能够带来利润的技术产品或服务的能力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>losing streak -  连续亏损    <p>原文例句：The so-called Magnificent Seven, which includes Apple, Amazon.com, Alphabet, Microsoft, Meta Platforms, Tesla and Nvidia, slipped for the last four trading days, the longest losing streak in a month</p>    <p>例句讲解：“losing streak”意为“连续亏损”，强调一段时间内连续出现亏损或负面业绩。在这个语境中，“losing streak”具体指代科技股连续四天出现下跌。</p></li>    <li>soft landing -  软着陆    <p>原文例句：Though the Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023 as investors mulled the Federal Reserve’s ability to execute a soft landing for the US economy</p>    <p>例句讲解：“soft landing”意为“软着陆”，强调经济在经历一段时间衰退或低迷后，能够平稳地恢复到增长状态。在这个语境中，“soft landing”具体指代美联储能否在不引发经济衰退的情况下控制通货膨胀。</p></li>    <li>all-time high - 历史最高点    <p>原文例句：Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier, and some of the group – Amazon, Alphabet, Meta and Tesla – are still below their all-time highs, signalling they could have room to run.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“all-time high”意为“历史最高点”，强调某项资产或指标达到其历史以来的最高水平。在这个语境中，“all-time high”具体指代科技股在2023年创下的历史最高股价。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Shares of Apple, down 4.6 per cent in the time period, lead the slump that has erased US$383 billion in market value.    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Shares of Apple，谓语是lead the slump，宾语是that has erased US$383 billion in market value。介词短语in the time period表示“在这个时间段内”。介词短语that has erased US$383 billion in market value是一个定语从句，修饰先行词slump，表示“已经抹去了3830亿美元的市值”。这个句子告诉我们，苹果公司的股价在一段时间内下跌了4.6%，引领了抹去3830亿美元市值的跌势。</p></li>    <li>But, the largest tech names also have their work cut out for them in 2024.    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是the largest tech names，谓语是have their work cut out for them in 2024。介词短语in 2024表示“在2024年”。分词短语have their work cut out for them表示“有艰巨的任务”。这个句子告诉我们，在2024年，最大的科技公司也面临着艰巨的任务。</p></li>    <li>“In December everyone bought the sizzle,” he said. “Now we have to see if the steak is any good.”    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，由两个简单句组成，用逗号分隔。第一个简单句的主语是everyone，谓语是bought the sizzle。第二个简单句的主语是we，谓语是have to see if the steak is any good。连词Now表示“现在”。介词短语if the steak is any good表示“牛排是否好吃”。这个句子告诉我们，在12月份，每个人都购买了“炒作”，而现在我们必须看看“牛排”是否好吃。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Gerunds - 动名词    <p>原文例句：Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets.</p>    <p>语法讲解：动名词是指以-ing结尾的动词形式，它可以充当名词，在句子中担任主语、宾语、表语或定语等成分。在这个例句中，动名词market作主语，表示“市场”。</p></li>    <li>Comparative and superlative adjectives - 比较级和最高级形容词    <p>原文例句：The Nasdaq 100 Index has also fallen in the last four trading days.    <p>语法讲解：比较级和最高级形容词用于比较两个或多个事物或人。比较级形容词表示“更加”，最高级形容词表示“最”。在这个例句中，形容词last作比较级，表示“最后”。</p></li>    <li>Passive voice - 被动语态    <p>原文例句：Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier.    <p>语法讲解  <ul><li>The Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023</li>
<li>Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD</li>
</ul><p>The largest technology stocks that lifted the broader market last year are having a less-rosy start to 2024.</p><p>The so-called Magnificent Seven, which includes Apple, Amazon.com, Alphabet, Microsoft, Meta Platforms, Tesla and Nvidia, slipped for the last four trading days, the longest losing streak in a month, according to the Bloomberg Magnificent 7 Price Return Index.</p><p>Shares of Apple, down 4.6 per cent in the time period, lead the slump that has erased US$383 billion in market value. The Nasdaq 100 Index has also fallen in the last four trading days.</p><p>“We don’t know if last year’s rally has fully ended, but it is completely normal to expect markets will pull back after a rally like we saw,” said Steve Sosnick, chief strategist at Interactive Brokers Group. “Without the year-end factors that turbocharged the rally, I think we’re seeing the party winding down.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" title="">Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets</a></h3><p>It is a signal that investor doubts over the sticking power of the 2023 rally were well-placed.</p><p>Though the Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023 as investors mulled the Federal Reserve’s ability to execute a soft landing for the US economy, which would likely mean fewer interest rate cuts than expected.</p><p>“You’re not going to get high-single-digit or double-digit earnings growth if we get something worse than a soft landing,” Sosnick said. “But we’re not going to get six cuts with a soft landing.”</p><p>A few members of the group have also seen specific stock pressure early this year. Apple shares have been weighed down after gaining a new bear; Barclays analysts early this week downgraded shares of the tech giant to underweight, saying they expect soft demand for iPhones going forward.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" title="">Apple hits 7-week low after Barclays downgrade on demand concerns</a></h3><p>Tesla has shed 8.8 per cent in the last four days, its longest streak of losses in more than four weeks. Though Tesla reported on Tuesday that it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as the top seller of electric cars to China’s BYD.</p><p>To be sure, it is likely too early to say the tech-focused rally is over. Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier, and some of the group – Amazon, Alphabet, Meta and Tesla – are still below their all-time highs, signalling they could have room to run.</p><p>But, the largest tech names also have their work cut out for them in 2024. The companies need to continue to deliver not only solid technology, but profitable technology going forward, according to Sosnick.</p><p>“In December everyone bought the sizzle,” he said. “Now we have to see if the steak is any good.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>New refund policies from Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com spark fears of customer abuse among merchants</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247168/new-refund-policies-alibabas-taobao-and-jdcom-spark-fears-customer-abuse-among-merchants</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  淘宝、京东相继推出新的退货政策，消费者可申请仅退款并保留产品，引发商家担忧。一些商家担心，消费者可能会滥用该政策，影响其经营。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: E-commerce platforms introduce controversial refund policy allowing buyers to keep items after receiving a refund. </li>    <li>Theme: Concerns over the potential abuse of the new "refund only" policies by consumers, leading to financial losses for merchants.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Some merchants feel that the new policy favors consumers and can be exploited. They fear that it may increase the number of refund claims and burden merchants with higher costs.</li>    <li>Main information: Alibaba's Taobao and JD.com offer "refund only" option for dissatisfied customers in certain cases, but merchants express concerns about abuse and fear of being penalized by platforms. Some merchants have voiced their anger on social media, criticizing the potential for the policy to be taken advantage of by dishonest buyers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  淘宝、京东相继推出了新的退货政策，允许消费者在对产品不满意的情况下申请仅退款并保留产品。这一政策引发了一些商家的担忧，他们担心消费者可能会滥用该政策，从而影响他们的经营。  <ul>    <li>摘要：电商平台推出有争议的退货政策，允许买家在收到退款后仍保留商品。</li>    <li>主题：消费者可能滥用新的“仅退款”政策，导致商家蒙受经济损失，从而引发担忧。</li>    <li>观点：部分商家认为新政策偏袒消费者且容易被利用。他们担心这可能会增加退款索赔的数量，并给商家带来更高的成本负担。</li>    <li>主要信息：阿里巴巴旗下的淘宝和京东在某些情况下为不满意商品的消费者提供“仅退款”选项，但商家对该政策的滥用和来自平台的惩罚表示担忧。一些商家在社交媒体上表达了愤怒，批评不诚实的买家可能利用该政策。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>abuse (n.) - /əˈbjuːs/ 滥用，误用，损害。    <p>原文例句：Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse under new refund policies. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，由a-（表示否定）和use（使用）构成，即“错误或过度使用，滥用”。在这个例句中，它指的是一些商家对新退货政策下可能出现的滥用行为表示担忧。 </p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>spark (v.) - /spɑːrk/ 引发，激发，点燃。    <p>原文例句：New “refund only” policies introduced by Chinese e-commerce players including Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao and JD.com have sparked concern among some sellers about potential abuse of the terms, according to merchants and analysts.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于Middle English，由spark（火花）演变而来，表示“突然发生或爆发，引发，激发”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国电商平台新出台的“仅退款”政策引发了一些卖家对可能存在的条款滥用行为的担忧。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>based on - 以……为基础。    <p>原文例句：Both Taobao and JD.com have said that any decisions on refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由based（基于）和on（在……之上）构成的，表示“以……为基础，以……为依据”。在这个例句中，它指的是淘宝和京东表示，平台上的任何退款请求决定都将基于多个指标，包括商家的销售记录和买家的购买记录，以及大数据分析来支持判断。 </p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>run a shop - 经营一家商店。    <p>原文例句：The 33-year-old online shop owner, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of retribution from the platforms, said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products, because they will bear higher costs in the event of more claims.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由run（经营）和shop（商店）构成的，表示“经营一家商店”。在这个例句中，它指的是这位33岁的网上店主表示，新退货政策可能会适得其反，并打击那些投资于高品质产品的卖家，因为在索赔增加的情况下，他们将承担更高的成本。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li> JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy - 京东、阿里巴巴的淘宝推出“仅退款”政策，以对抗拼多多的策略。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，由两个独立结构组成：JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy和to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy。其中，JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy是主句，主语是JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao，谓语是push，宾语是‘refund only’ policy。to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy是一个目的状语从句，表示京东、阿里巴巴的淘宝推出“仅退款”政策的目的或意图，即是为了对抗拼多多的策略。这个句子的意思是说，京东、阿里巴巴的淘宝推出“仅退款”政策，以对抗拼多多的策略。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间之前发生的或持续到过去某个时间的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：By following this [Pinduoduo] refund policy … [rival platforms] will give their merchants a dilemma, he added.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去完成时的句子，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词形式。这种时态表示在过去某个时间之前发生或持续到过去某个时间的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的完成性或结果。在这个例句中，它表示在遵循这个[拼多多]退货政策之后…[竞争平台]会让他们的商家进退两难，这个句子强调了在遵循这个退货政策之后商家所面临的困境。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 强调句子中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：This refund terms only works for merchants who sell dirt-cheap goods,” she said, adding that the policy clearly favoured consumers. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句型，结构是：强调成分 + be + 主语 + 其他。其中强调成分可以是名词、形容词、副词等，强调句型句子强调了句中某个成分的信息。在这个例句中，强调成分是This refund terms，强调了这个退款条款只适用于那些销售廉价商品的商家，这个句子强调了这个退款条款适用于哪些商家。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Taobao and JD.com have introduced policies that allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it</li>
<li>Some merchants have raised concerns that consumers may look to exploit the terms of these ‘refund only’ policies, hitting their operations</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/85b29bec-f2e3-42ad-ba41-d20ec559a707_664d3160.jpg" /><figcaption>Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse under new refund policies. Photo: SCMP</figcaption></figure><p>New “refund only” policies introduced by Chinese e-commerce players including Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao and JD.com have sparked concern among some sellers about potential abuse of the terms, according to merchants and analysts.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com in late December introduced new policies that – in certain circumstances – allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it. This may occur when a consumer complains about the poor quality of a product, or about an inaccurate and misleading description on the platform. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Alibaba, whose company mission is “to make it easy to do business anywhere”, had a long internal debate over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo, which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it.</p><p>Even though some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse, Alibaba came down on the side of consumer rights in such a situation as merchants are ultimately dependent on buyer confidence, according to a person briefed on the discussions who asked not to be identified.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>However, since the policy went into effect last week there has been an increased number of claims under the “refund but keep the purchase” policy, according to one merchant who runs apparel shops on both Taobao and JD.com, adding that some consumers were looking to exploit the situation.</p><p>The 33-year-old online shop owner, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of retribution from the platforms, said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products, because they will bear higher costs in the event of more claims.</p><p>“This refund terms only works for merchants who sell dirt-cheap goods,” she said, adding that the policy clearly favoured consumers.</p><p>Meanwhile, some merchants took to social media platforms such as Douyin and Weibo to express anger at the potential for policy abuse.</p><p>One user with the handle “PengqiangweiVerna” posted on Weibo that the practice will “foster a group of online freeloaders”. Another Douyin user called “Xinzhouxiaohuolang” posted a dozen videos denouncing such refund requests.</p><p>Both Taobao and JD.com have said that any decisions on refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments.</p><p>A person familiar with the situation at Taobao, who asked not to be identified as they are not authorised to talk to the media, said that the platform has offered merchants an appeal option if they think they have been wronged.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Wednesday.</p><p>Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice was initially launched in 2021 and is seen as a key factor behind the Shanghai-based budget-shopping platform’s rise to prominence.</p><p>Tang Guangyao, a 38-year-old Beijing software developer, said he has shifted from other e-commerce platforms to Pinduoduo as a primary shopping channel owing to its robust consumer protection, even though it focuses on budget prices.</p><p>But some analysts say simply following Pinduoduo’s lead may not work for rival platforms.</p><p>“This [new refund policy] isn’t very practical for platforms such as Taobao, Tmall and JD.com,” said Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangzhou-based iiMedia, pointing out that Pinduoduo’s focus on rock-bottom prices means that the costs of the scheme are more bearable than for merchants on rival sites.</p><p>“By following this [Pinduoduo] refund policy … [rival platforms] will give their merchants a dilemma,” he added.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei’s HarmonyOS to beat Apple’s iOS as the No. 2 smartphone operating system in China in 2024: TechInsights report</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>  <li>Huawei's self-developed HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple's iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year. </li>    <li>The increased adoption of HarmonyOS will be driven by Huawei's return to the 5G smartphone segment with the launch of the Mate 60 series.</li>    <li>HarmonyOS is projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</li>    <li>Several major Chinese companies, including Alibaba, JD.com, and Meituan, have started to develop native apps for HarmonyOS.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>华为自研的鸿蒙操作系统预计今年将超越苹果iOS成为中国第二大操作系统。</li>    <li>HarmonyOS的采用率上升将由华为重返5G智能手机领域并推出Mate 60系列手机所推动。</li>    <li>HarmonyOS预计将在2024年推出HarmonyOS Next版本，该版本不支持基于安卓的应用程序。</li>    <li>包括阿里巴巴、京东和美团在内的几家主要中国公司已开始为HarmonyOS开发原生应用程序。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>surpass (v.) - /sərˈpæs/ 超越，超过。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year driven by the US-sanctioned firm’s comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to a report by TechInsights.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由sur-（超过）和pass（通过）组成的，表示“超过，超越”。在这个例句中，它表示华为自研的鸿蒙操作系统预计今年将超越苹果iOS成为中国第二大操作系统。</p></li>    <li>alternative (n.) - /ɔːlˈtɜːnətɪv/ 替代品，选择。    <p>原文例句：Huawei’s smartphones are all powered by HarmonyOS, its self-developed Android alternative launched in August 2019, three months after the US government added the firm to its Entity List. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由alter（另一个）和nativus（本地）组成，意为“另一个选择”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为自研的鸿蒙操作系统，是Android的替代品。</p></li>    <li>sanction (n.) - /ˈsæŋkʃən/ 制裁，制约。    <p>原文例句：Under this trade blacklist, Huawei is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由sanctus（神圣）和actio（行动）组成，意为“神圣的行动”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国的贸易制裁，华为被禁止从供应商处购买软件、芯片和其他美国原产技术，除非得到华盛顿的批准。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>driven by - 由……驱使，由于……而。    <p>原文例句：Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment, which started with the surprise launch in late August of its Mate 60 Pro, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由drive（驾驶，推动）和by（由……）组成的，表示“由……驱使，由于……而”。在这个例句中，它表示HarmonyOS的采用率上升将由华为重返5G智能手机领域所推动。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei’s smartphones are all powered by HarmonyOS, its self-developed Android alternative launched in August 2019, three months after the US government added the firm to its Entity List. - 华为的智能手机均搭载HarmonyOS，这是其自研的安卓替代系统，于2019年8月发布，当时距离美国政府将该公司列入实体清单已有三个月。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huawei’s smartphones are all powered by HarmonyOS，其中主语是Huawei’s smartphones，谓语是are powered by HarmonyOS。its self-developed Android alternative launched in August 2019是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰HarmonyOS，表示这是一款华为自研的Android替代系统，于2019年8月发布。three months after the US government added the firm to its Entity List是一个时间状语从句，表示从美国政府将该公司列入实体清单后的三个月后。这个句子的意思是说，华为的智能手机均搭载HarmonyOS，这是其自研的安卓替代系统，于2019年8月发布，当时距离美国政府将该公司列入实体清单已有三个月。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作定语 - 表示对先行词的修饰和限定。    <p>原文例句：Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment, which started with the surprise launch in late August of its Mate 60 Pro, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在分词短语是由现在分词和其宾语、状语等构成的，可以用来修饰和限定先行词。在这个例句中，现在分词短语which started with the surprise launch in late August of its Mate 60 Pro, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology用来修饰先行词HarmonyOS adoption，表示HarmonyOS的采用率上升将由华为重返5G智能手机领域所推动。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Increased HarmonyOS adoption is expected to be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment</li>
<li>TechInsights also expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/83c4b156-87f3-4acb-b3f4-8cb885281387_c0009114.jpg" /><figcaption>Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year driven by the US-sanctioned firm’s comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to a report by TechInsights.</p><p>While Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, Canadian research firm TechInsights said in a report released on Wednesday.</p><p>Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment, which started with the surprise launch in late August of its Mate 60 Pro, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology.</p><p>TechInsights also expects Huawei to make a solid recovery in 2024, according to the report.</p><p>Huawei’s smartphones are all powered by HarmonyOS, its self-developed Android alternative launched in August 2019, three months after the US government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">added the firm to its Entity List</a>. Under this trade blacklist, Huawei is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>On its release, the Mate 60 Pro inspired <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">a wave of patriotic fervour</a> among Chinese consumers, and the Shenzhen-based firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241541/huawei-has-big-problem-popular-mate-60-5g-smartphones-theres-not-enough-supply-meet-growing-demand" target="_self" title="">faced supply issues as it scrambled to crank up production to meet demand</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" title="">Huawei sees 9 per cent sales growth in 2023, boosted by Mate 60 Pro 5G comeback</a></h3><p>TechInsights expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months. Huawei’s product portfolio further expanded last week when it launched new smartphone models under its mid-range Nova series.</p><p>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p><p>Huawei is expected to launch a developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next in the first quarter of 2024, and is already working with China’s major companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p><p>Last month, Chinese financial technology giant Ant Group, the fintech affiliate of South China Morning Post owner <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, said it is building a new version of mobile payment app Alipay based on HarmonyOS, after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242703/alibaba-develops-native-dingtalk-app-harmonyos-huawei-aims-end-support-android-apps?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba started development on a new version of DingTalk</a>, its workplace collaboration app, for the platform.</p><p>Other major Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> companies – including e-commerce firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>, video gaming giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netease?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">NetEase</a> and food delivery market leader <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> – in November already started to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241371/chinese-big-tech-firms-jdcom-netease-and-meituan-rush-hire-harmonyos-based-app-developers-huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">recruit developers to build native apps for HarmonyOS</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mcdonalds?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">McDonald’s</a> China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year – became <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244236/mcdonalds-china-pushes-development-native-apps-based-harmonyos-adoption-huaweis-mobile-operating?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239589/xiaomi-launches-home-grown-cross-device-system-hyperos-us-sanctioned-huawei-moves-further-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS Next</a>.</p><p>It remains to be seen whether these efforts will have a halo effect on other smartphone makers and make HarmonyOS a default operating system for not just smartphones but also laptops and cars in China, TechInsights said.</p><p>More than 700 million devices currently run on HarmonyOS, with more than 2.2 million third-party developers creating apps for the platform, according to Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group, speaking at the company’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230293/tech-war-huawei-revive-smartphone-business-back-fresh-ai-powered-operating-system-even-us-sanctions?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">annual developer conference in August</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple dominates global premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground on the back of its new 5G handsets</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  Apple retained its leading position as the top vendor in the global premium smartphone market in 2023, capturing a significant 71% market share, according to research firm Counterpoint. However, the company's dominance faced challenges, as Huawei made a strong comeback with its 5G Mate 60 series and Samsung gained ground with its foldable smartphones.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple remains the dominant player in the premium smartphone segment despite increased competition from Huawei and Samsung.</li>    <li>Theme: The dynamics of the global premium smartphone market in 2023, highlighting Apple's resilience amidst rising competition.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Counterpoint's perspective on the growth of the premium smartphone segment and the impact of factors such as 5G technology, foldable phones, and consumer preferences.</li>    <li>Main information: Apple's market share decline from 75% in 2022 to 71% in 2023; Huawei's resurgence with its new 5G smartphones; Samsung's gains in the premium segment; the increasing importance of the premium segment in the global smartphone market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  苹果在2023年继续保持全球高端智能手机供应商的领先地位，市场份额高达71%，根据研究公司Counterpoint的数据。然而，这家美国公司的领先地位同比有所下降，华为凭借其Mate 60系列5G手机强势回归，三星的可折叠手机也取得了市场份额的增长。  <ul>    <li>摘要：尽管面临来自华为和三星的日益激烈的竞争，但苹果仍然是高端智能手机领域的主导者。</li>    <li>主题：2023年全球高端智能手机市场的动态，突显了苹果在竞争日益激烈的市场中的韧性。</li>    <li>观点：Counterpoint对高端智能手机细分市场增长的观点，以及5G技术、可折叠手机和消费者偏好等因素的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果的市场份额从2022年的75%下降到2023年的71%；华为凭借其新的5G智能手机强势回归；三星在高端细分市场中的份额增加；高端细分市场在全球智能手机市场中的重要性日益增加。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>resurgence (n.) - /rɪˈsɜːrdʒəns/ 复苏，回升。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies’ strong 5G handset market comeback with its Mate 60 series. - 华为凭借其Mate 60系列5G手机强势回归。</p>    <p>例句讲解：“resurgence”由re-（重新）和surge（激增）组成，意为“复苏，回升”，强调事物的重新兴起或复兴。在这个例句中，它描述了华为凭借其Mate 60系列5G手机的推出，在5G手机市场实现了强势回归。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>foldable (adj.) - /ˈfoʊldəbəl/ 可折叠的。    <p>原文例句：Samsung gained ground with its foldable smartphones. - 三星凭借其可折叠手机取得了市场份额的增长。</p>    <p>例句讲解：“foldable”由fold（折叠）和-able（可……的）组成，意为“可折叠的”，强调物体可以弯曲或折叠。在这个例句中，它描述了三星的可折叠智能手机，即能够折叠或弯曲的智能手机，取得了市场份额的增长。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>premium smartphone - 高端智能手机。    <p>原文例句：Apple remained the world’s top vendor of premium smartphones in 2023. - 苹果在2023年继续保持全球高端智能手机供应商的领先地位。</p>    <p>例句讲解：“premium smartphone”意为“高端智能手机”，强调智能手机具有高性能、高价格和高品质等特点。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果在2023年继续保持全球高端智能手机供应商的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei, which released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020, as well as the gains made by Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy S23 series and its latest foldable phones. - 然而，苹果的市场份额从2022年的75%下降到2023年，原因是华为凭借其自2020年10月以来发布的首款5G智能手机强势回归，以及三星电子Galaxy S23系列和最新可折叠手机取得的市场份额增长。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Apple’s share was down from 75 per cent in 2022，其中主语是Apple’s share，谓语是was down，宾语是from 75 per cent in 2022。amid the resurgence of Huawei, which released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020, as well as the gains made by Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy S23 series and its latest foldable phones是一个介词短语作状语，表示在华为强势回归以及三星电子Galaxy S23系列和最新可折叠手机取得市场份额增长的背景下。这个句子的意思是说，苹果的市场份额从2022年的75%下降到2023年，原因是华为凭借其自2020年10月以来发布的首款5G智能手机强势回归，以及三星电子Galaxy S23系列和最新可折叠手机取得的市场份额增长。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由一个分词和其修饰语或宾语组成的短语。    <p>原文例句：Apple continued to lead the smartphone industry’s premium segment in 2023, but saw its worldwide share decline mainly because of US-sanctioned Huawei Technologies’ strong 5G handset market comeback with its Mate 60 series. - 苹果在2023年继续保持智能手机行业高端细分市场的领先地位，但其全球市场份额下降，主要原因是美国制裁的华为技术有限公司凭借其Mate 60系列5G手机强势回归手机市场。</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语可以作定语、状语或表语。在这个例句中，US-sanctioned Huawei Technologies’ strong 5G handset market comeback with its Mate 60 series是一个分词短语，由分词短语US-sanctioned Huawei Technologies’ strong 5G handset market comeback和其宾语with its Mate 60 series组成，作状语，表示苹果全球市场份额下降的主要原因是美国制裁的华为技术有限公司凭借其Mate 60系列5G手机强势回归手机市场。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示比较。    <p>原文例句：Samsung retained the global No 2 spot in the premium segment with a share of 17 per cent, compared to 16 per cent in 2022. - 三星凭借17%的市场份额继续保持全球高端细分市场的第二位，而2022年的市场份额为16%。</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是形容词或副词的一种形式，表示比较。它通常通过在形容词或副词后添加-er后缀来形成。在这个例句中，compared to 16 per cent in 2022是一个比较级短语，表示与2022年的16%相比。这个句子的意思是说，三星凭借17%的市场份额继续保持全球高端细分市场的第二位，而2022年的市场份额为16%。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple remained the world’s top vendor of premium smartphones in 2023, with a 71 per cent market share, according to research firm Counterpoint</li>
<li>The US firm’s lead, however, declined year on year amid Huawei’s 5G comeback with its Mate 60 series and the gains made by Samsung’s foldable phones</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/64d88f21-13d4-47d7-a021-0a71facc64d7_e98ebaba.jpg" /><figcaption>Apple’s iPhone 15 Pro and Pro Max models are seen on display at a store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 22, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> continued to lead the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> industry’s premium segment in 2023, but saw its worldwide share decline mainly because of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-sanctioned</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>’ strong <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/5g/news" target="_self" title="">5G</a> handset market comeback with its Mate 60 series.</p><p>The global premium smartphone market, where handsets are priced from US$600, saw Apple remain the “undisputed leader” last year with a dominant 71 per cent share, according to the latest industry report released on Tuesday by Counterpoint Research.</p><p>Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei, which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020</a>, as well as the gains made by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a>’ Galaxy S23 series and its latest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foldable-phones" target="_self" title="">foldable phones</a>.</p><p>Samsung retained the global No 2 spot in the premium segment with a share of 17 per cent, compared to 16 per cent in 2022. Still, No 3 Huawei captured more new ground year on year with a 5 per cent share, up from 3 per cent in 2022, according to the Counterpoint report.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/cb3a9a4b-0ce5-45f4-91e6-798c2c4c40f0_5babf532.jpg" title="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> last year took the fourth and fifth spots in the premium smartphone segment with a 2 per cent and 1 per cent share, respectively.</p><p>The latest market data shows the resilience of the premium segment, despite the projected decrease in the overall global smartphone market in 2023 – global handset shipments are forecast to hit their lowest level in almost a decade with a 5 per cent decline, according to an earlier Counterpoint report.</p><p>The premium segment, meanwhile, was expected to account for nearly one-fourth of global smartphone market sales and 60 per cent of the industry’s revenue in 2023. Counterpoint data shows that the so-called ultra-premium segment, where smartphones cost more than US$1,000, accounted for one-third of total premium handset sales last year.</p><p>Over the past few years, the premium segment has emerged as a growth area in the otherwise weak worldwide smartphone market. Counterpoint projected the premium segment sales share to triple to 24 per cent in 2023, compared to 6 per cent in 2016.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3246457/ranked-top-5-smartphones-2023-iphone-15-pro-max-and-google-pixel-8-pro-two-foldable-phones-and-best" title="">Top 5 smartphones of 2023, from iPhone 15 Pro Max to the best camera phone</a></h3><p>“There has been a shift in consumer buying patterns in the smartphone market,” Counterpoint senior analyst Varun Mishra said in the premium segment report. “Considering the importance a smartphone holds, consumers are willing to spend more to get a high-quality device that they can use for a longer period.”</p><p>Much of the global premium segment’s growth last year was driven by China, western Europe, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/india" target="_self" title="">India</a>, and the Middle East-and-Africa regions, according to Counterpoint.</p><p>India is already the world’s fastest-growing market for premium smartphones, the Counterpoint report said. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217435/apple-opens-first-retail-store-india-us-tech-giant-sharpens-focus-south-asian-nation-major-market" target="_self" title="">Apple opened its first retail store in India</a> last April, underscoring the US tech titan’s increasing focus on the South Asian nation as a key sales market and alternative manufacturing hub to China.</p><p>“Owning the latest and greatest flagships has also become a status symbol for many consumers, especially in emerging markets where they are jumping directly from the mid-price band to the premium band,” Mishra said. “Further, these devices are increasingly becoming more affordable due to promotion seasons and financing options.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance’s Douyin makes instant refunds mandatory, following PDD, Taobao and JD.com amid fierce e-commerce competition</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247160/bytedances-douyin-makes-instant-refunds-mandatory-following-pdd-taobao-and-jdcom-amid-fierce-e</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary</h2>  <ul>    <li>In a bid to woo consumers, Douyin has introduced a compulsory instant refund policy.</li>    <li>The new policy mandates merchants to immediately return money to customers on request, even before receiving returned goods.</li>    <li> This follows similar moves by e-commerce rivals Taobao and Pinduoduo in a bid to gain a competitive edge.</li>    <li>The trend of offering "refund without returning goods" aims to attract price-sensitive consumers in China.</li>    <li>Douyin, owned by ByteDance, allows users to get refunds as soon as they mail back the returned parcel.</li>    <li>The new policy does not apply to customized products or non-tangible goods, with a limit of 1,500 yuan (US$211) for instant refunds.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary</h2>  <ul>    <li>为吸引消费者，抖音推出强制即时退款政策。</li>    <li>新政强制要求商家在接到用户要求后立即退款，即使没有收到退回的货物。</li>    <li>这是继电商竞争对手淘宝和拼多多采取类似举措之后，为获得竞争优势而采取的举措。</li>    <li>提供“无需退货退款”的趋势旨在吸引中国价格敏感的消费者。</li>    <li>抖音由字节跳动拥有，它允许用户在寄回退货包裹后立即获得退款。</li>    <li>新政策不适用于定制产品或非实物商品，即时退款限额为 1,500 元（211 美元）。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words</h2>  <ul>    <li> Woo (v.) - /wʊ/ 吸引，招徕。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com recently started offering refunds without returns to woo consumers away from rising budget e-commerce champion Pinduoduo。</p>    <p>例句讲解：Woo是一个动词，意为“吸引，招徕”。在这个例句中，它描述了阿里巴巴旗下的淘宝和京东为了吸引消费者远离新兴的预算电子商务巨头拼多多，最近开始提供无理由退款服务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li> Mandate (v.) - /ˈmæn.dət/ 命令，授权。    <p>原文例句：Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok that is betting big on e-commerce, has made its “express refund” policy mandatory, forcing merchants to immediately return money to consumers upon request to compete with similar offerings on Taobao and Pinduoduo.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Mandate是一个动词，意为“命令，授权”。在这个例句中，它描述了抖音这家中国版TikTok，为了在大电子商务领域占有一席之地，已经将其“快速退款”政策定为强制性，要求商家在接到消费者的退款请求后立即退还货款，以与淘宝和拼多多等平台提供的类似服务竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Phrases</h2>  <ul>    <li> Gain a competitive edge -获得竞争优势。    <p>原文例句：The trend of offering "refund without returning goods" aims to attract price-sensitive consumers in China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Gain a competitive edge是一个短语，意为“获得竞争优势”。在这个例句中，它描述了提供“无需退货退款”的趋势旨在吸引中国国内对价格敏感的消费者，从而领先于竞争对手获得优势。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li> Price-sensitive consumers -对价格敏感的消费者。    <p>原文例句：The trend of offering "refund without returning goods" aims to attract price-sensitive consumers in China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Price-sensitive consumers是一个短语，意为“对价格敏感的消费者”。在这个例句中，它描述了提供“无需退货退款”的趋势旨在吸引中国国内对价格敏感的消费者，从而领先于竞争对手获得优势。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Sentences</h2>  <ul>    <li>Douyin’s new refund service is not available for customised products or non-tangible goods such as memberships. - 抖音的新退款服务不适用于定制产品或非实物商品，例如会员资格。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个否定句，主语是Douyin’s new refund service，谓语是不及物动词is not available，宾语是for customised products or non-tangible goods such as memberships。这是一个复合句，由两个简单句“Douyin’s new refund service is not available for customised products”和“Douyin’s new refund service is not available for non-tangible goods such as memberships”连接而成，中间用or连接。这个句子的意思是说，抖音的新退款服务不适用于定制产品或非实物商品，例如会员资格。</p>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Instant refunds are also limited to 1,500 yuan (US$211).</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个主动语态的一般现在时句子，主语是Instant refunds，谓语是are limited to 1,500 yuan (US$211)。这是一个简单句，没有从句或分句。这个句子的意思是说，即时退款也限制在1500元（211美元）以内。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar</h2>  <ul>    <li>Modal verbs -情态动词。    <p>原文例句：Consumers are able to get a refund as soon as they mail back the returned parcel.</p>    <p>语法讲解：情态动词是表示说话人对动作或状态的态度、能力或许可的助动词。常见的情态动词包括can、could、may、might、must、shall、should、will和would。在例句中，情态动词able表示消费者有能力在寄回退货包裹后立即获得退款。</p></li>    <li>Passive voice -被动语态。    <p>原文例句：The policy of allowing refunds without returns has started to gain favour as platforms look for any possible edge over rivals.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是指句子中动作的承受者或接受者是主语，而动作的执行者是宾语或根本没有提及。被动语态通常由be + past participle的形式构成。在例句中，主语是The policy of allowing refunds without returns，谓语是由be + past participle形式的started to gain favour构成，宾语是as platforms look for any possible edge over rivals。这种结构表示允许无理由退款的政策已经开始受到平台的青睐，因为这些平台正在寻找任何可能超过竞争对手的优势。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Merchants selling on the short video app Douyin can no longer opt out of the option to instantly refund up to US$211 before receiving returned goods</li>
<li>Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com recently started offering refunds without returns to woo consumers away from rising budget e-commerce champion Pinduoduo</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/3ce8d4ad-d4c8-4569-8e73-e028869c8250_11da8613.jpg" /><figcaption>The logo of Douyin displayed next to a mobile phone displaying an e-commerce site on the app in an illustration picture taken on October 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Douyin, the Chinese version of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a> that is betting big on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce">e-commerce</a>, has made its “express refund” policy mandatory, forcing merchants to immediately return money to consumers upon request to compete with similar offerings on Taobao and Pinduoduo.</p><p>The platform operated by Beijing-based <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance">ByteDance</a>, which added a shopping channel in 2019, allows users to get a refund as soon as they mail back the returned parcel, rather than when the merchant receives it. A recent policy update regarding the service introduced in 2021 denies merchants the option of turning it off.</p><p>E-commerce platforms are turning to policies known as “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason” as part of a push to be more consumer-friendly at the expense of merchants amid intensified competition. Online retail sales of tangible goods in China increased 8.3 per cent in the first 11 months of 2023, according to the National Bureau of Statistics.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>Budget shopping app <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo">Pinduoduo</a>, owned by PDD Holdings, was the first major e-commerce site to introduce a similar refunds policy in 2021 allowing users to get their money back without returning goods found to not match merchant descriptions. This was seen as a major factor in helping Pinduoduo woo price-sensitive Chinese consumers away from competing platforms.</p><p>The policy of allowing refunds without returns has started to gain favour as platforms look for any possible edge over rivals.</p><p>Taobao, the e-commerce platform from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom">JD.com</a> last week rolled out their own <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating">“refund only” policies</a>, finally matching the option from Pinduoduo. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Douyin has offered refunds without returns since September.</p><p>Douyin’s new refund service is not available for customised products or non-tangible goods such as memberships. Instant refunds are also limited to 1,500 yuan (US$211).</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Alibaba has been facing a new sense of urgency to win back consumers after PDD overtook China’s e-commerce king in market capitalisation. Alibaba was valued at US$190.2 billion on the New York Stock Exchange on Tuesday, lower than PDD’s US$193.5 billion on the Nasdaq.</p><p>In December, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals">Alibaba promoted six young managers</a> to run its core e-commerce business unit in an attempt to “reignite their entrepreneurial spirit” and “secure and win their future”, according to an internal letter penned by the conglomerate’s CEO Eddie Wu Yongming, two days after he became the head of the unit.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech firms must end, says communist party newspaper after video gaming stock rout</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's regulatory authorities should stop their erratic behavior and allow internet companies self-governance to promote growth and international competitiveness.</li>    <li>Theme: The impact of regulatory actions on China's internet sector and the need for a more balanced approach.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The Study Times opinion piece calls for an end to extreme regulatory swings and advocates for cross-departmental coordination, considering the views of regulated parties, and allowing self-governance.</li>    <li>Main information: Examples of regulatory actions, such as NPPA's draft regulation on video game spending and the Cyberspace Administration of China's data security requirements, have negatively affected internet companies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国的监管部门应停止其反复无常的行为，并允许互联网公司自我治理，以促进其增长和国际竞争力。</li>    <li>主题：监管行动对中国互联网行业的影响，以及对更加平衡的监管方法的必要性。</li>    <li>观点：学习时报的评论文章呼吁停止极端监管的摆动，并提倡跨部门协调，考虑被监管方的意见，并允许自我治理。</li>    <li>主要信息：监管行动的例子，例如国家新闻出版署关于电子游戏支出的草案监管和国家网络安全局的数据安全要求，对互联网公司产生了负面影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>erratic (adj.) - /ɛːˈrætɪk/ 无规律的，不定的。    <p>原文例句：China’s disciplinary enforcers add ‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语erraticus（游荡的），指的是不规则，不定，变化无常的情况。在这个例句中，它描述了中国的执法人员将“不良”书籍、性行为和毒品列为严重罪行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>curb (v.) - /kɜːb/ 抑制，限制。    <p>原文例句：Beijing’s campaign of “curbing irrational expansion of capital” in 2020 unleashed a race among different ministries and watchdogs to claim authority in checking and approving internet businesses.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语curber（弯曲），指的是抑制，限制或控制。在这个例句中，它描述了北京在2020年开展的“遏制资本无序扩张”的运动，引发了不同部门和监督机构之间的竞赛，以争夺检查和批准互联网企业的权力。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>cross-departmental coordination - 跨部门协调。    <p>原文例句：China must improve “cross-departmental coordination” to avoid duplicated enforcement and checks.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由cross-（交叉的），departmental（部门的）和coordination（协调）组成，指的是不同部门之间的协调合作。在这个例句中，它指中国需要提高跨部门的协调合作，以避免重复的执法和检查。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese regulators should loosen their grip and allow “self-governance” by Chinese internet companies, it added. - 中国监管部门应放松对中国互联网公司的控制并允许其进行“自我治理”。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是Chinese regulators，谓语是should loosen their grip and allow “self-governance”，宾语是Chinese internet companies。it added是一个附加信息，说明这句话是作者的补充观点。    在这个例句中，it added这一附加信息表示作者在陈述完“中国监管部门应放松对中国互联网公司的控制”这一观点后，又补充了一句“并允许其进行‘自我治理’”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>名词性从句 - 可以充当名词的从句。    <p>原文例句：China’s disciplinary enforcers add ‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences. </p>    <p>语法讲解：名词性从句可以在句中充当主语、宾语、表语和定语等。它通常由that、whether、who、whom等关联词引导。在这个例句中，名词性从句“‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences”充当宾语，说明了中国执法人员将“不良”书籍、性行为和毒品列为严重罪行。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>倒装 - 将句子中某些成分的正常顺序颠倒过来。    <p>原文例句：It remains unknown whether China’s different regulators will heed the advice. </p>    <p>语法讲解：倒装是英语中常见的一种修辞手法，目的是强调句子的某个成分或引起读者的注意。在这个例句中，将主语It提前，谓语remains unknown后置，强调了句子主语的不确定性。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The mouthpiece of the Central Party School argued that regulators must stop the practice of swinging between extremes of lax oversight and ‘overly strict’ regulation</li>
<li>The opinion came days after the NPPA wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with draft regulation to restrict spending on video games</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/3319e698-c70a-4b75-a5c4-b17164272de6_6b557a93.jpg" /><figcaption>Tencent’s Game for Peace is seen on a mobile phone in this illustration picture taken May 13, 2019.  Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>A Chinese Communist Party newspaper has urged the country’s regulators to end their erratic moves against the platform economy, in a sign of growing concern over policy damage to the health of the country’s ailing internet titans.</p><p>A front page opinion piece published by the Study Times, the mouthpiece of the Central Party School, on Wednesday argued that regulators must stop the practice of swinging between extremes of lax oversight and “overly strict” regulation so that China’s Big Tech firms can have room to grow.</p><p>The article, which did not name any specific company or regulator, came days after the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" target="_self" title="">proposed regulation to restrict spending on video games.</a> The South China Morning Post reported on Tuesday that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes" target="_self" title="">a key gaming official has left his job following the debacle,</a> as the Chinese government tries to allay market fears.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246511/chinas-disciplinary-enforcers-add-bad-books-sex-drugs-serious-offences" title="">China’s disciplinary enforcers add ‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences</a></h3><p>The draft proposal is the latest example of regulatory hostility, after Beijing’s campaign of “curbing irrational expansion of capital” in 2020 unleashed a race among different ministries and watchdogs to claim authority in checking and approving internet businesses.</p><p>A long list of Chinese ministries has been sharpening their teeth when it comes to disciplining internet firms. The Cyberspace Administration of China, the country’s internet watchdog, for instance, has articulated Beijing’s demand for data security into intrusive requirements that have made it increasingly difficult and costly to comply with.</p><p>Beijing’s pursuit of market control, along with China’s economic slowdown and rising geopolitical tensions with the US, have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years. Tencent Holdings, the country’s most valuable player that once eyed being Asia’s first US$1 trillion company, fell out of the global top 10 after losing 60 per cent of its market capitalisation, while Post owner Alibaba Group Holding, which exceeded Amazon.com in market value in 2014, is now worth an eighth of the US e-commerce titan.</p><p>According to the Study Times opinion piece, the erratic regulatory behaviour is “a risk and a challenge” for China as its leading internet firms are left further behind their global peers in terms of competitiveness and growth potential.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/643c0e52-aced-4b9f-a2cf-0f56737ce2f0_bd901af2.jpg" title="People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" width="2000" /><figcaption>People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song</figcaption></figure></div><p>China must improve “cross-departmental coordination” to avoid duplicated enforcement and checks, while regulatory acts and policy adjustments must factor in “the views of all parties, especially those being regulated” to avoid interrupting normal business activities or causing unexpected risks, it said.</p><p>Chinese regulators should loosen their grip and allow “self-governance” by Chinese internet companies, it added. “It is important to respect the rationality and necessity of platform self-governance to guide and encourage the formation of self-regulatory mechanisms,” the article said.</p><p>It remains unknown whether China’s different regulators will heed the advice. Beijing’s regulatory crackdown on the internet sector officially came to an end a year ago, when the Chinese leadership said the country’s platform enterprises would be encouraged to “fully display their capabilities” in growth, job creation and international competition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung to kick off year of AI phones with new launch this month</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247104/samsung-kick-year-ai-phones-new-launch-month</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In the smartphone industry, Samsung is embracing artificial intelligence (AI) as a key strategy to differentiate its products and drive sales in 2024. The company's upcoming Galaxy S24 device is expected to showcase advanced AI capabilities, moving beyond improvements in camera technology and flexible displays. This move reflects a broader trend in the tech industry, with generative AI tools like ChatGPT and Dall-E gaining prominence and leading to increased demand for AI integration in devices.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung's focus on AI in its upcoming smartphone launch.</li>    <li>Theme: The growing importance of AI in the smartphone market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Samsung's leadership position in AI-powered smartphones.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's Galaxy S24 launch event, expected AI features, market trends, and industry leaders in AI integration.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在智能手机领域，三星將人工智能（AI）視為 2024 年產品差異化的關鍵戰略，以推進銷量。三星即將推出的 Galaxy S24 設備預計將展示先進的 AI 功能，超越相機技術和柔性顯示螢幕方面的改進。此舉反映了科技行業的一個更廣泛的趨勢，即生成式 AI 工具（如 ChatGPT 和 Dall-E）日益突出，並導致對設備中 AI 集成的需求增加。   <ul>    <li>摘要：三星在即將推出的智能手機發布會上關注 AI。</li>    <li>主題：人工智能在智能手機市場的重要性日益提高。</li>    <li>觀點：三星在人工智能智慧型手機領域的領先地位。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星 Galaxy S24 發佈會、預計的 AI 功能、市場趨勢以及 AI 集成領域的行业領導者。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>flagship (adj.) - /ˈflæɡʃɪp/ 旗舰的，首要的。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由flag（旗帜）和ship（船）组成，用于形容“最优秀的”，也用于形容“公司的主要品牌”。在这个例句中，它形容三星的下一款旗舰设备——可能被称为 Galaxy S24。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>generative (adj.) - /ˈdʒɛn(ə)rətɪv/  生成性的，产生性的。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由genus（出生，起源）和-ative（-的）组成，表示“能产生某种东西或使某种东西产生”。在这个例句中，它描述了预计到2027年底将会有超过十亿部内置生成式AI的智能手机被运送。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stand out - 引人注意，脱颖而出。    <p>原文例句：In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由stand（站立）和out（在外面）组成，表示“站出来，使突出”。在这个例句中，它表示过去几年里，三星和其他智能手机制造商依靠相机技术和柔性显示屏的改进 来脱颖而出。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company has been making iPhones and other products in India，其中主语是The company，谓语是has been making，宾语是iPhones and other products in India。for several years是一个时间状语，表示持续了几年，including the latest iPhone 15是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示包括最新的 iPhone 15。这个句子的意思是说，该公司已经在印度生产 iPhone 和其他产品好几年了，包括最新的 iPhone 15。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>there be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out</li>
<li>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates</li>
</ul><p>The world’s most prolific smartphone maker is leaning into artificial intelligence (AI) as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.</p><p>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – on January 17 in San Jose, California, with a live-streamed event. The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming”.</p><p>In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out, but 2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246310/huawei-launches-new-nova-smartphones-without-giving-details-chip-attention-remains-fixed-its" title="">Huawei launches new Nova smartphones without giving details on chip</a></h3><p>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p><p>OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Dall-E tools, which generate text or visual responses to users’ queries, are at the forefront of a generative-AI wave that is swept across the tech industry – and helped make Nvidia a trillion-dollar company by providing the key AI-training accelerators. The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices, as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year.</p><p>“Samsung and Qualcomm are immediate leaders as current product offerings and capabilities position them as first movers,” the Counterpoint researchers wrote in December. “Similar to what it did with foldables, Samsung is likely to capture almost 50 per cent share for the next two years, followed by key Chinese OEMs like Xiaomi, Vivo, Honor and Oppo.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
