<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Tesla cuts prices in China on Model 3 and Model Y EVs to keep commanding lead in premium segment of fast-growing market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  特斯拉下调其在中国制造车辆的价格，以维持其在全球最大电动汽车市场高端细分市场的领先地位。特斯拉上海工厂去年向中国买家交付了603,664辆电动汽车，同比增长37.3%，高于2022年37%的增幅。中国电动汽车制造商正在加剧竞争，迫使一些领先企业通过降价来吸引客户。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tesla lowers prices of its locally-built vehicles to maintain leading position in China’s premium EV market.</li>    <li>Theme: Tesla’s price adjustments in the Chinese market to stay competitive amidst growing competition from domestic rivals.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Tesla’s strategy to retain market share in a highly competitive environment; the impact of rising competition on the strategies of Chinese EV makers.</li>    <li>Main information: Model 3 and Model Y price reduction; Tesla’s 2023 sales growth and market share in China; dynamics and challenges in the Chinese EV market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  特斯拉下调其上海制造汽车的价格，以保持其在全球最大电动汽车市场高端细分市场的领先地位。特斯拉上海工厂去年向中国买家交付了603,664辆电动汽车，同比增长37.3%，高于2022年37%的增幅。中国电动汽车制造商正在加剧竞争，迫使一些领先企业通过降价来吸引客户。  <ul>    <li>摘要：特斯拉下调其本地制造汽车的价格，以保持在中国高端电动汽车市场的领先地位。</li>    <li>主题：特斯拉在面对国内竞争对手日益激烈的竞争中调整价格以保持竞争力的策略。</li>    <li>观点：特斯拉在竞争激烈的环境中保持市场份额的策略；竞争加剧对中国电动汽车制造商战略的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：Model 3和Model Y降价；特斯拉2023年在中国市场的销售增长和市场份额；中国电动汽车市场的动态和挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>launch (v.) - /lɔːntʃ/ 发射，发起，推出。    <p>原文例句：Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“launch”用作动词，表示“发射，发起，推出”。例句中的“Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars”意思是“中国本土的竞争对手已经推出了一系列新的智能电动汽车来挑战美国电动汽车制造商”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>raft (n.) - /rɑːft/ 木筏，大量，大量。    <p>原文例句：Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“raft”用作名词，可以表示“木筏，大量，大量”。例句中的“a raft of new intelligent electric cars”意思是“大量新的智能电动汽车”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>premium segment - 高端细分市场。    <P>原文例句：Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market.</P>    <p>例句讲解：“premium segment”是由“premium”（优质的，高级的）和“segment”（部分，细分市场）组成的词组，表示“高端细分市场”。在这个例句中，它指的是全球最大的电动汽车市场的高端细分市场。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>People look at a Tesla Model 3 at a showroom in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFETesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market. - 人们在2024年1月6日于北京一家展厅里参观特斯拉Model 3。特斯拉已将上海制造的汽车价格最多下调6%，以努力保持其在全球最大的电动汽车市场中的领先地位。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent，其中主语是Tesla，谓语是has cut，宾语是the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent。People look at a Tesla Model 3 at a showroom in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFETesla是一个并列句，表示两件事情同时发生。这个句子的意思是说，人们在2024年1月6日于北京一家展厅里参观特斯拉Model 3，特斯拉已将上海制造的汽车价格最多下调6%，以努力保持其在全球最大的电动汽车市场中的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 被动语态是英语中的一种句子结构，它将句子中的宾语变为主语，把主动语态中的谓语动词变为过去分词，并使用助动词be来表示。    <p>原文例句：The prices cuts come after Tesla reported 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是The price cuts，谓语是come，宾语是15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December，助动词是be的过去分词been。这个句子的意思是说，在特斯拉报告称12月在中国大陆的销售额环比增长15.7%至75,805辆汽车后，这些价格下调就来了。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式 - 不定式是指动词的非谓语形式, 通常由to加上动词原形组成。    <p>原文例句：Tesla also lowered the price of the dual-motor version of the Model 3 by 3.9 per cent to 285,900 yuan and offered a 2.1 per cent discount on the dual-motor Model Y, which now sells for 299,900 yuan. </p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式是指动词的非谓语形式，由to加上动词原形组成。在这个句子中，不定式是用作后置定语，用来修饰名词yuan，表示价格降低的幅度。例如“lowered the price... by 3.9 per cent”表示“降低价格... 3.9%”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Carmaker cut prices by up to 6 per cent after reporting 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December</li>
<li>‘Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder,’ analyst says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/7e2c041a-9f88-4d42-864b-ea64912c8bf0_9e3fcf96.jpg" /><figcaption>People look at a Tesla Model 3 at a showroom in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p><a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest <a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> market.</p><p>The Texas-based company announced on Friday that the price of the entry-level edition of its Model 3 will be reduced from 261,400 yuan (US$36,814) to 245,900 yuan, while the starting price of the Model Y is now 258,900 yuan, down from 266,400 yuan.</p><p>The price cuts come after Tesla reported 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December, according to data released by the China Passenger Car Association.</p><p>“Tesla apparently hopes to maintain its market share in the highly competitive market,” said Phate Zhang, founder of Shanghai-based EV data provider CnEVPost. “Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua" class="image-inline caption" height="1618" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/eb3603e2-9af8-4fa3-8ecc-aae102cfa6f6_a8c0939e.jpg" title="Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua" width="2000" /><figcaption>Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure></div><p>Tesla also lowered the price of the dual-motor version of the Model 3 by 3.9 per cent to 285,900 yuan and offered a 2.1 per cent discount on the dual-motor Model Y, which now sells for 299,900 yuan.</p><p>The front-runner in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3241811/chinas-premium-ev-segment-set-cutthroat-competition-huawei-baidu-and-xiaomi-join-fray" target="_self" title="">China’s premium electric vehicle (EV) segment</a> delivered 603,664 EVs made in its Shanghai Gigafactory to buyers in China last year, up 37.3 per cent from 2022. The growth was nearly unchanged from the 37 per cent sales rise recorded in 2022 when it delivered about 440,000 vehicles.</p><p>The company’s domestic rivals are not exactly nipping at its heels. Its closest competitor in the premium segment, <a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a>, delivered about 376,000 cars in 2023.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Tesla adjusts the prices of its locally built vehicles regularly based on production costs, Grace Tao, Tesla’s head of communications and government affairs in China, said on the microblogging site Weibo last January. Since January 2020, Tesla China cut prices on its Chinese-made models six times. This is the first reduction since August 2023; Tesla slightly raised prices between October and November when growth of deliveries in China slowed.</p><p>The Gigafactory, Tesla’s largest production hub worldwide, has an annual capacity of about 1 million units.</p><p>Aside from deliveries to mainland customers, the Shanghai factory also shipped 344,078 vehicles to markets like Japan and Germany in 2023, up 26.9 per cent year on year, according to data compiled by the CnEVPost.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" title="">Chinese EV maker shows off flying car but admits urban use is far off</a></h3><p>Sales of electric cars in China jumped 37 per cent last year, with deliveries of pure EVs and plug-in hybrids hitting 8.9 million units. At present, mainland China accounts for about 60 per cent of global EV sales.</p><p>But sales growth of battery-powered vehicles in mainland China is expected to slow to 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November.</p><p>Intensifying competition is piling pressure on the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3237078/chinas-ev-war-only-strongest-will-survive-byd-xpengs-dominance-knock-out-15-pretenders-amid-supply" target="_self" title="">200-plus Chinese EV makers</a> this year, with some leading players spearheading price cuts to lure customers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247906/vw-and-gm-lose-ground-chinese-ev-makers-petrol-heavy-line-ups-fall-out-favour-worlds-largest-car" title="">VW and GM lose ground to Chinese EV makers as petrol-heavy line-ups lose favour</a></h3><p>A new round of price cuts is in effect, with BYD, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest EV maker</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> offering discounts to bolster sales.</p><p>Early last month, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a> cut the price of its Han luxury car by as much as 20,000 yuan to meet its annual sales target. Xpeng followed by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3245621/china-evs-xpeng-cuts-price-bestselling-g6-suv-maintain-high-sales-volume-amid-intensifying" target="_self" title="">cutting the price of its bestselling G6 SUV</a> by 10,000 yuan, or about 5 per cent.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US$3 billion top Asia fund bets on Tencent again despite China gaming rules, favours Samsung over TSMC in chip market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248169/us3-billion-top-asia-fund-bets-tencent-again-despite-china-gaming-rules-favours-samsung-over-tsmc</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which outperformed its peers, added Tencent Holdings back to its portfolio due to its attractive valuation despite gaming restrictions in China.</li>    <li>Jonathan Pines, who manages the fund, believes the nation's beaten-down market offers "absolutely incredible" valuations, making Tencent's shares very cheap.</li>    <li>Pines sold most of his Tencent and TSMC shares a year ago, but now prefers Samsung Electronics in the semiconductor space due to its better earnings prospects and position in the memory chip sector.</li>    <li>While Korea's largest company, Samsung, reported a 35% drop in operating income due to weak demand, Pines remains positive on its earnings trajectory.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund 在优于同行的情况下，尽管中国对游戏进行了限制，但仍因其具有吸引力的估值而将腾讯控股重新纳入了其投资组合。</li>    <li>管理该基金的乔纳森·派恩斯认为，该国被打压的市场提供了“绝对令人难以置信”的估值，使腾讯的股票非常便宜。</li>    <li>派恩斯在一年多前抛售了大部分腾讯和台积电股票，但现在由于其更好的盈利前景和在存储芯片领域的定位，更青睐三星电子在半导体领域的地位。</li>    <li>尽管韩国最大的公司三星由于消费电子产品需求疲软而报告营业收入下降 35%，但派恩斯仍对其收益轨迹持积极态度。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>outperform (v.) - /ˌaʊtˈpɜːrfɔːrm/ 表现更好，胜过。    <p>原文例句：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由out-（超越，胜过）和perform（表演，演出）构成的，表示“表现更好，胜过”。在这个例句中，它表示Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund在过去三年中，表现优于其83%的同行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>valuation (n.) - /væljuˈeɪʃən/ 估值，估价。    <p>原文例句：Tencent yielded its position as Asia’s second-most valuable company after China’s new rules on online gaming erased US$53 billion off its market value in 2023, capping a third year of losses. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由value（价值，估值）和-ation（状态，过程）构成的，表示“估值，估价”。在这个例句中，它表示腾讯在中国发布新的在线游戏规则后，其市值在2023年减少了530亿美元，使其在亚洲最有价值公司中的排名从第二位下降。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>短语：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ultra-cheap valuations - 超级便宜的估值。    <p>原文例句：While China currently is not the preferred investment destination for many, a combination of ultra-cheap valuations and low allocations outweighs the risks of investing in the nation’s stocks, according to Pines. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语由ultra-cheap（超级便宜的）和valuations（估值）组成，表示“超级便宜的估值”。在这个例句中，它表示尽管中国目前不是许多人的首选投资目的地，但根据派恩斯的说法，超低估值和低配仓的组合超过了投资该国股票的风险。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>cyclical downturn - 周期性衰退。    <p>原文例句：TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语由cyclical（周期的）和downturn（衰退）组成，表示“周期性衰退”。在这个例句中，它表示台积电即将面临周期性衰退，其股票交易价格接近账面价值的五倍，而三星的收益将要复苏，派恩斯补充说，韩国公司在存储芯片领域的定位使其目前更具优势。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China released draft guidelines on December 22, 2023, aimed at curbing excessive spending on online gaming. - 中国于 2023 年 12 月 22 日发布了征求意见稿，旨在遏制在线游戏过度支出。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是China，谓语是released,宾语是draft guidelines。on December 22, 2023是一个时间状语，修饰动词released，表示中国于 2023 年 12 月 22 日发布了征求意见稿。aimed at curbing excessive spending on online gaming是一个现在分词短语作目的状语，修饰动词released，表示中国发布征求意见稿的目的是为了遏制在线游戏过度支出。这个句子的意思是说，中国于 2023 年 12 月 22 日发布了征求意见稿，旨在遏制在线游戏过度支出。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 强调句型用于强调句子中的某个成分，强调句型有多种形式，其中一种是“It is/was…that/who…”句型。    <p>原文例句：It is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句型，强调的是TSMC即将面临周期性衰退。结构是：It is/was…that/who…，其中It is/was是系动词，that/who是关系代词，后面的句子是对强调成分的解释。在这个例句中，It is是系动词，that引导了一个句子，对TSMC即将面临周期性衰退进行了解释。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式作目的语 - 不定式可以作目的语，表示动作或状态的目的。    <p>原文例句：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which outperformed most of its peers has added Tencent Holdings back to its portfolio recently, betting on the gaming company’s attractive valuation despite further industry curbs by the Chinese government. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个不定式作目的语的例子。结构是：动词+不定式，其中动词表示动作或状态，不定式表示目的。在这个例句中，betting是动词，on the gaming company’s attractive valuation是不定式，表示Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund押注腾讯控股具有吸引力的估值。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Investment reflects fund’s optimism over beaten-down market, where valuations are ‘absolutely incredible’, says fund manager</li>
<li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund also prefers Samsung Electronics over TSMC in the semiconductor market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/b3633bc7-a417-4b09-b1bb-2156486982fa_cf3478d7.jpg" /><figcaption>A man plays an online game from Tencent on a train. China released draft guidelines on December 22, 2023, aimed at curbing excessive spending on online gaming. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>A fund that outperformed most of its peers has added Tencent Holdings back to its portfolio recently, betting on the gaming company’s attractive valuation despite further industry curbs by the Chinese government.</p><p>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246161/chinas-video-gaming-watchdog-speaks-out-after-draft-spending-rules-roil-market" target="_self" title="">draft rule on gaming restrictions in December</a>. The investment reflects the fund’s optimism over the nation’s beaten-down market, where valuations are “absolutely incredible”, said Jonathan Pines, who manages the US$3.1 billion fund.</p><p>“We are buying it now because of its very cheap value,” he said in an interview Wednesday, referring to Tencent’s shares. Pines’ fund sold most of its shares in Tencent as well as in Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) about a year ago.</p><p>Tencent yielded its position as Asia’s second-most valuable company after China’s new rules on online gaming erased US$53 billion off its market value in 2023, capping a third year of losses. The shares trade at less than 16 times forward earnings, or about half the 10-year average, making them attractive, Pines said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations" title="">ByteDance confirms talks with Tencent, other buyers for video game operations</a></h3><p>While China currently is not the preferred investment destination for many, a combination of ultra-cheap valuations and low allocations outweighs the risks of investing in the nation’s stocks, according to Pines.</p><p>“We think the risks of investing in China are worth taking because the stocks are so cheap,” he said.</p><p>The fund, which is also overweight on South Korea, prefers Samsung Electronics to TSMC in the Asia semiconductor space.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" title="">China to curb excess spending on video games in blow for world’s biggest market</a></h3><p>TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now.</p><p>While Korea’s largest company this week reported a steeper-than-expected 35 per cent drop in operating income, reflecting weak demand for consumer electronics globally, Pines said the results would not prevent him from being positive on its earnings trajectory. “Things are going to improve from here,” he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Google slashes over 1,000 jobs to focus on AI amid competition with Microsoft, OpenAI</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248158/google-slashes-over-1000-jobs-focus-ai-amid-competition-microsoft-openai</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Google is laying off employees in its digital assistant, hardware, and engineering teams to save costs and focus on artificial intelligence (AI).</li>    <li>The layoffs affected a variety of employees, including vice-presidents and directors, with some earning millions in annual compensation.</li>    <li>Google and its leaders have been emphasizing cost-cutting measures to allocate resources to their top priorities.</li>    <li>The Alphabet Workers Union reported that more than 1,000 employees have been laid off, with some questioning the company's focus on cost-cutting over trust-building.</li>    <li>Google's efforts to refocus on AI come as rivals like Microsoft and ChatGPT make advancements in the field.</li>    <li>The layoffs have caused anxiety among Google employees, with some expressing concerns about future job security and questioning the company's priorities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>谷歌公司正在对其数字助理、硬件和工程团队的员工进行裁员，以节省成本并专注于人工智能（AI）。</li>    <li>此次裁员影响了包括副总裁和董事在内的多名员工，其中一些员工的年薪高达数百万美元。</li>    <li>谷歌及其领导层一直强调削减成本措施，以便将资源分配给他们的首要任务。</li>    <li>字母工人联盟报告说，已有超过 1,000 名员工被解雇，一些人质疑该公司更注重削减成本而不是建立信任。</li>    <li>谷歌重新关注人工智能的努力正值微软和 ChatGPT 等竞争对手在该领域取得进展之际。</li>    <li>此次裁员引起了谷歌员工的焦虑，一些人对未来的工作保障表示担忧，并质疑该公司的优先事项。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>core (adj.) - /kɔːr/ 核心，核心的。    <p>原文例句：Google’s core internet search business feels the heat from the AI offerings of rivals Microsoft and ChatGPT-creator OpenAI. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源于拉丁语，意味着“中心，核心”。在这个例句中，它描述了谷歌的核心互联网搜索业务感受到来自微软和 ChatGPT 的 AI 产品的竞争压力。</p></li>    <li>layoff (n.) - /ˈleɪˌɔːf/ 解雇，裁员。    <p>原文例句：Alphabet’s Google is laying off hundreds of people working on its digital assistant, hardware and engineering teams as part of a continued effort to lower costs and focus on artificial intelligence (AI).The affected employees included those working on the voice-based Google Assistant and the augmented reality hardware team. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由lay（放置，放下）和off（离开，关闭）组成的，表示“放下来，解雇”。在这个例句中，它指的是Alphabet 的谷歌公司正在解雇數百名員工，以降低成本並专注于人工智能（AI）。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>vice president - 副总裁    <p>原文例句：The cuts struck both rank-and-file employees and executives, including four vice-presidents and 25 directors. </p>    <p>例句讲解：vice president 意为副总裁或副主席，是副手的意思，其主要职责和工作内容是协助正长官处理日常工作，并对上级负责，对正长官提出的指示或政策提供advice（建议），并参加上级的决策会议。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Throughout the second half of 2023, a number of our teams made changes to become more efficient and work better, and to align their resources to their biggest product priorities. - 在 2023 年下半年，我们的一些团队做出了改变，以便变得更加高效，更好地工作，并将他们的资源与最大的产品优先事项保持一致。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是a number of our teams made changes，其中主语是a number of our teams，谓语是made changes，宾语是to become more efficient and work better, and to align their resources to their biggest product priorities。Throughout the second half of 2023是一个时间状语，表示在 2023 年下半年。to become more efficient and work better, and to align their resources to their biggest product priorities是一个目的状语，表示做出的改变的目的是为了变得更加高效，更好地工作，并将他们的资源与最大的产品优先事项保持一致。这个句子的意思是说，在 2023 年下半年，我们的一些团队做出了改变，以便变得更加高效，更好地工作，并将他们的资源与最大的产品优先事项保持一致。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语做定语 - 分词短语可以充当定语，修饰名词或代词。    <p>原文例句：The company continued to make smaller trims over the course of 2023, including lay-offs within teams focused on recruiting, news products and the Waze mapping app. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，分词短语including lay-offs within teams focused on recruiting, news products and the Waze mapping app作定语，修饰名词trims。这个分词短语表示公司在2023年全年继续进行小规模裁员，其中包括专注于招聘、新闻产品和Waze地图应用程序的团队内裁员。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The affected employees include those working on the voice-based Google Assistant and the augmented reality hardware team</li>
<li>The cuts struck both rank-and-file employees and executives, including four vice-presidents and 25 directors</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/663b61ac-615c-43fb-8726-9289f3dd1057_e5c63b15.jpg" /><figcaption>A Google logo seen during the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>Alphabet’s Google is laying off hundreds of people working on its digital assistant, hardware and engineering teams as part of a continued effort to lower costs and focus on artificial intelligence (AI).</p><p>The affected employees included those working on the voice-based Google Assistant and the augmented reality hardware team. The central engineering organisation was also hit by cuts, the company said.</p><p>The reductions come as Google’s core internet search business feels the heat from the AI offerings of rivals Microsoft and ChatGPT-creator OpenAI. On calls with investors in recent months, Google executives pledged to scrutinise their operations to identify places where they can make cuts, and free up resources to invest in their biggest priorities.</p><p>“Throughout the second half of 2023, a number of our teams made changes to become more efficient and work better, and to align their resources to their biggest product priorities,” a spokesperson for the Mountain View, California-based company said in a statement. “Some teams are continuing to make these kinds of organisational changes, which include some role eliminations globally.”</p><p>Alphabet shares were little changed on Thursday, closing at US$142.08 in New York.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A statue of the Android mascot. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/e277ff08-d4f0-488c-b2be-05c62a346d28_0c42f09f.jpg" title="A statue of the Android mascot. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>A statue of the Android mascot. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>The cuts struck both rank-and-file employees and executives. Disclosures filed by Google with the state of California show that 630 workers in the state have been let go this week, including four vice-presidents and 25 directors. Employees at those levels often earn millions of dollars per year in compensation, according to a person with knowledge of the matter.</p><p>The Alphabet Workers Union, which represents some Google employees, said more than 1,000 workers have been let go so far in total.</p><p>The co-founders of Fitbit, James Park and Eric Friedman, are also leaving Google as part of the reorganisation, a company spokesperson confirmed. Google acquired the smartwatch company in 2019 for US$2.1 billion.</p><p>Workers at the search giant have been on edge since January of last year, when Alphabet said it would <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3207638/google-parent-company-alphabet-lay-12000-workers-ai-focus-intensifies" target="_self" title="">cut about 12,000 jobs</a>, more than 6 per cent of its global workforce. That sent shock waves through Silicon Valley.</p><p>The company continued to make smaller trims over the course of 2023, including lay-offs within teams focused on recruiting, news products and the Waze mapping app.</p><p>While the large round of cuts in January 2023 was telegraphed by Alphabet chief executive officer Sundar Pichai, this year’s reductions have been communicated by lower-level leaders, such as vice-presidents and human resources, according to a current employee and a former worker.</p><p>Googlers and recently laid-off employees shared information with each other about the cuts in Discord chats, hallway conversations and other social networks, two current employees told Bloomberg. A document noting which roles got cut, as well as resources for laid-off coworkers, circulated among workers on Wednesday and Thursday, one worker said.</p><p>Staffers thought the company leadership would have learned from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3208941/google-workers-stage-rallies-against-job-cuts-low-wages" target="_self" title="">the outcry that large-scale job losses provoked</a> last year, a current employee said, noting that Google is focused almost exclusively on cost-cutting now. The employee said everyone is talking about having a Plan B.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239082/microsofts-bets-generative-ai-boost-azure-cloud-business-alphabets-google-cloud-disappoints" title="">Microsoft’s AI bets lift cloud business, as Google Cloud disappoints</a></h3><p>Workers said it was difficult to get a full picture of how many jobs were affected. Google – which had about 182,000 employees as of September 30, according to regulatory filings – said more cuts could be expected throughout January as decisions are made at the department level.</p><p>The company employed 190,700 workers before the lay-offs last year, in addition to tens of thousands of contractors around the world.</p><p>One of the Google employees who lost his job this week said the first sign of trouble came when he tried to check his work email, only to find he had been logged off. He found a message delivering the news that he had lost his job in his personal email.</p><p>Over the past year, there have been several rounds of micro-lay-offs, the worker said, speaking on condition of anonymity for fear of professional repercussions. He said it has killed morale at the company and is not conducive to creating trust.</p><p>Some Googlers have come to view January as a new grim annual tradition of mass lay-offs.</p><p>While Google executives have framed the cuts as a way to refocus resources on the company’s biggest priorities, the worker who was just fired said that he and a number of his teammates who were let go were working on AI.</p><p>Amazon.com also laid off hundreds of staff in its Prime Video and studios business this week, raising questions about whether another major round of job cuts was under way in Silicon Valley.</p><p>Semafor first reported the lay-offs to the Google Assistant team, while 9to5Google first reported the reorganisation for hardware. Affected staff have begun receiving the news and will have the opportunity to apply for open positions elsewhere within Google, the company said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US bitcoin ETF trades soar to US$4.6 billion on first day after landmark SEC approval</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248152/us-bitcoin-etfs-trades-soar-us46-billion-first-day-after-landmark-sec-approval</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) approved the first spot bitcoin ETFs, leading to the launch of these products in the US.</li>    <li>The new ETFs saw significant trading volumes, with Grayscale, BlackRock, and Fidelity dominating.</li>    <li>Fees for the new ETFs are lower than the industry standard, with some firms offering fee waivers.</li>    <li>Bitcoin price increased to its highest level since December 2021 following the ETF launches.</li>    <li>Analysts predict varying estimates for the amount of inflows that spot bitcoin ETFs could attract.</li>    <li>Concerns remain regarding the volatility and risk associated with cryptocurrencies, with some experts cautioning against investing in them.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>美国证券交易委员会（SEC）批准了首批现货比特币ETF，这些产品在美国推出。</li>    <li>新ETF的交易量很大，其中灰度、贝莱德和富达占据主导地位。</li>    <li>新ETF的费用低于行业标准，一些公司甚至提供了一段时间的免费费用或一定美元价值资产的免费费用。</li>    <li>ETF推出后，比特币价格涨至2021年12月以来的最高水平。</li>    <li>分析师对现货比特币ETF可能吸引的流入量预计不同。</li>    <li>对于加密货币的波动性和风险，人们仍然存在担忧，一些专家告诫不要投资加密货币。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>green light (n.) - /ɡriːn laɪt/ 绿灯，许可；批准。    <p>原文例句：The green light from the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) for the products finally came late on Wednesday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由green（绿色）和light（光）组成的，表示“绿灯，许可，批准”，美国证券交易委员会（SEC）最终在周三晚间为这些产品开绿灯。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>spark (v.) - /spɑːrk/ 引起，触发。    <p>原文例句：The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由spark（火花，火星）组成的，表示“引起，触发”，监管部门的点头引发了发行人之间激烈的市场份额竞争。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>nod (n.) - /nɑːd/ 点头，同意。    <p>原文例句：The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由nod（点头）组成的，表示“点头，同意”，监管部门的点头引发了发行人之间激烈的市场份额竞争。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>waive (v.) - /weɪv/ 放弃，免除。    <p>原文例句：After its ETF started trading, Valkyrie cut its fees a second time to 0.25 per cent and waived them for the first three months.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由waive（挥舞）组成的，表示“放弃，免除”，在ETF开始交易后，Valkyrie第二次将费用降至0.25%，并在前三个月免除费用。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>implosion (n.) - /ɪmˈpləʊʒən/ 突然收缩，爆炸。    <p>原文例句：The broader investment community still views cryptocurrencies as risky, with scandals such as the implosion of crypto exchange FTX in 2022 adding to investors’ wariness.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由in-（向内）和plode（爆炸）组成的，表示“突然收缩，爆炸”，更广泛的投资界仍然认为加密货币具有风险，2022年FTX加密货币交易所的爆炸等丑闻增加了投资者的谨慎。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>euphoria (n.) - /juːˈfɔːriə/ 欣喜若狂。    <p>原文例句：Some analysts cautioned that the euphoria around the approval might be premature.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由eu-（美好）和phoria（状态）组成的，表示“欣喜若狂”，一些分析师警告说，围绕批准的欣喜若狂可能为时过早。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>spark intense competition - 触发激烈竞争    <p>原文例句：The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由spark（引起，触发）和intense competition（激烈竞争）组成的，表示“触发激烈竞争”，监管部门的点头引发了发行人之间激烈的市场份额竞争。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers, some of whom slashed the fees for their products well below the US ETF industry’s standard even before Thursday’s launch. - 监管部门的点头引发了发行人之间激烈的市场份额竞争，其中一些发行人甚至在星期四推出之前就把其产品的费用大幅降低到远低于美国ETF行业标准的水平。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers。其中主语是The regulatory nod，谓语是sparked，宾语是intense competition for market share among the issuers。some of whom slashed the fees for their products well below the US ETF industry’s standard even before Thursday’s launch是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰发行人，表示其中一些发行人甚至在星期四推出之前就把其产品的费用大幅降低到远低于美国ETF行业标准的水平。这个句子的意思是说，监管部门的点头引发了发行人之间激烈的市场份额竞争，其中一些发行人甚至在星期四推出之前就把其产品的费用大幅降低到远低于美国ETF行业标准的水平。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式 - 用于表示可能性、能力、必要性等。    <p>原文例句：Circle Internet Financial, the company behind stablecoin USDC, said it had confidentially filed for a US initial public offering.</p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式是由to加动词原形构成的，它可以表示可能性、能力、必要性等。在这个例句中，不定式had confidentially filed for a US initial public offering表示Circle Internet Financial公司已经秘密提交了在美国首次公开募股（IPO）的申请。</p>    </li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>分词 - 用于表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The green light from the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) for the products finally came late on Wednesday.</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词是由动词原形加-ing或-ed构成的，它可以表示动作或状态。在这个例句中，现在分词coming表示动作，它修饰light，表示美国证券交易委员会（SEC）终于在周三晚间为这些产品开绿灯。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including those from BlackRock, Grayscale and Fidelity – began trading in the US on Thursday</li>
<li>The ETF launches lifted the price of bitcoin up to its highest level since December 2021</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ba11cbce-0732-4b24-95d7-8df4f18e140b_28c230ae.jpg" /><figcaption>Representatives and guests from BlackRock rang the opening bell as bitcoin spot ETFs began trading on the Nasdaq Exchange on Thursday. Photo: Getty Images/AFP </figcaption></figure><p>US-listed bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs) saw US$4.6 billion worth of shares trade hands as of Thursday afternoon, according to LSEG data, as investors jumped into the landmark products approved by the US securities regulator on Wednesday.</p><p>The products mark a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry that will test whether digital assets – still viewed by many professionals as risky – can gain broader acceptance as an investment.</p><p>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust, Grayscale Bitcoin Trust and ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF, among others – began trading Thursday morning, kicking off a fierce competition for market share.</p><p>Grayscale, BlackRock and Fidelity dominated trading volumes, the LSEG data showed.</p><p>“Trading volumes have been relatively strong for new ETF products,” said Todd Rosenbluth, strategist at VettaFi. “But this is a longer race than just a single day’s trading.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ae8a3757-ffff-4ff6-8d4c-962edf286621_a66cec46.jpg" title="The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">green light from the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)</a> for the products finally came late on Wednesday, following a decade-long tussle with the crypto industry.</p><p>Some executives called out bitcoin as a high-risk investment, and Vanguard – the largest provider of mutual funds – said it had no plans to make the new batch of spot bitcoin ETFs available on its platform to its brokerage clients.</p><p>The SEC had earlier rejected all spot bitcoin ETFs on investor protection concerns. SEC chairman Gary Gensler said in a statement on Wednesday that the approvals were not an endorsement of bitcoin, calling it a “speculative, volatile asset”.</p><p>The ETF launches lifted the price of bitcoin up to its highest level since December 2021. It was last up 0.77 per cent at US$46,303, while the price of ether, the second-largest cryptocurrency, was up 2.79 per cent at US$2597.95.</p><h3>RACE FOR MARKET SHARE</h3><p>The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers, some of whom slashed the fees for their products well below the US ETF industry’s standard even before Thursday’s launch.</p><p>Fees on the new bitcoin ETFs range from 0.2 per cent to 1.5 per cent, with many firms also offering to waive fees entirely for a certain period or for a certain dollar volume of assets. After its ETF started trading, Valkyrie cut its fees a second time to 0.25 per cent and waived them for the first three months.</p><p>Grayscale was approved to convert its existing bitcoin trust into an ETF on Thursday, overnight creating the world’s largest bitcoin ETF with more than US$28 billion in assets under management.</p><p>Estimates for how much spot bitcoin ETFs could reel in vary widely. Analysts at Bernstein estimated that flows will build up gradually to cross US$10 billion in 2024, while Standard Chartered analysts this week said the ETFs could draw US$50 billion to US$100 billion this year alone. Other analysts have said inflows could be US$55 billion over five years.</p><p>As the ETFs began trading on Thursday, market participants were closely watching bid-ask spreads: the difference between the price for a trader to buy into an ETF and the price it can be sold. ETFs with narrower spreads are typically viewed as more desirable.</p><p>Trading volume, internal plumbing and the number of participants involved “are critically important to driving the spreads to a good spot”, said Jason Stoneberg, director of product strategy at Invesco, whose ETF with Galaxy Digital debuted on Thursday.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>Some analysts cautioned that the euphoria around the approval might be premature. The broader investment community still views cryptocurrencies as risky, with scandals such as the implosion of crypto exchange FTX in 2022 adding to investors’ wariness.</p><p>A Vanguard spokeswoman said the firm had no plans to launch its own crypto investment products, and that its focus remains on core asset classes such as stocks, bonds and cash, which it views “as the blocks of a well-balanced, long-term investment portfolio”.</p><p>Speaking at a webinar on Thursday, Sharmin Mossavar-Rahmani, head of the Investment Strategy Group and chief investment officer of wealth management at Goldman Sachs, said cryptocurrencies had no place in an investment portfolio.</p><p>“When you think about it, where is there any value to something like bitcoin?” she said. “We don’t think it is an asset class to invest in.”</p><h3>CRYPTO STOCKS GAIN</h3><p>Still, some expect the products to pave the way for even more innovative crypto ETFs, including spot ether products.</p><p>Grayscale CEO Michael Sonnenshein said in an interview Thursday that the firm plans to file for a covered call ETF in an effort to allow investors to generate income from options on its spot bitcoin product.</p><p>Cryptocurrency-related stocks initially climbed higher on Thursday, but ended the day lower, with bitcoin miners Riot Platforms and Marathon Digital dropping 15.8 per cent and 12.6 per cent respectively.</p><p>Bitcoin investor Microstrategy fell 5.2 per cent and crypto exchange Coinbase 6.7 per cent. The ProShares Bitcoin Strategy ETF, which tracks bitcoin futures, gained 0.44 per cent.</p><p>Also on Thursday, Circle Internet Financial, the company behind stablecoin USDC, said it had confidentially filed for a US initial public offering. Circle controls the issuance and governance of USDC, a cryptocurrency pegged to the US dollar.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>European Union not in ‘Champions League’ of economic security, ASML rep says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3248135/european-union-not-champions-league-economic-security-senior-asml-official-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In the European Union's efforts to reduce its reliance on China, ASML's top EU lobbyist, Wouter Baljon, voiced strong criticisms. He painted a bleak picture of Europe's position, stating that it was not in the "Champions League" of economic security and struggled to even reach the Europa League level. ASML, a Dutch semiconductor equipment giant and industry leader, feels the brunt of geopolitical tensions, as it has been forced to stop selling certain advanced machines to Chinese buyers, and the US policy focuses on suppressing China's industrial progress. Baljon emphasized that export controls have become an industrial policy instrument, not merely about dual-use goods.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: European tech leader criticizes EU's approach to economic security and trade with China.</li>    <li>Theme: Balancing security and economic interests in the face of global geopolitical dynamics.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The EU should prioritize competitiveness and growth, ensuring that security concerns do not overshadow economic development.</li>    <li>Main information: ASML's representative Wouter Baljon's remarks highlighting EU's challenges in economic security; industry representatives expressing concerns about regulatory overreach; the US policy aimed at limiting China's technological progress.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在欧盟努力减少对中国的依赖时，ASML的欧盟顶级说客沃特·巴尔容表达了强烈的批评意见。他描绘了一幅欧盟地位黯淡无光的景象，称其不在经济安全的“冠军联赛”中，甚至难以达到欧罗巴联赛的水平。ASML是一家荷兰半导体设备巨头和行业领导者，它感受到了地缘政治紧张局势的冲击，被迫停止向中国买家出售某些先进机器，而美国政策则致力于抑制中国的工业进步。巴尔容强调，出口控制已经成为一项产业政策工具，而不仅仅是关于两用商品。  <ul>    <li>摘要：欧洲科技巨头批评欧盟在经济安全和与中国贸易方面的方法。</li>    <li>主题：在全球地缘政治动态中平衡安全和经济利益。</li>    <li>观点：欧盟应优先考虑竞争力和增长，确保安全问题不会掩盖经济发展。</li>    <li>主要信息：ASML代表沃特·巴尔容的言论凸显了欧盟在经济安全方面面临的挑战；行业代表对监管力度过大表达关切；美国政策旨在限制中国的技术进步。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>lobbyist (n.) - /ˈlɑːbɪst/ 游说者，说客。    <p>原文例句：Baljon delivered his comments in Brussels during an event hosted by the European Policy Centre. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于lobby（大厅，游说），表示“游说者，说客”。在这个例句中，它指的是ASML的欧盟顶级说客Wouter Baljon在布鲁塞尔发表了他的评论。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>curtail (v.) - /kɜːˈteɪl/ 减少，削减。    <p>原文例句：The American policy was “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, Baljon said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于curt（短的）和tail（尾巴），表示“减少，削减”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国政策旨在减少中国取得工业进步的能力。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Champions League - 欧洲冠军联赛。    <P>原文例句：If you think about the Champions League of economic security and geoeconomic statecraft, we have to think of the United States, we have to think of China, and we also have to think of Japan.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这是一个专有名词，指的是欧洲足球俱乐部协会联盟组织的年度足球比赛，是欧洲俱乐部足球最高级别的赛事。在这个例句中，它表示经济安全和地缘经济治国的冠军联赛。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>We are not an incumbent unfortunately. As the EU 27, we are a challenger, and we need the instruments and the approaches to reflect this.”<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是We are a challenger，其中主语是We，谓语是are，宾语是challenger。not an incumbent unfortunately是一个状语，修饰主句，表示我们不幸地不是现任者。As the EU 27是一个状语从句，作原因状语，表示作为欧盟27国，S我们是一个挑战者。and we need the instruments and the approaches to reflect this是一个同位语从句，作目的状语，表示我们需要相应的工具和方法来反映这一点。这个句子的意思是说，我们不幸地不是现任者，作为欧盟27国，我们是一个挑战者，我们需要相应的工具和方法来反映这一点。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The American policy was “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, Baljon said, adding that the EU was living in “la-la land” if it thought otherwise.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示动作或状态。结构是：现在分词（-ing形式）+ 名词或代词。在这个例句中，分词短语是curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress，表示削减中国取得工业进步的能力。这个句子的意思是说，美国政策旨在减少中国取得工业进步的能力，Baljon说，欧盟如果认为事实并非如此，那就是活在“梦境中”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较句 - 表示两者的比较。    <p>原文例句：“We are not an incumbent unfortunately. As the EU 27, we are a challenger, and we need the instruments and the approaches to reflect this.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示两者的比较。结构是：主语 + be not + as + 形容词或副词 + as + 宾语。在这个例句中，主语是We，谓语是be not，宾语是as + 形容词或副词 + as challenger。这个句子的意思是说，我们不幸地不是现任者，作为欧盟27国，我们是一个挑战者。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Dutch semiconductor equipment giant among several business groups on continent critical of Brussels’ efforts to de-risk its relations with Beijing</li>
<li>American policy “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, ASML’s top EU lobbyist adds</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/3ee1f9f0-3899-41eb-8332-c26934257ad0_b5a707dc.jpg" /><figcaption>A view of ASML Holding NV headquarters in Veldhoven, Netherlands. The Dutch semiconductor equipment company, a world leader in chipmaking, is valued at US$285 billion. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/european-union" target="_self" title="">European Union</a> is not in the “Champions League of economic security”, and even “struggles to perform at Europa League level”.</p><p>That was the withering assessment of a senior representative of ASML, Europe’s most valuable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> company, who used a football analogy to attack Brussels’ efforts to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3241838/eu-leader-ursula-von-der-leyen-urges-states-begin-economic-de-risking-china-or-face-trouble" target="_self" title="">de-risk its relations with China</a>.</p><p>“If you think about the Champions League of economic security and geoeconomic statecraft, we have to think of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>, we have to think of China, and we also have to think of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a>,” said Wouter Baljon, the Dutch company’s top EU lobbyist, referring to Europe’s premier football tournament.</p><p>“If you think of the Europa League, or tier two, we look at countries particularly in our industry, like [<a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South] Korea</a>, like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>, and at best Europe, the EU as a collective.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>“The EU clearly … aspires to be in the Champions League, but for high technology, they struggled to perform at Europa League-level,” said Baljon at an event in Brussels on Wednesday, referring to the continent’s inferior competition.</p><p>ASML, valued at US$285 billion, is the world leader in the chipmaking equipment essential for manufacturing advanced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductors</a> and considered the crown jewel in Europe’s tech sector.</p><p>Its executives should have a good idea of who’s who in the pantheon of geopolitical arm-twisting, having been caught in the cross hairs of a fierce <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/us-china-tech-war-rivalry/news" target="_self" title="">US-China tech war</a>.</p><p>ASML has been forced to stop selling some advanced precision lithography machines to Chinese buyers at the behest of the Biden administration.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247042/chip-industry-giant-asml-blocked-us-netherlands-shipping-equipment-china-ahead-export-deadline" title="">ASML blocked from shipping chip-making equipment to China ahead of deadline</a></h3><p>The American policy was “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, Baljon said, adding that the EU was living in “la-la land” if it thought otherwise.</p><p>“We haven’t acknowledged that export controls have become an industrial policy instrument. We still live in this la-la land that it’s about dual-use goods, it’s military-civil fusion.”</p><p>Baljon delivered his comments in Brussels during an event hosted by the European Policy Centre on the EU’s capacity to act as an economic security power as it looks to reduce its dependencies on Beijing.</p><p>Earlier in the day, EU industry chief Thierry Breton described Europe as a “third bloc” in a multipolar world.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ba9b8fc1-5a69-4091-bb98-4a2a845fa781_1126e908.jpg" title="Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>“We need to continue to promote Europe as a third bloc, a balancing force between the US and China,” the commissioner said at the event. “Of course, we will remain an open continent, but on our terms, more assertive than ever.”</p><p>However, ASML’s representative was less confident, saying the European Commission would struggle to define an economic security strategy without the buy-in of powerful member states, which have pushed back against the policy.</p><p>“A certain humbleness might certainly help the EU to act as a collective, particularly in high technology,” said Baljon. “We are not an incumbent unfortunately. As the EU 27, we are a challenger, and we need the instruments and the approaches to reflect this.”</p><p>“We might speak of the ‘geopolitical commission’, but at this point, I think it’s only as geopolitical as [the] Franco-German axis allows it to be, and you also don’t have the manpower to really be in this Champions League.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened" title="">China’s imports of Dutch chip-making equipment surged tenfold in November</a></h3><p>The EU will present an “initiative” on screening outbound investments and a proposal on export controls for four crucial technologies, including microchips, on January 24. These form part of a package of tools aimed at de-risking its trading ties with China.</p><p>Baljon’s remarks were among a series of broadsides voiced at the event as businesses lined up to criticise the EU’s plans.</p><p>Malte Lohan, director general of Orgalim, a trade association representing Europe’s tech industries, said firms in his sector were facing “a tsunami of regulation”.</p><p>“You can’t just regulate your way to economic security from a few office blocks in Brussels,” Lohan said, adding he was “very nervous” about an “unprecedented shift to public intervention in our supply chains”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3244922/eu-china-relations-amid-brussels-de-risk-plans-european-firms-are-reluctant-speak-china" title="">EU firms are reluctant to speak up on China as Brussels tries to de-risk</a></h3><p>“If you look at any one of the instruments in isolation, of course there’s always a very good reason for it … I think we need to accept that this is a completely new paradigm in terms of how supply chains are regulated through public-sector intervention.”</p><p>Luisa Santos, deputy director general at BusinessEurope, another lobby group, said the EU endangered its competitiveness by putting security concerns ahead of economic growth.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ukraine-war" target="_self" title="">war</a> in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ukraine" target="_self" title="">Ukraine</a> had “created a new consensus in the business community” on the security issues Europe faces, she said.</p><p>“But we should not overdo it also, because we have other problems that we need to deal with and we have not dealt with yet, including our competitiveness … what we have seen in these last years is that compared to other partners in terms of overall competitiveness … we [in Europe] are not in such good shape.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China smartphone brand Realme unveils new handset on sidelines of trade show as its biggest rivals stay home</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248116/ces-2024-china-smartphone-brand-realme-unveils-new-handset-sidelines-trade-show-its-biggest-rivals</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Realme unveiled the 12 Pro+ smartphone, targeting young global users with enhanced zoom capabilities on a budget-friendly device. The company emphasized its commitment to providing outstanding products for users at all price segments. Realme hosted a parallel event during CES 2024 in Las Vegas, showcasing its new handset as part of its rebranding efforts. With its slogan changed to "Make it real", Realme aims to capture a niche market segment amid global smartphone sales decline and China's economic recovery challenges.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Realme unveils the 12 Pro+ smartphone with superior zoom capabilities at an affordable price, catering to young overseas users.</li>    <li>Theme: Realme's focus on delivering outstanding products to young users, particularly in a budget-friendly segment.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Realme's strategic approach to targeting a niche market and adapting to global challenges in the smartphone industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Realme's 12 Pro+ smartphone features an advanced periscope lens with a large sensor, targeting young users' preference for zoom photography. The company collaborated with a renowned watch designer for the device's aesthetics and highlighted its commitment to providing quality products across price segments.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  Realme发布了12 Pro+智能手机，以增强变焦功能为卖点，以优惠的价格，瞄准全球年轻用户。该公司强调，他们致力于为所有价位用户提供出众的产品。Realme在拉斯维加斯的CES 2024期间举办了一场平行活动，展示了其新手机，作为其改品牌工作的一部分。Realme的口号已更改为“Make it real”，旨在在全球智能手机销量下降以及中国经济复苏面临挑战的情况下，占据细分市场。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Realme发布了12 Pro+智能手机，具有卓越的变焦功能，价格实惠，面向年轻的海外用户。</li>    <li>主题：Realme专注于为年轻用户提供出众的产品，尤其是在价格实惠的细分市场。</li>    <li>观点：Realme以战略眼光瞄准利基市场，并在智能手机行业中适应全球挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：Realme的12 Pro+智能手机配备了先进的长焦镜头，具有较大的传感器，满足年轻用户对变焦摄影的偏好。该公司与著名手表设计师合作，提升了该设备的审美设计，并强调了其致力于为所有价位用户提供优质产品的承诺。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>half-inch (adj.) - 半英寸的。    <p>原文例句：So the firm has combined a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词由half（半个）和inch（英寸）组成，表示“半英寸”，即长度为半英寸。在这个例句中，它指的是Realme在中端智能手机系列中，将半英寸传感器与3倍光学变焦潜望镜镜头相结合。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make public  (v.) - 公开，公开发表。    <p>原文例句：While the chipset used in the 12 Pro+ will not be made public until closer to its formal launch.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由make（使，让）和public（公共的）组成，表示“使公开，公开发表”。在这个例句中，它指的是Realme在12 Pro+中使用的芯片组，直到正式发布临近时才会公布。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>on to something (phrase) - 发现或意识到某些重要的或有价值的东西。    <p>原文例句：Realme acknowledged challenges from the pandemic, component shortages and longer replacement cycles from consumers, but the firm also touted its sales numbers – more than 200 million handsets sold since its incubation at Oppo – as “giving us confidence that we’re on to something”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由on（在）和something（某物）组成，表示“发现或意识到某些重要的或有价值的东西”。在这个例句中，它指的是Realme承认有挑战，比如疫情、零部件短缺和消费者更换周期延长，但该公司也吹捧他们的销售数字——自从从Oppo孵化以来已经售出了超过2亿部手机——作为“让我们相信我们发现了重要的东西”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>a pre-briefing (n.) - 预简报，预先介绍会。    <p>原文例句：Realme said it did not exhibit at CES because the 12 Pro+ handset has not officially launched yet. It organised a pre-briefing in Las Vegas because many of its contacts across a variety of markets would be in town for the world’s largest consumer electronics show.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由pre-（之前的）和briefing（简报）组成，表示“预简报，预先介绍会”。在这个例句中，它指的是Realme表示他们没有在CES展出，因为12 Pro+手机尚未正式发布。他们组织了在拉斯维加斯的预简报，因为许多来自不同市场的联系人会在这个全球最大的消费电子展中到访。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“What sets us apart from other brands is that we are fully committed to the young generation,” Sam Cheung, senior marketing communications manager for Realme, said in his presentation during the firm’s hour-long event on the sidelines of CES 2024. - “我们与其他品牌的不同之处在于，我们完全致力于年轻一代，”Realme的高级营销传播经理山姆·张在他在一小时的活动中在2024 CES的间隙进行了介绍时说。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是“What sets us apart from other brands is that we are fully committed to the young generation”，其中主语是“What sets us apart from other brands”，谓语是“is”，宾语是“that we are fully committed to the young generation”。“Sam Cheung, senior marketing communications manager for Realme, said in his presentation”是一个插入语，表示山姆·张是Realme的高级营销传播经理，他在介绍时说。“during the firm’s hour-long event on the sidelines of CES 2024”是一个介词短语作状语，表示活动的时间和地点，即在2024年CES的间隙的为期一小时的活动中。这个句子的意思是说，“我们与其他品牌的不同之处在于，我们完全致力于年轻一代，”Realme的高级营销传播经理山姆·张在他在一小时的活动中在2024 CES的间隙进行了介绍时说。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>定语从句 - 定语从句是对先行词进行修饰和限定的句子。    <p>原文例句：“We believe that every user at every price segment deserves an outstanding product,” Cheung said in his presentation.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个定语从句，由“that every user at every price segment deserves an outstanding product”组成，修饰先行词“We”。这个定语从句是对先行词“We”进行修饰和限定，表示我们相信每个用户在每个价格区间都应该拥有一款出色的产品。这个句子的意思是说，“我们相信每个用户在每个价格区间都应该拥有一款出色的产品，”张在他的介绍中说。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The new 12 Pro+ handset to launch at the end of January provides a better zoom lens at a budget price, as Realme caters to young overseas users</li>
<li>Realme sister brand OnePlus was also in Las Vegas, while Xiaomi, Oppo and Vivo sat out the world’s largest consumer electronics show</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/1486c8f9-79ff-40ce-9c1a-5163f3d4b7b2_2eaa662e.jpg" /><figcaption>Realme unveiled the 12 Pro+ smartphone at an event parallel to the CES trade show. The company is targeting young users with better zoom capabilities in a budget device. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" target="_self" title="">Realme</a>, owned by mainland consumer hardware giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/2184877/meet-godfather-chinas-smartphone-industry" target="_self" title="">BBK Electronics</a> which also controls <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/vivo" target="_self" title="">Vivo</a>, held a parallel event in Las Vegas on the sidelines of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ces" target="_self" title="">CES</a> trade show to unveil its new handset as part of a rebranding effort targeting young overseas users.</p><p>While not an official exhibitor at CES, Realme was one of only two major Chinese smartphone brands to show up in Las Vegas this week. On Wednesday, Realme introduced its 12-series smartphones at the same hotel where its sister brand, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oneplus" target="_self" title="">OnePlus</a>, had a series of suites booked for its own presentations outside CES.</p><p>Realme said its latest 12 Pro+ handset has the largest sensor in any periscope lens on a smartphone sold globally, but pointed out that the company’s GT 5 Pro handset sold in China technically has a bigger lens.</p><p>“What sets us apart from other brands is that we are fully committed to the young generation,” Sam Cheung, senior marketing communications manager for Realme, said in his presentation during the firm’s hour-long event on the sidelines of CES 2024. “At Realme, we believe that every user at every price segment deserves an outstanding product.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1506" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/714bf56a-c08f-4ee3-bc44-695f0ea16d52_68aef08b.jpg" title="Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Realme, which did not reveal pricing for its latest handsets, said the chipset used in the 12 Pro+ will not be made public until closer to its formal launch. While the new device uses a mid-tier <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/qualcomm" target="_self" title="">Qualcomm</a> processor, Realme said it collaborated with the US chip design firm on a solution to improve image-processing speed.</p><p>The 11 Pro+ smartphone launched by Realme last year costs 2,799 yuan, or about US$400.</p><p>At its event, Realme said the firm’s slogan, “Dare to leap”, has been changed to “Make it real” as part of a rebranding effort.</p><p>The company said it was focused on a niche market segment, where it has found success overseas at a time when global smartphone sales are slumping and China’s post-pandemic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chinas-economic-recovery" target="_self" title="">economic recovery</a> has sputtered.</p><p>Realme acknowledged challenges from the pandemic, component shortages and longer replacement cycles from consumers, but the firm also touted its sales numbers – more than <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments">200 million handsets sold</a> since its incubation at Oppo – as “giving us confidence that we’re on to something”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" title="">China’s Realme surges past 200 million smartphone shipments</a></h3><p>Moving forward, Realme aims to double down on what it believes young users want most in a smartphone. The answer it came up with is better photos when zooming in. So the firm has combined a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones.</p><p>It also collaborated with watch designer Ollivier Savéo, who previously worked at Rolex and Piaget, among others, on a design evocative of famed Swiss watches.</p><p>At a time of rising scrutiny of all things Chinese, Realme made its latest product announcement in a country leading the charge against tech from China and where the company does not even sell smartphones.</p><p>For all the other missing Chinese brands – and the smattering of journalists and influencers who showed up to cover the Realme event – it may as well have been part of the show. Vivo and Oppo, two of China’s biggest smartphone brands, were nowhere to be found in Las Vegas, even though Realme spun out of Oppo. OnePlus, the Oppo-owned brand, had suites booked for private showings, but also had no presence on the CES exhibition floor.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>Neither <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> nor <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-blacklisted</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> were at CES.</p><p>Realme said it did not exhibit at CES because the 12 Pro+ handset has not officially launched yet. It organised a pre-briefing in Las Vegas because many of its contacts across a variety of markets would be in town for the world’s largest consumer electronics show.</p><p>While the company set a goal last year of selling in more than 100 markets over the next five years, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> is one market where it may not expand owing to the complexities of getting domestic network carrier support.</p><p>The bulk of US handset sales still happen through mobile network operators, forcing smartphone brands to strike deals to find success. OnePlus has struggled with this situation, despite the glowing reviews received by many of its devices from US tech media.</p><p>Realme said it was still trying to cooperate with a US carrier to get into the market, where 87 per cent of teenagers own an iPhone, according to a survey by investment bank Piper Sandler.</p><p>Meanwhile, Realme has been selling in parts of Europe and Latin America, which it described as an important market for the company’s upcoming 12-series handsets.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia reveals progress in China’s self-driving chip market, setting up competition with domestic players</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248095/nvidia-reveals-progress-chinas-self-driving-chip-market-setting-competition-domestic-players</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia has gained popularity among Chinese EV makers for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system.</li>    <li>The growing demand for autonomous vehicles in China is intensifying competition in the sector.</li>    <li>Chinese companies like Horizon Robotics and Black Sesame are competing with Nvidia in autonomous driving technology.</li>    <li>Geely-backed ZEEKR signed up with Nvidia.</li>    <li>The emergence of Huawei as a major player in the Chinese autonomous driving market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia的自动驾驶系统Drive Thor在中国电动汽车制造商中颇受欢迎。</li>    <li>中国对自动驾驶汽车的需求不断增长，加剧了该领域的竞争。</li>    <li>地平线机器人和黑芝麻智能等中国公司正在自动驾驶技术领域与英伟达展开竞争。</li>    <li>吉利控股的ZEEKR签约与Nvidia合作。</li>    <li>华为成为中国自动驾驶市场的主要参与者。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>autonomous (adj.) - /ɔːˈtɑːnəməs/ 自主，自动的。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源于Greek，由auto（自，自我）和nomos（法律，规则）组成，意为“自我管理，自主”。在这个例句中，它指的是Nvidia的自动驾驶系统Drive Thor，该系统能够实现汽车的自动驾驶功能。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>navigate-on-autopilot (n.) - 自动驾驶导航。    <p>原文例句：“Nvidia remains predominant in terms of smart-driving chips in China,” said Brady Wang, an associate director with research firm Counterpoint. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由navigate（导航）和autopilot（自动驾驶）组成的复合词，表示“自动驾驶导航”。在这个例句中，它指的是Nvidia在中国的智能驾驶芯片市场中的主导地位。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>smart passenger vehicle - 智能乘用车。    <P>原文例句：In 2022, China sold about 7 million units of smart passenger vehicles equipped with assisted autonomous driving systems, which translates into a market penetration rate of 35 per cent. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由smart（智能的，聪明的）、passenger（乘客）和vehicle（车辆）组成的，表示“智能乘用车”。在这个例句中，它指的是配备了辅助自动驾驶系统的智能乘用车。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The MIIT in November issued a new policy that encourages EV makers to bring vehicles equipped with high-levels of autonomous driving to Chinese roads, in a major effort to accomplish Chinese President Xi Jinping’s vision of building a strong and modern transport network. - 中国工业和信息化部在 11 月份发布了一项新政策，鼓励电动汽车制造商将配备高水平自动驾驶功能的车辆引入中国道路，作为实现中国国家主席习近平建设强大而现代化交通网络愿景的重大努力。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The MIIT issued a new policy，其中主语是The MIIT，谓语是issued，宾语是a new policy。that encourages EV makers to bring vehicles equipped with high-levels of autonomous driving to Chinese roads是一个定语从句，修饰new policy，表示这项新政策鼓励电动汽车制造商将配备高水平自动驾驶功能的车辆引入中国道路。in a major effort to accomplish Chinese President Xi Jinping’s vision of building a strong and modern transport network是一个目的状语，表示这项新政策的目的是实现中国国家主席习近平建设强大而现代化交通网络的愿景。这个句子的意思是说，中国工业和信息化部在 11 月份发布了一项新政策，鼓励电动汽车制造商将配备高水平自动驾驶功能的车辆引入中国道路，作为实现中国国家主席习近平建设强大而现代化交通网络愿景的重大努力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语作定语 - 可以修饰名词或代词，使句子结构更加紧凑。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，backed ZEEKR是一个分词短语，作定语修饰ZEEKR，表示由吉利控股的ZEEKR。分词短语可以使句子结构更加紧凑，同时也可以提供更多的信息。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Autonomous-driving systems have become a competitive sector as China pushes greater adoption of advanced self-driving technology</li>
<li>Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/46325582-beb7-45f2-ae5c-8a43d08517a8_f1163133.jpg" /><figcaption>Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system. Photo: EPA-EFE </figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia, the US chip maker banned by Washington from selling its most advanced semiconductors to China, has revealed solid progress in the mainland’s electric vehicle (EV) market with its self-driving technology.</p><p>Nvidia said at the CES consumer electronics show in Las Vegas that Chinese EV makers, including Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR, have snapped up its Drive Thor autonomous driving system to enhance performance of their vehicles. This sets up increased competition with local self-driving system providers such as Huawei Technologies.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246414/huawei-and-xiaomi-launch-new-ev-models-china-reigniting-worries-about-price-wars-worlds-largest-ev" target="_self" title="">Autonomous-driving systems</a>, seen as the brains behind future cars, have become a competitive sector as China pushes greater adoption of advanced self-driving technology. Nvidia added Drive Thor – which integrates automated and assisted driving, in-vehicle infotainment, and parking in one single system – to its family of automotive system-on-a-chip solutions in September 2022.</p><p>As of June last year, Nvidia – which is unable to ship its advanced AI chips to China due to US trade sanctions – had about a 52 per cent share of the global navigate-on-autopilot (NOA) market and cooperation agreements with 25 automotive original equipment makers globally, according to data from Gasgoo Institute, a Shanghai-based research company.</p><p>“Nvidia remains predominant in terms of smart-driving chips in China,” said Brady Wang, an associate director with research firm Counterpoint. “But competition between Chinese manufacturers and foreign companies is set to intensify as they compete for a slice of the autonomous driving segment in China’s EV market.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>Chinese EV makers have been big buyers of Nvidia auto chips. For example, Nio’s flagship sedans ET5 and ES7, Li Auto’s L9 model and Xpeng’s G9 vehicle all come equipped with Nvidia’s Orin chips. Automotive chips are seen as a less sensitive area of the semiconductor market by US authorities when it comes to setting trade sanctions.</p><p>In 2022, China sold about 7 million units of smart passenger vehicles equipped with assisted autonomous driving systems, which translates into a market penetration rate of 35 per cent. In the first half of 2023, the market penetration rate rose to almost 43 per cent, according to data from China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT).</p><p>The MIIT in November issued a new policy that encourages EV makers to bring vehicles equipped with high-levels of autonomous driving to Chinese roads, in a major effort to accomplish Chinese President Xi Jinping’s vision of building a strong and modern transport network.</p><p>Thanks to policy stimulus, Chinese autonomous driving system solution providers – including Horizon Robotics and Black Sesame Technologies – have stepped up their game and are set for greater competition with the likes of Nvidia, Qualcomm, and Intel-owned MobileEye in areas such as autonomous driving chips and full-stack smart car solutions.</p><p>Nvidia topped China’s NOA computing solutions market with a share of 53 per cent in the first half of 2023, followed by smart mobility start-up Horizon Robotics with 31 per cent, and Texas Instruments with 9 per cent, according to data from the Gaogong Industry Research Institute (GGII), which tracks nascent industries in China such as EVs and batteries. Huawei and MobileEye ranked in equal 4th place with a 4 per cent market share each.</p><p>Huawei has emerged as a leading player due to its experience in auto chip design and hardware systems after it set up a smart car solution unit in 2019, the year it was added to a US trade blacklist. Under these sanctions, Huawei could not buy most US-origin semiconductors and had to rely on its own smart-driving chips.</p><p>Priot to the 2023 Shanghai Auto Show in April, Huawei launched its own home-grown smart driving platform, called advanced driving system 2.0 (ADS) and powered by a Huawei-made chipset MDC 610, according to a report by research company Counterpoint and a note in July by Kaiyuan Securities.</p><p>In November, Huawei announced it was transferring core technologies from its smart car business into a new joint venture with state-backed Changan Automobile. The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243139/huawei-accelerates-smart-car-ambitions-invitation-four-carmakers-invest-changan-joint-venture" target="_self" title="">new venture</a>, in which Changan has a 40 per cent stake, is open to other car makers as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3235762/superior-teslas-model-s-huawei-and-chery-automobile-ev-venture-luxeed-launch-first-production-model?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">equity investors</a>.</p><p>Despite still being in the red, the firm’s car unit achieved sales of 2.1 billion yuan (US$305 million) in 2022 and 1 billion yuan in revenue in the first half of last year, according to company information.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple supplier BOE, one of the world’s top display makers, forges US$9 billion deal to build next-generation plant in southwestern China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248092/apple-supplier-boe-one-worlds-top-display-makers-forges-us9-billion-deal-build-next-generation-plant</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  BOE Technology Group, a major display manufacturer, announced plans to establish a 63 billion yuan production complex in Chengdu, China, focusing on advanced display manufacturing. This project aligns with the Chinese government's efforts to bolster its position in the global display industry and drive economic recovery. The new facility is expected to position Chengdu as a leading manufacturing hub for flexible panels. Construction is estimated to take 34 months, with mass production targeted for the fourth quarter of 2026.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: BOE Technology Group's new production complex in Chengdu for advanced displays aims to meet global demand and boost China's display manufacturing capacity.</li>    <li>Theme: The ongoing efforts of China to strengthen its role in the global display industry through collaboration with private companies and investment in advanced manufacturing.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: BOE's production complex in Chengdu is seen as a strategic step in China's mission to dominate the global display manufacturing market.</li>    <li>Main information: The project's investment, location, focus on advanced displays, production timeline, and its contribution to China's position in the display industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  京东方科技集团将在中国成都投资兴建一座630亿元人民币的生产基地，专注于先进显示屏制造，该项目符合中国政府为提升其全球显示行业地位和推动经济复苏而做出的努力。这座新基地将让成都成为柔性面板制造领先的中心，预计工期34个月，2026年第四季度进行批量生产。  <ul>    <li>摘要：京东方科技集团在成都建立的新生产基地，旨在满足全球需求并提升中国显示屏制造产能。</li>    <li>主题：中国正在通过与私营企业合作和投资先进制造业来强化其在全球显示行业的作用。</li>    <li>观点：京东方在成都的生产基地被视为中国实现全球显示屏制造市场主导地位的战略举措。</li>    <li>主要信息：项目投资、选址、对先进显示屏的关注、生产时间表及其对中国显示产业地位的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>AMOLED (n.) - active-matrix organic light-emitting diode 主动矩阵有机发光二极管    <p>原文例句：BOE will build its so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED – for active-matrix organic light-emitting diode – production facility to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets, according to the firm.</p>    <p>例句讲解：AMOLED是主动矩阵有机发光二极管的缩写，是一种显示技术，用于生产轻薄、节能的显示屏，常用于智能手机、平板电脑和笔记本电脑等设备。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>substrate (n.) - 基底、衬底    <p>原文例句：The next-generation plant is designed to produce 32,000 glass substrates – each measuring 2,290 millimetres by 2,620mm – every month.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Substrate在该语境中指显示屏制造过程中使用的基板或衬底，通常由玻璃或其他材料制成，为显示屏的显示层提供支撑和结构。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>   <li>in terms of - 就……而论，就……而言</li>    <p>原文例句：The deal represents the largest single industrial project in terms of investment in Chengdu, the capital of southwestern Sichuan province.</p>    <p>例句讲解：In terms of是固定搭配，表示“就…而言”，在这个例句中，In terms of investment是就投资而言的意思。整句话的意思是，这项交易就投资而言，是成都市有史以来规模最大的一笔工业项目。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China is forecast to dominate global display manufacturing capacity, with a 72 per cent market share from 2026 to 2027, the DSCC report said.    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是China，谓语是forecast to dominate，宾语是global display manufacturing capacity，介词短语from 2026 to 2027表示时间范围，状语with a 72 per cent market share表示市场份额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，其构成是：have/has + 过去分词。在这个例句中，have是助动词，established是过去分词。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>BOE’s so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex is expected to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets</li>
<li>The deal represents the largest single industrial project in terms of investment in Chengdu, the capital of southwestern Sichuan province</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/f510ed59-cdd2-46ae-9e74-0cdf88c294bd_6e2e158b.jpg" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group’s new production complex for advanced displays in Chengdu, capital of southwestern Sichuan province, is expected to start mass production by the fourth quarter of 2026. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> supplier <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/3024664/how-chinese-accountant-turned-dying-state-owned-factory-worlds-no-1?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">BOE Technology Group</a>, one of the world’s largest display makers, will set up a 63-billion yuan (US$9 billion) next-generation production complex in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chengdu" target="_self" title="">Chengdu</a>, capital of southwestern Sichuan province, that is expected to bolster mainland China’s lead in display manufacturing capacity over the next few years.</p><p>The Chengdu municipal government on Wednesday said in a statement that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/beijing" target="_self" title="">Beijing</a>-based BOE and the city’s Hi-Tech Industrial Development Zone have signed the contract to build the plant, representing the largest single industrial project in the capital in terms of investment.</p><p>BOE, which initially announced the project last December, will build its so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED – for active-matrix organic light-emitting diode – production facility to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets, according to the firm.</p><p>Shares of BOE in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shenzhen" target="_self" title="">Shenzhen</a> closed up 1.07 per cent to 3.76 yuan on Thursday.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/81c3e4de-5983-4500-9e40-24c9b7f0441d_edd804f5.jpg" title="BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>The deal underscores efforts by Chinese local governments to increase collaboration with Big Tech companies in the private sector, which is in line with the mainland’s efforts to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3210306/chinas-key-private-sector-needs-continuity-stability-support-economic-recovery-doubts-remain" target="_self" title="">restore business confidence and drive economic recovery</a>.</p><p>The new BOE production facility is expected to position Chengdu as the display industry’s largest manufacturing base for advanced flexible panels.</p><p>Construction of the new plant is estimated to take 34 months, according to BOE, and mass production is projected to start by the fourth quarter of 2026. The next-generation plant is designed to produce 32,000 glass substrates – each measuring 2,290 millimetres by 2,620mm – every month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/73fdd8a8-8b16-4d68-8c5f-e654e2a0eacf_1126e908.jpg" title="BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Apart from accommodating larger substrates, BOE said its Gen-8.6 AMOLED production line will be able to enhance panel-cutting efficiency for mid-size displays, reduce production costs, lower power consumption and achieve an extended lifespan.</p><p>OLED displays for mobile and other information technology devices are expected to enjoy rapid expansion between 2022 and 2027, with a compound annual growth rate of 7.3 per cent, according to a recent report by Display Supply Chain Consultants (DSCC).</p><p>China is forecast to dominate global display manufacturing capacity, with a 72 per cent market share from 2026 to 2027, the DSCC report said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/3024664/how-chinese-accountant-turned-dying-state-owned-factory-worlds-no-1" title="">How Chinese accountant turned dying factory into No 1 display maker</a></h3><p>By comparison, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>’s market shares are expected to reach 8 per cent and 17 per cent, respectively, in 2027.</p><p>The global OLED market is predicted to generate US$64 billion in revenue in 2026, driven by demand for panels used in laptops, computers monitors and tablets, according to DSCC.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei secures JD.com as HarmonyOS partner as home-grown software emerges as alternative for Apple iOS, Android in China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248044/huawei-secures-jdcom-harmonyos-partner-home-grown-software-emerges-alternative-apple-ios-android</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Huawei has partnered with Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com to develop an app for HarmonyOS Next, which is expected to surpass Apple's iOS as the second-largest operating system in China in 2023. The company aims to promote wider adoption of its home-grown operating system, driven by the success of the Mate 60 series.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei and JD.com collaborate to develop an app for HarmonyOS Next.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's push for wider adoption of HarmonyOS and its potential to become the second-largest operating system in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: HarmonyOS as a viable alternative to Android and iOS in the Chinese market.</li>    <li>Main information: JD.com's role in developing an app for HarmonyOS Next; Huawei's collaboration with other Chinese internet companies for native app development; projection of HarmonyOS Next surpassing iOS in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  华为与中国电商巨头京东合作开发一款应用于HarmonyOS Next的应用软件，预计该系统将于2023年超越苹果iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。华为计划推动其国产操作系统更广泛的采用，其推动力来自于华为Mate 60系列手机的成功。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为和京东合作开发HarmonyOS Next应用软件。</li>    <li>主题：华为推动HarmonyOS更广泛的采用，该系统有可能成为中国第二大操作系统。</li>    <li>观点：在中国的市场中，HarmonyOS是Android和iOS的可行替代品。</li>    <li>主要信息：京东开发HarmonyOS Next应用软件的作用；华为与其他中国互联网公司合作开发原生应用；HarmonyOS Next超越iOS成为中国第二大操作系统的预测。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>projection (n.) - /prəˈdʒɛkʃən/ 预测，投影。    <p>原文例句：Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”, Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由pro-（向前）和jacere（投掷）组成，意为“投射，预测，预计”。在这个例句中，它指的是HarmonyOS的一个新的里程碑，即JD.com成为其一个重量级的合作伙伴。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>scenario (n.) - /sɪˈnɛəriˌoʊ/ 情景，场景。    <p>原文例句：JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform and its ability to support transitions between multiple scenarios. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由skena（舞台）和graphos（绘画）组成，意为“场景，场景”。在这个例句中，它指的是HarmonyOS Next的多场景切换能力，即可以在不同的场景之间进行切换。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take the lead - 带头，领头，引领。    <P>原文例句：Huawei is taking the lead in the development of HarmonyOS, China's first mobile operating system. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词是由take（抓，取）和lead（引领，领导）构成的，表示“带头，领头”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为在HarmonyOS的开发中发挥着引领作用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of HarmonyOS, which is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS in China this year. - 华为正在推动HarmonyOS的更广泛采用，预计今年将在中国超过苹果的iOS。<p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of HarmonyOS，其中主语是Huawei，谓语是is pushing，宾语是wider adoption of HarmonyOS。which is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS in China this year是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰HarmonyOS，表示HarmonyOS预计今年将在中国超过苹果的iOS。这个句子的意思是说，华为正在推动HarmonyOS的更广泛采用，预计今年将在中国超过苹果的iOS。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示现在正在发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of HarmonyOS. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，结构是：be + 动词-ing。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，动词-ing是动词的现在分词形式。这种时态表示动作或状态正在现在进行或发生。在这个例句中，be用的是is，表示华为正在推动HarmonyOS的更广泛采用。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的承受者承受的。    <p>原文例句：HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative in August 2019. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的语态，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的过去分词形式。这种语态表示动作或状态是由句子中的承受者承受的。在这个例句中，be用的是was，表示HarmonyOS是被作为Android的替代品推出.</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform</li>
<li>Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of HarmonyOS, which is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS in China this year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/5435c70a-132e-4030-86c0-5a8e160d23ce_92ca8b90.jpg" /><figcaption>A billboard advertising Huawei’s Harmony OS at the Smart China Expo in Chongqing, Sept. 4, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has secured another partner to promote use of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3136017/will-huaweis-harmony-operating-system-end-global-duopoly-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS</a>, as the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">US-sanctioned</a> telecommunications equipment giant continues to take on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p><p>Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform and its ability to support transitions between multiple scenarios, Richard Yu Chengdong, chief executive of Huawei’s consumer business group, said on Wednesday.</p><p>Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”, Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo.</p><p>Joining with a growing number of Chinese internet companies, Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of its home-grown HarmonyOS, which is projected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" target="_self" title="">surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China</a> this year, according to Canadian research firm TechInsights.</p><p>While Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, driven by the firm’s smartphone comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to TechInsights.</p><p>The self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative in August 2019, three months after the US government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">added Huawei to its Entity List</a>. Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p><p>A developer preview of HarmonyOS Next is expected to be launched in the first quarter of 2024. Huawei is already working with major Chinese companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p><p>Ant Group, the fintech affiliate of South China Morning Post owner <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, said last month that it was building a new version of mobile payment app Alipay based on HarmonyOS, after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242703/alibaba-develops-native-dingtalk-app-harmonyos-huawei-aims-end-support-android-apps?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba started development on a new version of DingTalk</a>, its workplace collaboration app.</p><p>Other major Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> companies – including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>, video gaming giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netease?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">NetEase</a> and food delivery market leader <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> – in November started to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241371/chinese-big-tech-firms-jdcom-netease-and-meituan-rush-hire-harmonyos-based-app-developers-huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">recruit developers to build native apps for HarmonyOS</a>.</p><p>McDonald’s China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees – became <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244236/mcdonalds-china-pushes-development-native-apps-based-harmonyos-adoption-huaweis-mobile-operating?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239589/xiaomi-launches-home-grown-cross-device-system-hyperos-us-sanctioned-huawei-moves-further-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS Next</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Elon Musk’s X tells watchdog it has shed 1,000 ‘safety’ staff</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248024/elon-musks-x-tells-watchdog-it-has-shed-1000-safety-staff</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  In Australia, the eSafety Commission criticized Twitter's mass layoffs and reinstatement of banned accounts, citing a surge in harmful content. The commission highlighted the loss of 80% of software engineers responsible for safety, creating a situation conducive to hate speech dissemination. Australia has led efforts to regulate social media, requiring tech companies to address issues like child sexual abuse. However, X failed to respond to a fine and initiated legal action to overturn it.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Australian watchdog criticizes Twitter layoffs and account reinstatement, emphasizing increased harmful content risks.</li>    <li>Theme: Social media regulation, particularly Twitter's impact on online safety, content moderation, and harmful content control.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of online safety and content moderation, the importance of tech companies taking responsibility, and the potential consequences of inadequate moderation.</li>    <li>Main information: Twitter layoffs, reinstatement of banned accounts, concerns over moderation capabilities, Australia's regulatory efforts, and Twitter's lack of response to fines and ongoing legal action.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  澳大利亚电子安全委员会批评推特大规模裁员和恢复禁言账号的做法，认为此举导致有害内容激增。该委员会强调失去 80% 负责安全工作的软件工程师，造成了有利于仇恨言论传播的局面。澳大利亚一直引领社交媒体监管工作，要求科技公司解决儿童性虐待等问题。然而，推特不仅未回应罚款，还提起法律诉讼，试图推翻该罚款。  <ul>    <li>摘要：澳大利亚监管机构批评推特裁员和恢复账号的做法，强调有害内容风险加剧。</li>    <li>主题：社交媒体监管，特别是推特对在线安全、内容审核和有害内容控制的影响。</li>    <li>观点：在线安全和内容审核的重要性，科技公司承担责任的重要性以及审核不足的潜在后果。</li>    <li>主要信息：推特裁员、恢复禁言账号、对审核能力的担忧、澳大利亚的监管工作以及推特对罚款和正在进行的法律诉讼的回应缺失。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>curbing (v.) - /ˈkɜːbɪŋ/ 抑制，节制。    <p>原文例句：Tech group with TikTok and Meta sues Ohio over law curbing children’s social media use.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由curb（抑制，节制）+ing构成的，表示“抑制，节制”。在这个例句中，它表示科技集团和TikTok、Meta起诉俄亥俄州限制儿童使用社交媒体的法律。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>eradicate (v.) - /ɪˈrædɪkeɪt/ 消除，根除。    <p>原文例句：“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away, it would be like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers,”     <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由ex（出，外）和radicate（根除）构成的，表示“根除，消灭”。在这个例句中，Inman Grant说，“如果解雇了 80% 的这些专业工程师，就相当于沃尔沃——以其安全标准而闻名——解雇了他们所有的设计师或工程师一样”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>deep cuts - 大幅削减。    <p>原文例句：Australia’s eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由deep（深，深入）和cuts（切，割）组成，表示“大幅削减”。在这个例句中，它表示澳大利亚电子安全委员会表示，这些“大幅削减”和恢复数千个被禁止的账户，为有害内容的传播创造了一个“完美风暴”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>They showed 1,213 specialist “trust and safety staff”, including contractors, had left X since it was acquired by Musk in October 2022.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是They showed，其中主语是They，谓语是showed，宾语是1,213 specialist “trust and safety staff”。including contractors是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰specialist “trust and safety staff”，表示包括承包商。had left X是一个过去完成时态的动词，表示在过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。since it was acquired by Musk in October 2022是一个时间状语，表示自马斯克于 2022 年 10 月收购以来的时间。这个句子的意思是说，他们显示自马斯克在 2022 年 10 月收购 X 以来，包括承包商在内的 1,213 名专员“信任和安全人员”已经离开 X。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设或不真实的情况。    <p>原文例句：“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away, it would be like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers,” she told AFP.</p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种用来表示假设或不真实情况的语法形式。它通常用过去式或过去完成时态来表示。在这个例句中，虚拟语气用过去式would be like来表示一种假设的情况，即如果解雇了 80% 的这些专业工程师，就相当于沃尔沃——以其安全标准而闻名——解雇了他们所有的设计师或工程师一样。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式 - 表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Commissioner Julie Inman Grant, a former Twitter employee, said it was the first time these figures had been made public.</p>    <p>语法讲解：动词不定式是由动词的原形加to构成的，表示动作或状态。在这个例句中，动词不定式been made public表示被公布出来。这个句子的意思是说，委员会委员朱莉·英曼·格兰特，前推特员工，表示这是这些数据首次被公开。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The eSafety Commission said the ‘deep cuts’ and reinstatement of banned accounts created a ‘perfect storm’ for the spread of harmful content</li>
<li>Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing firms to outline how they are tackling hate speech and child sexual abuse</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/194a6a33-50f8-40c7-89c1-765fdcb76853_d3339bb6.jpg" /><figcaption>In a photo illustration, the Twitter X logo is displayed on the screen of a smartphone. Photo: SOPA Images/Zuma Press/TNS</figcaption></figure><p>Elon Musk’s X has shed more than 1,000 staff globally from teams responsible for stopping abusive content online, according to new figures released Thursday by Australia’s online watchdog.</p><p>Australia’s eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content.</p><p>The regulator has in recent months zeroed in on X – formerly known as Twitter – previously saying Musk’s takeover coincided with a spike in “toxicity and hate” on the platform.</p><p>Using Australia’s groundbreaking Online Safety Act, the eSafety Commission has obtained a detailed breakdown of software engineers, content moderators and other safety staff working at X.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247497/tech-trade-group-representing-tiktok-snapchat-and-meta-sues-ohio-over-states-new-law-limiting" title="">Tech group with TikTok and Meta sues Ohio over law curbing children’s social media use</a></h3><p>Commissioner Julie Inman Grant, a former Twitter employee, said it was the first time these figures had been made public.</p><p>They showed 1,213 specialist “trust and safety staff”, including contractors, had left X since it was acquired by Musk in October 2022.</p><p>This included 80 per cent of the software engineers focused on “trust and safety issues”, said Inman Grant.</p><p>“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away, it would be like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers,” she told AFP.</p><p>“You’ve got a perfect storm. You’re drastically decreasing your defences, and you’re introducing repeat offenders back onto the platform.”</p><p>Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing tech companies to outline how they are tackling issues such as hate speech and child sexual abuse.</p><p>But attempts to exercise these powers have occasionally been met with indifference. In October last year, the eSafety Commission slapped X with an A$610,500 (US$388,000) fine, saying it had failed to show how it was cracking down on child pornography.</p><p>But X ignored the deadline to pay the fine, before launching ongoing legal action to have it overturned.</p><p>X did not reply to AFP’s request for comment, instead sending an automated response that read “busy now, please check back later”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
