<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>ByteDance’s Douyin makes instant refunds mandatory, following PDD, Taobao and JD.com amid fierce e-commerce competition</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247160/bytedances-douyin-makes-instant-refunds-mandatory-following-pdd-taobao-and-jdcom-amid-fierce-e</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has made its “express refund” policy mandatory for merchants. This forces them to immediately return money to consumers upon request, competing with similar offerings on Taobao and Pinduoduo. E-commerce platforms are adopting “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason” policies to attract consumers amid intensified competition.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Douyin's mandatory "express refund" policy pushes merchants to offer immediate refunds, mirroring similar practices on rival platforms.</li>    <li>Theme: E-commerce competition drives the adoption of consumer-friendly policies, such as instant refunds without returns.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Platforms prioritize customer satisfaction at the expense of merchants to gain a competitive edge.</li>    <li>Main information: Douyin's mandatory express refund policy; similar policies on Taobao and Pinduoduo; competition among e-commerce platforms for consumer attention.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  抖音作为中国版的TikTok，强制实施“极速退款”政策，迫使商家在消费者提出退款请求后立刻返还货款，与淘宝和拼多多上的同类举措展开竞争。在竞争日益激烈的电子商务市场中，电商平台纷纷采用“无需退货退款”或“无理由退款”的政策，以吸引消费者。  <ul>    <li>摘要：抖音强制实施“极速退款”政策，推动商家提供即时退款，与竞争平台上的类似做法相呼应。</li>    <li>主题：电子商务竞争推动了以客户满意为导向的政策的采用，例如无需退货的即时退款。</li>    <li>观点：平台以牺牲商家利益为代价，优先考虑客户满意度，以获得竞争优势。</li>    <li>主要信息：抖音强制实施的极速退款政策；淘宝和拼多多上类似的政策；电商平台之间争夺消费者注意力的竞争。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>woo (v.) - /wʊ/ 追求，引诱，吸引。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com recently started offering refunds without returns to woo consumers away from rising budget e-commerce champion Pinduoduo.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词的意思是“追求，引诱，吸引”。在这个句子中，它表示阿里巴巴的淘宝和京东最近开始提供无需退货的退款，以吸引消费者，让他们远离快速发展的预算电子商务冠军拼多多。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>tangible (adj.) - /ˈtændʒəbəl/ 有形的，实实在在的。    <p>原文例句：Online retail sales of tangible goods in China increased 8.3 per cent in the first 11 months of 2023, according to the National Bureau of Statistics.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词的意思是“有形的，实实在在的”。在这个句子中，它表示根据国家统计局的数据，2023年前11个月，中国有形商品的在线零售额增长了8.3%。</p>    </li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>at the expense of - 以……为代价    <P>原文例句：E-commerce platforms are turning to policies known as “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason” as part of a push to be more consumer-friendly at the expense of merchants amid intensified competition. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由at（在……），the（确指），expense（费用，花费）和of（属于，关于）组成的，表示“以……为代价”。在这个例句中，它表示电商平台正在转向“无需退货退款”或“无理由退款”等政策，作为在竞争加剧的环境中以牺牲商家利益为代价取悦消费者的举措之一。</p></li>  </ul><ul>        <li>gain favor - 获得信赖或支持    <P>原文例句：The policy of allowing refunds without returns has started to gain favor as platforms look for any possible edge over rivals.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由gain（获得）和favor（支持，有利的条件）组成的，表示“获得信赖或支持”。在这个例句中，它表示允许无需退货退款的政策开始受到青睐，因为平台都在寻找任何可能比竞争对手更有利的优势。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</li><p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，主句是JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy，其中主语是JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao，谓语是push，宾语是‘refund only’ policy。to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示京东、阿里巴巴的淘宝推出“仅退款”政策是为了与拼多多的策略竞争。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语 - 表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba has been facing a new sense of urgency to win back consumers after PDD overtook China’s e-commerce king in market capitalisation. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示动作或状态。结构是：主语 + be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。在这个例句中，be用的是has been，表示现在完成时态，主语是Alibaba，现在分词是facing，表示面对，宾语是a new sense of urgency，表示一种新的紧迫感。这个句子的意思是说，阿里巴巴在拼多多超过中国电商之王后，面临着一种新的紧迫感，想要赢回消费者。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Merchants selling on the short video app Douyin can no longer opt out of the option to instantly refund up to US$211 before receiving returned goods</li>
<li>Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com recently started offering refunds without returns to woo consumers away from rising budget e-commerce champion Pinduoduo</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/3ce8d4ad-d4c8-4569-8e73-e028869c8250_11da8613.jpg" /><figcaption>The logo of Douyin displayed next to a mobile phone displaying an e-commerce site on the app in an illustration picture taken on October 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Douyin, the Chinese version of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a> that is betting big on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce">e-commerce</a>, has made its “express refund” policy mandatory, forcing merchants to immediately return money to consumers upon request to compete with similar offerings on Taobao and Pinduoduo.</p><p>The platform operated by Beijing-based <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance">ByteDance</a>, which added a shopping channel in 2019, allows users to get a refund as soon as they mail back the returned parcel, rather than when the merchant receives it. A recent policy update regarding the service introduced in 2021 denies merchants the option of turning it off.</p><p>E-commerce platforms are turning to policies known as “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason” as part of a push to be more consumer-friendly at the expense of merchants amid intensified competition. Online retail sales of tangible goods in China increased 8.3 per cent in the first 11 months of 2023, according to the National Bureau of Statistics.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>Budget shopping app <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo">Pinduoduo</a>, owned by PDD Holdings, was the first major e-commerce site to introduce a similar refunds policy in 2021 allowing users to get their money back without returning goods found to not match merchant descriptions. This was seen as a major factor in helping Pinduoduo woo price-sensitive Chinese consumers away from competing platforms.</p><p>The policy of allowing refunds without returns has started to gain favour as platforms look for any possible edge over rivals.</p><p>Taobao, the e-commerce platform from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom">JD.com</a> last week rolled out their own <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating">“refund only” policies</a>, finally matching the option from Pinduoduo. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Douyin has offered refunds without returns since September.</p><p>Douyin’s new refund service is not available for customised products or non-tangible goods such as memberships. Instant refunds are also limited to 1,500 yuan (US$211).</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Alibaba has been facing a new sense of urgency to win back consumers after PDD overtook China’s e-commerce king in market capitalisation. Alibaba was valued at US$190.2 billion on the New York Stock Exchange on Tuesday, lower than PDD’s US$193.5 billion on the Nasdaq.</p><p>In December, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals">Alibaba promoted six young managers</a> to run its core e-commerce business unit in an attempt to “reignite their entrepreneurial spirit” and “secure and win their future”, according to an internal letter penned by the conglomerate’s CEO Eddie Wu Yongming, two days after he became the head of the unit.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech firms must end, says communist party newspaper after video gaming stock rout</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  The Study Times, the mouthpiece of the Central Party School, has criticized China's regulators for swinging between lax oversight and overly strict regulation, which is damaging the health of internet companies. The article argues that regulators must stop such erratic behavior and allow internet companies to grow.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese regulators are urged to end erratic moves against internet companies.</li>    <li>Theme: The negative impact of regulatory instability on China's internet titans.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Regulators should promote stable and predictable regulatory environment for internet companies.</li>    <li>Main information: The Study Times article criticizing regulators' behavior; the impact of regulations on Chinese gaming stocks; the need for improved coordination among regulators; the proposal for self-governance by internet companies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中央党校机关报《学习时报》批评中国监管部门在宽松监督和“过于严格”监管之间摇摆，损害了互联网公司的健康发展。文章认为，监管部门必须停止这种反复无常的行为，让互联网公司有成长的空间。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国监管部门被敦促停止针对互联网公司的反复无常的举动。</li>    <li>主题：监管的不稳定性对中国互联网巨头造成的负面影响。</li>    <li>观点：监管部门应为互联网公司营造稳定和可预测的监管环境。</li>    <li>主要信息：《学习时报》文章批评监管部门的行为；监管对中国游戏股的影响；监管部门之间需要加强协调；建议互联网公司进行自我管理。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unleash (v.) - /ʌnˈliːʃ/ 释放，放开。    <p>原文例句：Beijing’s campaign of “curbing irrational expansion of capital” in 2020 unleashed a race among different ministries and watchdogs to claim authority in checking and approving internet businesses.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由un-（否定）和leash（皮带）构成的，意为“释放，放开”。在这个例句中，它表示北京在2020年开展的“抑制资本无序扩张”运动引发了不同部门和监管机构争夺审查和批准互联网业务的权力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>articulate (v.) - /ɑːrˈtɪkjʊleɪt/ 表达，阐述。    <p>原文例句：The Cyberspace Administration of China, the country’s internet watchdog, for instance, has articulated Beijing’s demand for data security into intrusive requirements that have made it increasingly difficult and costly to comply with.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由ar-（向）和ticulare（指关节）组成，意为“用语言表达，阐述”。在这个例句中，指的是中国国家互联网监督管理机构，该机构将北京对数据安全的要求具体化为侵入性的规定，使得企业合规变得更加困难和昂贵。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：China is left further behind their global peers in terms of competitiveness and growth potential. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，China is left further behind their global peers in terms of competitiveness and growth potential.， 它表示中国在竞争力和增长潜力方面落后于全球同行。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song. - 2023年11月18日，人们在北京一家购物中心玩电子游戏。摄影师：Simon Song。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是People，谓语是play，宾语是video games。in a shopping mall in Beijing是地点状语，November 18, 2023是时间状语，Photo: Simon Song是图片说明。这个句子的意思是说，2023年11月18日，人们在北京一家购物中心玩电子游戏，这张照片由Simon Song拍摄。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动名词作主语 - 动名词可以作主语，表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Beijing’s pursuit of market control, along with China’s economic slowdown and rising geopolitical tensions with the US, have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，动名词Beijing’s pursuit of market control, China’s economic slowdown, 和rising geopolitical tensions with the US作主语，表示动作或状态，谓语have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The Cyberspace Administration of China, the country’s internet watchdog, for instance, has articulated Beijing’s demand for data security into intrusive requirements that have made it increasingly difficult and costly to comply with.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，has articulated Beijing’s demand for data security into intrusive requirements表示中国国家互联网监督管理机构已经将北京对数据安全的要求转化为侵入性的规定，目前仍然持续着。它强调了这项规定仍然对企业合规造成困难和昂贵成本的影响。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The mouthpiece of the Central Party School argued that regulators must stop the practice of swinging between extremes of lax oversight and ‘overly strict’ regulation</li>
<li>The opinion came days after the NPPA wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with draft regulation to restrict spending on video games</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/3319e698-c70a-4b75-a5c4-b17164272de6_6b557a93.jpg" /><figcaption>Tencent’s Game for Peace is seen on a mobile phone in this illustration picture taken May 13, 2019.  Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>A Chinese Communist Party newspaper has urged the country’s regulators to end their erratic moves against the platform economy, in a sign of growing concern over policy damage to the health of the country’s ailing internet titans.</p><p>A front page opinion piece published by the Study Times, the mouthpiece of the Central Party School, on Wednesday argued that regulators must stop the practice of swinging between extremes of lax oversight and “overly strict” regulation so that China’s Big Tech firms can have room to grow.</p><p>The article, which did not name any specific company or regulator, came days after the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" target="_self" title="">proposed regulation to restrict spending on video games.</a> The South China Morning Post reported on Tuesday that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes" target="_self" title="">a key gaming official has left his job following the debacle,</a> as the Chinese government tries to allay market fears.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246511/chinas-disciplinary-enforcers-add-bad-books-sex-drugs-serious-offences" title="">China’s disciplinary enforcers add ‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences</a></h3><p>The draft proposal is the latest example of regulatory hostility, after Beijing’s campaign of “curbing irrational expansion of capital” in 2020 unleashed a race among different ministries and watchdogs to claim authority in checking and approving internet businesses.</p><p>A long list of Chinese ministries has been sharpening their teeth when it comes to disciplining internet firms. The Cyberspace Administration of China, the country’s internet watchdog, for instance, has articulated Beijing’s demand for data security into intrusive requirements that have made it increasingly difficult and costly to comply with.</p><p>Beijing’s pursuit of market control, along with China’s economic slowdown and rising geopolitical tensions with the US, have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years. Tencent Holdings, the country’s most valuable player that once eyed being Asia’s first US$1 trillion company, fell out of the global top 10 after losing 60 per cent of its market capitalisation, while Post owner Alibaba Group Holding, which exceeded Amazon.com in market value in 2014, is now worth an eighth of the US e-commerce titan.</p><p>According to the Study Times opinion piece, the erratic regulatory behaviour is “a risk and a challenge” for China as its leading internet firms are left further behind their global peers in terms of competitiveness and growth potential.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/643c0e52-aced-4b9f-a2cf-0f56737ce2f0_bd901af2.jpg" title="People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" width="2000" /><figcaption>People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song</figcaption></figure></div><p>China must improve “cross-departmental coordination” to avoid duplicated enforcement and checks, while regulatory acts and policy adjustments must factor in “the views of all parties, especially those being regulated” to avoid interrupting normal business activities or causing unexpected risks, it said.</p><p>Chinese regulators should loosen their grip and allow “self-governance” by Chinese internet companies, it added. “It is important to respect the rationality and necessity of platform self-governance to guide and encourage the formation of self-regulatory mechanisms,” the article said.</p><p>It remains unknown whether China’s different regulators will heed the advice. Beijing’s regulatory crackdown on the internet sector officially came to an end a year ago, when the Chinese leadership said the country’s platform enterprises would be encouraged to “fully display their capabilities” in growth, job creation and international competition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung to kick off year of AI phones with new launch this month</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247104/samsung-kick-year-ai-phones-new-launch-month</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Samsung, a prominent smartphone manufacturer, intends to introduce its new flagship model in 2024, emphasizing advancements in artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities. By the end of 2027, over a billion smartphones featuring built-in generative AI are projected to be shipped.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung's focus on AI for its upcoming flagship device; prediction of a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI by 2027.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's strategic shift towards AI integration to differentiate its smartphones in the market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of AI technology in driving sales and competition in the smartphone industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's Galaxy S24 launch event; reliance on camera and display improvements in the past; expectations of AI taking center stage; Counterpoint Research's projections on generative AI smartphone shipments.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  三星，作为著名的智能手机制造商，计划在2024年推出其新款旗舰机型，重点突出人工智能（AI）能力的提升。预计到2027年底，将有超过十亿部具有内置生成式人工智能的智能手机出货。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星新款旗舰设备对人工智能的关注；到2027年出货量将超过十亿部具有内置生成式人工智能的智能手机的预测。</li>    <li>主题：三星战略性地转向人工智能集成，以使其智能手机在市场上与众不同。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能技术在推动智能手机行业销售和竞争中的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星Galaxy S24发布会；过去对摄像头和显示屏改进的依赖；对人工智能成为中心舞台的期望；Counterpoint Research对生成式人工智能智能手机出货量的预测。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>prominent (adj.) - /ˈprɑːmɪnənt/ 突出的，显着的，著名的。    <p>原文例句：Samsung, a prominent smartphone manufacturer, intends to introduce its new flagship model in 2024, emphasizing advancements in artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语promovere，意思是“向前移动”。它表示“突出的，显着的，著名的”。在这个例句中，它被用来形容三星，一个著名的智能手机制造商。</p></li>    <li>generative (adj.) - /ˈdʒɛnərətɪv/ 生成型的，创造性的。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语generare，意思是“产生，创造”。它表示“生成型的，创造性的”。在这个例句中，它被用来形容一种新的智能手机技术，这种技术可以生成新的内容，如文本或图像。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take center stage - 成为焦点，成为中心。    <p>原文例句：In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out, but 2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿取）和center stage（中心舞台）组成的，表示“成为焦点，成为中心”。在这个例句中，它表示AI能力将在2024年成为智能手机行业的焦点。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company plans to launch its next flagship device – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – on January 17 in San Jose, California, with a live-streamed event. - 该公司计划于1月17日在加州圣何塞举行现场直播活动，推出其下一款旗舰设备——可能被称为Galaxy S24。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company plans to launch its next flagship device，其中主语是The company，谓语是plans to launch，宾语是其下一款旗舰设备。likely to be known as the Galaxy S24是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰flagship device，表示其下一款旗舰设备可能被称为Galaxy S24。on January 17 in San Jose, California, with a live-streamed event是一个时间状语，表示推出时间和地点。这个句子的意思是说，该公司计划于1月17日在加州圣何塞举行现场直播活动，推出其下一款旗舰设备，这款设备可能被称为Galaxy S24。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示三星和其他智能手机制造商从过去的某个时间开始一直依赖相机技术和柔性显示屏的改进脱颖而出。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out</li>
<li>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates</li>
</ul><p>The world’s most prolific smartphone maker is leaning into artificial intelligence (AI) as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.</p><p>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – on January 17 in San Jose, California, with a live-streamed event. The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming”.</p><p>In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out, but 2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246310/huawei-launches-new-nova-smartphones-without-giving-details-chip-attention-remains-fixed-its" title="">Huawei launches new Nova smartphones without giving details on chip</a></h3><p>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p><p>OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Dall-E tools, which generate text or visual responses to users’ queries, are at the forefront of a generative-AI wave that is swept across the tech industry – and helped make Nvidia a trillion-dollar company by providing the key AI-training accelerators. The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices, as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year.</p><p>“Samsung and Qualcomm are immediate leaders as current product offerings and capabilities position them as first movers,” the Counterpoint researchers wrote in December. “Similar to what it did with foldables, Samsung is likely to capture almost 50 per cent share for the next two years, followed by key Chinese OEMs like Xiaomi, Vivo, Honor and Oppo.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok use</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247089/montana-appealing-ruling-blocked-state-barring-tiktok-use</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice of appeal to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals challenging a lower court ruling that blocked the state's ban on the video-sharing app TikTok. The ban, which was set to take effect on January 1, was blocked by US District Judge Donald Molloy, who said it "oversteps state power" and violates the Constitution. TikTok and Knudsen's office have not commented on the appeal.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Montana appeals federal court ruling blocking its ban on TikTok.</li>    <li>Theme: Legal challenge to Montana's ban on TikTok over concerns about user data privacy and potential Chinese spying.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Differing perspectives on the state's authority to regulate social media platforms; debate over the balance between national security and individual privacy rights.</li>    <li>Main information: Notice of appeal filed by Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen; preliminary injunction issued by US District Judge Donald Molloy blocking the ban; TikTok's denial of sharing user data with the Chinese government; ongoing efforts to restrict TikTok in the US.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  蒙大拿州总检察长奥斯汀·努德森已提交上诉通知，向美国第九巡回上诉法院提出上诉，挑战下级法院阻止该州禁止视频共享应用程序 TikTok 的裁决。这项禁令原定于 1 月 1 日生效，但被美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊阻止，称其“逾越了州权”且违反宪法。TikTok 和努德森的办公室尚未对上诉发表评论。  <ul>    <li>摘要：蒙大拿州对联邦法院阻止其禁止 TikTok 的裁决提出上诉。</li>    <li>主题：对蒙大拿州禁止 TikTok 的法律挑战，原因是担心用户数据隐私和潜在的中国间谍活动。</li>    <li>观点：对于该州监管社交媒体平台的权力存在不同看法；争论国家安全与个人隐私权之间的平衡。</li>    <li>主要信息：蒙大拿州总检察长奥斯汀·努德森提交的上诉通知；美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊发布的阻止该禁令的初步禁令；TikTok 否认与中国政府共享用户数据；美国正在进行限制 TikTok 的努力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>preliminary (adj.) - /prɪˈlɪmɪnəri/ 临时的，初步的。    <p>原文例句：US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由prae（在……前面）和liminaris（门槛的）组成，意为“在门槛上的，临时的”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊于 11 月 30 日发布的初步禁令，以阻止该禁令，称蒙大拿州的法律“逾越了州权”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>violate (v.) - /ˈvaɪləʊleɪt/ 违反，侵犯。    <p>原文例句：Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government and the state’s action was too sweeping.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由vis（暴力）和latus（携带的）组成，意为“使用暴力，侵犯，违反”。在这个例句中，它指的是莫洛伊表示，蒙大拿州寻求行使联邦政府持有的外交政策权力，而该州的行动过于广泛。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take effect - 生效，发生作用。    <P>原文例句：Montana’s ban had been set to take effect on January 1, but US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban on the Chinese-owned app, saying Montana’s law “violates the Constitution in more ways than one” and “oversteps state power”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，取）和effect（效果，作用）构成的，表示“生效，发生作用”。在这个例句中，它表示蒙大拿州的禁令原定于 1 月 1 日生效，但美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊于 11 月 30 日发布了初步禁令，阻止了对这款中国应用程序的禁令，称蒙大拿州的法律“以多种方式违反了宪法”并“逾越了州权”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TikTok and Knudsen’s office did not immediately comment. - TikTok和努德森的办公室没有立即发表评论。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是TikTok and Knudsen’s office，谓语是did not comment，宾语是immediately。这个句子的意思是说，TikTok和努德森的办公室没有立即发表评论。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TikTok has faced efforts by some in Congress to ban the app or give the Biden administration's powers to impose restrictions or bar foreign-owned apps, but those efforts have stalled.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示TikTok面临着一些国会议员的禁令或授予拜登政府权力以对外国应用程序实施限制或禁令的努力，但这些努力已经停滞不前。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、愿望、可能性或不确定性。    <p>原文例句：Many states and the US government have barred TikTok on government-owned devices, but only Montana has sought to completely bar the app’s use.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语气，用虚拟语气来表示对事件的假设、猜测或愿望。结构是：would/could/should/might + 动词原形。其中would用于过去时，could用于现在时和将来时，should用于建议或义务，might用于可能性或推测。在这个例句中，it表示许多州和美国政府都在政府拥有的设备上禁止使用 TikTok，但只有蒙大拿州寻求完全禁止使用该应用程序。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice that the state is appealing the ruling to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals</li>
<li>US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’</li>
</ul><p>Montana said on Tuesday it was appealing a decision by a US judge in November to block the state's first-of-its kind ban on the use of short-video sharing app TikTok.</p><p>Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice that the state is appealing the ruling to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals.</p><p>Montana’s ban had been set to take effect on January 1, but US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban on the Chinese-owned app, saying Montana’s law “violates the Constitution in more ways than one” and “oversteps state power”.</p><p>TikTok and Knudsen’s office did not immediately comment. Molloy had previously said preliminary pretrial statements were due by January 16.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246313/taiwan-elections-tiktok-teams-fact-checkers-stop-disinformation-site" title="">TikTok teams up with fact checkers to stop election disinformation on site</a></h3><p>TikTok users in Montana also had filed suit last year to block the ban approved by the state legislature, which cited concerns about the personal data of Montana users and potential Chinese spying.</p><p>In earlier court filings, TikTok said it “has not shared, and would not share, US user data with the Chinese government, and has taken substantial measures to protect the privacy and security of TikTok users”. Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government and the state’s action was too sweeping.</p><p>TikTok has faced efforts by some in Congress to ban the app or give the Biden administration's powers to impose restrictions or bar foreign-owned apps, but those efforts have stalled.</p><p>Many states and the US government have barred TikTok on government-owned devices, but only Montana has sought to completely bar the app’s use.</p><p>Former President Donald Trump in 2020 sought to bar new downloads of TikTok and Chinese-owned WeChat, but a series of court decisions blocked the effective ban from taking effect.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple hits 7-week low after Barclays downgrade on demand concerns</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Apple's stock faced a decline after a year of growth, leading to various concerns and discussions among analysts. The main points of the article include:  <ul>    <li>Apple's shares surged in 2023, reaching a record high, but recently experienced a drop due to demand slowdown and bearish market analysis.</li>    <li>Barclays downgraded Apple's stock and predicts weak demand for its devices, contributing to negative market sentiment.</li>    <li>Concerns about iPhone 15's performance and subdued demand in developed markets are cited as reasons for the pessimistic outlook.</li>    <li>Apple's services business, which includes the app store, faces scrutiny and poses additional risks to the company's revenue.</li>    <li>The stock rout resulted in a significant loss in market capitalization, erasing over $100 billion in value.</li>    <li>Analysts remain divided on Apple's stock performance, with some maintaining a "buy" rating and others issuing "sell" recommendations.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果公司股票在经历了一年多的增长后，最近却面临着大幅下跌，引发了分析师们不同的评论和讨论。文章的主要内容包括：  <ul>    <li>苹果公司股票在 2023 年大幅上涨，并在去年 12 月中旬创下历史新高，但最近由于需求放缓和看跌的市场分析而出现下跌。</li>    <li>巴克莱银行将苹果股票评级下调，并预测其设备的需求疲软，导致市场情绪负面。</li>    <li>对 iPhone 15 性能的担忧和发达市场需求疲软被认为是悲观前景的原因。</li>    <li>苹果公司的服务业务，包括应用商店，正面临审查，并给公司营收带来了额外的风险。</li>    <li>股票暴跌导致市值大幅缩水，损失超过 1000 亿美元。</li>    <li>分析师们对苹果股票的走势仍存在分歧，一些人维持“买入”评级，而另一些人则发出“卖出”建议。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>grapple (v.) - /ˈɡræp(ə)l/ 努力对付，应付。    <p>原文例句：The company has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语grapan（抓住），表示“努力对付，应付”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司自去年年初以来一直努力应对需求放缓的局面。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>lacklustre (adj.) - /ˈlæklʌstər/ 缺乏光泽，暗淡的。    <p>原文例句：“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long said in a client note, pointing to the China weakness as well as subdued demand in developed markets. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由lack（缺乏）和lustre（光泽）构成的，表示“缺乏光泽，暗淡的”。在这个例句中，它指的是巴克莱分析师蒂姆·朗对 iPhone 15 缺乏亮眼表现的看法，并认为 iPhone 16 也会如此。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>subdued (adj.) - /səbˈdjud/  平静的，抑制的。<p>原文例句：Long is rated four out of five stars for his recommendation accuracy on Apple, according to LSEG data.The brokerage also warned risks were mounting for Apple’s services business, which has come under the scanner in countries including the United States over app store practices.The business has often outpaced growth in Apple’s hardware segment in recent years and now accounts for nearly a quarter of the company’s total revenue.Apple to appeal US watch ban in patent dispute</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由sub-（在……下面，次于）和due（适当的）构成，表示“平静的，抑制的”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果服务的增长一直都低于硬件业务的增长。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>under the scanner - 受到审查，受到关注。    <P>原文例句：The brokerage also warned risks were mounting for Apple’s services business, which has come under the scanner in countries including the United States over app store practices. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由under（在……下面，被……控制）和scanner（扫描仪）构成的，表示“受到审查，受到关注”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果的服务业务在美国和其他国家因应用商店的做法而受到审查。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Barclays analyst Tim Long said in a client note, pointing to the China weakness as well as subdued demand in developed markets. - 巴克莱分析师蒂姆·朗在一份客户报告中指出中国市场的疲软以及发达市场的需求疲软这两个因素。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Barclays analyst Tim Long said，其中主语是Barclays analyst Tim Long，谓语是said。in a client note, pointing to the China weakness as well as subdued demand in developed markets是一个介词短语作状语，表示巴克莱分析师蒂姆·朗在一份客户报告中指出，修饰said。这个句子的意思是说，巴克莱分析师蒂姆·朗在一份客户报告中指出中国市场的疲软以及发达市场的需求疲软这两个因素。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式作宾语 - 表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Analysts, on average, rate the iPhone maker “buy”, with a median price target of US$200. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个动词不定式作宾语的例子。动词不定式是由to加动词原形构成的，可以作主语、宾语、表语或状语。在这个例句中，动词不定式作宾语，表示分析师们平均对iPhone制造商的评级是“买入”，目标价格中值为200美元。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>介词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态发生的时间、地点、方式等。    <p>原文例句：Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral” and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个介词短语作状语的例子。介词短语是由介词和名词或代词构成的，可以作状语、定语或补语。在这个例句中，介词短语作状语，表示巴克莱将该股票评级从“中性”下调至“低配”，并将12个月的目标价格下调1美元至160美元。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple’s shares rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech firms led the markets</li>
<li>The company has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates</li>
</ul><p>Apple on Tuesday fell nearly 3.6 per cent to a seven-week low after Barclays downgraded the shares of the world’s most valuable company on concerns that demand for its devices, from the iPhone to the Mac, will remain weak in 2024.</p><p>Barclays is the second brokerage to have the equivalent of a “sell” rating on the stock, which now has its most number of bearish recommendations in at least two years, according to LSEG data.</p><p>The stock accounts for a hefty 7 per cent of the S&amp;P 500’s market weight – the broader index was dragged 0.56 per cent lower on Tuesday.</p><p>Apple rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech companies led the markets.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245817/apple-ramps-vision-pro-production-aiming-launch-february" title="">Apple ramps up Vision Pro production, aiming for launch by February</a></h3><p>Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates. Its performance in China has also been a worry after the revival of local rival Huawei Technologies.</p><p>“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long said in a client note, pointing to the China weakness as well as subdued demand in developed markets.</p><p>Long is rated four out of five stars for his recommendation accuracy on Apple, according to LSEG data.</p><p>The brokerage also warned risks were mounting for Apple’s services business, which has come under the scanner in countries including the United States over app store practices.</p><p>The business has often outpaced growth in Apple’s hardware segment in recent years and now accounts for nearly a quarter of the company’s total revenue.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3246322/us-import-ban-certain-apple-watch-models-takes-effect-over-patent-clash" title="">Apple to appeal US watch ban in patent dispute</a></h3><p>The stock rout on Tuesday erased more than US$100 billion of Apple’s market capitalisation, as its shares closed at US$185.64.</p><p>Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral” and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160. Before Tuesday, Itau BBA’s “sell” was the only bearish rating on Apple since July 2022.</p><p>Analysts, on average, rate the iPhone maker “buy”, with a median price target of US$200. The company trades at about 28.7 times its 12-month forward earnings estimates, much higher than the S&amp;P 500’s 19.8.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese video gaming official steps down after market rout linked to proposed rule changes, sources say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>After causing a significant loss of value in the Chinese gaming sector, a key official, Feng Shixin, has left his role in overseeing video games at the Central Propaganda Department.</li>    <li>The proposed draft rules from the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) had a negative impact on stock market sentiment, prompting Feng's departure.</li>    <li>The government's efforts to limit the damage caused by these draft rules, which included approving 105 new video games for sale in December, indicated a more supportive stance towards the gaming industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国共产党中央宣传部出版局局长冯仕新，因监管视频游戏行业的提案造成中国游戏产业大幅贬值，已辞去其在中央宣传部出版局的职务。</li>    <li>国家新闻出版署（NPPA）发布的指导意见，造成了股市动荡，进而导致冯仕新离职。</li>    <li>政府批准了105款新游戏在12月发售，这表明了政府对于游戏产业的支持立场，也是为了减少该指导意见的负面影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>regulate (v.) - /ˈrɛgjʊleɪt/ 规范，管理。    <p>原文例句：Any regulation that could have “a significant impact on capital markets” must be coordinated with financial management departments in advance. </p>    <p>例句讲解：regulate源于拉丁语rego，意为“统治，领导”。它通常用于正式环境中，强调对某事或某人的控制和管理。这里，它指任何可能对资本市场产生重大影响的规定都必须提前与财务管理部门协调。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>oversee (v.) - /ˌəʊvərˈsiː/ 监督，管理。    <p>原文例句：Feng Shixin has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, overseeing the country’s video gaming industry. </p>    <p>例句讲解：oversee源于古英语 oferseon，意为“看管，照看”。它通常用于正式环境中，表示对某事或某人的持续观察和管理。这里，它指冯仕新辞去了他在共产党中央宣传部出版局局长的职务，该职务负责监督中国的视频游戏行业。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>cap (v.) - /kæp/ 上限，限制。    <p>原文例句：Video game developers would have to implement measures to cap user spending, with bans on “excessive” rewards for activity such as daily logins and top-ups for fresh spending by consumers. </p>    <p>例句讲解：cap源于中世纪拉丁语cappa，意为“斗篷，罩衣”。它通常用于经济或金融领域，表示对某项支出的限制或上限。这里，它指游戏开发者必须采取措施限制用户支出，例如禁止对每日登录和消费者充值等活动提供“过量”奖励。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>video gaming - 电子游戏，电子游戏行业。    <p>原文例句：A key Chinese official involved in oversight of the country’s video gaming industry has stepped down after proposed regulation last month wiped out billions of dollars of value from Chinese gaming stocks. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“video gaming”常用于描述涉及电子游戏的活动和产业。它涵盖了广泛的电子游戏领域，包括游戏开发、发行、销售和玩电子游戏等。在这个句子中，它指的是中国电子游戏行业。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>public feedback - 公众反馈，民意反馈。    <p>原文例句：According to the published proposals, which are open to public feedback until January 22, video game developers would have to implement measures to cap user spending, with bans on “excessive” rewards for activity such as daily logins and top-ups for fresh spending by consumers. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“public feedback”是指从公众收集到的意见、建议和反应。它通常用于政府、企业或其他组织收集公众对某个政策、产品或服务的看法。在这个句子中，它指的是对已公布的提议征求公众意见，这些提议将于1月22日前开放。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China’s video gaming watchdog speaks out after spending rules roil market - 中国视频游戏监管机构在支出规则扰乱市场后发声。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是China’s video gaming watchdog，谓语是speaks out，宾语是after spending rules roil market。China’s video gaming watchdog是一个名词短语，由China’s和video gaming watchdog组成，表示中国的视频游戏监管机构。speaks out是一个动词短语，表示发声，发表意见。after spending rules roil market是一个介词短语，由after和spending rules roil market组成，表示在支出规则扰乱市场之后。这个句子的意思是，中国的视频游戏监管机构在支出规则扰乱市场后发声。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 强调句型是用来强调句子中的某个成分，强调句型有两种形式：部分倒装和it is/was+被强调成分+that/who。    <p>原文例句：It was the proposed regulation changes that dealt a fresh blow to already-fragile investor confidence in Chinese stocks. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句，强调成分是proposed regulation changes。强调句型有两种形式：部分倒装和it is/was+被强调成分+that/who。在这个句子中，使用的是it is/was+被强调成分+that/who。it是形式主语，was是谓语动词，proposed regulation changes是被强调成分，that引导强调句的从句。强调句的从句又可以分为陈述句、疑问句和感叹句。在这个句子中，强调句的从句是一个陈述句。这个句子的意思是，正是拟议的监管变化对已经脆弱的中国股票投资者信心造成了新的打击。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>动名词作宾语 - 动名词可以作宾语。    <p>原文例句：China vows ‘substantial measures’ to shore up economy as headwinds grow - 中国承诺采取“实质性措施”来支持经济，因为逆风不断增强。</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，动名词shore up economy作谓语动词vows的宾语。shore up economy的意思是“支持经济”。这个句子的意思是，中国承诺采取“实质性措施”来支持经济，因为逆风不断增强。动名词作宾语是动名词的一种常见用法，动名词作宾语时，可以表示动作、过程或状态。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Feng Shixin has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, people say</li>
<li>Move comes as Beijing attempts to limit the damage from draft rules from watchdog aimed at reining back spending on video games</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/c1897329-2f24-429e-bd01-4e017c08984b_8dd3a965.jpg" /><figcaption>Feng Shixin has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, people say. Photo: Xinhua </figcaption></figure><p>A key Chinese official involved in oversight of the country’s video gaming industry has stepped down after proposed regulation last month wiped out billions of dollars of value from Chinese gaming stocks, according to people familiar with the situation.</p><p>Feng Shixin, a long-serving official, has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, one person told the South China Morning Post, asking not to be identified due to the sensitivity of the matter.</p><p>A second person, who also asked for anonymity, said Feng’s departure was a sign that China may walk back some of last month’s proposed restrictions on consumer spending in video games, which surprised the market due to their severity.</p><p>The National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA), the agency that answers directly to the propaganda authority in overseeing China’s video gaming industry, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246161/chinas-video-gaming-watchdog-speaks-out-after-draft-spending-rules-roil-market" title="">China’s video gaming watchdog speaks out after spending rules roil market</a></h3><p>Feng’s departure comes as Beijing attempts to limit the damage from the NPPA’s disclosure on December 23 of draft rules aimed at reining back spending on video games, which triggered a global sell-off of China gaming stocks, including leading players such as Tencent Holdings and NetEase.</p><p>The departure also underscored the importance of shielding financial markets from being whipsawed by haphazard government policies. Any regulation that could have “a significant impact on capital markets” <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3170664/chinas-vice-premier-liu-he-vows-support-economic-growth" target="_self" title="">must be coordinated</a> with financial management departments in advance, the Xinhua news agency reported in March 2022, quoting then Vice-Premier Liu He.</p><p>According to the published proposals, which are open to public feedback until January 22, video game developers would have to implement measures to cap user spending, with bans on “excessive” rewards for activity such as daily logins and top-ups for fresh spending by consumers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3170664/chinas-vice-premier-liu-he-vows-support-economic-growth" title="">China vows ‘substantial measures’ to shore up economy as headwinds grow</a></h3><p>The timing and severity of the proposed rule changes dealt a fresh blow to already-fragile investor confidence in Chinese stocks. NetEase, the country’s No. 2 gaming operator, fell by nearly a quarter in a single trading day, with Tencent dropping over 12 per cent.</p><p>The new rules appeared to be at odds with a recent change in Beijing’s tone towards the video gaming industry – previously subject to a harsh crackdown – and broad efforts by the government to stabilise stock market sentiment and support the country’s private sector.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>In an attempt at damage control, the NPPA subsequently said the proposed regulation changes were aimed at “healthy development” of the gaming industry and that it would “revise and improve” the rules.</p><p>Meanwhile, the regulator approved 105 new <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">video games</a> for sale in China for December, the most in 17 months, in a supportive gesture to an industry with combined annual sales of 300 billion yuan (US$40 billion) in 2023.</p><p>Feng is a veteran regulator. He delivered keynote speeches at the China Gaming Industry Annual Conference, the yearly gathering of officials and executives for three consecutive years in 2018, 2019 and 2020 as a deputy publication bureau chief.</p><p>In December 2020, Feng urged China’s gaming companies to be vigilant about gaming content and not to “provide channels for any harmful content”.</p><p>At the latest annual conference in December 2023, Yang Fang, an official from the NPPA, delivered the keynote speech after Feng delegated the task to her.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/markets/article/3246336/hong-kong-stocks-recover-tencent-netease-recoup-part-us63-billion-sell-while-new-china-report-aids" title="">Hong Kong stocks rebound as Tencent, NetEase rally, China data aids sentiment</a></h3><p>China has developed a sophisticated regulatory system for video gaming since the propaganda department took over the regulatory authority in 2018 from other ministries.</p><p>All online video games must go through rigorous screening to obtain licences before being released to the public and monetised, and all players are required to have real-name registration.</p><p>Prior to a recent easing, Chinese authorities had deemed video gaming as “spiritual opium” and implemented several rules to avoid addiction among minors and to promote healthy growth of the industry.</p><p>In the summer of 2021, China imposed a play time ceiling of three hours per week – from 8pm to 9pm on Fridays, Saturdays and Sundays – for players under the age of 18.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chip industry giant ASML blocked by US, Netherlands from shipping equipment to China ahead of export deadline</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247042/chip-industry-giant-asml-blocked-us-netherlands-shipping-equipment-china-ahead-export-deadline</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In a blow to China's efforts to stockpile advanced chip technology, Dutch chip-making equipment manufacturer ASML was forced to cancel shipments to China after having export licenses partially revoked. The Dutch government's move came after pressure from the United States, which has imposed new restrictions on the sale of chip-making equipment to China. ASML's CEO expressed confidence that the company would be able to mitigate the impact of the license revocation and export controls on its financial outlook.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Partial revocation of export licenses for ASML's chip-making equipment to China due to US pressure.</li>    <li>Theme: The ongoing conflict between the US and China over advanced chip technology.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The US's use of export controls as a strategic weapon to curb China's technological progress.</li>    <li>Main information: ASML's canceled shipments to China; the Dutch government's partial license revocation; China's heavy stockpiling of chip-making equipment; ASML's response to the challenges and its financial outlook.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  芯片制造设备制造商 ASML 因出口许可证被部分吊销而被迫取消对中国的部分发货，这对中国积累先进芯片技术的努力造成了打击。荷兰政府此举是在美国施压后做出的，美国对向中国出售芯片制造设备实施了新的限制。ASML 首席执行官表示相信该公司能够减轻许可证吊销和出口管制对其财务前景的影响。  <ul>    <li>摘要：由于美国施压，ASML 出口给中国的芯片制造设备的出口许可证被部分吊销。</li>    <li>主题：美国和中国之间关于先进芯片技术的持续冲突。</li>    <li>观点：美国将出口管制作为战略武器以遏制中国技术进步。</li>    <li>主要信息：ASML 取消对中国的发货；荷兰政府部分吊销许可证；中国大量囤积芯片制造设备；ASML 对挑战和财务前景的回应。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revoke (v.) - /rɪˈvoʊk/ 撤消，废除。    <p>原文例句：A licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government, impacting a small number of customers in China,” the company said in a statement on Monday.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由re-（重新）和voke（呼吁，召唤）组成的，表示“重新召唤，撤销，废除”。在这个例句中，它表示荷兰政府最近部分撤销了2023年出货NXT:2050i和NXT:2100i[深紫外(DUV)]光刻系统以及其他一些产品的许可证，影响了中国的一些客户。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>slate (v.) - /sleɪt/ 安排，计划。    <p>原文例句：However, from September, the Dutch equipment maker had been able to apply for licences to ship some of its less advanced DUV systems to China ahead of new restrictions that came into effect on January 1. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由Middle English的slatte（板）演变而来的，表示“板，板岩，编制清单，安排，计划”。在这个例句中，它表示从9月份开始，荷兰设备制造商能够申请许可证，以便在新限制于1月1日生效之前，向中国运送一些他们不太先进的DUV系统。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>import (v.) - /ˈɪmpɔːrt/ 进口。    <p>原文例句：China imported 42 lithography systems in November for US$816.8 million, with companies in the Netherlands and Japan accounting for nearly the entire amount spent on such imports.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由im-（进入）和portus（港口）组成的，表示“进口，导入”。在这个例句中，它表示中国在11月份进口了42套光刻系统，价值8.168亿美元，其中来自荷兰和日本的公司几乎占据了所有进口支出。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：In recent years, China has been ASML’s third-largest market after Taiwan and South Korea, but it jumped to first place in the third quarter of 2023, accounting for 46 per cent of sales. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示在销售方面，中国是ASML近年来继台湾和韩国之后的第三大市场，但在2023年第三季度，中国跃居第一，占销售额的46%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>new restrictions - 新的限制。    <P>原文例句：However, from September, the Dutch equipment maker had been able to apply for licences to ship some of its less advanced DUV systems to China ahead of new restrictions that came into effect on January 1. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由new（新的）和restrictions（限制）组成的，表示“新的限制”。在这个例句中，它表示从9月份开始，荷兰设备制造商能够申请许可证，以便在新限制于1月1日生效之前，向中国运送一些他们不太先进的DUV系统。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“ASML is fully committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations, including export control legislation in the countries in which we operate,” it added. - ASML补充说，该公司完全致力于遵守所有适用的法律法规，包括其运营所在国家的出口管制法规。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是ASML is fully committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations，其中主语是ASML，谓语是is fully committed to complying，宾语是all applicable laws and regulations。including export control legislation in the countries in which we operate是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示ASML遵守所有适用法律法规的方式或范围，即包括其运营所在国家的出口管制法规。这个句子的意思是说，ASML补充说，该公司完全致力于遵守所有适用的法律法规，包括其运营所在国家的出口管制法规。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>条件状语从句 - 表示条件。    <p>原文例句：If US President Joe Biden’s administration had requested that ASML cancel several shipments of DUV systems to China weeks ahead of new rules coming into force this month, Bloomberg reported on Tuesday that US President Joe Biden’s administration had requested that ASML cancel several shipments of DUV systems to China weeks ahead of new rules coming into force this month.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个条件状语从句，由if引导，表示条件。其中的主语是US President Joe Biden’s administration，谓语是had requested，宾语是that ASML cancel several shipments of DUV systems to China weeks ahead of new rules coming into force this month。这个从句修饰主句Bloomberg reported on Tuesday that US President Joe Biden’s administration had requested that ASML cancel several shipments of DUV systems to China weeks ahead of new rules coming into force this month，表示如果美国总统拜登的政府在新的规则本月生效之前的几周要求ASML取消几批DUV系统对中国的发货，那么彭博社周二报道，美国总统拜登的政府要求ASML在新的规则本月生效之前的几周取消几批DUV系统对中国的发货。这个句子的意思是说，彭博社周二报道，美国总统拜登的政府要求ASML在新的规则本月生效之前的几周取消几批DUV系统对中国的发货，如果美国总统拜登的政府在新的规则本月生效之前的几周要求ASML取消几批DUV系统对中国的发货。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>并列句 - 表示并列关系。    <p>原文例句：In November, Shen Bo, senior vice-president of ASML and president of its China arm, reportedly signalled that the company was working to speed up deliveries to China to meet demand for DUV machines.  <ul><li>The maker of critical lithography systems said a licence to export some machines to China was partially revoked, but does not expect an impact on bottom line</li>
<li>The Chinese Foreign Ministry slammed the ‘hegemonic and bullying behaviour’ of the US and urged the Netherlands to uphold fair market principles</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/04ce0805-1869-40cf-9ab0-deeaa9b9e4ca_60c0c0ac.jpg" /><figcaption>The logo of chip equipment maker ASML seen at its booth during Semicon China, a trade fair for the semiconductor industry, in Shanghai on June 29, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Dutch chip-making equipment manufacturer ASML was forced to cancel some shipments to China after having licences partially revoked, in a blow to the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls">apparent efforts to stockpile</a> related technology ahead of new restrictions.</p><p>“A licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government, impacting a small number of customers in China,” the company said in a statement on Monday.</p><p>On Tuesday, Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesman Wang Wenbin condemned the “hegemonic and bullying behaviour” from the US, urging the Netherlands to uphold fair market principles and honour its contractual obligations.</p><p>Under US pressure, ASML already restricts Chinese clients from buying its more advanced extreme ultraviolet (EUV) lithography systems, which are used to produce the world’s most cutting-edge chips. ASML has a near monopoly on the machines.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Wang Wenbin, gestures during a press conference in Beijing on January 2, 2024, where he discussed the suspension on some exports of Dutch company ASML to China. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/608cf9f2-a296-426f-8d3a-a814ac9f96ea_5af09944.jpg" title="China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Wang Wenbin, gestures during a press conference in Beijing on January 2, 2024, where he discussed the suspension on some exports of Dutch company ASML to China. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Wang Wenbin, gestures during a press conference in Beijing on January 2, 2024, where he discussed the suspension on some exports of Dutch company ASML to China. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>However, from September, the Dutch equipment maker had been able to apply for licences to ship some of its less advanced DUV systems to China ahead of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls">new restrictions</a> that came into effect on January 1. The Dutch manufacturer received three such licences.</p><p>Lithography tools are complex projection systems that are considered the most important equipment needed in the process of producing integrated circuits. China is considered years behind in this tech, and has so far struggled to close the gap with leading firms despite heavy government investment.</p><p>Ahead of the Dutch restrictions, and following the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy">expanded US export restrictions</a> on DUV machines in October, Chinese manufacturers have been importing and stockpiling <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened">record numbers</a> of chip-making equipment from abroad.</p><p>China imported 42 lithography systems in November for US$816.8 million, with companies in the Netherlands and Japan accounting for nearly the entire amount spent on such imports.</p><p>China’s imports of critical chip-making lithography systems from the Netherlands, in particular, surged 1,050 per cent in value that month. The Netherlands is the biggest exporter of lithography machines, almost all of which come from ASML – though the company does not have the same hold on the DUV market as on EUV.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened" title="">China’s imports of Dutch chip-making equipment surged tenfold in November</a></h3><p>After a teardown of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a>’ latest 5G smartphone, the Mate 60 Pro, concluded that Chinese chip maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductor-manufacturing-international-corporation-smic" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductor-manufacturing-international-corporation-smic">Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC)</a> produced the device’s advanced 7-nanometre chip using DUV lithography machines, some <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain">experts predicted</a> more would be done to restrict China’s access to such technology.</p><p>Citing anonymous sources, Bloomberg reported on Tuesday that US President <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/people/joe-biden" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/people/joe-biden">Joe Biden</a>’s administration had requested that ASML cancel several shipments of DUV systems to China weeks ahead of new rules coming into force this month.</p><p>A spokeswoman from ASML declined to comment on that timeline, but noted that it was unlikely that the company would receive new licences for the NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i DUV machines in 2024.</p><p>“In recent discussions with the US government, ASML has obtained further clarification of the scope and impact of the US export control regulations,” the equipment maker said in its Monday statement.</p><p>“ASML is fully committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations, including export control legislation in the countries in which we operate,” it added.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>In recent years, China has been ASML’s third-largest market after Taiwan and South Korea, but it jumped to first place in the third quarter of 2023, accounting for 46 per cent of sales. This was up from 24 per cent in the previous quarter and 8 per cent in the first quarter.</p><p>In November, Shen Bo, senior vice-president of ASML and president of its China arm, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240290/dutch-chip-equipment-giant-asml-looks-speed-delivery-mature-lithography-machines-china-clients" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240290/dutch-chip-equipment-giant-asml-looks-speed-delivery-mature-lithography-machines-china-clients">reportedly signalled</a> that the company was working to speed up deliveries to China to meet demand for DUV machines. At the time, the company had a backlog of €35 billion (US$37 billion) from orders made in 2021 and 2022, which included orders from China, he added.</p><p>In an investor call the previous month, ASML CEO Peter Wennink said the company had fulfilled less than 50 per cent of Chinese clients’ orders in the previous two years, but shifting demand from other customers created an opportunity to fulfil more orders in the country.</p><p>In its most recent statement, ASML said it did not expect the licence revocation or the latest US export controls to have a material impact on its 2023 financial outlook, echoing similar sentiments expressed in its latest financial report.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Baidu’s move to cancel YY Live acquisition amid fierce market competition, tougher regulation a boon to firm’s AI business expansion, analysts say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247038/baidus-move-cancel-yy-live-acquisition-amid-fierce-market-competition-tougher-regulation-boon-firms</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Baidu has terminated its $3.6 billion acquisition of Joyy's live-streaming business, YY Live, due to regulatory issues. Analysts believe this move reflects Baidu's focus on generative AI development, including its popular chatbot Ernie Bot. Baidu aims to integrate AI into all its products and services to boost revenue and profit. Joyy plans to explore legal options, while facing fierce competition and regulatory challenges in the live-streaming sector.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Baidu shifts focus to AI development, cancels YY Live acquisition.</li>    <li>Theme: Baidu's decision to terminate the acquisition of YY Live highlights its commitment to AI-driven business and product strategy.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The growing importance of generative AI in China's internet sector and its potential to drive economic recovery.</li>    <li>Main information: Baidu's AI initiatives, including Ernie Bot and Ernie 3.5; reasons for terminating the YY Live deal; Joyy's response and its challenges in the live-streaming market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  百度终止了以36亿美元收购欢聚集团的直播业务YY Live。分析师认为，此举反映出百度正将重点放在生成式AI开发上，包括其广受欢迎的聊天机器人Ernie Bot。百度旨在将AI集成到其所有产品和服务中，以提高收入和利润。欢聚集团计划探索法律途径，同时在直播领域面临激烈的竞争和监管挑战。  <ul>    <li>摘要：百度将重点转移至AI开发，终止YY Live收购。</li>    <li>主题：百度决定终止收购YY Live，凸显其致力于AI驱动的业务和产品战略。</li>    <li>观点：生成式AI在中國互联网行业日益重要，并有潜力推动经济复苏。</li>    <li>主要信息：百度的人工智能举措，包括Ernie Bot和Ernie 3.5；终止YY Live交易的原因；欢聚集团的回应及其在直播市场面临的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>generative AI (n.) - 生成式人工智能。    <p>原文例句：Analysts said that China’s internet sector “has been undergoing changes”, which reflects Baidu’s focus on generative AI.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“generative AI”是“generative”（生成性的）和“AI”（人工智能）的组合，指利用人工智能技术生成新的数据或内容。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>chatbot (n.) - 聊天机器人。    <p>原文例句：Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“chatbot”是指能够与人类进行对话的人工智能程序，通常用于提供客户服务、回答问题或执行任务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>shrunk (v.) - 萎缩。    <p>原文例句：The market cap of Nasdaq-listed Joyy has shrunk by a third over the past three years.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“shrunk”是shrink的过去式，意为“缩小、萎缩”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fierce competition (n.) - 激烈的竞争。    <p>原文例句：Beijing-based angel investor Timothy Guo Tao said in a post that “fierce competition and tougher regulation on live streaming” services on the mainland could have also played a part in Baidu’s decision to bring the YY Live deal to an end.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“fierce competition”意为“激烈的竞争”，强调竞争的激烈程度和残酷性。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>regulatory issues (n.) - 监管问题。    <p>原文例句：Baidu said its affiliate Moon SPV exercised the right to terminate the US$3.6 billion acquisition of YY Live from Singapore-based Joyy because the deal lapsed, as it failed to meet certain conditions that include obtaining the necessary regulatory approvals from government authorities as of December 31.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“regulatory issues”意为“监管问题”，指政府或相关机构对企业或行业进行监管时可能遇到的问题或障碍。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>short video platforms (n.) - 短视频平台。    <p>原文例句：Joyy’s YY Live had also been the target of criticism from US hedge fund Muddy Waters, which labelled Joyy “a multibillion-dollar fraud” in a report just days after Baidu entered the deal to buy YY Live.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“short video platforms”意为“短视频平台”，指提供用户上传和观看短视频内容的网络平台。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Analysts indicated that China’s internet sector “has been undergoing changes”, which reflects Baidu’s focus on generative AI.    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是analysts，谓语是indicated，宾语是that China’s internet sector “has been undergoing changes”, which reflects Baidu’s focus on generative AI。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours.    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Baidu launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot，其中主语是Baidu，谓语是launched，宾语是the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot。从句是enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours，其中主语是enabling subscribers，谓语是to make，宾语是100 inquiries。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：As of December 28, Ernie Bot already amassed more than 100 million users, according to Baidu.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个表示过去完成时的句子，结构是：had + 过去分词。在这个句子中，had是助动词，过去分词是amassed，表示在12月28日之前，Ernie Bot已经积累了超过1亿用户。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个表示现在完成进行时的句子，结构是：have/has been + 现在分词。在这个句子中，have是助动词，现在分词是launching，表示百度自去年11月开始一直在推出其类ChatGPT服务Ernie Bot的付费版本。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Cancelling the YY Live acquisition is expected to help Baidu put more teeth into its artificial intelligence-centric business and product strategy</li>
<li>That move was ‘not totally unexpected’ amid changes in China’s internet sector, where the growing focus has been on generative AI, analysts said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/0c0aab40-f9c0-4f96-af99-649dd4a00b3d_8d4efc03.jpg" /><figcaption>Internet search giant Baidu has been sharpening its focus on artificial intelligence development initiatives. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>’s decision to terminate its acquisition of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> firm Joyy’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/live-streaming" target="_self" title="">live-streaming</a> business shows the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> search giant’s sharpened focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) development initiatives, according to analysts, as Chinese companies <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3239981/baidu-launches-paid-version-ernie-bot-chinese-firms-rush-make-money-their-generative-ai-chatbots" target="_self" title="">race to cash in on the technology</a> and help <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3224050/can-ai-give-china-upper-hand-surpass-us-and-become-worlds-top-economy-after-chatgpt-changed-game" target="_self" title="">boost the country’s economic recovery</a>.</p><p>In a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong-stock-market" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong stock exchange</a> filing on Monday, Baidu said its affiliate Moon SPV exercised the right to terminate the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3110190/baidu-buys-live-streaming-service-yy-it-seeks-catch-rivals-such" target="_self" title="">US$3.6 billion acquisition of YY Live</a> from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/singapore" target="_self" title="">Singapore</a>-based Joyy because the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246921/baidus-live-streaming-ambitions-dealt-blow-lapse-us36-billion-deal-buy-joyys-yy-live" target="_self" title="">deal lapsed, as it failed to meet certain conditions</a> that include obtaining the necessary regulatory approvals from government authorities as of December 31.</p><p>This move was “not totally unexpected, given investors have been waiting for more details in past years”, Jefferies equity analysts Thomas Chong and Zoey Zong said in a research note on Monday following Baidu’s announcement. They indicated that China’s internet sector “has been undergoing changes”, which reflects Baidu’s focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">generative AI</a>.</p><p>“For Baidu, Ernie Bot [has already] achieved a milestone in user base and [helps] reconstruct all [of the company’s] products with AI,” the Jefferies analysts said in their report, citing an announcement made during the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238197/baidu-says-ai-chatbot-ernie-now-matches-openais-gpt-4-unveils-new-enterprise-tools" target="_self" title="">Baidu World 2023 conference in Beijing</a> last October.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours. The company’s more basic artificial intelligence chatbot, Ernie 3.5 remains free of charge to the public. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1192" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/efbd36b2-fd43-498a-9fc7-a6ca3fe68665_3190cbb8.jpg" title="Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours. The company’s more basic artificial intelligence chatbot, Ernie 3.5 remains free of charge to the public. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours. The company’s more basic artificial intelligence chatbot, Ernie 3.5 remains free of charge to the public. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>By cancelling the YY Live deal, Baidu could put more teeth into its AI-centric business and product strategy, which co-founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3211124/baidu-beats-fourth-quarter-estimates-internet-search-giant-bets-future-developing-chinas-answer?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Robin Li Yanhong</a> said in the firm’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242461/baidu-forecasts-ai-revenue-growth-and-limited-short-term-impact-us-chip-curbs" target="_self" title="">third-quarter earnings report</a> was setting “the stage for sustained multi-year revenue and profit expansion within our Ernie and Ernie Bot ecosystem”.</p><p>In the company’s earnings call in November, Li said Ernie Bot was handling tens of millions of queries daily three months into its public roll-out, while thousands of enterprises have adopted Baidu’s AI services. As of December 28, Ernie Bot already amassed more than 100 million users, according to Baidu.</p><p>Still, Baidu aims to discuss with Joyy the next steps after the termination of the YY Live share purchase agreement. Baidu’s Hong Kong-listed shares edged down 0.7 per cent to HK$115.3 (US$14.76) on Tuesday.</p><p>Joyy, however, “is seeking legal advice” and “will consider all options at its disposal”. The company claims that the deal, which was entered into in November 2020, was “substantially completed” in February 2021, with certain matters to be completed in future.</p><p>The market cap of Nasdaq-listed Joyy has shrunk by a third over the past three years. The firm’s shares closed at US$39.7 on December 29, which was lower than its November 2020 level of around US$60.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246921/baidus-live-streaming-ambitions-dealt-blow-lapse-us36-billion-deal-buy-joyys-yy-live" title="">Baidu’s bid to buy Joyy’s live-streaming business lapses</a></h3><p>On microblogging service <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/weibo" target="_self" title="">Weibo</a>, Beijing-based angel investor Timothy Guo Tao said in a post that “fierce competition and tougher regulation on live streaming” services on the mainland could have also played a part in Baidu’s decision to bring the YY Live deal to an end.</p><p>In November, YY Live’s monthly active users totalled 16 million, lower than <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/douyu" target="_self" title="">Douyu International</a>’s 31 million and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/huya" target="_self" title="">Huya</a>’s 23 million, according to market intelligence firm Analysys. In July 2021, the Chinese government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3140625/chinas-antitrust-regulator-blocks-tencents-us53-billion-merger-game" target="_self" title="">blocked the US$5.3 billion merger</a> of video game streamers Douyu and Huya.</p><p>Even though YY Live is a pioneer of China’s live-streaming sector, it has been overtaken by younger market players like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243683/douyin-chinese-version-tiktok-testing-paid-videos-again-some-users-push-back" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Kuaishou Technology</a>, which are China’s top two short video platforms that also provide live- streaming features.</p><p>Joyy’s YY Live had also been the target of criticism from US hedge fund Muddy Waters, which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3110485/muddy-waters-targets-chinese-social-media-company-joyy-days-after" target="_self" title="">labelled Joyy “a multibillion-dollar fraud”</a> in a report just days after Baidu entered the deal to buy YY Live. The American short seller claimed that up to 90 per cent of YY Live’s live-streaming revenue was fraudulent. Joyy refuted the report, asserting that it “contained numerous errors, unsubstantiated statements and misleading conclusions”.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>With Baidu’s deal cancelled, YY Live must now “rethink its competition strategy”, said Chen Yuxin, analyst at LeadLeo Research Institute.</p><p>YY Live, according to Chen, has become a laggard in the live-streaming industry, where it has neither expanded into e-commerce nor transformed into a strong social media platform in China.</p><p>Tighter scrutiny by mainland regulators on live-streaming services could also be more challenging for YY Live to compete. Chen said <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242432/video-game-streamer-douyu-confirms-ceos-arrest-china-after-weeks-speculation-about-gambling-content" target="_self" title="">the arrest of Douyu chief executive Chen Shaojie</a> in November on suspicion of opening a casino “rang a bell to the entire industry that the authority will further strengthen regulation of the live-streaming industry”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
