<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Tech war: China chip imports fall in 2023 but semiconductors remain country’s largest item ahead of crude oil</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248269/tech-war-china-chip-imports-fall-2023-semiconductors-remain-countrys-largest-item-ahead-crude-oil</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>   <ul>    <li>China's imports of integrated circuits (ICs) dropped in both volume and value in 2023.</li>    <li>The decline reflects economic headwinds, weak smartphone and laptop sales, and China's efforts to boost local chip production. </li>    <li>China is unable to directly purchase advanced chips due to US export controls, but is making progress in producing legacy chips domestically. </li>    <li>Imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices also fell in 2023.</li>    <li>US export controls, intensified in October 2022, have disrupted global fabless and semiconductor tools companies.</li>    <li>China is increasing its domestic chip production capacity, aiming to reduce reliance on imported chips.</li>    <li>China's share of mature process capacity is expected to reach 39% by 2027, up from 31% in 2023.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>2023 年中国进口集成电路（IC）数量和价值均出现下降。</li>    <li>这反映了经济下行、智能手机和笔记本电脑销售疲软以及中国努力提高本地芯片产能等因素的影响。</li>    <li>中国无法直接购买先进芯片，因为受到美国出口管制，但正在努力在国内生产传统芯片。</li>    <li>去年，二极管和类似半导体器件的进口量也出现了下降。</li>    <li>2022 年 10 月美国加大了出口管制，对全球无晶圆厂企业和半导体工具公司在中国的业务造成了广泛干扰。</li>    <li>中国正在增加其国内芯片产能，目的是减少对进口芯片的依赖。</li>    <li>预计到 2027 年，中国成熟工艺产能的份额将从 2023 年的 31% 上升到 39%。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>headwinds (n.) - /ˈhɛdwɪndz/ 逆风，阻力，不利条件。    <p>原文例句：The weaker imports of ICs and semiconductor devices reflect economic headwinds in the world’s second-largest economy last year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由head（头）和wind（风）组成的，意为“逆风，阻力”。在这个例句中，它指的是经济下行、智能手机和笔记本电脑销售疲软等不利条件。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>commodity (n.) - /kəˈmɑːdəti/ 商品，货物，土产。    <p>原文例句：Diodes and similar semiconductor devices, a proxy of garden-variety commodity chips, were also down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，意为“商品，货物，土产”。在这个例句中，它指的是普通、标准的商品芯片，包括二极管和类似的半导体器件。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>procurement (n.)- /prəˈkjʊərmənt/ 采购，购买，采办。    <p>原文例句：These efforts may also have contributed to the decline of imported chips as China added mature capacity to enable production of the vast majority of chips locally.    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，意为“采购，购买”在这个例句中，它指的是中国增加成熟产能以实现在本地生产绝大多数芯片。这可能也导致了进口芯片数量下降。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>integrated circuit (IC) - 集成电路。    <p>原文例句：China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由integrated（集成的）和circuit（电路）组成的，意为“集成电路”。</p></li>  </ul><ul>    <li>semiconductor device - 半导体器件。    <p>原文例句：Imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices were also down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由semiconductor（半导体）和device（器件）组成的，意为“半导体器件”。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>According to the customs data, China’s imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices, a proxy of garden-variety commodity chips, were also down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year. - 根据海关数据，去年中国二极管和类似半导体器件的进口量也下降了23.8%。    <p>句子分析：这是一个陈述句，主语是China’s imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices，谓语是were down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year。这个句子表示，根据海关数据，去年中国二极管和类似半导体器件的进口量也下降了23.8%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语作定语 - 分词短语可以作定语，用来修饰名词或代词。    <p>原文例句：China is making solid progress in boosting local output of legacy chips, including those being used in cars and home appliances, to satisfy domestic demand. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，being used in cars and home appliances是一个分词短语，作定语修饰chips。这个分词短语表示这些芯片被用于汽车和家用电器中。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In 2023, China imported a total of 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion</li>
<li>Under rigid US export measures, China is unable to directly purchase advanced chips such as Nvidia’s H100 and A100 GPUs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/7a87b40d-bebc-417b-9aa1-baaa805bde8c_3c46d64f.jpg" /><figcaption>China chip imports fall in 2023 on economic headwinds and localisation efforts. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023, although semiconductors remained the mainland’s largest import item ahead of crude oil, according to customs data released on Friday.</p><p>In 2023, China imported a total of 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion, down 10.8 per cent by volume and 15.4 per cent in value from 2022, official data showed. By comparison, the country spent US$337.5 billion importing crude oil last year, a fall of 7.7 per cent.</p><p>The weaker imports of ICs and semiconductor devices reflect economic headwinds in the world’s second-largest economy last year, in particular China’s weak smartphone and laptop sales. Meanwhile, the data was also affected by China’s efforts to boost local output to cut reliance on imported chips.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248095/nvidia-reveals-progress-chinas-self-driving-chip-market-setting-competition-domestic-players" title="">Nvidia reveals progress in China’s self-driving chip market as competition revs up</a></h3><p>Under rigid US export control measures, China is unable to directly buy advanced chips, such as the H100 and A100 graphics processing units designed by US-based Nvidia. However, the country is making solid progress in boosting local output of legacy chips, including those being used in cars and home appliances, to satisfy domestic demand.</p><p>According to the customs data, China’s imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices, a proxy of garden-variety commodity chips, were also down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year.</p><p>The US intensified its export controls on China in October 2022, which caused widespread disruption for global fabless and semiconductor tools companies in their China-related businesses. In October last year, the US further tightened the noose, cutting China’s access to workaround chips that Nvidia had tailor-made for mainland customers.</p><p>In a state-backed drive to build a more resilient domestic chip supply chain, China’s semiconductor players have upped their localisation efforts with closer cooperation between the biggest companies. These efforts may also have contributed to the decline of imported chips as China added mature capacity to enable production of the vast majority of chips locally.</p><p>China currently has 44 semiconductor wafer fabs in operation and a further 22 under construction, Taiwan-based IC research company TrendForce said in a recent note. By the end of 2024, the capacity for mature chip production – defined as 28-nanometre and older technologies – will be expanded at 32 Chinese fabs.</p><p>The massive expansion, which has caused alarm in the US and EU, will see China’s global share of mature process capacity reach 39 per cent by 2027, up from 31 per cent in 2023, with room for further growth if equipment procurement proceeds smoothly, the TrendForce note said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tencent’s e-commerce drive takes off in 2023 on the back of super app WeChat’s short video and live streaming function</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248254/tencents-e-commerce-drive-takes-2023-back-super-app-wechats-short-video-and-live-streaming-function</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: WeChat Channels, a short video and live streaming platform, has seen substantial growth in its e-commerce business and advertising revenue in 2023.</li>    <li>Theme: The rapid growth of WeChat Channels in China's live streaming e-commerce market, driven by its TikTok-style short video function and extensive user base.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: WeChat Channels is reshaping China's e-commerce landscape and posing a significant challenge to other leading short video platforms.</li>    <li>Main information: WeChat's online orders increased by 244% year-over-year; WeChat Channels has become a major revenue driver for Tencent; Tencent plans to expand its e-commerce business and advertising presence on the platform.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>摘要：微信频道，一个短视频和直播平台，在 2023 年其电商业务和广告收入方面都取得了大幅增长。</li>    <li>主题：在中国的直播电商市场，微信频道的快速增长是由其抖音风格的短视频功能和广泛的用户群推动的。</li>    <li>观点：微信频道正在改变中国的电商格局，并对其他领先的短视频平台构成重大挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：微信的在线订单同比增长244%；微信频道已成为腾讯的主要收入来源；腾讯计划在该平台上扩展其电商业务和广告业务。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Gross merchandise volume (GMV) - 商品交易总额。    <p>原文例句：WeChat’s short video and live streaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023, according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p>    <p>例句讲解：GMV是指平台上销售的商品的总价值。在这个例句中，它指的是微信短视频和直播功能使平台在 2023 年的商品交易总额几乎增长了三倍。</p></li>    <li>Inroads - 逐渐进入。    <p>原文例句：The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s internet industry, as Tencent Holdings quietly made inroads into the live-streaming e-commerce market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：inroads是指逐渐进入或渗透。在这个例句中，它是指腾讯控股悄悄进入直播电商市场。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Short video platform - 短视频平台。    <p>原文例句：Tencent was expected to hit 100 billion yuan (US$13.9 billion) in e-commerce GMV, a measure of the total value of goods sold online, through WeChat Channels last year, according to a report last month by Chinese media outlet LatePost.</p>    <p>例句讲解：短视频平台是指那些允许用户创建和分享短视频的内容平台。在这个例句中，它是指通过微信频道销售的商品的总价值。</p></li>    <li>Online retail business - 在线零售业务。    <p>原文例句：Tencent has bet on swiftly building its online retail business on the back of the country’s vast number of WeChat users, estimated at 1.34 billion.</p>    <p>例句讲解：在线零售业务是指通过互联网销售商品或服务的业务。在这个例句中，它是指腾讯押注于通过其庞大的微信用户群快速建立其在线零售业务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>WeChat’s short video and live streaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023, according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province. - 微信短视频和直播功能使平台在 2023 年的商品交易总额几乎增长了三倍，根据周四在广州举行的年度开放课专业开发者大会上发布的信息。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 被动语态是指句子中主语接受动作或状态，而不是执行动作。    <p>原文例句：The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s internet industry, as Tencent Holdings quietly made inroads into the live-streaming e-commerce market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，“The progress of WeChat Channels" 是句子主语，"has been closely watched" 是被动语态，表示微信频道的进展受到了密切关注。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Online orders made through WeChat’s short video and live streaming function, Channels, grew more than 244 per cent in 2023 over the previous year</li>
<li>WeChat Channels has also become a major driver of Tencent’s advertising business, which grew 20 per cent year on year in the third quarter</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/424841e5-a3ac-4b8a-ae91-51168cfa301a_99a90435.jpg" /><figcaption>The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s internet industry, as Tencent Holdings quietly made inroads into the live-streaming e-commerce market. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>, China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> giant, saw its ubiquitous super <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">app</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> achieve significant growth in its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/live-streaming" target="_self" title="">live-streaming</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce business</a> last year, thanks to the popularity of its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a>-style short video function.</p><p>WeChat’s short video and live streaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023, according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/guangzhou-0" target="_self" title="">Guangzhou</a>, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p><p>While the platform’s exact GMV figures were not released, conference attendees were told that the number of orders made through WeChat’s video function – marketed as Channels – grew more than 244 per cent in 2023 over the previous year, according to a report by Chinese online media outlet Thepaper.cn.</p><p>A number of attendees at the conference, which was held as a closed-door event exclusive to industry partners, on Friday confirmed the reported growth rate. Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="2408" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/382a2415-7317-4bb1-8359-257715bbe26b_8190c8e6.jpg" title="Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>WeChat’s high GMV performance last year showed how prescient Tencent founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/abacus/who-what/who/article/3028219/pony-ma-tycoon-behind-chinas-social-media-and-gaming-giant" target="_self" title="">Pony Ma Huateng</a> was in December 2022, when he told an internal town hall meeting that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3204291/tencents-pony-ma-says-cost-cutting-will-continue-2023-and-pins-hope-short-video-major-growth-driver" target="_self" title="">short video was key to the company’s future</a>.</p><p>The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> industry, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244790/tencent-set-hit-e-commerce-sales-milestone-2023-closing-short-video-rivals-bytedance-kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Tencent quietly made inroads</a> into the live-streaming e-commerce market to take on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Kuaishou Technology</a> – the country’s two largest short video platforms.</p><p>Tencent was expected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244790/tencent-set-hit-e-commerce-sales-milestone-2023-closing-short-video-rivals-bytedance-kuaishou" target="_self" title="">hit 100 billion yuan (US$13.9 billion) in e-commerce GMV</a>, a measure of the total value of goods sold online, through WeChat Channels last year, according to a report last month by Chinese media outlet LatePost.</p><p>While the e-commerce turnover on WeChat Channels is small compared with those of Kuaishou and TikTok’s Chinese sibling Douyin, Tencent has bet on swiftly building its online retail business on the back of the country’s vast number of WeChat users, estimated at 1.34 billion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/648b1380-6ea8-4522-b681-e27f1eb67183_1126e908.jpg" title="WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Tencent also plans to expand its live-streaming e-commerce-related headcount and broaden its product categories, as the WeChat Pay team builds the vital transaction infrastructure to facilitate online payments, according to the LatePost report.</p><p>WeChat Channels has already become a major driver of Tencent’s advertising business, which increased 20 per cent year on year in the third quarter, the fastest growth achieved by all of the company’s business segments in that period. During the second quarter, WeChat Channels raked in 3 billion yuan (US$421 million) in advertising revenue.</p><p>Launched in 2020, Channels has been growing rapidly and had about 813 million active users as of June 2022. That number was ahead of Douyin’s 680 million users and the 390 million on Kuaishou, according to estimates by Chinese data analytics firm QuestMobile.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tesla cuts prices in China on Model 3 and Model Y EVs to keep commanding lead in premium segment of fast-growing market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tesla has lowered the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles to maintain its position in China's electric vehicle market.</li>    <li>The price cuts ranged from 2.1% to 6%, affecting models like the Model 3 and Model Y.</li>    <li>Tesla is facing increasing competition from Chinese EV makers, who have been launching new intelligent electric cars.<li>Despite the price cuts, Tesla remains the leader in China's premium EV segment, delivering over 600,000 vehicles in 2023.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>特斯拉降低上海制造汽车价格，以保持其在中国电动汽车市场的地位。</li>    <li>降价幅度从 2.1% 到 6% 不等，涉及 Model 3 和 Model Y 等车型。</li>    <li>特斯拉正面临中国电动汽车制造商的激烈竞争，它们推出了新的智能电动汽车。</li>    <li>尽管降价，特斯拉仍是中国豪华电动汽车领域的领先者，2023 年交付超过 60 万辆汽车。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>rival (n.) - 对手，竞争者。    <p>原文例句：Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“rival”意为“对手，竞争者”，指在某一方面与另一人或另一方竞争的人或事物。在这个例句中，“Chinese home-grown rivals”指中国本土的电动汽车制造商，他们是特斯拉在美国电动汽车市场上的竞争对手。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>raft (n.) - 一堆，一串。    <p>原文例句：Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“raft”意为“一堆，一串”，指大量或许多的东西。在这个例句中，“raft of new intelligent electric cars”指中国本土电动汽车制造商推出的大量或许多新的智能电动汽车。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>mount (v.) - 举起，安装，发起。    <p>原文例句：Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“mount”意为“举起，安装，发起”，指将某物放置或安装在某个位置，或发起或开始某项活动。在这个例句中，“mount a challenge”指发起挑战，即中国本土的电动汽车制造商发起对美国电动汽车制造商的挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li> leading position - 领先地位。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“leading position”意为“领先地位”，指在某一方面或领域处于领先的地位。在这个例句中，“leading position”指特斯拉在全球最大的电动汽车市场——中国豪华电动汽车市场的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>price cut - 降价。    <p>原文例句：The price cuts come after Tesla reported 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“price cut”意为“降价”，指降低商品或服务的价格。在这个例句中，“price cuts”指特斯拉在12月份报告了15.7%的月度销量增长后，随后进行的降价。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>sales growth - 销量增长。    <p>原文例句：The price cuts come after Tesla reported 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“sales growth”意为“销量增长”，指商品或服务的销量在一段时间内增加。在这个例句中，“sales growth”指特斯拉在12月份报告的15.7%的月度销量增长。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent，其中主语是Tesla，谓语是has cut，宾语是the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles。as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market是一个状语从句，表示特斯拉降价的原因或目的是为了保持其在全球最大的电动汽车市场——豪华电动汽车市场的领先地位。这个句子的意思是说，特斯拉将上海制造的汽车的价格降低了高达6%，这是为了保持其在世界最大的电动汽车市场——豪华电动汽车市场的领先地位。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Comparative and superlative adjectives - 比较级和最高级形容词。    <p>原文例句：Tesla is the leading EV maker in China, and it has the largest production hub worldwide.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级形容词和最高级形容词用于比较两个或多个事物或人的性质或状态。比较级形容词的形式是：形容词词干+er，最高级形容词的形式是：形容词词干+est。在这个例句中，“leading”是“lead”的比较级形容词形式，表示“领先的”；“largest”是“large”的最高级形容词形式，表示“最大的”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>Infinitive - 不定式。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式是由“to”加动词原形构成的非限定动词形式。它可以充当名词、形容词或副词。在这个例句中，“to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market”是一个不定式短语，充当目的状语，表示特斯拉降价的目的或原因，即为了保持其在全球最大的电动汽车市场——豪华电动汽车市场的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Carmaker cut prices by up to 6 per cent after reporting 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December</li>
<li>‘Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder,’ analyst says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/7e2c041a-9f88-4d42-864b-ea64912c8bf0_9e3fcf96.jpg" /><figcaption>People look at a Tesla Model 3 at a showroom in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p><a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest <a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> market.</p><p>The Texas-based company announced on Friday that the price of the entry-level edition of its Model 3 will be reduced from 261,400 yuan (US$36,814) to 245,900 yuan, while the starting price of the Model Y is now 258,900 yuan, down from 266,400 yuan.</p><p>The price cuts come after Tesla reported 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December, according to data released by the China Passenger Car Association.</p><p>“Tesla apparently hopes to maintain its market share in the highly competitive market,” said Phate Zhang, founder of Shanghai-based EV data provider CnEVPost. “Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua" class="image-inline caption" height="1618" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/eb3603e2-9af8-4fa3-8ecc-aae102cfa6f6_a8c0939e.jpg" title="Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua" width="2000" /><figcaption>Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure></div><p>Tesla also lowered the price of the dual-motor version of the Model 3 by 3.9 per cent to 285,900 yuan and offered a 2.1 per cent discount on the dual-motor Model Y, which now sells for 299,900 yuan.</p><p>The front-runner in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3241811/chinas-premium-ev-segment-set-cutthroat-competition-huawei-baidu-and-xiaomi-join-fray" target="_self" title="">China’s premium electric vehicle (EV) segment</a> delivered 603,664 EVs made in its Shanghai Gigafactory to buyers in China last year, up 37.3 per cent from 2022. The growth was nearly unchanged from the 37 per cent sales rise recorded in 2022 when it delivered about 440,000 vehicles.</p><p>The company’s domestic rivals are not exactly nipping at its heels. Its closest competitor in the premium segment, <a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a>, delivered about 376,000 cars in 2023.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Tesla adjusts the prices of its locally built vehicles regularly based on production costs, Grace Tao, Tesla’s head of communications and government affairs in China, said on the microblogging site Weibo last January. Since January 2020, Tesla China cut prices on its Chinese-made models six times. This is the first reduction since August 2023; Tesla slightly raised prices between October and November when growth of deliveries in China slowed.</p><p>The Gigafactory, Tesla’s largest production hub worldwide, has an annual capacity of about 1 million units.</p><p>Aside from deliveries to mainland customers, the Shanghai factory also shipped 344,078 vehicles to markets like Japan and Germany in 2023, up 26.9 per cent year on year, according to data compiled by the CnEVPost.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" title="">Chinese EV maker shows off flying car but admits urban use is far off</a></h3><p>Sales of electric cars in China jumped 37 per cent last year, with deliveries of pure EVs and plug-in hybrids hitting 8.9 million units. At present, mainland China accounts for about 60 per cent of global EV sales.</p><p>But sales growth of battery-powered vehicles in mainland China is expected to slow to 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November.</p><p>Intensifying competition is piling pressure on the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3237078/chinas-ev-war-only-strongest-will-survive-byd-xpengs-dominance-knock-out-15-pretenders-amid-supply" target="_self" title="">200-plus Chinese EV makers</a> this year, with some leading players spearheading price cuts to lure customers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247906/vw-and-gm-lose-ground-chinese-ev-makers-petrol-heavy-line-ups-fall-out-favour-worlds-largest-car" title="">VW and GM lose ground to Chinese EV makers as petrol-heavy line-ups lose favour</a></h3><p>A new round of price cuts is in effect, with BYD, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest EV maker</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> offering discounts to bolster sales.</p><p>Early last month, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a> cut the price of its Han luxury car by as much as 20,000 yuan to meet its annual sales target. Xpeng followed by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3245621/china-evs-xpeng-cuts-price-bestselling-g6-suv-maintain-high-sales-volume-amid-intensifying" target="_self" title="">cutting the price of its bestselling G6 SUV</a> by 10,000 yuan, or about 5 per cent.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US$3 billion top Asia fund bets on Tencent again despite China gaming rules, favours Samsung over TSMC in chip market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248169/us3-billion-top-asia-fund-bets-tencent-again-despite-china-gaming-rules-favours-samsung-over-tsmc</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund bought Tencent Holdings, betting on its attractive valuation despite further industry curbs by the Chinese government.</li>    <li>The fund's manager, Jonathan Pines, said the purchase reflects the fund's optimism over the nation's beaten-down market, where valuations are "absolutely incredible".</li>    <li>Tencent's shares trade at less than 16 times forward earnings, or about half the 10-year average, making them attractive.</li>    <li>The fund prefers Samsung Electronics to TSMC in the Asia semiconductor space due to Samsung's stronger earnings outlook and position in the memory chip sector.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund 买入了腾讯控股，押注其具有吸引力的估值，尽管中国政府进一步收紧了行业限制。</li>    <li>该基金的经理乔纳森·派恩斯表示，此次购买反映了该基金对中国被打压的市场的乐观情绪，那里的估值“绝对令人难以置信”。</li>    <li>腾讯的股票交易价格不到其未来收益的 16 倍，约为 10 年平均水平的一半，这使其具有吸引力。</li>    <li>由于三星在内存芯片领域的地位和更强劲的收益前景，该基金在亚洲半导体领域更青睐三星电子，而不是台积电。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>attractive (adj.) - /əˈtræktɪv/ 有吸引力的。    <p>原文例句：The fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语trahere（拉，吸引），意思是“有吸引力的，诱人的”。在这个例句中，指的是腾讯股票具有吸引力的估值。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>valuation (n.) - /ˌvæljuˈeɪʃən/ 估值。    <p>原文例句：The investment reflects the fund’s optimism over the nation’s beaten-down market, where valuations are “absolutely incredible”, said Jonathan Pines, who manages the US$3.1 billion fund.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语valere（值，价值），意思“估值，评估”。在这个例句中，指的是腾讯股票的估值非常具有吸引力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2><ul><li>sold most of its shares in - 出售了其大部分股票<p>原文例句：Pines’ fund sold most of its shares in Tencent as well as in Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) about a year ago.</p><p>例句讲解：这个词组是由sold（出售），most（大部分），of（介词，表示“从……”）和shares（股票）组成的。它表示“出售了其大部分股票”。在这个例句中，指的是Pines的基金在大约一年前出售了其在腾讯和台积电的大部分股票。</p></li></ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2><ul><li>Tencent yielded its position as Asia’s second-most valuable company after China’s new rules on online gaming erased US$53 billion off its market value in 2023, capping a third year of losses. - 在中国新的网络游戏规定于2023年导致其市值减少了530亿美元后，腾讯失去了其作为亚洲第二有价值公司的头衔，标志着其连续第三年亏损。<p>句子讲解：这个句子由两个分句组成：Tencent yielded its position as Asia’s second-most valuable company和after China’s new rules on online gaming erased US$53 billion off its market value in 2023, capping a third year of losses。第一个分句指腾讯失去了其作为亚洲第二有价值公司的头衔。第二个分句指中国新的网络游戏规定导致腾讯的市值在2023年减少了530亿美元，标志着其连续第三年亏损。这两个分句用after连接起来，表示后者对前者起原因和解释作用。整个句子的意思是在中国新的网络游戏规定导致腾讯的市值在2023年减少了530亿美元后，腾讯失去了其作为亚洲第二有价值公司的头衔，标志着其连续第三年亏损。</p></li></ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，并且仍然处于进行中的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Pines’ fund sold most of its shares in Tencent as well as in Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) about a year ago. - Pines的基金在大约一年前出售了其在腾讯和台积电的大部分股票。</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是由have/has和过去分词构成的。在这个例子中，have是助动词，sold是过去分词，表示Pines的基金在大约一年前出售了其在腾讯和台积电的大部分股票，并且这个动作已经完成了，但其结果或影响仍然持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Investment reflects fund’s optimism over beaten-down market, where valuations are ‘absolutely incredible’, says fund manager</li>
<li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund also prefers Samsung Electronics over TSMC in the semiconductor market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/b3633bc7-a417-4b09-b1bb-2156486982fa_cf3478d7.jpg" /><figcaption>A man plays an online game from Tencent on a train. China released draft guidelines on December 22, 2023, aimed at curbing excessive spending on online gaming. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>A fund that outperformed most of its peers has added Tencent Holdings back to its portfolio recently, betting on the gaming company’s attractive valuation despite further industry curbs by the Chinese government.</p><p>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246161/chinas-video-gaming-watchdog-speaks-out-after-draft-spending-rules-roil-market" target="_self" title="">draft rule on gaming restrictions in December</a>. The investment reflects the fund’s optimism over the nation’s beaten-down market, where valuations are “absolutely incredible”, said Jonathan Pines, who manages the US$3.1 billion fund.</p><p>“We are buying it now because of its very cheap value,” he said in an interview Wednesday, referring to Tencent’s shares. Pines’ fund sold most of its shares in Tencent as well as in Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) about a year ago.</p><p>Tencent yielded its position as Asia’s second-most valuable company after China’s new rules on online gaming erased US$53 billion off its market value in 2023, capping a third year of losses. The shares trade at less than 16 times forward earnings, or about half the 10-year average, making them attractive, Pines said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations" title="">ByteDance confirms talks with Tencent, other buyers for video game operations</a></h3><p>While China currently is not the preferred investment destination for many, a combination of ultra-cheap valuations and low allocations outweighs the risks of investing in the nation’s stocks, according to Pines.</p><p>“We think the risks of investing in China are worth taking because the stocks are so cheap,” he said.</p><p>The fund, which is also overweight on South Korea, prefers Samsung Electronics to TSMC in the Asia semiconductor space.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" title="">China to curb excess spending on video games in blow for world’s biggest market</a></h3><p>TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now.</p><p>While Korea’s largest company this week reported a steeper-than-expected 35 per cent drop in operating income, reflecting weak demand for consumer electronics globally, Pines said the results would not prevent him from being positive on its earnings trajectory. “Things are going to improve from here,” he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Google slashes over 1,000 jobs to focus on AI amid competition with Microsoft, OpenAI</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248158/google-slashes-over-1000-jobs-focus-ai-amid-competition-microsoft-openai</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Alphabet公司旗下的谷歌正在进行持续的成本降低和专注于人工智能（AI）的努力，解雇了数百名员工，其中包括语音助手谷歌助理、增强现实硬件团队和核心工程组织的工作人员。此次裁员旨在提高效率，并将资源分配到重点产品上，但受到员工的担忧。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Google裁员数千人，包括语音助手、硬件、工程等团队，以降低成本并专注于人工智能。</li>    <li>Theme: 谷歌裁员数百名员工，涉及不同团队和职位，旨在调整运营效率，释放资源。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 裁员是谷歌应对竞争和成本控制的举措，但受到员工的担忧，或影响公司文化和士气。</li>    <li>Main information: 受影响团队包括语音助手、增强现实硬件、工程等；裁员包括普通员工和高管；原因据称是为了提高效率和优化运营。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Alphabet旗下的谷歌公司裁掉其数字助理、硬件和工程团队的数百名员工，旨在降低成本，专注于人工智能(AI)领域。受到影响的员工包括语音助手谷歌助理和增强现实硬件团队的工作人员。此次裁员事件发生在谷歌的核心互联网搜索业务受到来自AI竞争对手微软和ChatGPT开发商OpenAI的竞争压力之际。谷歌高管承诺审查其运营，以识别需要削减成本和资源的地方，以便将资源分配给重大项目优先事项。谷歌方面还表示，部分团队仍在进行组织变革，其中包括一些角色的全球裁员。  <ul>    <li>摘要：谷歌裁员数千人，涉及语音助手、硬件、工程等团队，以降低成本并专注于人工智能。</li>    <li>主题：谷歌裁员数百名员工，涉及不同团队和职位，旨在调整运营效率，释放资源。</li>    <li>观点：裁员是谷歌应对竞争和成本控制的举措，但受到员工的担忧，或影响公司文化和士气。</li>    <li>主要信息：受影响团队包括语音助手、增强现实硬件、工程等；裁员包括普通员工和高管；原因据称是为了提高效率和优化运营。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rank-and-file (adj.) - 基层的，普通的。    <p>原文例句：The cuts struck both rank-and-file employees and executives, including four vice-presidents and 25 directors. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由rank（等级，阶级）和file（文件，档案）组成，表示“基层的，普通的”。在这个例句中，它指的是普通员工和高管，包括四位副总裁和25位董事。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>redundancy (n.) - 多余，冗余。    <p>原文例句：Google executives pledged to scrutinise their operations to identify places where they can make cuts, and free up resources to invest in their biggest priorities.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由re-（再，又）和dundant（重复）组成，表示“多余的，重复的”。在这个例句中，它指的是谷歌高管承诺审查其运营，以识别可以进行裁员和释放资源，以便将资源投资到他们的最大优先事项上。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>lower costs - 降低成本。    <P>原文例句：The affected employees included those working on the voice-based Google Assistant and the augmented reality hardware team. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由lower（更低）和costs（成本）组成，表示“降低成本”。在这个例句中，它指的是降低成本以提高效率和优化运营。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Google executives pledged to scrutinise their operations to identify places where they can make cuts, and free up resources to invest in their biggest priorities. - 谷歌高管承诺审查其运营，以识别可以进行裁员和释放资源，以便将资源投资到他们的最大优先事项上。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Google executives pledged，其中主语是Google executives，谓语是pledged。to scrutinise their operations to identify places where they can make cuts, and free up resources to invest in their biggest priorities是一个不定式短语作目的语，表示谷歌高管承诺审查其运营，以识别可以进行裁员和释放资源，以便将资源投资到他们的最大优先事项上。这个句子的意思是说，谷歌高管承诺审查其运营，以识别可以进行裁员和释放资源，以便将资源投资到他们的最大优先事项上。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态由主语接受。    <p>原文例句：The reductions come as Google’s core internet search business feels the heat from the AI offerings of rivals Microsoft and ChatGPT-creator OpenAI.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是The reductions，谓语是come。be动词feels用的是第三人称单数形式，表示谷歌的核心互联网搜索业务感受到了来自竞争对手微软和ChatGPT创建者OpenAI的人工智能产品的压力。这个句子的意思是说，谷歌的核心互联网搜索业务感受到了来自竞争对手微软和ChatGPT创建者OpenAI的人工智能产品的压力。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Google acquired the smartwatch company in 2019 for US$2.1 billion.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时的句子，主语是Google，谓语是acquired。have用的是第三人称单数形式，acquired是动词的过去分词。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。这个句子的意思是说，谷歌在2019年以21亿美元收购了这家智能手表公司。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The affected employees include those working on the voice-based Google Assistant and the augmented reality hardware team</li>
<li>The cuts struck both rank-and-file employees and executives, including four vice-presidents and 25 directors</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/663b61ac-615c-43fb-8726-9289f3dd1057_e5c63b15.jpg" /><figcaption>A Google logo seen during the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>Alphabet’s Google is laying off hundreds of people working on its digital assistant, hardware and engineering teams as part of a continued effort to lower costs and focus on artificial intelligence (AI).</p><p>The affected employees included those working on the voice-based Google Assistant and the augmented reality hardware team. The central engineering organisation was also hit by cuts, the company said.</p><p>The reductions come as Google’s core internet search business feels the heat from the AI offerings of rivals Microsoft and ChatGPT-creator OpenAI. On calls with investors in recent months, Google executives pledged to scrutinise their operations to identify places where they can make cuts, and free up resources to invest in their biggest priorities.</p><p>“Throughout the second half of 2023, a number of our teams made changes to become more efficient and work better, and to align their resources to their biggest product priorities,” a spokesperson for the Mountain View, California-based company said in a statement. “Some teams are continuing to make these kinds of organisational changes, which include some role eliminations globally.”</p><p>Alphabet shares were little changed on Thursday, closing at US$142.08 in New York.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A statue of the Android mascot. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/e277ff08-d4f0-488c-b2be-05c62a346d28_0c42f09f.jpg" title="A statue of the Android mascot. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>A statue of the Android mascot. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>The cuts struck both rank-and-file employees and executives. Disclosures filed by Google with the state of California show that 630 workers in the state have been let go this week, including four vice-presidents and 25 directors. Employees at those levels often earn millions of dollars per year in compensation, according to a person with knowledge of the matter.</p><p>The Alphabet Workers Union, which represents some Google employees, said more than 1,000 workers have been let go so far in total.</p><p>The co-founders of Fitbit, James Park and Eric Friedman, are also leaving Google as part of the reorganisation, a company spokesperson confirmed. Google acquired the smartwatch company in 2019 for US$2.1 billion.</p><p>Workers at the search giant have been on edge since January of last year, when Alphabet said it would <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3207638/google-parent-company-alphabet-lay-12000-workers-ai-focus-intensifies" target="_self" title="">cut about 12,000 jobs</a>, more than 6 per cent of its global workforce. That sent shock waves through Silicon Valley.</p><p>The company continued to make smaller trims over the course of 2023, including lay-offs within teams focused on recruiting, news products and the Waze mapping app.</p><p>While the large round of cuts in January 2023 was telegraphed by Alphabet chief executive officer Sundar Pichai, this year’s reductions have been communicated by lower-level leaders, such as vice-presidents and human resources, according to a current employee and a former worker.</p><p>Googlers and recently laid-off employees shared information with each other about the cuts in Discord chats, hallway conversations and other social networks, two current employees told Bloomberg. A document noting which roles got cut, as well as resources for laid-off coworkers, circulated among workers on Wednesday and Thursday, one worker said.</p><p>Staffers thought the company leadership would have learned from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3208941/google-workers-stage-rallies-against-job-cuts-low-wages" target="_self" title="">the outcry that large-scale job losses provoked</a> last year, a current employee said, noting that Google is focused almost exclusively on cost-cutting now. The employee said everyone is talking about having a Plan B.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239082/microsofts-bets-generative-ai-boost-azure-cloud-business-alphabets-google-cloud-disappoints" title="">Microsoft’s AI bets lift cloud business, as Google Cloud disappoints</a></h3><p>Workers said it was difficult to get a full picture of how many jobs were affected. Google – which had about 182,000 employees as of September 30, according to regulatory filings – said more cuts could be expected throughout January as decisions are made at the department level.</p><p>The company employed 190,700 workers before the lay-offs last year, in addition to tens of thousands of contractors around the world.</p><p>One of the Google employees who lost his job this week said the first sign of trouble came when he tried to check his work email, only to find he had been logged off. He found a message delivering the news that he had lost his job in his personal email.</p><p>Over the past year, there have been several rounds of micro-lay-offs, the worker said, speaking on condition of anonymity for fear of professional repercussions. He said it has killed morale at the company and is not conducive to creating trust.</p><p>Some Googlers have come to view January as a new grim annual tradition of mass lay-offs.</p><p>While Google executives have framed the cuts as a way to refocus resources on the company’s biggest priorities, the worker who was just fired said that he and a number of his teammates who were let go were working on AI.</p><p>Amazon.com also laid off hundreds of staff in its Prime Video and studios business this week, raising questions about whether another major round of job cuts was under way in Silicon Valley.</p><p>Semafor first reported the lay-offs to the Google Assistant team, while 9to5Google first reported the reorganisation for hardware. Affected staff have begun receiving the news and will have the opportunity to apply for open positions elsewhere within Google, the company said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US bitcoin ETF trades soar to US$4.6 billion on first day after landmark SEC approval</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248152/us-bitcoin-etfs-trades-soar-us46-billion-first-day-after-landmark-sec-approval</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Eleven innovative Spot Bitcoin ETFs, including ones from Grayscale, BlackRock, and Fidelity, commenced trading in the United States, igniting market activity and optimism in the cryptocurrency sector. These ETFs introduced on the Nasdaq Exchange saw considerable trading volumes, signaling their significance in the long-standing debate over the acceptance of digital assets as mainstream investments. Amidst the anticipation and enthusiasm, industry experts highlighted the need for prudent investment strategies due to the inherent volatility and speculative nature of Bitcoin.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Spot Bitcoin ETFs debut in the US, marking a significant milestone for digital asset acceptance.</li>    <li>Theme: Launch of several Spot Bitcoin ETFs, driving market participation and raising discussions on the role of cryptocurrencies in investment portfolios.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The ETF debuts reflect the growing recognition of Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies in the financial landscape, but emphasize the importance of measured approaches due to their inherent risks.</li>    <li>Main information: Eleven Spot Bitcoin ETFs commence trading, sparking competition among issuers and attracting investor interest; Varying estimates on potential inflows; Regulatory approvals follow decade-long deliberations; Crypto-related stocks experience initial gains but end lower.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在美国，包括灰度（Grayscale）、贝莱德（BlackRock）和富达（Fidelity）在内的11只创新的比特币现货ETF开始交易，点燃了加密货币行业的市场活动和乐观情绪。在纳斯达克交易所推出的这些ETF交易量很大，预示着它们在长期争论将数字资产作为主流投资的地位方面具有重要意义。在充满期待和热情的情况下，行业专家强调了由于比特币固有的波动性和投机性而需采取审慎的投资策略的必要性。  <ul>    <li>摘要：比特币现货ETF在美国首次亮相，标志着数字资产被接受的重要里程碑。</li>    <li>主题：多只比特币现货ETF的推出，推动了市场参与并引发了关于加密货币在投资组合中的作用的讨论。</li>    <li>观点：ETF首次亮相反映了金融领域对比特币和加密货币日益增长的认可，但强调了由于其固有风险而采取稳健方法的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：11只比特币现货ETF开始交易，引发发行机构之间的竞争并吸引了投资者的兴趣；对潜在流入的估计各不相同；监管部门批准是在经过十年的审议后做出的；与加密货币相关的股票最初上涨，但最终收盘下跌。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>landmark (n.) - /ˈlændˌmɑːrk/ 划时代的，里程碑式的。    <p>原文例句：The products mark a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry that will test whether digital assets – still viewed by many professionals as risky – can gain broader acceptance as an investment.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由land（土地）和mark（标记）组成的，表示“界标，里程碑，划时代的”。在这个例句中，它指的是加密货币行业的一个分水岭时刻，将考验数字资产（仍被许多专业人士视为有风险的）能否作为一种投资而被更广泛地接受。    </p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>vanguard (n.) - /ˈvænˌgɑːrd/ 领队，先锋。    <p>原文例句：Vanguard – the largest provider of mutual funds – said it had no plans to make the new batch of spot bitcoin ETFs available on its platform to its brokerage clients.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语avan（前进）和garde（警卫），表示“领队，先锋”。在这个例句中，它指的是Vanguard，全球最大的共同基金供应商，它表示不打算在其平台上向其经纪客户提供新一批的比特币现货ETF。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>kick off - 开始，启动。    <P>原文例句：Grayscale, BlackRock and Fidelity dominated trading volumes, the LSEG data showed.“Trading volumes have been relatively strong for new ETF products,” said Todd Rosenbluth, strategist at VettaFi. “But this is a longer race than just a single day’s trading.    </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由kick（踢）和off（离开）组成的，表示“开始，启动，引发”。在这个例句中，它表示Grayscale、BlackRock和Fidelity在交易量方面占据主导地位，根据LSEG的数据显示，“新ETF产品的交易量相对强劲，”VettaFi的策略师Todd Rosenbluth表示。“但这比单日的交易更漫长。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The products mark a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry that will test whether digital assets – still viewed by many professionals as risky – can gain broader acceptance as an investment. - 这些产品标志着加密货币行业的一个分水岭时刻，将考验数字资产（仍被许多专业人士视为有风险的）能否作为一种投资被更广泛地接受。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The products mark a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry，其中主语是The products，谓语是mark，宾语是a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry。that will test whether digital assets – still viewed by many professionals as risky – can gain broader acceptance as an investment是一个定语从句，修饰The products，表示这些产品将考验数字资产（仍被许多专业人士视为有风险的）能否作为一种投资被更广泛地接受。这个句子的意思是说，这些产品标志着加密货币行业的一个分水岭时刻，将考验数字资产（仍被许多专业人士视为有风险的）能否作为一种投资被更广泛地接受。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去式 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The SEC had earlier rejected all spot bitcoin ETFs on investor protection concerns. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去的动作，表示美国证券交易委员会（SEC）之前出于投资者保护的担忧而拒绝了所有比特币现货ETF。它的标志是动词的过去式，在这个例句中，rejected是reject的过去式。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示两个或多个事物或人之间的比较。    <p>原文例句：The green light from the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) for the products finally came late on Wednesday, following a decade-long tussle with the crypto industry.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个比较级，表示美国证券交易委员会（SEC）最终在周三深夜为这些产品开绿灯，此前与加密货币行业进行了十年的拉锯战。它的标志是形容词或副词的比较级，在这个例句中，longer是long的比较级。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including those from BlackRock, Grayscale and Fidelity – began trading in the US on Thursday</li>
<li>The ETF launches lifted the price of bitcoin up to its highest level since December 2021</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ba11cbce-0732-4b24-95d7-8df4f18e140b_28c230ae.jpg" /><figcaption>Representatives and guests from BlackRock rang the opening bell as bitcoin spot ETFs began trading on the Nasdaq Exchange on Thursday. Photo: Getty Images/AFP </figcaption></figure><p>US-listed bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs) saw US$4.6 billion worth of shares trade hands as of Thursday afternoon, according to LSEG data, as investors jumped into the landmark products approved by the US securities regulator on Wednesday.</p><p>The products mark a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry that will test whether digital assets – still viewed by many professionals as risky – can gain broader acceptance as an investment.</p><p>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust, Grayscale Bitcoin Trust and ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF, among others – began trading Thursday morning, kicking off a fierce competition for market share.</p><p>Grayscale, BlackRock and Fidelity dominated trading volumes, the LSEG data showed.</p><p>“Trading volumes have been relatively strong for new ETF products,” said Todd Rosenbluth, strategist at VettaFi. “But this is a longer race than just a single day’s trading.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ae8a3757-ffff-4ff6-8d4c-962edf286621_a66cec46.jpg" title="The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">green light from the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)</a> for the products finally came late on Wednesday, following a decade-long tussle with the crypto industry.</p><p>Some executives called out bitcoin as a high-risk investment, and Vanguard – the largest provider of mutual funds – said it had no plans to make the new batch of spot bitcoin ETFs available on its platform to its brokerage clients.</p><p>The SEC had earlier rejected all spot bitcoin ETFs on investor protection concerns. SEC chairman Gary Gensler said in a statement on Wednesday that the approvals were not an endorsement of bitcoin, calling it a “speculative, volatile asset”.</p><p>The ETF launches lifted the price of bitcoin up to its highest level since December 2021. It was last up 0.77 per cent at US$46,303, while the price of ether, the second-largest cryptocurrency, was up 2.79 per cent at US$2597.95.</p><h3>RACE FOR MARKET SHARE</h3><p>The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers, some of whom slashed the fees for their products well below the US ETF industry’s standard even before Thursday’s launch.</p><p>Fees on the new bitcoin ETFs range from 0.2 per cent to 1.5 per cent, with many firms also offering to waive fees entirely for a certain period or for a certain dollar volume of assets. After its ETF started trading, Valkyrie cut its fees a second time to 0.25 per cent and waived them for the first three months.</p><p>Grayscale was approved to convert its existing bitcoin trust into an ETF on Thursday, overnight creating the world’s largest bitcoin ETF with more than US$28 billion in assets under management.</p><p>Estimates for how much spot bitcoin ETFs could reel in vary widely. Analysts at Bernstein estimated that flows will build up gradually to cross US$10 billion in 2024, while Standard Chartered analysts this week said the ETFs could draw US$50 billion to US$100 billion this year alone. Other analysts have said inflows could be US$55 billion over five years.</p><p>As the ETFs began trading on Thursday, market participants were closely watching bid-ask spreads: the difference between the price for a trader to buy into an ETF and the price it can be sold. ETFs with narrower spreads are typically viewed as more desirable.</p><p>Trading volume, internal plumbing and the number of participants involved “are critically important to driving the spreads to a good spot”, said Jason Stoneberg, director of product strategy at Invesco, whose ETF with Galaxy Digital debuted on Thursday.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>Some analysts cautioned that the euphoria around the approval might be premature. The broader investment community still views cryptocurrencies as risky, with scandals such as the implosion of crypto exchange FTX in 2022 adding to investors’ wariness.</p><p>A Vanguard spokeswoman said the firm had no plans to launch its own crypto investment products, and that its focus remains on core asset classes such as stocks, bonds and cash, which it views “as the blocks of a well-balanced, long-term investment portfolio”.</p><p>Speaking at a webinar on Thursday, Sharmin Mossavar-Rahmani, head of the Investment Strategy Group and chief investment officer of wealth management at Goldman Sachs, said cryptocurrencies had no place in an investment portfolio.</p><p>“When you think about it, where is there any value to something like bitcoin?” she said. “We don’t think it is an asset class to invest in.”</p><h3>CRYPTO STOCKS GAIN</h3><p>Still, some expect the products to pave the way for even more innovative crypto ETFs, including spot ether products.</p><p>Grayscale CEO Michael Sonnenshein said in an interview Thursday that the firm plans to file for a covered call ETF in an effort to allow investors to generate income from options on its spot bitcoin product.</p><p>Cryptocurrency-related stocks initially climbed higher on Thursday, but ended the day lower, with bitcoin miners Riot Platforms and Marathon Digital dropping 15.8 per cent and 12.6 per cent respectively.</p><p>Bitcoin investor Microstrategy fell 5.2 per cent and crypto exchange Coinbase 6.7 per cent. The ProShares Bitcoin Strategy ETF, which tracks bitcoin futures, gained 0.44 per cent.</p><p>Also on Thursday, Circle Internet Financial, the company behind stablecoin USDC, said it had confidentially filed for a US initial public offering. Circle controls the issuance and governance of USDC, a cryptocurrency pegged to the US dollar.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>European Union not in ‘Champions League’ of economic security, ASML rep says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3248135/european-union-not-champions-league-economic-security-senior-asml-official-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>ASML, Europe's top tech company, criticizes the EU's approach to managing economic relations with China. </li>    <li>The EU, like the Europa League in football, struggles compared to the Champions League competitors in the United States, China and Japan. </li>    <li>ASML's top EU lobbyist, Wouter Baljon, highlights the impact of U.S. export controls on curtailing China's industrial progress. </li>    <li>EU Industry Chief Thierry Breton calls for Europe to be a balancing force in a multipolar world between the US and China, but ASML believes the EU lacks geopolitical influence. </li>    <li>Businesses express concerns about the EU's proposed screening of outbound investments and export controls on crucial technologies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>欧洲最顶尖技术公司ASML对欧盟处理与中国经济关系的方式提出批评。</li>    <li>将欧盟比喻为足球比赛中的欧罗巴联赛，其与美国、中国和日本这些“欧洲冠军联赛”的竞争对手相比，表现出巨大差距。</li>    <li>ASML的欧盟首席游说者沃特·巴尔容强调，美国的出口管制针对的是抑制中国的工业化进程。</li>    <li>欧盟工业总监蒂埃里·布雷东呼吁欧洲在中美之间作为多极世界中的平衡力量，但ASML认为欧盟缺乏地缘政治影响力。</li>    <li>企业们对欧盟提出的对外投资审查和关键技术出口管制提案表示担忧。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Geopolitical (adj.) - /ˌdʒiːoʊpəˈlɪtɪkəl/ 地缘政治的，国际政治的。    <p>原文例句：That was the withering assessment of a senior representative of ASML, Europe’s most valuable technology company, who used a football analogy to attack Brussels’ efforts to de-risk its relations with China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词由geo-（地球的）和political（政治的）组成，意为“与国际政治相关的”。在这个例句中，它指的是欧洲最具价值的技术公司ASML的高级代表，他用足球类比来攻击布鲁塞尔方面为减少与中国的关系风险而做出的努力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>La-la land (n.) - /ˈlɑː lɑː læːnd/ 梦幻世界，乌托邦。    <p>原文例句：The American policy was “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, Baljon said, adding that the EU was living in “la-la land” if it thought otherwise.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于电影“La La Land”，意为“梦幻世界”或“乌托邦”。在这个例句中，它指的是巴尔戎表示，美国的政策是“完全限制中国取得工业进步”，并补充说，如果欧盟认为情况并非如此，那他们就是生活在“幻想世界”中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Perform at Europa League-level - 表现水平达到欧罗巴联赛级别。    <p>原文例句：“The EU clearly … aspires to be in the Champions League, but for high technology, they struggled to perform at Europa League-level,” said Baljon at an event in Brussels on Wednesday, referring to the continent’s inferior competition.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由Perform（表现），at（在），Europa League（欧罗巴联赛），level（级别）组成，意为“表现水平达到欧罗巴联赛级别”。在这个例句中，巴尔容在星期三出席布鲁塞尔举行的活动中提到，“欧盟显然……渴望进入冠军联赛，但在高科技领域，他们努力达到欧罗巴联赛的水平”，指的是欧洲表现不佳的足球赛事。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ASML has been forced to stop selling some advanced precision lithography machines to Chinese buyers at the behest of the Biden administration. - 在拜登政府的命令下，ASML被迫停止向中国买家销售一些先进的精密光刻机。    <p>句子分析：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是ASML，谓语是被迫停止（has been forced to stop），宾语是销售（selling）一些先进的精密光刻机（advanced precision lithography machines）给中国买家（Chinese buyers）。at the behest of the Biden administration是一个介词短语，表示“在拜登政府的要求下”。这个句子的意思是说，在拜登政府的要求下，ASML被迫停止向中国买家销售一些先进的精密光刻机。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Public-sector intervention - 公共部门干预。    <p>原文例句：“You can’t just regulate your way to economic security from a few office blocks in Brussels,” Lohan said, adding he was “very nervous” about an “unprecedented shift to public intervention in our supply chains”.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个名词短语，由public-sector（公共部门的）和intervention（干预）组成，意为“公共部门的干预”。在这个例句中，洛汉说道，“你不能仅仅从布鲁塞尔的几个办公楼里通过监管来实现经济安全”，并补充说他“非常担心”对“我们供应链中公共部门干预的空前转变”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Dutch semiconductor equipment giant among several business groups on continent critical of Brussels’ efforts to de-risk its relations with Beijing</li>
<li>American policy “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, ASML’s top EU lobbyist adds</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/3ee1f9f0-3899-41eb-8332-c26934257ad0_b5a707dc.jpg" /><figcaption>A view of ASML Holding NV headquarters in Veldhoven, Netherlands. The Dutch semiconductor equipment company, a world leader in chipmaking, is valued at US$285 billion. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/european-union" target="_self" title="">European Union</a> is not in the “Champions League of economic security”, and even “struggles to perform at Europa League level”.</p><p>That was the withering assessment of a senior representative of ASML, Europe’s most valuable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> company, who used a football analogy to attack Brussels’ efforts to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3241838/eu-leader-ursula-von-der-leyen-urges-states-begin-economic-de-risking-china-or-face-trouble" target="_self" title="">de-risk its relations with China</a>.</p><p>“If you think about the Champions League of economic security and geoeconomic statecraft, we have to think of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>, we have to think of China, and we also have to think of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a>,” said Wouter Baljon, the Dutch company’s top EU lobbyist, referring to Europe’s premier football tournament.</p><p>“If you think of the Europa League, or tier two, we look at countries particularly in our industry, like [<a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South] Korea</a>, like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>, and at best Europe, the EU as a collective.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>“The EU clearly … aspires to be in the Champions League, but for high technology, they struggled to perform at Europa League-level,” said Baljon at an event in Brussels on Wednesday, referring to the continent’s inferior competition.</p><p>ASML, valued at US$285 billion, is the world leader in the chipmaking equipment essential for manufacturing advanced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductors</a> and considered the crown jewel in Europe’s tech sector.</p><p>Its executives should have a good idea of who’s who in the pantheon of geopolitical arm-twisting, having been caught in the cross hairs of a fierce <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/us-china-tech-war-rivalry/news" target="_self" title="">US-China tech war</a>.</p><p>ASML has been forced to stop selling some advanced precision lithography machines to Chinese buyers at the behest of the Biden administration.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247042/chip-industry-giant-asml-blocked-us-netherlands-shipping-equipment-china-ahead-export-deadline" title="">ASML blocked from shipping chip-making equipment to China ahead of deadline</a></h3><p>The American policy was “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, Baljon said, adding that the EU was living in “la-la land” if it thought otherwise.</p><p>“We haven’t acknowledged that export controls have become an industrial policy instrument. We still live in this la-la land that it’s about dual-use goods, it’s military-civil fusion.”</p><p>Baljon delivered his comments in Brussels during an event hosted by the European Policy Centre on the EU’s capacity to act as an economic security power as it looks to reduce its dependencies on Beijing.</p><p>Earlier in the day, EU industry chief Thierry Breton described Europe as a “third bloc” in a multipolar world.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ba9b8fc1-5a69-4091-bb98-4a2a845fa781_1126e908.jpg" title="Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>“We need to continue to promote Europe as a third bloc, a balancing force between the US and China,” the commissioner said at the event. “Of course, we will remain an open continent, but on our terms, more assertive than ever.”</p><p>However, ASML’s representative was less confident, saying the European Commission would struggle to define an economic security strategy without the buy-in of powerful member states, which have pushed back against the policy.</p><p>“A certain humbleness might certainly help the EU to act as a collective, particularly in high technology,” said Baljon. “We are not an incumbent unfortunately. As the EU 27, we are a challenger, and we need the instruments and the approaches to reflect this.”</p><p>“We might speak of the ‘geopolitical commission’, but at this point, I think it’s only as geopolitical as [the] Franco-German axis allows it to be, and you also don’t have the manpower to really be in this Champions League.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened" title="">China’s imports of Dutch chip-making equipment surged tenfold in November</a></h3><p>The EU will present an “initiative” on screening outbound investments and a proposal on export controls for four crucial technologies, including microchips, on January 24. These form part of a package of tools aimed at de-risking its trading ties with China.</p><p>Baljon’s remarks were among a series of broadsides voiced at the event as businesses lined up to criticise the EU’s plans.</p><p>Malte Lohan, director general of Orgalim, a trade association representing Europe’s tech industries, said firms in his sector were facing “a tsunami of regulation”.</p><p>“You can’t just regulate your way to economic security from a few office blocks in Brussels,” Lohan said, adding he was “very nervous” about an “unprecedented shift to public intervention in our supply chains”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3244922/eu-china-relations-amid-brussels-de-risk-plans-european-firms-are-reluctant-speak-china" title="">EU firms are reluctant to speak up on China as Brussels tries to de-risk</a></h3><p>“If you look at any one of the instruments in isolation, of course there’s always a very good reason for it … I think we need to accept that this is a completely new paradigm in terms of how supply chains are regulated through public-sector intervention.”</p><p>Luisa Santos, deputy director general at BusinessEurope, another lobby group, said the EU endangered its competitiveness by putting security concerns ahead of economic growth.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ukraine-war" target="_self" title="">war</a> in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ukraine" target="_self" title="">Ukraine</a> had “created a new consensus in the business community” on the security issues Europe faces, she said.</p><p>“But we should not overdo it also, because we have other problems that we need to deal with and we have not dealt with yet, including our competitiveness … what we have seen in these last years is that compared to other partners in terms of overall competitiveness … we [in Europe] are not in such good shape.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
