<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>HashKey claims ‘unicorn status’ after raising US$100 million for one of Hong Kong’s two licensed cryptocurrency exchanges</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248601/hashkey-claims-unicorn-status-after-raising-us100-million-one-hong-kongs-two-licensed-cryptocurrency</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  HashKey Group, a Hong Kong-based cryptocurrency company, has raised nearly US$100 million in funding, valuing the company at over US$1 billion, making it a unicorn company. The funding will be used to solidify its web3 ecosystem, diversify its licensed product offerings in Hong Kong, and develop its business globally.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: HashKey Group secures US$100 million in funding, reaching unicorn status.</li>    <li>Theme: HashKey's funding success signifies the growing acceptance of cryptocurrency in Hong Kong.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The increasing interest in virtual asset trading platforms in Hong Kong.</li>    <li>Main information: HashKey's business operations and plans for expansion; the regulatory landscape for cryptocurrency exchanges in Hong Kong; the market dynamics and challenges in the cryptocurrency industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  总部位于香港的加密货币公司 HashKey Group 在一轮融资中筹集了近 1 亿美元，使该公司的估值超过 10 亿美元，成为一家独角兽企业。这笔资金将用于巩固其 Web3 生态系统，使其在香港获得许可的产品更加多样化，并在全球范围内拓展业务。  <ul>    <li>摘要：HashKey Group 获资 1 亿美元，成为独角兽公司。</li>    <li>主题：HashKey 的融资成功标志着加密货币在香港的接受程度越来越高。</li>    <li>观点：人们对香港虚拟资产交易平台的兴趣日益浓厚。</li>    <li>主要信息：HashKey 的业务运营和扩张计划；香港加密货币交易所的监管环境；加密货币行业市场动态和挑战。</li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Venture capital (n.) - /ˈvɛntʃər ˈkæpɪtəl/ 风险资本。    <p>原文例句：Venture capital funding in the cryptocurrency industry plunged last year following a series of collapses in 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Venture capital”是一个由venture（冒险）和capital（资本）构成的复合词，指的是一种为有发展潜力的创业企业提供资金的投资方式，这类投资具有高风险、高收益的特点。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Exchange-traded funds (ETF) - /ɪkˈstʃeɪndʒ trædɪd fʌnd/ 交易型开放式指数基金。    <p>原文例句：The market recently bounced back on the back of enthusiasm brought by the US's approval of the first spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs).</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Exchange-traded funds”是一种类似于股票的开放式投资基金，它在交易所上市交易，可以像股票一样买卖，且具有分散投资和投资组合多样的特点。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take part in - 参加，参与。    <p>原文例句：Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Take part in”是一个常用的短语，意思是“参加，参与”。例如：“I took part in the singing competition.”（我参加了歌唱比赛。）</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>make a statement - 发表声明。    <p>原文例句：The Hong Kong-based company said in a statement on Tuesday, without disclosing any names.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Make a statement”是一个正式的短语，意思是“发表声明”。例如：“The company made a statement denying the allegations.”（该公司发表声明否认了指控。）</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>HashKey Group, established in Hong Kong in 2018, was approved by the Securities and Futures Commission last August to serve retail investors under the city’s new regime for centralised cryptocurrency exchanges. - HashKey Group 成立于 2018 年，去年 8 月获得证券及期货委员会批准，允许其根据该市针对中心化加密货币交易所的新制度为散户投资者提供服务。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是HashKey Group was approved，其中主语是HashKey Group，谓语是was approved，宾语是to serve retail investors。established in Hong Kong in 2018是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰HashKey Group，表示HashKey Group成立于2018年。last August是一个时间状语，表示去年8月。to serve retail investors under the city’s new regime for centralised cryptocurrency exchanges是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示以在该市针对中心化加密货币交易所的新制度下为散户投资者提供服务为目的。这个句子的意思是说，HashKey Group成立于2018年，去年8月获得证券及期货委员会批准，允许其根据该市针对中心化加密货币交易所的新制度为散户投资者提供服务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：HashKey Group, established in Hong Kong in 2018...</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是现在完成时的用法，表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。结构为：have/has + 过去分词。例如：“I have been working on this project for two weeks.”（我已经在这个项目上工作了两周。）</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或物实施或经历的。    <p>原文例句：The exchange attracted 15,500 registered users at the end of 2023...</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是被动语态的用法，表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或物实施或经历的。结构为：be + 过去分词。例如：“The book was written by a famous author.”（这本书是由一位著名作家写的。）</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, HashKey Group said</li>
<li>OKX Ventures is one of the lead investors in HashKey’s funding round, Bloomberg reported</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/3db425dc-5d1c-4046-8dd8-4e916a7cbc11_056fab3a.jpg" /><figcaption>A view of HashKey Group’s booth during the 2021 Hong Kong FinTech Week at the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre on 3 November 2021. Photo: Shutterstock.</figcaption></figure><p>HashKey Group, the company behind one of Hong Kong’s two cryptocurrency exchanges approved to serve retail investors, said it raised nearly US$100 million in a funding round that valued it at more than US$1 billion, making it a so-called unicorn company.</p><p>Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, the Hong Kong-based company <a href="https://group.hashkey.com/en/newsroom/HashKey-Group-Series-A-Financing-Round" target="_self" title="">said in a statement</a> on Tuesday, without disclosing any names.</p><p>OKX Ventures, the investment arm of OKX, one of the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchanges and an applicant for Hong Kong’s virtual asset exchange license, is one of the lead investors in HashKey’s funding round, Bloomberg reported. HashKey and OKX both declined to comment.</p><p>HashKey operates the licensed HashKey Exchange, the HashKey Capital venture capital and asset management arm and other blockchain technology services. It will use the funding to “solidify” its web3 ecosystem, diversify its licensed product offerings in Hong Kong and develop its business globally, it said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246047/chinas-crypto-craving-back-door-binance-traders-look-more-important-exchanges-future-wake-us" title="">China’s back-door cryptocurrency traders look more important than ever to Binance’s future</a></h3><p>HashKey Group, established in Hong Kong in 2018, was approved by the Securities and Futures Commission <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3229913/hashkey-and-osl-receive-hong-kongs-first-approvals-operate-crypto-exchanges-retail-investors" target="_self" title="">last August</a> to serve retail investors under the city’s new regime for centralised cryptocurrency exchanges.</p><p>The exchange attracted 15,500 registered users at the end of 2023, with daily trading volume exceeding US$630 million in December, HashKey said last month. Nearly 40 per cent of the value traded on its platform came from professional investors, it said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3201697/what-are-virtual-assets-hong-kong-and-what-do-citys-new-rules-mean-crypto-trading" title="">What does Hong Kong mean by virtual assets?</a></h3><p>HashKey Exchange handled US$15.3 million in trading volume over 24 hours through Tuesday, according to the market tracker CoinGecko. That is a trickle compared with the US$13.6 billion transacted over the same period on Binance, the world’s largest exchange for cryptocurrencies.</p><p>HashKey is one of a range of cryptocurrency firms banking on Hong Kong’s push to embrace the virtual asset industry, even as public perception of the sector has plunged following scandals involving companies including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ftx" target="_self" title="">FTX</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jpex-cryptocurrency-scandal" target="_self" title="">JPEX</a>.</p><p>Twelve companies have so far submitted their applications for Hong Kong’s licence for virtual asset trading platforms.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3237817/hong-kongs-crypto-hub-dream-mired-high-costs-other-barriers-one-year-jpex-one-stumbling-block" title="">High costs cloud Hong Kong’s crypto hub dream</a></h3><p>Venture capital funding in the cryptocurrency industry plunged last year following a series of collapses in 2022. In the three months ending September 2023, cryptocurrency firms around the world raised US$1.8 billion across 309 deals, representing a 69.6 per cent decline in deal value and 55.9 per cent drop in deal numbers from the same period a year ago, according to data by PitchBook.</p><p>The market recently bounced back on the back of enthusiasm brought by the US’ approval of the first spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs), which allow investors to gain exposure to virtual assets without directly buying any cryptocurrency tokens.</p><p>Hong Kong last month also said that it will move to open up retail access to cryptocurrency spot ETFs, after previously only allowing retail participation in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3203539/crypto-futures-etfs-debut-hong-kong-lukewarm-interest-after-market-turmoil-ftx-collapse?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">cryptocurrency futures ETFs</a>, which hold cryptocurrency futures contracts, instead of direct investments in cryptocurrency tokens at their spot prices.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech war: Chinese chip-tool giant Naura forecasts surge in 2023 sales on strong local demand amid US export controls</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3248610/tech-war-chinese-chip-tool-giant-naura-forecasts-surge-2023-sales-strong-local-demand-amid-us-export</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese semiconductor equipment manufacturer Naura Technology Group expects significant growth in 2023 revenue and net profit due to technological advancements and increased market share.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Naura's technology breakthroughs drive local demand amidst a global semiconductor supply crunch.</li>    <li>Theme: Naura's success amidst geopolitical tensions and the global chip shortage highlights China's efforts towards semiconductor self-sufficiency.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Importance of domestic innovation and collaboration in securing China's semiconductor supply chain.</li>    <li>Main information: Naura's revenue growth projections, technology advancements, and increasing market share; Chinese foundries' reliance on domestic tool suppliers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国半导体设备制造商纳芯科技集团预计，由于技术突破和市场份额的增加，2023 年营收和净利润将大幅增长。  <ul>    <li>摘要：在全球半导体供应紧缩的情况下，纳芯的技术突破带动当地需求。</li>    <li>主题：纳芯在政治紧张和全球芯片短缺中取得成功，凸显了中国为实现半导体自给自足所做的努力。</li>    <li>观点：指出本土创新与合作对于确保中国半导体供应链安全的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：纳芯的营收增长预测、技术进步以及市场份额的提升；中国晶圆厂对本土设备供应商的依赖。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>breakthrough (n.) - /ˈbreɪkθruː/ 突破，突破口。    <p>原文例句：[Naura] has made technology breakthroughs and achieved volume production of more than a dozen of semiconductor equipment including etching, deposition and cleaning, and furnace, which help the company to cover more semiconductor manufacturing processes, leading to higher market shares,” Naura said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由break（打破）和through（穿过）组成，表示“突破，突破口”。在这个例句中，它指的是纳芯的技术突破，即在蚀刻、沉积、清洗和炉子等十多种半导体设备上实现了批量生产，帮助公司覆盖更多的半导体制造工艺，从而赢得更高的市场份额。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>foundry (n.) - /ˈfaʊndriː/ 铸造厂，代工半导体厂。    <p>原文例句：Beijing-based Naura counts China’s largest foundries as major clients, such as Yangtze Memory Technologies Corp (YMTC).</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源于古英语fundere（铸造），表示“铸造厂，代工半导体厂”。在这个例句中，它指的是纳芯的的主要客户，如长江存储等中国最大的晶圆代工厂。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>pulled out - 退出，撤出。    <P>原文例句：With foreign semiconductor equipment manufacturers pulling out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由pull（拉）和out（退出）组成，表示“退出，撤出”。在这个例句中，它指的是外国半导体设备制造商退出中国，即由于美国的出口管制和地缘政治紧张局势，一些外国半导体设备制造商决定退出中国市场。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Amid a government-supported semiconductor self-sufficiency drive, YMTC has been in talks with domestic tool suppliers, including what was said to be a major company based in the Chinese capital, to produce replacements for crucial parts widely found in its equipment made by US firm Lam Research, sources told the Post last year. - 在政府支持半导体自给自足的推动下，长江存储一直与国内的工具供应商进行谈判，其中包括一家据称位于中国首都的大型公司，以生产在美国公司 Lam Research 制造的设备中广泛使用的关键部件的替代品，消息人士去年告诉邮报。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是YMTC has been in talks with domestic tool suppliers，其中主语是YMTC，谓语是has been in talks，宾语是domestic tool suppliers。Amid a government-supported semiconductor self-sufficiency drive是一个介词短语作状语，修饰主语YMTC，表示长江存储一直与国内的工具供应商进行谈判是在政府支持半导体自给自足的推动下进行的。to produce replacements for crucial parts widely found in its equipment made by US firm Lam Research是一个不定式短语作目的状语，修饰主语YMTC，表示长江存储与国内工具供应商谈判的目的是生产在美国公司Lam Research制造的设备中广泛使用的关键部件的替代品。这个句子的意思是说，在政府支持半导体自给自足的推动下，长江存储一直在与国内的工具供应商进行谈判，其中包括一家据称位于中国首都的大型公司，以生产在美国公司Lam Research制造的设备中广泛使用的关键部件的替代品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前发生的或完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Lam Research has suspended equipment supply and services to clients in mainland China after Washington tightened US export controls in October 2022. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间点之前发生或完成，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示Lam Research在2022年10月华盛顿收紧美国出口管制之后暂停了对中国大陆客户的设备供应和服务，即Lam Research在2022年10月之前已经停止了对中国大陆客户的设备供应和服务。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较级 - 用于比较两个对象或两个值之间的差异。    <p>原文例句：Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment China, Naura’s main rival, has said it expects 2023 revenue to rise more than 30 per cent on the back of strong demand from mainland fabs.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是一个形容词或副词的一种形式，用于比较两个对象或两个值之间的差异。比较级通常是在形容词或副词的词尾加上-er或more。在这个例句中，more than 30 per cent是一个比较级，表示超过30%。这个句子的意思是说，纳芯的主要竞争对手、先进微电子制造设备（中国）表示，预计 2023 年收入将增长超过 30%，这得益于来自中国大陆晶圆厂的强劲需求。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Naura Technology expects a jump in both its revenue and net profit in 2023, as technology breakthroughs drive local demand</li>
<li>With foreign semiconductor equipment manufacturers pulling out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/dc40cd20-632e-4e89-9957-bc5f891f0b1e_628de1bf.jpg" /><figcaption>Naura Technology Group expects last year’s sales to grow by roughly half. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>State-backed Chinese semiconductor equipment giant Naura Technology Group expects its 2023 revenue to jump by around half from a year earlier, as leaps in its technology helped it gain a larger market share in the country.</p><p>The company said in a regulatory filing on Monday evening that its revenue last year is projected to grow between 42 per cent and 57 per cent to 20.9 billion yuan and 23.1 billion yuan (US$2.93 billion and US$3.24 billion).</p><p>“[Naura] has made technology breakthroughs and achieved volume production of more than a dozen of semiconductor equipment including etching, deposition and cleaning, and furnace, which help the company to cover more semiconductor manufacturing processes, leading to higher market shares,” Naura said.</p><p>Net profits are expected to increase between 57 per cent and 80 per cent to between 3.3 billion yuan and 3.8 billion yuan.</p><p>The company said it received over 30 billion yuan worth of new equipment orders in 2023, over 70 per cent of them related to semiconductor-related tools. It did not disclose similar figures in its revenue forecasts for 2022 or 2021.</p><p>Beijing-based Naura counts China’s largest foundries as major clients, such as Yangtze Memory Technologies Corp (YMTC).</p><p>Amid a government-supported semiconductor self-sufficiency drive, YMTC has been in talks with domestic tool suppliers, including what was said to be a major company based in the Chinese capital, to produce replacements for crucial parts widely found in its equipment made by US firm Lam Research, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3235074/tech-war-chinas-top-memory-chip-maker-ymtc-forges-closer-ties-domestic-supplier-replace-us-parts" target="_self" title="">sources told the Post last year</a>.</p><p>Lam Research has suspended equipment supply and services to clients in mainland China after Washington tightened US export controls in October 2022.</p><p>With foreign players pulling their staff and operations out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives. The surging demand has helped lift sales of Chinese equipment manufacturers, although most of their products – especially those in advanced nodes below 10 nanometres – are thought to lag in quality.</p><p>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment China, Naura’s main rival, has said it expects 2023 revenue to rise more than 30 per cent on the back of strong demand from mainland fabs.</p><p>Shares of Shenzhen-listed Naura rose around 3 per cent to nearly 239 yuan in the morning trading session on Tuesday.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Microsoft launches consumer version of Copilot for US$20 a month with access to ChatGPT technology through Office</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248564/microsoft-launches-consumer-version-copilot-us20-month-access-chatgpt-technology-through-office</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Microsoft releases a consumer version of its AI tool Copilot for $20 per month.</li>    <li>The new version of Copilot, called Copilot Pro, integrates with Office suite (Word, Outlook, Excel, PowerPoint) and offers ChatGPT features and image generation.</li>    <li>The subscription requirement for businesses has been dropped, allowing smaller companies and individuals to use Copilot.</li>    <li>Microsoft expects high demand, as seen in the queues for Windows 95 software in the past.</li>    <li>The company plans to launch a builder tool that enables users to create their own Copilots for specific topics and will retain some consumer data to improve the product.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>微软发布了其AI工具Copilot的消费者版本，每月收费20美元。</li>    <li>Copilot的新版本名为Copilot Pro，可与Office套件（Word、Outlook、Excel、PowerPoint）集成，并提供ChatGPT功能和图像生成。</li>    <li>不再强制要求企业订阅，允许较小的公司和个人使用Copilot。</li>    <li>微软预计需求量很大，这从过去排队购买Windows 95软件的队伍中可见一斑。</li>    <li>该公司计划推出一个构建工具，使用户能够创建自己的针对特定主题的Copilot，该服务目前已向企业提供。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>subscription (n.) - /ˌsʌbˈskrɪpʃən/ 订阅，认购。    <p>原文例句：Companies previously had to buy at least 300 subscriptions to use Copilot, a requirement Microsoft is getting rid of </p>    <p>例句讲解：subscription是一个名词，表示“订阅，认购”。在这个例句中，它指的是企业以前必须购买至少300个订阅才能使用Copilot，这是一个微软正在取消的要求。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>integrate (v.) - /ˈɪntɪgreɪt/ 集成，整合。    <p>原文例句：The new version of Copilot, called Copilot Pro, integrates with Office suite (Word, Outlook, Excel, PowerPoint) and offers ChatGPT features and image generation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：integrate是一个动词，表示“集成，整合”。在这个例句中，它指的是Copilot的新版本，称为Copilot Pro，可与Office套件（Word、Outlook、Excel、PowerPoint）集成，并提供ChatGPT功能和图像生成。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>be attended by - 有人参加。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft announced the new services ahead of the World Economic Forum in Davos, which will be attended by chief executive officer Satya Nadella.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由be（是），attended（参加）和by（由）构成的，表示“由……参加，由……参与”。在这个例句中，它表示世界经济论坛将在达沃斯举行，首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉将参加。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in the past - 在过去，从前。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft expects high demand, as seen in the queues for Windows 95 software in the past.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指过去发生的事情或情况。在这个例句中，它表示微软预计会有很高的需求，就像过去人们排队购买Windows 95软件一样。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Microsoft has debuted a consumer version of its Copilot artificial intelligence tool. - 微软首次推出其Copilot人工智能工具的消费者版本。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Microsoft has debuted，其中主语是Microsoft，谓语是has debuted，宾语是a consumer version of its Copilot artificial intelligence tool。Photo: AP Photo是一个插入语，表示这篇文章附有美联社的照片。这个句子的意思是说，微软首次推出其Copilot人工智能工具的消费者版本。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The company plans to roll out a builder tool, similar to what OpenAI unveiled last year, that will let individuals create their own Copilots for a specific topic, a service that is already available to enterprises. - 该公司计划推出一个构建工具，类似于OpenAI去年推出的工具，该工具将允许个人为特定主题创建自己的Copilot，这项服务目前已向企业提供。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The company plans to roll out，其中主语是The company，谓语是plans to roll out，宾语是一个不定式作目的语，即roll out a builder tool。similar to what OpenAI unveiled last year是一个形容词短语，修饰builder tool，表示该构建工具类似于OpenAI去年推出的工具。that will let individuals create their own Copilots for a specific topic是一个定语从句，修饰builder tool，表示该构建工具将允许个人为特定主题创建自己的Copilot。a service that is already available to enterprises是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰builder tool，表示这项服务目前已向企业提供。这个句子的意思是说，该公司计划推出一个构建工具，类似于OpenAI去年推出的工具，该工具将允许个人为特定主题创建自己的Copilot，这项服务目前已向企业提供。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词作定语 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态对当前状态的影响或原因。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft has debuted a consumer version of its Copilot artificial intelligence tool.</p>    <p>语法讲解：debuted是一个过去分词，作定语，修饰tool，表示该工具是微软首次推出的。这个句子的意思是说，微软首次推出其Copilot人工智能工具的消费者版本。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人对某件事的假设、猜测或愿望。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft plans to roll out a builder tool, similar to what OpenAI unveiled last year, that will let individuals create their own Copilots for a specific topic, a service that is already available to enterprises.</p>    <p>语法讲解：will let是虚拟语气，表示微软计划推出一个构建工具，该工具将允许个人为特定主题创建自己的Copilot。这个句子的意思是说，该公司计划推出一个构建工具，类似于OpenAI去年推出的工具，该工具将允许个人为特定主题创建自己的Copilot，这项服务目前已向企业提供。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Consumers of Office will be able to use Copilot Pro to help answer questions and create content in Word, Outlook, Excel and PowerPoint</li>
<li>Companies previously had to buy at least 300 subscriptions to use Copilot, a requirement Microsoft is getting rid of</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/60d99f9f-7754-4b8a-9cd6-70a210df5cd6_c9e26244.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft has debuted a consumer version of its Copilot artificial intelligence tool. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure><p>Microsoft is opening up its artificial intelligence assistant to consumers and making the corporate version available to smaller companies as it tries to increase the number of paying customers for the new services.</p><p>Microsoft is selling a US$20-a-month consumer version of Copilot, with access to OpenAI’s latest ChatGPT technology and image-creation features, the Redmond, Washington-based software giant said in a statement.</p><p>Consumers with a cloud subscription to Office will be able to use Copilot to help answer questions, summarise data and create content in Word, Outlook, Excel and PowerPoint.</p><p>The company, which has been selling a similar product to large businesses for a monthly fee of US$30 per user, will get rid of the 300-subscription minimum for its enterprise service.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>As Microsoft has revamped nearly all of its products around artificial intelligence tools based on technology from OpenAI, its Office products remain one of the best ways to get customers to pay extra for AI assistance.</p><p>Executives have said demand is unusually high, with Azure chief Scott Guthrie likening it to the queues outside shops to purchase Windows 95 software nearly three decades ago.</p><p>Microsoft has been testing the Office-based copilot, now called Copilot for Microsoft 365, since March. The company began selling it widely in November, as long as companies purchased at least 300 subscriptions. That left out small businesses and those that wanted to begin with a smaller trial, said Jared Spataro, a Microsoft vice-president, in an interview.</p><p>“We have just never seen demand in the commercial space for a product like we are seeing for Copilot from Microsoft 365,’’ he said. “We have had pressure I have never seen from small and medium businesses saying ‘why will you not let us buy this? Let us try it’.”</p><p>Microsoft announced the new services ahead of the World Economic Forum in Davos, which will be attended by chief executive officer Satya Nadella.</p><p>Microsoft’s consumer service, called Copilot Pro, offers similar features to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3235800/openai-updates-chatgpt-ability-hear-and-speak-see-images-it-still-cannot-sing" target="_self" title="">OpenAI’s ChatGPT Plus</a> at the same price, though the integration with Office differentiates their product, Spataro said.</p><p>The company plans to roll out a builder tool, similar to what OpenAI unveiled last year, that will let individuals create their own Copilots for a specific topic, a service that is already available to enterprises.</p><p>Microsoft’s privacy rules for the consumer version also differ from the business one. Unlike data from corporate customers, Microsoft said it will retain a portion of prompts and responses from the consumer model to retrain models and improve the product.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>AirPods maker Goertek to open Vietnam factory as part of Apple’s supply chain diversification</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248542/airpods-maker-goertek-open-vietnam-factory-part-apples-supply-chain-diversification</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Apple announced that its supplier Goertek will set up a wholly-owned subsidiary in Vietnam with an investment of up to $280 million to meet the demands of business expansion in Southeast Asia. This subsidiary will produce consumer electronics products and contribute to the company's future development and client requirements. Additionally, Apple is urging its manufacturing partners to diversify their operations outside China to decrease reliance on the region, leading to investments in countries like Vietnam, India, and the US.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's supplier Goertek invests in Vietnam for business expansion.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's shifting production focus from China due to Covid-19 restrictions and its encouragement of suppliers to diversify globally.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of Covid-19 on Apple's supply chain; the benefits of diversifying production geographically.</li>    <li>Main information: Goertek's investment, location and production plan in Vietnam; Apple's strategy to reduce reliance on China; investment by Apple suppliers in other countries.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果公司宣布其供应商歌尔股份将在越南设立一家全资子公司，投资高达2.8亿美元，以满足其在东南亚业务扩张的需求。这家子公司将生产消费电子产品，并为公司的未来发展和客户需求做出贡献。此外，苹果正敦促其制造合作伙伴将业务多元化，扩展到中国以外地区，以减少对该地区的依赖，这导致了对越南、印度和美国等国家进行投资。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果供应商歌尔股份投资越南以实现业务扩张。</li>    <li>主题: 由于新冠肺炎疫情导致生产中断，苹果将生产重心从中国转向其他地区，并鼓励其供应商在全球范围内实现业务多元化。</li>    <li>观点：新冠肺炎疫情对苹果供应链的影响；在地理上实现生产多元化的优势。</li>    <li>主要信息：歌尔在越南的投资、生产计划和选址；苹果减少对中国依赖的战略；苹果供应商在其他国家进行的投资。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>incentive (n.) - /ˈɪns(ə)ntɪv/ 刺激，诱因。    <p>原文例句：Apple has been providing financial incentives to encourage its suppliers to relocate manufacturing operations to other countries.</p>    <p>例句讲解：该单词来源于拉丁语，由in（向内）和centivus（刺中心）构成，表示“刺激，诱因”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司为鼓励其供应商将制造业务迁至其他国家而提供的财务激励措施。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>disruption (n.) - /dɪsˈrʌpʃ(ə)n/ 打乱，中断。    <p>原文例句：Beijing's stringent Covid-19 restrictions during the pandemic disrupted the US firm's manufacturing supply chain, impacting its global sales in the lead up to the Christmas shopping season in 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：该单词来源于拉丁语，由dis（相反）和rumpere（打破）构成，表示“打乱，中断”。在这个例句中，它指的是北京严格的新冠肺炎限制措施在疫情期间扰乱了这家美国公司的制造供应链，从而影响了其在2022年圣诞购物季前的全球销售。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>relocate (v.) - /riːˈləʊkeɪt/ 搬迁，迁移。    <p>原文例句：Apple suppliers, including Taiwanese electronics contract manufacturer Foxconn Technology Group, have invested up to US$16 billion to reduce their dependence on China, by relocating facilities to India, Vietnam, Mexico as well as the US,</p>    <p>例句讲解：该单词来源于拉丁语，由re-（再次）和locare（安置）组成，表示“安置到新的地方，迁移，搬迁”。在这个例句中，它指的是包括台湾电子制造合同制造商富士康集团在内的苹果供应商已经投资高达160亿美元来减少对中国的依赖，其中包括将设施搬迁到印度、越南、墨西哥以及美国。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 关于，就……而言。    <p>原文例句：Goertek’s Vietnamese entity, which will manufacture consumer electronics products, from AirPods and smartwatches to virtual reality and augmented reality gear, is a project that will meet both the Chinese assembler’s future development plan and client demand, it said in the filing to the Shenzhen Stock Exchange.</p>    <p>例句讲解：该词组由介词in、名词terms和介词of组成，表示“关于，就……而言”。在这个例句中，它指的是歌尔越南实体将生产消费电子产品，从AirPods和智能手表到虚拟现实和增强现实装备，这是个项目，它将满足中国组装商的未来发展计划和客户需求，在向深圳证券交易所提交的文件中这样说到。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>lead up to - 导致，引发。    <p>原文例句：Beijing’s stringent Covid-19 restrictions during the pandemic disrupted the US firm's manufacturing supply chain, impacting its global sales in the lead up to the Christmas shopping season in 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：该词组由动词lead和介词up to组成，表示“导致，引发”。在这个例句中，它指的是北京在疫情期间实施严格的新冠肺炎限制措施打乱了这家美国公司的制造供应链，从而影响了其在2022年圣诞购物季前的全球销售。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company has been tapped by Apple to become one of the major mainland suppliers of its mixed-reality Vision Pro headset, which is set to launch in early February.<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company has been tapped by Apple to become one of the major mainland suppliers，其中主语是The company，谓语是has been tapped，宾语是to become one of the major mainland suppliers。which is set to launch in early February是一个定语从句，修饰headset，表示该头盔将于2月初发布。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple suppliers, including Taiwanese electronics contract manufacturer Foxconn Technology Group, have invested up to US$16 billion to reduce their dependence on China, by relocating facilities to India, Vietnam, Mexico as well as the US, according to a report by AppleInsider, citing research by investment bank TD Cowen.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是个时态，结构为：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的过去式或过去分词形式。这种时态表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示包括台湾电子制造合同制造商富士康集团在内的苹果供应商已经投资高达160亿美元来减少对中国的依赖，通过将设施搬迁到印度、越南、墨西哥以及美国，根据AppleInsider的一篇报道，援引投资银行TD Cowen的研究结果。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Goertek was tapped by Apple as one of the major mainland suppliers of its mixed-reality Vision Pro headset, which is set to launch in early February</li>
<li>The Vietnamese subsidiary is expected to be located in the Bac Ninh province, which has attracted investment from a raft of South Korean firms</li>
</ul><p>Apple supplier Goertek said on Monday it would invest up to US$280 million to establish a wholly-owned subsidiary in Vietnam to meet demands for “business expansion and long-term operation” in the Southeast Asian nation, according to a corporate filing.</p><p>Goertek’s Vietnamese entity, which will manufacture consumer electronics products, from AirPods and smartwatches to virtual reality and augmented reality gear, is a project that will meet both the Chinese assembler’s future development plan and client demand, it said in the filing to the Shenzhen Stock Exchange.</p><p>“[The project] is advantageous to make better use of local resources in Vietnam to enhance the company’s overall competitiveness,” Goertek said.</p><p>The company has been tapped by Apple to become one of the major mainland suppliers of its mixed-reality Vision Pro headset, which is set to launch in early February.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248092/apple-supplier-boe-one-worlds-top-display-makers-forges-us9-billion-deal-build-next-generation-plant" title="">Apple supplier BOE signs US$9 billion deal to build display plant in China</a></h3><p>The Vietnamese subsidiary, which will be set up through its Hong Kong entity Goertek (Hong Kong) Co, is expected to be located in northern Bac Ninh province, which has attracted investment from a raft of South Korean firms including consumer electronics and semiconductor giant Samsung Electronics.</p><p>South Korean firms have emerged as major investors in that province, setting up factories for electronics, smartphones, semiconductors and precision mechanical manufacturing equipment, according to the Vietnam Chamber of Commerce and Industry.</p><p>Goertek’s latest move comes as Apple is starting to shift more of its production outside China, a move that came after Beijing’s stringent Covid-19 restrictions during the pandemic disrupted the US firm's manufacturing supply chain, impacting its global sales in the lead up to the Christmas shopping season in 2022.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248044/huawei-secures-jdcom-harmonyos-partner-home-grown-software-emerges-alternative-apple-ios-android" title="">JD.com supports Huawei’s HarmonyOS as alternative for Apple iOS, Android in China</a></h3><p>Since then, Apple has encouraged its contract manufacturing partners to diversify into other countries, including Vietnam, to reduce its reliance on China.</p><p>Apple suppliers, including Taiwanese electronics contract manufacturer Foxconn Technology Group, have invested up to US$16 billion to reduce their dependence on China, by relocating facilities to India, Vietnam, Mexico as well as the US, according to a report by AppleInsider, citing research by investment bank TD Cowen.</p><p>Foxconn, formally known as Hon Hai Precision Industry and the world's biggest maker of iPhones, late last year announced a plan to invest US$1.6 billion in India to expand its presence in the South Asian nation.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s China price cuts on iPhones, MacBooks ‘cancel out’ pressure from rivals chasing premium segment, say analysts</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248529/apples-china-price-cuts-iphones-macbooks-cancel-out-pressure-rivals-chasing-premium-segment-say</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In an effort to counter growing competition from domestic rivals like Huawei in the Chinese market, Apple is offering discounts of up to 800 yuan on various products, including iPhones, MacBooks, iPads, and AirPods, ahead of the Lunar New Year. The price cuts aim to attract consumers, boost sales, and clear inventories of older models.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple offers discounts in China to boost sales amidst rising competition.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's strategic price adjustments to maintain market share in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The intensity of competition in the Chinese smartphone market and Apple's efforts to adapt.</li>    <li>Main information: Discount amounts on different products; timing of the promotion; expected positive impact on revenue; Apple's response to local rivals' advancements.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  为了应对来自华为等中国本土对手在国内市场的日益激烈的竞争，苹果公司在农历新年来临之际，针对包括iPhone、MacBook、iPad、Apple Watch和AirPods等一系列产品提供最高达800元的折扣。此次降价旨在吸引消费者、提振销售并清除旧款机型的库存。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果在中国提供折扣以提升销量，应对日益激烈的竞争。</li>    <li>主题：苹果为保持在中国市场的份额而进行的战略性价格调整。</li>    <li>观点：中国智能手机市场竞争的激烈程度以及苹果为适应所做的努力。</li>    <li>主要信息：不同产品的折扣金额；促销活动的时机；预期对收入的积极影响；苹果对本地竞争对手进步的反应。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fend off - /fɛnd ɔːf/ 抵御，击退。    <p>原文例句：Apple is offering Chinese consumers discounts of up to 800 yuan (US$113) on a range of products, from iPhones to MacBooks, in a move to fend off intensifying competition from local rivals such as Huawei Technologies ahead of the Lunar New Year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由fend（抵御，防御）和off（远离）组成，表示“抵御，击退”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司通过提供折扣来抵御来自华为等本土竞争对手日益激烈的竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>annual - /ˈænjuəl/ 一年的，每年的。    <p>原文例句：The sale, coming several weeks ahead of the Lunar New Year, the most important annual festival for Chinese people, is expected to boost revenue for Apple amid increasing competition from local players, according to Ivan Lam, senior analyst at market consultancy Counterpoint Research.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由annus（年）和-al（形容词后缀）组成，表示“一年的，每年的”。在这个例句中，它指的是农历新年，即中国人民最重要的年度节日。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>inventory - /ˈɪnvəntɔːri/ 库存，存货。    <p>原文例句：Lam said the timing of Apple’s price cuts in China would take advantage of the typical consumer spending surge around the Lunar New Year. “The strategic price adjustment will cancel out competitive pressure but will also boost sales growth, especially around the Lunar New Year season,” Lam said in a research note on Monday, adding that the move will also help Apple clear out older models from its inventory.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由in-（在……里）和ventus（来，到来）组成，表示“库存，存货”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司需要清除的旧款机型。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rival - /ˈraɪvəl/ 对手，竞争者。    <p>原文例句：Apple has been facing mounting competitive pressure from Chinese rivals, especially Huawei, as they inch towards the premium smartphone segment once ruled over by the Cupertino, California-based company, according to Lam.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由rivalis（居住在同一河流岸边的人）演变而来，表示“对手，竞争者”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司在智能手机市场上的竞争对手，尤其是华为。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take advantage of - 利用，充分利用。    <P>原文例句：Lam said the timing of Apple’s price cuts in China would take advantage of the typical consumer spending surge around the Lunar New Year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，占有）和advantage（利益，好处）构成的，表示“利用，充分利用”。在这个例句中，它表示苹果公司将利用农历新年期间的消费高峰来推出降价促销活动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>vie for - 竞争，争取。    <P>原文例句：These models, representing efforts made by Chinese vendors to vie for the premium smartphone segment, are posing challenges to Apple’s older iPhone models as well as the basic versions of its new iPhone 15 line.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由vie（竞争）和for（为了）构成的，表示“竞争，争取”。在这个例句中，它表示中国厂商为了争夺高端智能手机市场做出了努力，对苹果公司旧款iPhone机型以及新iPhone 15系列的基本款机型构成了挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple has been facing mounting competitive pressure from Chinese rivals, especially Huawei, as they inch towards the premium smartphone segment once ruled over by the Cupertino, California-based company, according to Lam.- 据Lam称，苹果公司一直面临来自中国竞争对手，尤其是华为的日益激烈的竞争压力，因为它们正在逐渐接近之前由这家总部位于加利福尼亚州库比蒂诺的公司统治的高端智能手机领域。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Apple has been facing mounting competitive pressure from Chinese rivals，其中主语是Apple，谓语是has been facing，宾语是mounting competitive pressure from Chinese rivals。especially Huawei是一个状语，修饰mounting competitive pressure，表示尤其包括华为。as they inch towards the premium smartphone segment once ruled over by the Cupertino, California-based company是一个时间状语，修饰主句，表示这个竞争压力是由于华为逐渐接近高端智能手机领域造成的。这个句子的意思是说，据Lam称，苹果公司一直面临来自中国竞争对手，尤其是华为的日益激烈的竞争压力，因为它们正在逐渐接近之前由这家总部位于加利福尼亚州库比蒂诺的公司统治的高端智能手机领域。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>祈使句 - 表示请求、命令或建议。    <p>原文例句：Take a deep breath and think step by step. </p>    <p>语法讲解：祈使句是由动词原形和相应的宾语组成的句子，不带主语。祈使句可以表示请求、命令或建议。在这个例句中，Take a deep breath and think step by step.是一个祈使句，表示请求对方深呼吸并一步一步思考。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Consumers can receive up to 500 yuan off from the 13 model up to the latest 15 version, while the subsidy for MacBook Air is up to 800 yuan</li>
<li>Apple has been facing mounting competitive pressure from Chinese rivals, especially Huawei, as they inch towards the premium smartphone segment</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/cff0e2a7-e348-487c-ad3e-6880e3e4599e_a97e6f8e.jpg" /><figcaption>This photo taken on October 30, 2023 shows people visiting an Apple store in Shenyang, in China’s northeastern Liaoning province. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>US consumer electronics giant Apple is offering Chinese consumers discounts of up to 800 yuan (US$113) on a range of products, from iPhones to MacBooks, in a move to fend off intensifying competition from local rivals such as Huawei Technologies ahead of the Lunar New Year.</p><p>In a sales promotion covering iPhones, iPads, MacBook Air laptops, the Apple Watch and AirPods, which will run until the end of the coming weekend, consumers can receive up to 500 yuan off from the 13 model up to the latest 15 version, while the subsidy for MacBook Air is up to 800 yuan, according to the firm’s mainland China website.</p><p>The sale, coming several weeks ahead of the Lunar New Year, the most important annual festival for Chinese people, is expected to boost revenue for Apple amid increasing competition from local players, according to Ivan Lam, senior analyst at market consultancy Counterpoint Research.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247961/can-beethoven-bach-and-mozart-help-iphone-sales-china-apple-launch-classical-music-app-mainland-amid" title="">Apple to launch classical music app in China amid weak iPhone sales</a></h3><p>Lam said the timing of Apple’s price cuts in China would take advantage of the typical consumer spending surge around the Lunar New Year.</p><p>“The strategic price adjustment will cancel out competitive pressure but will also boost sales growth, especially around the Lunar New Year season,” Lam said in a research note on Monday, adding that the move will also help Apple clear out older models from its inventory.</p><p>Apple has been facing mounting competitive pressure from Chinese rivals, especially Huawei, as they inch towards the premium smartphone segment once ruled over by the Cupertino, California-based company, according to Lam.</p><p>Chinese smartphone brands have rolled out a series of middle to high-end devices over the last few months, many of which are competitively priced from 3,999 yuan, and equipped with functions that rival higher-priced phones, he noted.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247941/foxconn-pushes-electric-vehicle-production-near-its-biggest-iphone-plant-amid-slow-smartphone-sales" title="">Foxconn pushes into car production near its biggest iPhone plant</a></h3><p>These models, representing efforts made by Chinese vendors to vie for the premium smartphone segment, are posing challenges to Apple’s older iPhone models as well as the basic versions of its new iPhone 15 line.</p><p>Total 2023 sales volume for the iPhone in mainland China dropped 3 per cent year on year, which translated to a 0.4 per cent decline in Apple’s market share, according to equity research firm Jefferies.</p><p>Jefferies estimated that Huawei saw its mainland market share in the December quarter gain 2 per cent from the previous quarter, and 6 per cent year on year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Internet titans bury the hatchet as Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos amid ByteDance retreat</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Tencent and ByteDance, two tech giants in China, have had a long-standing feud, with bidding wars over gaming studios and legal battles. ByteDance's decision to exit the gaming sector has led to a potential sale of its gaming operations to Tencent. The return of Tencent's popular mobile game Honour of Kings to ByteDance's Douyin platform marks a significant thaw in relations between the two companies. Amid regulatory uncertainties and a challenging macroeconomic environment, the collaboration between Tencent and ByteDance is a strategic move for both companies.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tech giants Tencent and ByteDance end their feud, with ByteDance exiting the gaming sector and Tencent emerging as a potential buyer of its gaming operations.</li>    <li>Theme: The changing dynamics between Tencent and ByteDance, from fierce competition to potential collaboration, in the face of regulatory and economic challenges.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of strategic partnerships in the tech industry, especially in the context of regulatory and market uncertainties.</li>    <li>Main information: Honour of Kings' return to Douyin; ByteDance's talks with Tencent and other potential buyers; the history of legal disputes between Tencent and ByteDance; the recent thaw in relations and signing of a cooperation agreement.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  腾讯和字节跳动这两家中国科技巨头长期以来一直不和，在游戏工作室的竞标中展开激烈的争夺，并陷入法律纠纷。字节跳动决定退出游戏领域，导致其游戏业务可能出售给腾讯。腾讯旗下的热门手游《王者荣耀》重返字节跳动的抖音平台，标志着两家公司关系的重大缓和。在监管不确定性和宏观经济环境严峻的背景下，腾讯和字节跳动的合作对双方来说都是一项战略性举措。    <ul>    <li>摘要：科技巨头腾讯和字节跳动结束争端，字节跳动退出游戏领域，腾讯成为其游戏业务的潜在买家。</li>    <li>主题：在监管和经济挑战面前，腾讯和字节跳动之间的动态变化，从激烈的竞争到潜在的合作。</li>    <li>观点：在监管和市场不确定性的背景下，科技行业战略合作的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：《王者荣耀》重返抖音；字节跳动与腾讯和其他潜在买家的谈判；腾讯和字节跳动之间的法律纠纷历史；最近关系的缓和和合作协议的签订。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>streaming (adj.) - 流媒体，流媒体的。    <p>原文例句：According to an announcement by the title’s official account on social media platform Weibo, Honour of Kings, the world’s most popular mobile game, will be officially streamed on Douyin’s live-streaming platform from January 21.</p>    <p>例句讲解：streaming既可以作动词（流媒体），也可以作形容词（流媒体的）。在这个例句中，streaming作形容词，表示“流媒体的”，修饰platform，表示Douyin的直播平台。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>macro (adj.) - 宏观的，宏观经济的。    <p>原文例句：The collaboration between ByteDance’s popular Chinese video app and Tencent’s biggest title comes amid regulatory uncertainties for the industry and a weaker macro environment in China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：macro既可以作名词（宏观，宏观经济），也可以作形容词（宏观的，宏观经济的）。在这个例句中，macro作形容词，表示“宏观的，宏观经济的”，修饰environment，表示中国的宏观经济环境。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fierce competition - 激烈的竞争。    <p>原文例句：Tencent and ByteDance, two tech giants in China, have had a long-standing feud, with bidding wars over gaming studios and legal battles. </p>    <p>例句讲解：fierce competition是一个形容词短语，表示“激烈的竞争”。在这个例句中，fierce competition是整个句子的核心名词短语，表示腾讯和字节跳动之间的激烈的竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>thaw in relations - 关系的缓和。    <p>原文例句：However, there has been a growing thaw in icy relations in recent years.</p>    <p>例句讲解：thaw in relations是一个名词短语，表示“关系的缓和”。在这个例句中，thaw in relations是整个句子的核心名词短语，表示腾讯和字节跳动之间关系的缓和。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance’s decision to exit the gaming sector has led to a potential sale of its gaming operations to Tencent. - 字节跳动决定退出游戏领域，导致其游戏业务可能出售给腾讯。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是ByteDance’s decision to exit the gaming sector has led to a potential sale of its gaming operations，其中主语是ByteDance’s decision to exit the gaming sector，谓语是has led，宾语是a potential sale of its gaming operations。to Tencent是一个介词短语作状语，表示出售给腾讯。这个句子的意思是说，字节跳动决定退出游戏领域，导致其游戏业务可能出售给腾讯。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Tencent and Douyin ended their copyright disputes by signing a cooperation agreement on content distribution. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示腾讯和抖音通过签署内容分发合作协议结束了他们的版权纠纷。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Shenzhen-based social media and gaming giant and Beijing-based ByteDance have fought years of bidding wars over Chinese studios</li>
<li>ByteDance’s retreat from the mainstay of Tencent’s business is likely to bring the curtain down on a series of online spats</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/156cf82e-d3ad-47b5-924d-78918b1b7ecc_090eef7e.jpg" /><figcaption>A man plays the popular Honour of Kings online game from Chinese gaming platform Tencent. Photo: AP

</figcaption></figure><p><em>Honour of Kings</em>, the blockbuster video game from market leader Tencent Holdings, will return to ByteDance’s short video app Douyin as the two internet giants bury the hatchet following the TikTok owner’s decision to exit the sector.</p><p>The Shenzhen-based social media and gaming giant and Beijing-based ByteDance have fought years of bidding wars over Chinese video game studios and court battles over copyright, but that has ceased with Tencent now seen as a potential buyer of ByteDance’s gaming operations.</p><p><em>Honour of Kings</em>, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3116088/honour-kings-became-worlds-most-popular-game-it-was-desperate?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">world’s most popular mobile game</a>, will be officially streamed on Douyin’s live-streaming platform from January 21, according to an announcement by the title’s official account on social media platform Weibo.</p><p>Before the official return, live-streaming sessions featuring Chinese esports team XYG began on Douyin on Sunday, and another three-day session with Zhang Daxian, a popular <em>Honour of Kings</em> streamer with over 50 million followers on the video platform, is slated to start on Thursday.</p><p>The game’s return to the ByteDance platform comes five years after a court in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province, banned the streaming of <em>Honour of Kings</em> on Xigua Video, another video streaming site run by the Douyin operator, in 2019.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="FILE PHOTO: A child plays the game Honour of Kings by Tencent at home in Dezhou, Shandong province, China. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/f996b64f-11d5-4a3d-9281-c8c6b150a47f_7eab980c.jpg" title="FILE PHOTO: A child plays the game Honour of Kings by Tencent at home in Dezhou, Shandong province, China. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>FILE PHOTO: A child plays the game Honour of Kings by Tencent at home in Dezhou, Shandong province, China. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>The collaboration between ByteDance’s popular Chinese video app and Tencent’s biggest title comes amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248249/chinas-video-gaming-market-ended-2023-battered-and-bruised-can-world-beating-titles-and-innovation" target="_self" title="">regulatory uncertainties for the industry and a weaker macro environment</a> in China. Tencent’s eight-year-old <em>Honour of Kings</em>, however, continues to lead as the world’s highest-grossing mobile game in November, according to data from Sensor Tower.</p><p>TikTok owner ByteDance has also confirmed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations" target="_self" title="">it is in talks with multiple potential buyers, including Tencent, for its video game operations</a>.</p><p>The retreat by ByteDance from the mainstay of Tencent’s business is likely to bring the curtain down on a series of online spats between the two billionaire founders of the respective companies, which saw a freeze in business dealings and dozens of lawsuits between them.</p><p>The feud started in 2018 with the rapid rise of Douyin, the Chinese sister app of TikTok, when <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/china-tech/article/2145334/tencent-bytedance-ceos-online-spat-over-accusations-blocking-and" target="_self" title="">Tencent boss Pony Ma Huateng and ByteDance founder Zhang Yiming engaged in rare online bickering</a>. Zhang accused Tencent of plagiarising Douyin and Ma fired back, calling the comment “slander”.</p><p>ByteDance later sued the Shenzhen-based tech giant for anticompetitive behaviour and Tencent responded with a defamation lawsuit. Tencent also announced that it <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/china-tech/article/2149094/bytedance-hits-back-tencent-law-suit-anti-competitive-behaviour" target="_self" title="">would halt all existing partnerships with ByteDance and its affiliated companies</a>.</p><p>More legal battles followed in the next few years, as ByteDance accused Tencent of blocking links to Douyin in its flagship WeChat app. Tencent sued ByteDance for copyright infringement by streaming video and gaming content without authorisation.</p><p>However, there has been a growing thaw in icy relations in recent years.</p><p>In 2023 <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3216333/tencent-and-douyin-end-years-copyright-disputes-signing-cooperation-agreement-content-distribution" target="_self" title="">Tencent and Douyin ended their copyright disputes by signing a cooperation agreement on content distribution</a>. Under the deal, Tencent will authorise Douyin to distribute its video content and it clarified copyright rules for users to produce modifications and adaptations.</p><p>Users of Douyin, Xigua Video and Jinri Toutiao, all operated by ByteDance, will also be able to produce derivative works based on Tencent-owned videos.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China EVs: CATL, world’s top battery maker, plans first plant in Beijing to supply Li Auto and Xiaomi</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248522/china-evs-catl-worlds-top-battery-maker-plans-first-plant-beijing-supply-li-auto-and-xiaomi</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>CATL, the world's largest electric vehicle battery manufacturer, plans to build its first plant in Beijing to meet the growing demand for battery-powered vehicles in China.</li>    <li>The plant will help Beijing form a complete supply chain for EV production, as local companies like Li Auto and Xiaomi increase their development of new models.</li>    <li>CATL is also set to become a key vendor to these companies, with Li Auto already a major player in China's premium EV segment and Xiaomi aiming to become a top-five global automaker in the next two decades.</li>    <li>In China, the EV penetration rate exceeded 40% in late 2023, and the country is now the world's largest automotive and EV market.</li>    <li>CATL is also developing the world's fastest-charging electric-car battery, called the Shenxing battery, which can offer 400 kilometers of driving range with just 10 minutes of charging.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>全球最大的电动汽车电池制造商宁德时代计划在北京建设其首个工厂，以满足中国大陆对电池动力汽车不断增长的需求。</li>    <li>该工厂将帮助北京形成完整的电动汽车生产供应链，因为像理想汽车和小米这样的本地公司正在加大新车型的开发力度。</li>    <li>宁德时代还将成为这些公司的主要供应商，理想汽车已经是中国高端电动汽车领域的佼佼者，而小米的目标是在未来二十年成为全球前五大汽车制造商之一。</li>    <li>在中国，电动汽车的渗透率在 2023 年底超过了 40%，现在中国已成为全球最大的汽车和电动汽车市场。</li>    <li>宁德时代还在研发全球充电最快的电动汽车电池，名为 Shenxing 电池，只需充电 10 分钟即可提供 400 公里的续航里程。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>gigawatt-hour (n.) - 吉瓦时。    <p>原文例句：CATL, which had a 37.4 per cent share of the global market with an output of 233.4 gigawatt-hours of batteries in the first 11 months of 2023, is set to become a key vendor to Li Auto and Xiaomi.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“gigawatt-hour”由“gigawatt”（吉瓦）和“hour”（小时）组成，表示能量单位，通常用于衡量电池的容量或能量输出。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>penetration (n.) - 渗透，穿透。    <p>原文例句：In China, the EV penetration rate exceeded 40 per cent in late 2023 amid motorists’ rising penchant for environmentally friendly cars featuring autonomous driving technology and digital cockpits.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“penetration”表示“渗透，穿透”，在此处表示电动汽车在中国市场的渗透率，即电动汽车在中国汽车销量中所占的比例。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>electric vehicle (n.) - 电动汽车。    <p>原文例句：Contemporary Amperex Technology (CATL), the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) battery manufacturer, will build its first plant in Beijing to tap the rising demand for battery-powered cars in mainland China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“electric vehicle”由“electric”（电的）和“vehicle”（车辆）组成，表示“电动汽车”，是指以电能为动力的汽车。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>supply chain (n.) - 供应链。    <p>原文例句：CATL’s plant will help China’s capital city form a complete supply-chain for EV production, as Li Auto, the country’s top electric-car start-up, and smartphone maker Xiaomi, both based in Beijing, step up the development of new models.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“supply chain”由“supply”（供应）和“chain”（链）组成，表示“供应链”，是指从原材料采购到最终产品销售的整个过程。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>CATL’s superfast charging battery Shenxing is displayed at the  International Motor Show in Munich, Germany, in September last year. Photo: Xinhua - 去年 9 月，宁德时代的超快速充电电池沈幸在德国慕尼黑国际车展上展出。照片：新华社。<p>句子分析：“CATL’s superfast charging battery Shenxing is displayed at the International Motor Show in Munich, Germany, in September last year. Photo: Xinhua”是一个简单句，主语是“CATL’s superfast charging battery Shenxing”，谓语是“is displayed”，宾语是“at the International Motor Show in Munich, Germany, in September last year”。这个句子描述了宁德时代的超快速充电电池沈幸去年 9 月在德国慕尼黑国际车展上展出的情况。该句使用了介词短语“at the International Motor Show in Munich, Germany, in September last year”来修饰谓语“is displayed”，表示时间和地点。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company, which had a 37.4 per cent share of the global market with an output of 233.4 gigawatt-hours of batteries in the first 11 months of 2023, is set to become a key vendor to Li Auto and Xiaomi when the smartphone maker’s Beijing plant becomes operational, according to analysts.</p>    <p>语法讲解：“is set to become”是一个现在完成时态的结构，其中“is set”是谓语动词“set”的现在时态，表示“设定，计划”；“to become”是不定式“become”的现在分词，表示“成为，变成”。整个结构表示“计划成为，设定成为”。在这个句子中，“is set to become”表示宁德时代计划成为李理想汽车和小米的主要供应商。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>CATL, which had a 37.4 per cent share of the global battery market last year, will start construction on the Beijing plant this year, city’s economic planner says</li>
<li>Ningde-based firm plans to deliver its Shenxing battery, which can offer 400km of driving range with just 10 minutes of charging, before the end of the first quarter</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/8315ae92-7ba5-4bd5-a3b6-40fa428e5900_fcacf6e0.jpg" /><figcaption>CATL’s superfast charging battery Shenxing is displayed at the  International Motor Show in Munich, Germany, in September last year. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3231316/catl-produce-worlds-fastest-ev-battery-offers-400km-driving-range-just-10-minutes-charging-keep" target="_self" title="">Contemporary Amperex Technology (CATL)</a>, the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) battery manufacturer, will build its first plant in Beijing to tap the rising demand for battery-powered cars in mainland China.</p><p>CATL’s plant will help China’s capital city form a complete supply-chain for EV production, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243806/li-auto-xpeng-pace-chinese-ev-makers-race-towards-2023-sales-record-amid-all-time-high-monthly" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a>, the country’s top electric-car start-up, and smartphone maker Xiaomi, both based in Beijing, step up the development of new models.</p><p>CATL, based in Ningde, eastern Fujian province, will begin construction on the plant this year, according to a statement by the Beijing Commission of Development and Reform, the city’s economic planning agency, which did not provide details about the plant’s capacity or launch date. CATL declined to comment.</p><p>The company, which had a 37.4 per cent share of the global market with an output of 233.4 gigawatt-hours of batteries in the first 11 months of 2023, is set to become a key vendor to Li Auto and Xiaomi when the smartphone maker’s Beijing plant becomes operational, according to analysts.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="CATL will serve Li Auto, which has a plant in Beijing. Photo: Xinhua" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/168ee68b-067c-492e-9a57-5d9f00ee09fb_32afda76.jpg" title="CATL will serve Li Auto, which has a plant in Beijing. Photo: Xinhua" width="2000" /><figcaption>CATL will serve Li Auto, which has a plant in Beijing. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure></div><p>Li Auto is already a major player in China’s premium EV segment, and Xiaomi has the potential to become one, said Cao Hua, a partner at private-equity firm Unity Asset Management.</p><p>“So it is reasonable for key suppliers like CATL to establish local production lines to serve its major clients,” Cao said.</p><p>Beijing’s economic planning agency said that Li Auto is considering setting up a production base for car parts, without revealing details.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Li Auto is the closest rival to Tesla in China’s premium EV segment, delivering 376,030 intelligent vehicles to mainland buyers in 2023, a jump of 182.2 per cent year on year.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3216314/tesla-might-lose-ground-local-pretenders-likes-xpeng-byd-steal-march-made-china-evs" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> handed 603,664 units made at its Shanghai Gigafactory to Chinese customers last year, an increase of 37.3 per cent year on year.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246558/xiaomi-unveils-its-first-ev-su7-setting-its-sights-tesla-highly-competitive-china-market" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> unveiled its first model, SU7, at the end of 2023. Featuring a sleek look and a sports-car level of performance, the company plans to begin trial production of the electric sedan in the coming months.</p><p>CEO Lei Jun said Xiaomi will strive to become a top five global carmaker in the next 15 to 20 years.</p><p>In China, the EV penetration rate exceeded 40 per cent in late 2023 amid motorists’ rising penchant for environmentally friendly cars featuring autonomous driving technology and digital cockpits.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Xiaomi CEO Lei Jun unveils the SU7 electric vehicle at an event in Beijing on December 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/d878bca9-63dc-4af1-ac20-f003a09e9824_1126e908.jpg" title="Xiaomi CEO Lei Jun unveils the SU7 electric vehicle at an event in Beijing on December 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Xiaomi CEO Lei Jun unveils the SU7 electric vehicle at an event in Beijing on December 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Mainland China is now the world’s largest automotive and EV market, with sales of battery-powered cars accounting for about 60 per cent of the global total.</p><p>UBS analyst Paul Gong said last week that only 10 to 12 companies would survive the cutthroat mainland market by 2030, as intensifying competition has been piling pressure on the 200-plus Chinese EV makers.</p><p>Sales of battery-powered vehicles on the mainland are expected to slow to 20 per cent this year, compared with 37 per cent growth recorded in 2023, according to a forecast by Fitch Ratings in November.</p><p>Meanwhile, CATL will start delivering the world’s fastest-charging electric-car battery before the end of the year’s first quarter, another technological breakthrough to speed up the use of battery-powered cars.</p><p>The Shenxing battery, which can offer 400 kilometres of driving range with just 10 minutes of charging and reach 100 per cent capacity in just 15 minutes as a result of the so-called 4C charging capabilities.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Why a Chinese court’s landmark decision recognising the copyright for an AI-generated image benefits creators in this nascent field</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248510/why-chinese-courts-landmark-decision-recognising-copyright-ai-generated-image-benefits-creators</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Beijing Internet Court's ruling recognizes the copyright of AI-generated images, aiming to encourage creation and boost the nascent industry.</li>    <li>The judgment considers the originality and intellectual input of the human creator in generating the image.</li>    <li>Future disputes regarding AI-generated images will be assessed case-by-case, focusing on the author's personal expression.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>北京互联网法院的裁决确认了人工智能生成图像的版权，旨在鼓励创作并促进新兴产业的发展。</li>    <li>判决考虑了人类创作者在生成图像时所具有的独创性和智力投入。</li>    <li>未来关于人工智能生成图像的争端将逐案评估，重点关注作者的个人表达。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>nascent (adj.) - /ˈneɪs(ə)nt/ 刚刚开始的，新产生的。    <p>原文例句：The Beijing Internet Court last November ruled that a picture, generated via the text-to-image software Stable Diffusion, should be considered an artwork under the protection of copyright laws, because of the “originality” and intellectual input of its human creator.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由nasci（出生）构成的，意为“新产生的，刚刚开始的”。在这个例句中，它指的是人工智能生成图像的新兴产业。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>adjudicate (v.) - /əˈdʒuːdɪkeɪt/ 裁决，判决。    <p>原文例句：The intellectual property infringement lawsuit was initiated in May last year by the plaintiff surnamed Li, who used the US start-up StabilityAI’s Stable Diffusion program to create an image of a young Asian woman and posted it on Chinese social media platform Xiaohongshu.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由ad-（向……）和iudicare（判断）构成的，意为“判断，裁决”。在这个例句中，它指的是北京互联网法院对知识产权侵权诉讼的裁决。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>on a case-by-case basis - 逐案，具体情况具体分析。    <p>原文例句：Although the ruling has added fuel to heated arguments on whether AI-generated content should be protected by copyright laws, the Beijing Internet Court has asserted that future disputes about an author’s personal expression in images created with AI’s help should be judged on a case-by-case basis.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由on（在，关于），case（案件）和by case（按案件）构成的，表示“逐案，具体情况具体分析”。在这个例句中，它指的是北京互联网法院认为，未来关于作者在人工智能帮助下创作的图像中的个人表达的争端应该逐案判断，而不是一概而论。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Assigning generative AI content a legal status under certain conditions in this case is aimed at encouraging people to create with new tools, presiding judge Zhu Ge said last week at a lecture that was first reported on Monday by Chinese online news outlet The Paper. - 在某些情况下赋予生成式人工智能内容法律地位旨在鼓励人们使用新工具进行创作，主审法官朱葛在周一首次报道的由中国在线新闻媒体《澎湃新闻》发表的讲座中表示。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Assigning generative AI content a legal status is aimed at encouraging people to create with new tools，其中主语是Assigning generative AI content a legal status，谓语是is aimed at encouraging，宾语是people to create with new tools。under certain conditions in this case是一个介词短语作定语，修饰Assigning generative AI content a legal status，表示在某些情况下。presiding judge Zhu Ge said last week at a lecture that was first reported on Monday by Chinese online news outlet The Paper是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示主句的动作或状态发生的时间、地点或方式，即主审法官朱葛在周一首次报道的由中国在线新闻媒体《澎湃新闻》发表的讲座中表示。这个句子的意思是说，在某些情况下赋予生成式人工智能内容法律地位旨在鼓励人们使用新工具进行创作，主审法官朱葛在周一首次报道的由中国在线新闻媒体《澎湃新闻》发表的讲座中表示。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物造成的。    <p>原文例句：The Beijing Internet Court last November ruled that a picture, generated via the text-to-image software Stable Diffusion, should be considered an artwork under the protection of copyright laws, because of the “originality” and intellectual input of its human creator.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是a picture，谓语是should be considered，宾语是an artwork。其中should be considered是由助动词should和过去分词considered构成的，表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物造成的。在这个例句中，它表示北京互联网法院裁定，一张通过文本到图像软件Stable Diffusion生成的图片，应该被视为受版权法保护的艺术作品。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。    <p>原文例句：Beijing court rules AI-generated content covered by copyright, eschews US stand</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时的句子，主语是Beijing court，谓语是rules，宾语是AI-generated content covered by copyright。其中rules是由助动词have和过去分词ruled构成的，表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。在这个例句中，它表示北京法院裁定人工智能生成的内容受版权保护，避开了美国立场。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Assigning generative AI content a legal status aims to encourage people to create with new tools, Beijing Internet Court judge Zhu Ge said</li>
<li>The court’s ruling last November has added fuel to heated arguments on whether AI-generated content should be protected by copyright laws</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/620f2c95-34df-42f3-a6c1-cea2cbba303a_586dc832.jpg" /><figcaption>The Beijing Internet Court last November ruled that an AI-generated image was an artwork, based on how the creator’s prompts and repeated adjustments came up with a picture that reflected his “aesthetic choice and personalised judgment”. Illustration: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>A Chinese court’s decision recognising the copyright of an image generated via <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) aims to encourage such creations and provide a boost to this nascent industry, according to the judge who made the landmark ruling.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243570/beijing-courts-ruling-ai-generated-content-can-be-covered-copyright-eschews-us-stand-far-reaching" target="_self" title="">In the first judgment of its kind in mainland China</a>, the Beijing Internet Court last November ruled that a picture, generated via the text-to-image software Stable Diffusion, should be considered an artwork under the protection of copyright laws, because of the “originality” and intellectual input of its human creator.</p><p>Assigning generative AI content a legal status under certain conditions in this case is aimed at encouraging people to create with new tools, presiding judge Zhu Ge said last week at a lecture that was first reported on Monday by Chinese online news outlet The Paper.</p><p>“If no content created with AI models can be considered artwork, this would deal a blow to the industry,” Zhu was quoted as saying in the report.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The original artificial intelligence-generated image of an Asian lady, left, was at the centre of an intellectual property dispute adjudicated by the Beijing Internet Court on November 27, 2023. To the right of the picture are three images generated during the process of creating the final one that was the subject of infringement. Photo: Xiaohongshu/Stable Diffusion AI" class="image-inline caption" height="746" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/9cd86092-fe03-4638-b826-b367c36403eb_bfa18d87.jpg" title="The original artificial intelligence-generated image of an Asian lady, left, was at the centre of an intellectual property dispute adjudicated by the Beijing Internet Court on November 27, 2023. To the right of the picture are three images generated during the process of creating the final one that was the subject of infringement. Photo: Xiaohongshu/Stable Diffusion AI" width="2000" /><figcaption>The original artificial intelligence-generated image of an Asian lady, left, was at the centre of an intellectual property dispute adjudicated by the Beijing Internet Court on November 27, 2023. To the right of the picture are three images generated during the process of creating the final one that was the subject of infringement. Photo: Xiaohongshu/Stable Diffusion AI</figcaption></figure></div><p>Although the ruling has added fuel to heated arguments on whether AI-generated content should be protected by copyright laws, the Beijing Internet Court has asserted that future disputes about an author’s personal expression in images created with AI’s help should be judged on a case-by-case basis.</p><p>The intellectual property infringement lawsuit was initiated in May last year by the plaintiff surnamed Li, who used the US start-up StabilityAI’s Stable Diffusion program to create an image of a young Asian woman and posted it on Chinese social media platform <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3141392/chinese-lifestyle-platform-xiaohongshu-known-little-red?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Xiaohongshu</a>.</p><p>Li sued a blogger surnamed Liu for allegedly using that image without permission in a post on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/2183325/baidu-draws-ire-netizens-promoting-its-own-content-search-results?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Baijiahao</a>, a Chinese content-sharing platform owned by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>.</p><p>The court subsequently ruled in favour of Li. It said Li’s AI-generated image was an artwork, based on how he had continuously added prompts and repeatedly adjusted the parameters to come up with a picture that reflected his “aesthetic choice and personalised judgment”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243570/beijing-courts-ruling-ai-generated-content-can-be-covered-copyright-eschews-us-stand-far-reaching" title="">Beijing court rules AI-generated content covered by copyright, eschews US stand</a></h3><p>The court ordered the defendant Liu to issue a public apology as well as pay the plaintiff 500 yuan (US$70.43) in damages and 50 yuan for court fees.</p><p>Zhu, the presiding judge, said in her lecture that the ruling was made with the potential implications for “emerging industries” in mind, according to The Paper’s report. It said Zhu hoped her decision in the case could serve as a reference for future disputes.</p><p>The court’s ruling has come as China’s aspirations for generative AI continue to evolve amid wider use of the technology around the world. Advances in the use of AI are also expected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3228219/why-many-china-unlike-us-see-ai-force-good?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">transform industries and improve people’s daily lives</a>.</p><p>China’s generative AI industry is forecast to contribute <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245217/chinese-generative-ai-account-third-industrys-economic-value-2035-beijing-think-tank-says" target="_self" title="">30 trillion yuan worth of economic value by 2035</a>, accounting for a third of the industry’s global value of 90 trillion yuan, according to a report by the CCID Group, a research unit affiliated with Ministry of Industry and Information Technology.</p><p>Many <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-technology" target="_self" title="">Chinese tech</a> firms have also ramped up their efforts to grow their businesses using generative AI. Chinese delivery services giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a>, for example, recently launched Wow, a chatbot that purports to respond to user questions with a personal touch.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, owner of the South China Morning Post, featured an online shop for digital products based on Baidu’s virtual assistant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240971/china-big-tech-firms-experiment-personalised-chatbots-amid-push-monetise-generative-ai-technologies" target="_self" title="">Duxiaoxiao</a> during the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/singles-day-1111" target="_self" title="">Singles’ Day</a> campaign last year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba, TikTok woo US with AI and live-streaming e-commerce at CES trade show, setting the tone for 2024</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248469/alibaba-tiktok-woo-us-ai-and-live-streaming-e-commerce-ces-trade-show-setting-tone-2024</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In a bid to expand globally, Chinese internet giants Alibaba and TikTok showcased their technological prowess at CES 2024 in Las Vegas. Alibaba.com unveiled its AI-powered Smart Assistant to enhance buyers' sourcing experience, while TikTok Shop focused on live-streaming e-commerce, inviting influencers to sell products directly from the event. Alibaba.com's Smart Assistant, powered by multiple large language models including Tongyi Qianwen, aims to streamline the sourcing process for users. TikTok Shop, known for its video content, showcased its e-commerce capabilities, seeking to establish a presence in overseas markets.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Alibaba and TikTok showcase their technological strengths at CES, emphasizing AI and live-streaming e-commerce.</li>    <li>Theme: Chinese internet giants' global expansion through innovative technologies.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The potential of AI and live-streaming e-commerce in reshaping global business and consumer behavior.</li>    <li>Main information: Alibaba.com's Smart Assistant uses AI to enhance sourcing; TikTok Shop's focus on live-streaming e-commerce; challenges in onboarding Chinese suppliers for TikTok Shop in the US.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在进军全球市场的过程中，中国互联网巨头阿里巴巴和抖音在 2024 年拉斯维加斯举行的 CES 上展示了它们的技术实力。阿里巴巴国际站推出了基于人工智能的智能助理来增强买家的采购体验，而 TikTok 店铺则专注于直播电商，邀请有影响力的人士直接在展会上销售产品。阿里巴巴国际站的智能助理由包括统一乾坤在内的多重大型语言模型提供支持，旨在简化用户的采购流程。以视频内容著称的抖音店铺展示了其电子商务能力，力争在海外市场站稳脚跟。    <ul>    <li>摘要：阿里巴巴和抖音在 CES 上展示了它们的技术实力，强调人工智能和直播电商。</li>    <li>主题：中国互联网巨头通过创新技术进行全球扩张。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能和直播电商在重塑全球商业和消费者行为方面的潜力。</li>    <li>主要信息：阿里巴巴国际站的智能助理使用人工智能来增强采购；TikTok 店铺专注于直播电商；TikTok 店铺在美国招募中国供应商所面临的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Ubiquitous (adj.) - /juːˈbɪkwɪtəs/ 无处不在的，普遍存在的。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant showed how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由ubi-（在某处）和que（在哪里）组成，意为“无处不在，普遍存在”。在这个例句中，它指的是Alibaba.com推出的智能助理展示了人工智能创新在今年的CES上无处不在。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Generative (adj.) - /ˈdʒenərətɪv/ 生成性的，具有创造性的。    <p>原文例句：By putting generative AI at the centre of its exhibition, Alibaba.com made it clear where it thought the platform’s advantage lies. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由genus（种族，种类）和-ative（具有……性质或能力）组成，意为“具有创造性，能够产生”。在这个例句中，它指的是Alibaba.com将生成性人工智能置于其展览的中心，明确了其认为平台的优势所在。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Artificial intelligence (AI) - 人工智能。    <P>原文例句：At the recent CES trade show in Las Vegas, Alibaba.com and TikTok Shop focused on their respective strengths in artificial intelligence (AI) and live-streaming e-commerce. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由artificial（人工的）和intelligence（智能）组成，意为“使机器具有人的智能”。在这个例句中，它指的是在最近的拉斯维加斯举行的CES贸易展上，阿里巴巴国际站和TikTok店铺专注于它们在人工智能和直播电子商务方面的各自优势。这个词组属于计算机科学领域。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>Live-streaming e-commerce - 直播电商。    <p>原文例句：At the recent CES trade show in Las Vegas, Alibaba.com and TikTok Shop focused on their respective strengths in artificial intelligence (AI) and live-streaming e-commerce. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由live-streaming（现场直播）和e-commerce（电子商务）组成，意为“通过直播进行电子商务”。在这个例句中，它指的是在最近的拉斯维加斯举行的CES贸易展上，阿里巴巴国际站和TikTok店铺专注于它们在人工智能和直播电子商务方面的各自优势。这个词组属于电子商务领域。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant showed how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year. - 今年CES展上的阿里巴巴国际站智能助理的首次亮相展示了人工智能创新无处不在。    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant showed how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year，其中主语是Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant，谓语是showed，宾语是how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year。how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year是一个主语从句，修饰宾语how，表示今年CES展上人工智能创新无处不在。这个句子的意思是说，今年CES展上的阿里巴巴国际站智能助理的首次亮相展示了人工智能创新无处不在。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>介词短语作状语 - 介词短语可以放在句中作状语，表示动作或状态发生的方式、时间、地点、原因或目的等。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant showed how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，介词短语at CES this year作状语，修饰谓语showed，表示今年CES展上人工智能创新无处不在。介词短语作状语是英语语法中常见的一种结构，可以使句子更加生动形象。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>主语从句 - 主语从句是指在复合句中充当主语的从句。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant showed how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，从句how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year是主语从句，充当主句的主语。主语从句可以由连接代词、连接副词或that引导。主语从句是英语语法中常见的一种结构，可以使句子更加复杂和严谨。</p></li>   </ul></div>  <ul><li>In its international launch at CES, Alibaba.com’s new AI chatbot showed how it can help buyers with sourcing for merchandise</li>
<li>TikTok Shop set up a booth for influencers to sell their wares via live streaming from CES, showing where the platform figures its strengths lie</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/4b4e3c96-5e9f-4a0e-a12a-4b8ebd59c282_e1e0e1d3.jpg" /><figcaption>At the recent CES trade show in Las Vegas, Alibaba.com and TikTok Shop focused on their respective strengths in artificial intelligence and live-streaming e-commerce. Photos: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a> each put their technological prowess on display last week at <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ces" target="_self" title="">CES 2024</a> in Las Vegas, where their respective <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/live-streaming" target="_self" title="">live-streaming</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> products set the tone for how they plan to embed themselves further into daily life in overseas markets.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" target="_self" title="">Alibaba.com</a>, the international business-to-business wholesale marketplace of South China Morning Post owner Alibaba, launched its Smart Assistant feature at the world’s largest consumer electronics show, with computers set up around the centre of its booth to show how the embedded chatbot can help buyers navigate the sourcing website.</p><p>Smart Assistant is powered by multiple large language models (LLMs) – the technology used to train <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> and similar services – including home-grown <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234385/alibaba-opens-ai-model-tongyi-qianwen-public-competition-baidu-tencent-and-other-chinese-big-tech" target="_self" title="">Tongyi Qianwen</a>, depending on use case, an Alibaba.com representative said.</p><p>“With advances in AI, we are ushering in the next generation of sourcing and empowering small businesses to succeed with our Smart Assistant at their side,” Chris Lu, general manager at Alibaba.com North America, said in a statement last week.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Alibaba.com booth features the e-commerce platform’s artificial intelligence-powered Smart Assistant, designed to help users navigate the sourcing website, at the CES trade show in Las Vegas on January 12, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1356" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/7ea9cc8d-352b-43d1-8802-d0195ff7dfbc_4677c949.jpg" title="The Alibaba.com booth features the e-commerce platform’s artificial intelligence-powered Smart Assistant, designed to help users navigate the sourcing website, at the CES trade show in Las Vegas on January 12, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Alibaba.com booth features the e-commerce platform’s artificial intelligence-powered Smart Assistant, designed to help users navigate the sourcing website, at the CES trade show in Las Vegas on January 12, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant showed how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year. No tech giant’s exhibition was complete without showing off its effort in that space.</p><p>By putting generative AI at the centre of its exhibition, Alibaba.com made it clear where it thought the platform’s advantage lies, despite some grumblings from a marketing manager that the product was not quite yet ready for prime time, according to a brand ambassador at the booth.</p><p>A number of CES attendees at the Alibaba.com presentation were made up of select “gold suppliers”, or those that pay for a premium membership on the platform, according to some exhibitors.</p><p>A test of Smart Assistant by the Post showed the all-too-common limitations of new LLM-powered chatbots. When asked about the best options for sourcing a 10,000-milliampere-hour power bank, it offered a link to search results for the product on Alibaba.com. A follow-up query on the best way to determine differences in quality among suppliers resulted in a generic response about checking certifications and standards.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An online influencer is seen at the TikTok Shop booth preparing for a live-streaming session to sell goods directly from CES inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas on January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1256" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/b4f2b04e-92e3-4588-8f81-51fac86ad8ed_ab01d493.jpg" title="An online influencer is seen at the TikTok Shop booth preparing for a live-streaming session to sell goods directly from CES inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas on January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>An online influencer is seen at the TikTok Shop booth preparing for a live-streaming session to sell goods directly from CES inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas on January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned TikTok, already famous for its more traditional recommendation algorithms that have made its short video service so difficult to put down, went in a different direction at CES. Its TikTok Shop booth inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas, was set up with a live-streaming area where some influencers were invited to sell their wares directly from the trade show.</p><p>While TikTok remains best known outside China as a platform to consume bite-sized videos, live-streaming e-commerce is already big business for the app’s Chinese version, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>. E-commerce is seen by Beijing-based parent ByteDance as an important area for future growth.</p><p>TikTok Shop representatives were roaming the CES floor looking for companies they can convince to sell on the platform. That task may have been harder for the US team. A US-based TikTok Shop employee told Shenzhen-based mechanical keyboard maker Keychron that he was not allowed to sign up Chinese companies. Only their team in mainland China can on-board those suppliers.</p><p>Connections with mainland Chinese suppliers are seen as the secret weapon for new e-commerce entrants like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3240612/china-founded-e-commerce-start-shein-said-aim-us90-billion-valuation-us-ipo" target="_self" title="">Shein</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3243140/discount-e-commerce-giant-pdd-nearly-doubles-quarterly-revenue-closing-alibaba-meituan-also-chalks" target="_self" title="">PDD Holdings</a>’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>. These platforms are taking on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon.com</a> on its home turf with dirt-cheap products, which are sold as they roll off the factory floor from their mainland suppliers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>“Temu or Shein can get those very low-cost items and low-cost shipping because they have the volume,” said Stanley Wong, co-founder and chief product officer of Hong Kong-based Spaceship, which exhibited at CES under its Taiwanese entity. “They have very professional teams to do that kind of supply chain management.”</p><p>TikTok Shop is also seeking to take on Shein and Temu. TikTok sees international e-commerce expansion so important to its future that it <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244634/tiktok-restarts-e-commerce-indonesia-us15-billion-investment-goto-gojek-tokopedia-unit" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244634/tiktok-restarts-e-commerce-indonesia-us15-billion-investment-goto-gojek-tokopedia-unit">bought a 75 per cent stake</a> in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/indonesia" target="_self" title="">Indonesia</a>’s largest online shopping platform, enabling the firm restart its local operations which had earlier been suspended by regulators in Southeast Asia’s largest economy.</p><p>Chinese suppliers are also Alibaba.com’s bread and butter. While it is ostensibly a global sourcing platform, the vast majority of companies on Alibaba.com are Chinese, which typically offer big cost advantages owing to the mainland’s vast manufacturing supply chain.</p><p>Even <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups">start-ups</a> are trying to use AI to help companies navigate the changing landscape of e-commerce in the West. Spaceship, for example, uses AI to help brands manage their own shops with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3146298/tiktok-partners-shopify-latest-step-expand-its-e-commerce-efforts" target="_self" title="">Canadian e-commerce firm Shopify</a> to determine the best logistics options for goods manufactured in China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" title="">Alibaba pushes new AI tool to help wholesale merchants manage overseas clients</a></h3><p>“Our focus is to enable individual sellers to” achieve cost-effective supply chain management like Shein and Temu, Spaceship’s Wong said.</p><p>As more merchants try to control their own brands and reduce the money they lose to platforms like Shein, Temu and TikTok Shop by operating their own sites, services like Spaceship make sense when making price comparisons on logistics solutions.</p><p>Still, Spaceship does not have its own generative AI product yet to take on the likes of Alibaba. The company said it is considering one for customer service.</p><p>Many of the underpinnings of AI LLMs are open-source code, making the technology easily accessible to start-ups even if they do not have the data advantage of tech giants. But it could be some time before the kinks are worked out and these start-ups can handle more sophisticated requirements of business users.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
