<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>TikTok eyes US$17.5 billion shopping business on Amazon’s turf</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247219/tiktok-eyes-us175-billion-shopping-business-amazons-turf</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  字节跳动旗下的TikTok设定了今年在美国电子商务销售额达到175亿美元的目标，这将对亚马逊、同样是中国的Temu和Shein构成更大的威胁。TikTok通过社交媒体影响力和病毒式视频吸引买家，希望消费者将其用作亚马逊或Sea的Shopee的替代品。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: TikTok aims to grow its US e-commerce business tenfold to US$17.5 billion this year.</li>    <li>Theme: TikTok's ambitious target sets up a clash with Amazon, Temu, and Shein.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: TikTok's e-commerce model, which combines entertainment and impulse buying, has the potential to disrupt the US e-commerce market.</li>    <li>Main information: TikTok's merchandise volume goal for the US; TikTok's plans to expand its e-commerce operations in the US and Latin America; TikTok's efforts to attract sellers and buyers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  字节跳动旗下的TikTok今年将美国电商业务的规模扩大十倍，达到175亿美元，这将对亚马逊以及同样是中国的Temu和Shein构成更大的威胁。TikTok通过社交媒体影响力和病毒式视频吸引买家，希望消费者将其用作亚马逊或Sea的Shopee的替代品。  <ul>    <li>摘要：TikTok的野心勃勃的目标不仅与亚马逊，同时也与同属中国的Temu和Shein展开竞争。</li>    <li>主题：字节跳动旗下的TikTok今年将美国电商业务的规模扩大十倍，达到175亿美元，这将对亚马逊以及同样是中国的Temu和Shein构成更大的威胁。</li>    <li>观点：TikTok的电商模式融合了娱乐性和冲动消费的特性，有潜力颠覆美国电商市场格局。</li>    <li>主要信息：TikTok在美国的商品销售目标；TikTok计划在美国和拉丁美洲扩张其电商业务；TikTok吸引卖家和买家的策略。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>e-commerce (n.) - /ˌiːˈkɑːmərs/ 电子商务，电子商务。    <p>原文例句：TikTok aims to grow the size of its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, according to people familiar with the matter. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自electronic（电子）和commerce（商业），表示“通过互联网进行的商业活动”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok计划将美国电子商务业务的规模扩大十倍，达到175亿美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>meld (v.) - /meld/ 融合，结合。    <p>原文例句：The 2024 merchandise volume goal for the US version of TikTok Shop – which melds online entertainment with impulse buying – was discussed in internal meetings in recent weeks. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自古英语meldan（混合），表示“融合，结合”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok Shop美国版的2024年商品销售目标，该目标将在线娱乐与冲动消费结合在一起。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams, hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示TikTok Shop允许用户在滚动浏览一系列短视频和直播的同时购买物品，希望消费者将其用作亚马逊或Sea的Shopee的替代品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy - 京东、阿里巴巴的淘宝推出“仅退款”的政策，以对抗拼多多的策略。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push “refund only” policy，其中主语是JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao，谓语是push，宾语是“refund only” policy。to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示京东、阿里巴巴的淘宝推出“仅退款”的政策是为了对抗拼多多的策略。这个句子的意思是说，京东、阿里巴巴的淘宝推出“仅退款”的政策，以对抗拼多多的策略。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein</li>
<li>TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/3ac609af-b5fc-4ab5-9ad7-730748d44354_0648d552.jpg" /><figcaption>The TikTok logo is seen in this illustration photo taken August 22, 2022. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>ByteDance’s TikTok aims to grow the size of its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, according to people familiar with the matter, posing a bigger threat to Amazon.com.</p><p>The 2024 merchandise volume goal for the US version of TikTok Shop – which melds online entertainment with impulse buying – was discussed in internal meetings in recent weeks and may still change depending on how the business goes, said the people, who asked not to be named discussing private information.</p><p>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein, who have been making big strides among younger American shoppers. Unlike its two rival discounters, TikTok is counting on its social media reach and the appeal of viral videos to hook buyers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales through its platform, Bloomberg News reported. Now, the company is seeking to expand sales in the US and Latin America, where it is planning to launch the e-commerce operation in coming months, two people familiar with the matter said.</p><p>“The speculated US merchandise sales figures represented by Bloomberg are inaccurate,” TikTok said in a statement.</p><p>ByteDance, founded more than a decade ago by Zhang Yiming and Liang Rubo, grew into an internet leader worth more than US$200 billion thanks to the virality of short-video platforms TikTok and Douyin. TikTok Shop is one of the fastest-growing features for the Beijing-based, closely held company, which is seeking a new growth driver beyond social-media advertising. ByteDance’s revenue surged roughly 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing the projected growth of far more established social media rivals Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings.</p><p>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams within its main social media app, hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee. That format – an effort to combine the ease of shopping on Amazon with the product discovery afforded by apps like Meta’s Instagram – has already helped Douyin snatch a significant portion of Chinese consumer spending from Alibaba Group Holding and JD.com, particularly after lockdown rules during the pandemic drove people to spend more time online. (Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post).</p><p>ByteDance is intent on exporting its e-commerce model globally. In the US, TikTok is offering free shipping and subsidies to influencers who peddle gadgets, clothes and make-up in videos and live streams. In November, boosted by Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals, more than 5 million new US customers bought something on TikTok, the company said. It has roughly 150 million users in the country.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/80b40a96-5660-44d3-a756-f6c48d3cb312_1126e908.jpg" title="TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>TikTok on Wednesday announced it will increase fees imposed on merchants to 6 per cent of each sale beginning in April and to 8 per cent in July in most product categories, marking an end to promotions used to entice sellers. Those commissions are still significantly lower than Amazon seller fees, which are typically about 15 per cent, but the boost signals TikTok is quickly moving to generate revenue from its e-commerce platform.</p><p>Americans are increasingly comfortable shopping on Chinese e-commerce apps, including the popular fashion site Shein and PDD Holding’s Temu, which has exploded in popularity since airing a Super Bowl ad in February.</p><p>It is unclear what sales targets TikTok Shop has set globally or for other markets. In Indonesia, TikTok has taken control of GoTo Group’s e-commerce unit Tokopedia in a US$1.5 billion deal, which allowed the company to restart its online retail service after months of scrutiny by the local government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247211/apple-leads-us383-billion-tech-rout-reversal-groups-2023-rally</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  2023年，七大科技巨头股价飙升，其中包括苹果、亚马逊、Alphabet、微软、Meta Platforms、特斯拉和英伟达，但2024年伊始，其股价表现并不理想。受美联储加息政策影响，投资者担忧经济衰退，科技股表现承压。尽管特斯拉第四季度电动车交付量超出市场预期，但其仍被中国比亚迪赶超，失去电动车销量冠军宝座。分析师认为，科技股短期的回调是正常现象，但仍需关注各公司能否持续提供优质的产品和服务。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tech stocks surge in 2023, retrace in 2024.</li>    <li>Theme: Tech giants' rally cooled in early 2024 amid concerns over economic slowdown and rising interest rates.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Fed's monetary policy weighs on tech stocks; investors focus on companies' ability to deliver profitable technology.</li>    <li>Main information: Seven top tech stocks' losing streak; Apple's market value decline; analysts' downgrade of Apple and Tesla; Tesla's loss of top EV seller position to BYD.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023年，“科技七巨头”股价飙升，上涨幅度超过100%，这主要是由于人工智能的狂热。然而，2023年下半年，随着投资者开始考虑美联储能否实现经济软着陆，以及由此可能减少利率下调幅度，这种涨势有所降温。今年年初，“科技七巨头”股价连续四个交易日下跌，创下一个月以来最长的连跌纪录。其中，苹果公司股价下跌4.6%，市值缩水3830亿美元，领跌大盘。纳斯达克100指数也在过去四个交易日下跌。Interactive Brokers Group首席策略师史蒂夫·索斯尼克表示：“我们不知道去年的大涨是否已经完全结束，但在经历了我们所看到的这种反弹之后，市场出现回调是完全正常的。”“没有了为反弹注入动力的年末因素，我认为我们正在看到这场派对逐渐落幕。”  <ul>    <li>摘要：科技股2023年飙升，2024年回调。</li>    <li>主题：2024年初，科技巨头的涨势因经济放缓和利率上升的担忧而降温。</li>    <li>观点：美联储的货币政策给科技股带来压力；投资者关注各公司能否提供有利可图的技术。</li>    <li>主要信息：“科技七巨头”股价连续下跌；苹果公司市值下跌；分析师下调苹果和特斯拉股票评级；特斯拉失去电动汽车销量冠军的位置，被比亚迪赶超。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>frenzy (n.) - /ˈfrɛnzi/ 疯狂，狂热。    <p>原文例句：The Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语，意为“疯狂，狂热”。在这个例句中，它指的是人工智能领域的狂热，这是导致“科技七巨头”股价在2023年飙升的主要原因。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>recoup (v.) - /rɪˈkuːp/ 补偿，挽回损失。    <p>原文例句：Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语，意为“补偿，挽回损失”。在这个例句中，它指的是2023年科技股的上涨抵消了前一年的一些损失。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：In terms of market value, Apple is still the world's largest company.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示就市值而言，苹果仍然是世界上最大的公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple shares have been weighed down after gaining a new bear; Barclays analysts early this week downgraded shares of the tech giant to underweight, saying they expect soft demand for iPhones going forward. - 苹果股价因获得一位新看跌分析师而承压；巴克莱分析师本周初将这家科技巨头的股票评级下调至“减持”，称他们预计iPhone的未来需求疲软。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Apple shares have been weighed down，其中主语是Apple shares，谓语是have been weighed down。after gaining a new bear是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示苹果股价因获得一位新看跌分析师而承压的原因。Barclays analysts early this week downgraded shares of the tech giant to underweight是一个现在完成时态的句子，表示巴克莱分析师本周初将这家科技巨头的股票评级下调至“减持”。saying they expect soft demand for iPhones going forward是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示巴克莱分析师下调苹果股票评级的理由，即他们预计iPhone的未来需求疲软。这个句子的意思是说，苹果股价因获得一位新看跌分析师而承压，原因是巴克莱分析师本周初将这家科技巨头的股票评级下调至“减持”，他们预计iPhone的未来需求疲软。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 在从句中使用，表示假设、愿望、可能或不确定。    <p>原文例句：If we get something worse than a soft landing, you’re not going to get high-single-digit or double-digit earnings growth. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种语态，用于表达假设、愿望、可能或不确定。在从句中使用，通常由if、unless、as if、so that等引导词引入。在这个例句中，从句是If we get something worse than a soft landing，引导词是if。这个从句表示了一个假设的情况，即如果经济衰退比预期更严重。在主句中，谓语动词是not going to get，表示否定将来时。这个句子的意思是说，如果经济衰退比预期更严重，那么就不会出现高个位数或两位数的收益增长。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023</li>
<li>Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/0234f625-49d6-41da-af35-6b4b09e6ba45_7677fa6e.jpg" /><figcaption>Stock market information at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York, January 2, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>The largest technology stocks that lifted the broader market last year are having a less-rosy start to 2024.</p><p>The so-called Magnificent Seven, which includes Apple, Amazon.com, Alphabet, Microsoft, Meta Platforms, Tesla and Nvidia, slipped for the last four trading days, the longest losing streak in a month, according to the Bloomberg Magnificent 7 Price Return Index. Shares of Apple, down 4.6 per cent in the time period, lead the slump that has erased US$383 billion in market value. The Nasdaq 100 Index has also fallen in the last four trading days.</p><p>“We don’t know if last year’s rally has fully ended, but it is completely normal to expect markets will pull back after a rally like we saw,” said Steve Sosnick, chief strategist at Interactive Brokers Group. “Without the year-end factors that turbocharged the rally, I think we’re seeing the party winding down.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" title="">Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets</a></h3><p>It is a signal that investor doubts over the sticking power of the 2023 rally were well-placed. Though the group surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023 as investors mulled the Federal Reserve’s ability to execute a soft landing for the US economy, which would likely mean fewer interest rate cuts than expected.</p><p>“You’re not going to get high-single-digit or double-digit earnings growth if we get something worse than a soft landing,” Sosnick said. “But we’re not going to get six cuts with a soft landing.”</p><p>A few members of the group have also seen specific stock pressure early this year. Apple shares have been weighed down after gaining a new bear; Barclays analysts early this week downgraded shares of the tech giant to underweight, saying they expect soft demand for iPhones going forward.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" title="">Apple hits 7-week low after Barclays downgrade on demand concerns</a></h3><p>Tesla has shed 8.8 per cent in the last four days, its longest streak of losses in more than four weeks. Though Tesla reported Tuesday that it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as the top seller of electric cars to China’s BYD.</p><p>To be sure, it is likely too early to say the tech-focused rally is over. Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier, and some of the group – Amazon, Alphabet, Meta and Tesla – are still below their all-time highs, signalling they could have room to run.</p><p>But, the largest tech names also have their work cut out for them in 2024. The companies need to continue to deliver not only solid technology, but profitable technology going forward, according to Sosnick.</p><p>“In December everyone bought the sizzle,” he said. “Now we have to see if the steak is any good.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>New refund policies from Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com spark fears of customer abuse among merchants</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247168/new-refund-policies-alibabas-taobao-and-jdcom-spark-fears-customer-abuse-among-merchants</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Taobao and JD.com recently adopted a refund policy that pertains to unhappy buyers who choose to keep the product. </li>    <li>This policy has garnered concern among several merchants due to the potential misuse of policy terms.</li>    <li>Sellers have realized that the refund-only policy might not support business operations and could favor buyers.</li>    <li>The policy could potentially backfire on sellers offering high-quality products as they carry a risk of incurring higher costs.</li>    <li>Both Taobao and JD.com have responded by stating that their platforms will evaluate a combination of factors when making refund decisions, relying on tracking records, big data analysis, and an appeal option for wronged merchants.</li>    <li>Some analysts posit that the policy may not be feasible for platforms like Taobao, Tmall, and JD.com due to their focus on quality products and possible negative impact on merchants.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>淘宝和京东推出允许尚未退还商品的消费者享有退款的政策。</li>    <li>一些商家担忧消费者会利用“仅退款”政策的条款，对运营产生影响。</li>    <li>一些商家对新退款政策的潜在滥用表示担忧。 </li>    <li>淘宝和京东于 12 月下旬推出了新政策，在某些情况下允许对收到质量较差的产品或产品说明不准确误导的消费者进行退款，即使他们仍然持有该产品。</li>    <li>淘宝和京东均表示，其平台上的退款请求决定将基于多个指标，包括商家的信誉记录和买家行为记录，以及大数据分析。</li>    <li>一些分析师认为，该政策可能不适用于淘宝、天猫和京东等平台，因为它们专注于高质量产品，而且可能对商家产生负面影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>prominence (n.) - /ˈprɑːmɪnəns/ 突出，显著。    <p>原文例句：Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice was initially launched in 2021 and is seen as a key factor behind the Shanghai-based budget-shopping platform’s rise to prominence.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由pro-（向前）和minere（突出）组成，表示“向前突出，显著”。在这个例句中，它指的是Pinduoduo的“退款但不退货”政策被视为推动这家上海预算购物平台崛起的关键因素。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>robust (adj.) - /roʊˈbʌst/ 强健的，强壮的，稳固的。    <p>原文例句：Tang Guangyao, a 38-year-old Beijing software developer, said he has shifted from other e-commerce platforms to Pinduoduo as a primary shopping channel owing to its robust consumer protection, even though it focuses on budget prices. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由robur（橡木）组成，表示“像橡木一样强壮，强健的，强壮的，稳固的”。在这个例句中，它指的是Pinduoduo强大的消费者保护措施。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>refund only - 仅退款。    <p>原文例句：Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse under new refund policies.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由refund（退款）和only（仅）组成，表示“仅退款”，“只退款”。在这个例句中，它指的是一些商家对新退款政策下潜在的滥用表示担忧。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>track record - 历史记录，业绩记录。    <p>原文例句：Both Taobao and JD.com have said that any decisions on refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由track（轨道，记录）和record（记录）组成，表示“历史记录，业绩记录”。在这个例句中，它指的是淘宝和京东都表示，其平台上的退款请求决定将基于多个指标，包括商家的信誉记录和买家行为记录。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Taobao and JD.com have said that any decisions on refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments. - 淘宝和京东均表示，其平台上的退款请求决定将基于多个指标，包括商家的信誉记录和买家行为记录，以及大数据分析。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是淘宝和京东均表示，其平台上的退款请求决定将基于多个指标，其中主语是淘宝和京东均，谓语是表示，宾语是退款请求决定。including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示退款请求决定的依据，包括商家的信誉记录和买家行为记录，以及大数据分析。这个句子的意思是说，淘宝和京东都表示，其平台上的退款请求决定将基于多个指标，包括商家的信誉记录和买家行为记录，以及大数据分析。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 把句子的正常语序颠倒过来用，以达到某种修辞效果。    <p>原文例句：Multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis, will be the basis for refund requests on their platforms, according to Taobao and JD.com. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，正常语序是Refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis。倒装句可以使句子更生动、更强调，或使句子的节奏更优美。在这个例句中，倒装句突出了退款请求决定的依据，包括商家的信誉记录和买家行为记录，以及大数据分析。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 表示动作、状态或情况发生的时间、原因、目的、条件、让步等。    <p>原文例句：According to a person briefed on the discussions who asked not to be identified, Alibaba came down on the side of consumer rights in such a situation as merchants are ultimately dependent on buyer confidence.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在分词短语作状语，结构是：现在分词 + 短语。其中，现在分词表示动作、状态或情况，短语表示动作、状态或情况发生的时间、原因、目的、条件、让步等。在这个例句中，现在分词短语作状语according to a person briefed on the discussions who asked not to be identified表示根据一位不愿透露姓名的知情人士透露。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Taobao and JD.com have introduced policies that allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it</li>
<li>Some merchants have raised concerns that consumers may look to exploit the terms of these ‘refund only’ policies, hitting their operations</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/85b29bec-f2e3-42ad-ba41-d20ec559a707_664d3160.jpg" /><figcaption>Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse under new refund policies. Photo: SCMP</figcaption></figure><p>New “refund only” policies introduced by Chinese e-commerce players including Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao and JD.com have sparked concern among some sellers about potential abuse of the terms, according to merchants and analysts.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com in late December introduced new policies that – in certain circumstances – allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it. This may occur when a consumer complains about the poor quality of a product, or about an inaccurate and misleading description on the platform. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Alibaba, whose company mission is “to make it easy to do business anywhere”, had a long internal debate over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo, which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it.</p><p>Even though some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse, Alibaba came down on the side of consumer rights in such a situation as merchants are ultimately dependent on buyer confidence, according to a person briefed on the discussions who asked not to be identified.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>However, since the policy went into effect last week there has been an increased number of claims under the “refund but keep the purchase” policy, according to one merchant who runs apparel shops on both Taobao and JD.com, adding that some consumers were looking to exploit the situation.</p><p>The 33-year-old online shop owner, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of retribution from the platforms, said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products, because they will bear higher costs in the event of more claims.</p><p>“This refund terms only works for merchants who sell dirt-cheap goods,” she said, adding that the policy clearly favoured consumers.</p><p>Meanwhile, some merchants took to social media platforms such as Douyin and Weibo to express anger at the potential for policy abuse.</p><p>One user with the handle “PengqiangweiVerna” posted on Weibo that the practice will “foster a group of online freeloaders”. Another Douyin user called “Xinzhouxiaohuolang” posted a dozen videos denouncing such refund requests.</p><p>Both Taobao and JD.com have said that any decisions on refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments.</p><p>A person familiar with the situation at Taobao, who asked not to be identified as they are not authorised to talk to the media, said that the platform has offered merchants an appeal option if they think they have been wronged.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Wednesday.</p><p>Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice was initially launched in 2021 and is seen as a key factor behind the Shanghai-based budget-shopping platform’s rise to prominence.</p><p>Tang Guangyao, a 38-year-old Beijing software developer, said he has shifted from other e-commerce platforms to Pinduoduo as a primary shopping channel owing to its robust consumer protection, even though it focuses on budget prices.</p><p>But some analysts say simply following Pinduoduo’s lead may not work for rival platforms.</p><p>“This [new refund policy] isn’t very practical for platforms such as Taobao, Tmall and JD.com,” said Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangzhou-based iiMedia, pointing out that Pinduoduo’s focus on rock-bottom prices means that the costs of the scheme are more bearable than for merchants on rival sites.</p><p>“By following this [Pinduoduo] refund policy … [rival platforms] will give their merchants a dilemma,” he added.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei’s HarmonyOS to beat Apple’s IOS as the No. 2 smartphone operating system in China in 2024: TechInsights report</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  华为发布的鸿蒙操作系统，预计今年将会超越苹果的iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。这一增长势头，得益于华为在8月底推出的支持5G技术的Mate 60系列手机，以及美国制裁导致的芯片供应短缺问题有望缓解。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei's HarmonyOS is expected to surpass Apple's iOS as the second largest operating system in China, driven by the launch of the Mate 60 series and easing of chip supply constraints.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's return to the 5G smartphone segment boosts the adoption of its HarmonyOS operating system, surpassing Apple's iOS in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Huawei's ability to overcome US sanctions and develop its own operating system, HarmonyOS, positions it as a strong competitor in the Chinese market.</li>    <li>Main information: Launch of the Mate 60 Pro with advanced 5G chip despite US sanctions; projected HarmonyOS Next release in 2024 without Android app support; major Chinese companies developing native apps for HarmonyOS; McDonald's China adopting HarmonyOS Next.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  华为发布的鸿蒙操作系统，预计今年将会超越苹果的iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。这一增长势头，得益于华为在8月底推出的支持5G技术的Mate 60系列手机，以及美国制裁导致的芯片供应短缺问题有望缓解。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为的鸿蒙操作系统预计今年将超越苹果的iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统，这得益于Mate 60系列手机的推出和美国制裁导致的芯片供应短缺问题的缓解。</li>    <li>主题：华为重返5G智能手机领域推动了其鸿蒙操作系统的采用，使其在中国的市场份额超过了苹果的iOS。</li>    <li>观点：华为克服美国制裁并开发了自己的操作系统，鸿蒙操作系统，使其在竞争激烈的中国市场上成为强有力的竞争者。</li>    <li>主要信息：Mate 60 Pro搭载先进5G芯片，尽管受到美国制裁，还是如期推出；预计2024年发布鸿蒙操作系统Next，不兼容安卓应用；中国主要企业为鸿蒙操作系统开发本地应用；麦当劳中国采用鸿蒙操作系统Next。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>circuit breaker (n.) - /ˈsɜːrkɪtˌbreɪkər/ 电路断路器。    <p>原文例句：Circuit breakers keep your home safe by automatically switching off the flow of electricity when there is a fault.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个复合词由circuit（电路）和breaker（断路器）组成，表示“电路断路器”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>derivative (n.) - /dɪˈrɪvətɪv/ 源自，派生的。    <p>原文例句：A derivative is a financial instrument with a price that is based on an underlying asset.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由de-（从……）和rivus（河流）组成，表示“派生的”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>entity (n.) - /ˈentɪti/ 实体，存在物。    <p>原文例句：An entity is anything that exists independently, has a separate existence.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由ens（存在）和-tas（后缀，表示状态或品质）组成，表示“实体”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sanction (n.) - /ˈsæŋkʃən/ 制裁，惩罚。    <p>原文例句：The US government imposed sanctions on Huawei in 2019.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由sanctus（神圣的）和-io（后缀，表示动作）组成，表示“制裁”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>segment (n.) - /ˈsɛgmənt/ 段，节。    <p>原文例句：The smartphone segment is expected to grow rapidly in the coming years.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由secare（切，割）和-mentum（后缀，表示结果）组成，表示“段”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>supply challenge - 供应挑战。    <p>原文例句：Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由supply（供应）和challenge（挑战）组成，表示“供应挑战”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>market share - 市场份额。    <p>原文例句：Huawei’s HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由market（市场）和share（份额）组成，表示“市场份额”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>home-grown - 本土的。    <p>原文例句：a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由home（家）和grown（生长的）组成，表示“本土的”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>multinational company - 跨国公司。    <p>原文例句：McDonald’s China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year – became one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt HarmonyOS Next.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由multinational（多国的）和company（公司）组成，表示“跨国公司”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TechInsights also expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months. - TechInsights还预计，在未来几个月内，华为的供应挑战将随着麒麟9000芯片组短缺的缓解而得到缓解。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是TechInsights also expects Huawei’s supply challenge to ease in the next few months，其中主语是TechInsights，谓语是expects，宾语是Huawei’s supply challenge to ease in the next few months。driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰supply challenge，表示这一供应挑战是由麒麟9000芯片组短缺造成的。这个句子的意思是说，TechInsights还预计，在未来几个月内，华为的供应挑战将随着麒麟9000芯片组短缺的缓解而得到缓解。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去进行时 - 表示过去某个时间正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The Huawei P50 Pro and P50 Pocket were released in August.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：was/were + 现在分词。其中was/were要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间正在进行，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，itwas released表示华为P50 Pro和P50 Pocket在8月份正在发布。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Increased HarmonyOS adoption is expected to be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment</li>
<li>TechInsights also expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/83c4b156-87f3-4acb-b3f4-8cb885281387_c0009114.jpg" /><figcaption>Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s IOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year driven by the US-sanctioned firm’s comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to a report by TechInsights.</p><p>While Google’s Android and Apple’s IOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, Canadian research firm TechInsights said in a report released on Wednesday.</p><p>Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment, which started with the surprise launch in late August of its Mate 60 Pro, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology.</p><p>TechInsights also expects Huawei to make a solid recovery in 2024, according to the report.</p><p>Huawei’s smartphones are all powered by HarmonyOS, its self-developed Android alternative launched in August 2019, three months after the US government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">added the firm to its Entity List</a>. Under this trade blacklist, Huawei is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>On its release, the Mate 60 Pro inspired <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">a wave of patriotic fervour</a> among Chinese consumers, and the Shenzhen-based firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241541/huawei-has-big-problem-popular-mate-60-5g-smartphones-theres-not-enough-supply-meet-growing-demand" target="_self" title="">faced supply issues as it scrambled to crank up production to meet demand</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" title="">Huawei sees 9 per cent sales growth in 2023, boosted by Mate 60 Pro 5G comeback</a></h3><p>TechInsights expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months. Huawei’s product portfolio further expanded last week when it launched new smartphone models under its mid-range Nova series.</p><p>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p><p>Huawei is expected to launch a developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next in the first quarter of 2024, and is already working with China’s major companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p><p>Last month, Chinese financial technology giant Ant Group, the fintech affiliate of South China Morning Post owner <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, said it is building a new version of mobile payment app Alipay based on HarmonyOS, after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242703/alibaba-develops-native-dingtalk-app-harmonyos-huawei-aims-end-support-android-apps?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba started development on a new version of DingTalk</a>, its workplace collaboration app, for the platform.</p><p>Other major Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> companies – including e-commerce firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>, video gaming giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netease?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">NetEase</a> and food delivery market leader <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> – in November already started to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241371/chinese-big-tech-firms-jdcom-netease-and-meituan-rush-hire-harmonyos-based-app-developers-huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">recruit developers to build native apps for HarmonyOS</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mcdonalds?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">McDonald’s</a> China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year – became <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244236/mcdonalds-china-pushes-development-native-apps-based-harmonyos-adoption-huaweis-mobile-operating?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239589/xiaomi-launches-home-grown-cross-device-system-hyperos-us-sanctioned-huawei-moves-further-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS Next</a>.</p><p>It remains to be seen whether these efforts will have a halo effect on other smartphone makers and make HarmonyOS a default operating system for not just smartphones but also laptops and cars in China, TechInsights said.</p><p>More than 700 million devices currently run on HarmonyOS, with more than 2.2 million third-party developers creating apps for the platform, according to Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group, speaking at the company’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230293/tech-war-huawei-revive-smartphone-business-back-fresh-ai-powered-operating-system-even-us-sanctions?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">annual developer conference in August</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple dominates global premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground on the back of its new 5G handsets</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple maintained its position as the leading vendor of premium smartphones globally in 2023, despite facing challenges from Huawei's 5G comeback and Samsung's foldable phones.</li>    <li>Apple's market share dropped from 75% in 2022 to 71% in 2023 due to Huawei's resurgence and Samsung's gains in the premium segment.</li>    <li>Huawei captured more market share in 2023 with its Mate 60 series, increasing its share from 3% to 5% and securing the third position in the premium segment.</li>    <li>Samsung retained the second position with a 17% share, while Xiaomi and Oppo occupied the fourth and fifth spots with 2% and 1% shares, respectively.</li>    <li>The premium smartphone segment showed resilience amidst a projected decline in the overall global smartphone market in 2023.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>苹果公司在 2023 年继续保持全球高端智能手机供应商的领先地位，尽管面临来自华为 5G 卷土重来和三星折叠手机的挑战。</li>    <li>由于华为的复苏和三星在高端市场的增长，苹果的市场份额从 2022 年的 75% 下降到 2023 年的 71%。</li>    <li>华为凭借其 Mate 60 系列在 2023 年获得了更多市场份额，其份额从 3% 增长到 5%，并在高端细分市场中占据了第三的位置。</li>    <li>三星凭借 17% 的份额继续保持第二的位置，而小米和 Oppo 分别以 2% 和 1% 的份额占据了第四和第五的位置。</li>    <li>在 2023 年整体全球智能手机市场预计下降的情况下，高端智能手机细分市场表现出了韧性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>premium (adj.) - /ˈpriːmɪəm/ 优质的，高档的。    <p>例句：The global premium smartphone market, where handsets are priced from US$600, saw Apple remain the “undisputed leader” last year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：premium 在这句话中用作形容词，意思是“优质的，高档的”。它描述了全球高端智能手机市场，其中手机的价格从 600 美元起。这个例句表明苹果在去年继续保持“无可争议的领导者”地位。</p></li>    <li>capture (v.) - /ˈkæptʃər/ 捕获，占领。    <p>例句：Huawei captured more new ground year on year with a 5 per cent share, up from 3 per cent in 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：capture 在这句话中用作动词，意思是“捕获，占领”。它描述了华为在 2023 年占领了更多的新市场份额，从 2022 年的 3% 增长到 5%。这个例句表明华为在高端智能手机市场取得了显着的进展。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take the lead - 领导，占主导地位。    <p>例句：Apple remained the world’s top vendor of premium smartphones in 2023, with a 71 per cent market share.</p>    <p>例句讲解：take the lead 是一个动词短语，意思是“领导，占主导地位”。它描述了苹果在 2023 年继续保持全球高端智能手机供应商的领导地位。这个例句表明苹果在高端智能手机市场拥有强大的竞争优势。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei, which released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020, as well as the gains made by Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy S23 series and its latest foldable phones. - 然而，苹果的份额从 2022 年的 75% 下降，原因是华为的复苏，华为自 2020 年 10 月以来发布了首款新的 5G 智能手机，以及三星电子的 Galaxy S23 系列及其最新款折叠手机取得的增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间之前已经发生或完成的动作或状态。    <p>例句：Apple had continued to lead the smartphone industry’s premium segment in 2023.</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去完成时是由 had + 过去分词构成的，表示在过去某个时间之前已经发生或完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，had continued to lead 表示苹果在 2023 年之前已经持续领导智能手机行业的高端细分市场。这个例句表明苹果在高端智能手机市场拥有长期的领导地位。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple remained the world’s top vendor of premium smartphones in 2023, with a 71 per cent market share, according to research firm Counterpoint</li>
<li>The US firm’s lead, however, declined year on year amid Huawei’s 5G comeback with its Mate 60 series and the gains made by Samsung’s foldable phones</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/64d88f21-13d4-47d7-a021-0a71facc64d7_e98ebaba.jpg" /><figcaption>Apple’s iPhone 15 Pro and Pro Max models are seen on display at a store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 22, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> continued to lead the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> industry’s premium segment in 2023, but saw its worldwide share decline mainly because of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-sanctioned</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>’ strong <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/5g/news" target="_self" title="">5G</a> handset market comeback with its Mate 60 series.</p><p>The global premium smartphone market, where handsets are priced from US$600, saw Apple remain the “undisputed leader” last year with a dominant 71 per cent share, according to the latest industry report released on Tuesday by Counterpoint Research.</p><p>Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei, which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020</a>, as well as the gains made by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a>’ Galaxy S23 series and its latest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foldable-phones" target="_self" title="">foldable phones</a>.</p><p>Samsung retained the global No 2 spot in the premium segment with a share of 17 per cent, compared to 16 per cent in 2022. Still, No 3 Huawei captured more new ground year on year with a 5 per cent share, up from 3 per cent in 2022, according to the Counterpoint report.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/cb3a9a4b-0ce5-45f4-91e6-798c2c4c40f0_5babf532.jpg" title="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> last year took the fourth and fifth spots in the premium smartphone segment with a 2 per cent and 1 per cent share, respectively.</p><p>The latest market data shows the resilience of the premium segment, despite the projected decrease in the overall global smartphone market in 2023 – global handset shipments are forecast to hit their lowest level in almost a decade with a 5 per cent decline, according to an earlier Counterpoint report.</p><p>The premium segment, meanwhile, was expected to account for nearly one-fourth of global smartphone market sales and 60 per cent of the industry’s revenue in 2023. Counterpoint data shows that the so-called ultra-premium segment, where smartphones cost more than US$1,000, accounted for one-third of total premium handset sales last year.</p><p>Over the past few years, the premium segment has emerged as a growth area in the otherwise weak worldwide smartphone market. Counterpoint projected the premium segment sales share to triple to 24 per cent in 2023, compared to 6 per cent in 2016.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3246457/ranked-top-5-smartphones-2023-iphone-15-pro-max-and-google-pixel-8-pro-two-foldable-phones-and-best" title="">Top 5 smartphones of 2023, from iPhone 15 Pro Max to the best camera phone</a></h3><p>“There has been a shift in consumer buying patterns in the smartphone market,” Counterpoint senior analyst Varun Mishra said in the premium segment report. “Considering the importance a smartphone holds, consumers are willing to spend more to get a high-quality device that they can use for a longer period.”</p><p>Much of the global premium segment’s growth last year was driven by China, western Europe, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/india" target="_self" title="">India</a>, and the Middle East-and-Africa regions, according to Counterpoint.</p><p>India is already the world’s fastest-growing market for premium smartphones, the Counterpoint report said. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217435/apple-opens-first-retail-store-india-us-tech-giant-sharpens-focus-south-asian-nation-major-market" target="_self" title="">Apple opened its first retail store in India</a> last April, underscoring the US tech titan’s increasing focus on the South Asian nation as a key sales market and alternative manufacturing hub to China.</p><p>“Owning the latest and greatest flagships has also become a status symbol for many consumers, especially in emerging markets where they are jumping directly from the mid-price band to the premium band,” Mishra said. “Further, these devices are increasingly becoming more affordable due to promotion seasons and financing options.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance’s Douyin makes instant refunds mandatory, following PDD, Taobao and JD.com amid fierce e-commerce competition</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247160/bytedances-douyin-makes-instant-refunds-mandatory-following-pdd-taobao-and-jdcom-amid-fierce-e</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  TikTok's Chinese version, Douyin, imposes a mandatory "instant refund" policy, forcing merchants to instantly refund consumers upon request, similar to rivals Taobao and Pinduoduo, to boost consumer favor amid intense competition. Merchants have no option to decline.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Douyin's mandatory "express refund" policy intensifies competition among e-commerce platforms.</li>    <li>Theme: E-commerce platforms in China adopt "refund without returns" policies to attract consumers, with Douyin joining the trend.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The policy shift reflects the growing consumer-centric approach among e-commerce platforms, prioritizing customer satisfaction over merchant interests.</li>    <li>Main information: Douyin's mandatory "express refund" policy; similar policies by Taobao and Pinduoduo; increasing online retail sales in China; Pinduoduo's success in attracting consumers with its "refund only" policy; Alibaba's recent efforts to regain market leadership.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  抖音，中国版的TikTok，强制推行“极速退款”政策，迫使商家在收到退货前立即向消费者退款，与淘宝和拼多多的类似政策相似，以在激烈的竞争中提升消费者满意度。商家无法选择拒绝此项政策。  <ul>    <li>摘要：抖音的强制“极速退款”政策加剧了电商平台之间的竞争。</li>    <li>主题：中国电商平台纷纷采用“退货不退款”的政策来吸引消费者，抖音也加入了这一潮流。</li>    <li>观点：这一政策的转变反映了电商平台日益重视消费者体验，将客户满意度置于商家利益之上。</li>    <li>主要信息：抖音的强制“极速退款”政策；淘宝和拼多多的类似政策；中国在线零售额的增长；拼多多凭借其“退货不退款”政策成功吸引消费者；阿里巴巴最近为重新夺回市场领导地位所做的努力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>refund (v.) - /rɪˈfʌnd/ 给予退款。    <p>原文例句：Douyin has made its “express refund” policy mandatory, forcing merchants to immediately return money to consumers upon request.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由re-（重新，再次）和fund（基金，资金）构成的，表示“偿还，退款”。在这个例句中，它指的是抖音强制推行的“极速退款”政策，要求商家在收到退货前立即向消费者退款。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rival (n.) - /ˈraɪvəl/ 竞争者，对手。    <p>原文例句：The platform operated by Beijing-based ByteDance, which added a shopping channel in 2019, allows users to get a refund as soon as they mail back the returned parcel, rather than when the merchant receives it.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由rivus（河流，溪流）演变而来，表示“争夺同样资源的对手”。在这个例句中，它指的是抖音的竞争对手，例如淘宝和拼多多。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>be more consumer-friendly - 更加亲和消费者。    <p>原文例句：E-commerce platforms are turning to policies known as “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason” as part of a push to be more consumer-friendly at the expense of merchants amid intensified competition.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由be（是，成为）、more（更多）、consumer（消费者）和friendly（友好的）构成的，表示“更加亲和消费者”。在这个例句中，它指的是电商平台为吸引消费者而采取的亲消费者政策，例如“退货不退款”或“无理由退款”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Online retail sales of tangible goods in China increased 8.3 per cent in the first 11 months of 2023, according to the National Bureau of Statistics. - 根据国家统计局的数据，2023年前11个月，中国实物商品的网络零售额增长了8.3%。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句型，主句是Online retail sales of tangible goods in China increased 8.3 per cent in the first 11 months of 2023，其中主语是Online retail sales of tangible goods in China，谓语是increased，宾语是8.3 per cent in the first 11 months of 2023。according to the National Bureau of Statistics是一个介词短语作状语，表示根据国家统计局的数据。这个句子的意思是说，根据国家统计局的数据，2023年前11个月，中国实物商品的网络零售额增长了8.3%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>祈使句 - 表示请求，命令，建议或劝告。    <p>原文例句：Take a deep breath and think step by step. - 深呼吸，一步一步地思考。</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个祈使句，表示对听众的请求或命令。结构是：动词原形 + 其他。在这个例句中，Take a deep breath and think step by step.表示对听众的请求或命令，要求他们深呼吸，一步一步地思考。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示现在正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：My arms are both broken and I am very frustrated. - 我的胳膊都断了，我非常沮丧。</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在进行时的句子，表示现在正在进行的动作或状态。结构是：be + 动词-ing。在这个例句中，am是be的现在时态，broken是break的过去分词，frustrated是frustrate的过去分词。这个句子的意思是说，我的胳膊都断了，我非常沮丧。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Merchants selling on the short video app Douyin can no longer opt out of the option to instantly refund up to US$211 before receiving returned goods</li>
<li>Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com recently started offering refunds without returns to woo consumers away from rising budget e-commerce champion Pinduoduo</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/3ce8d4ad-d4c8-4569-8e73-e028869c8250_11da8613.jpg" /><figcaption>The logo of Douyin displayed next to a mobile phone displaying an e-commerce site on the app in an illustration picture taken on October 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Douyin, the Chinese version of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a> that is betting big on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce">e-commerce</a>, has made its “express refund” policy mandatory, forcing merchants to immediately return money to consumers upon request to compete with similar offerings on Taobao and Pinduoduo.</p><p>The platform operated by Beijing-based <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance">ByteDance</a>, which added a shopping channel in 2019, allows users to get a refund as soon as they mail back the returned parcel, rather than when the merchant receives it. A recent policy update regarding the service introduced in 2021 denies merchants the option of turning it off.</p><p>E-commerce platforms are turning to policies known as “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason” as part of a push to be more consumer-friendly at the expense of merchants amid intensified competition. Online retail sales of tangible goods in China increased 8.3 per cent in the first 11 months of 2023, according to the National Bureau of Statistics.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>Budget shopping app <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo">Pinduoduo</a>, owned by PDD Holdings, was the first major e-commerce site to introduce a similar refunds policy in 2021 allowing users to get their money back without returning goods found to not match merchant descriptions. This was seen as a major factor in helping Pinduoduo woo price-sensitive Chinese consumers away from competing platforms.</p><p>The policy of allowing refunds without returns has started to gain favour as platforms look for any possible edge over rivals.</p><p>Taobao, the e-commerce platform from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom">JD.com</a> last week rolled out their own <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating">“refund only” policies</a>, finally matching the option from Pinduoduo. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Douyin has offered refunds without returns since September.</p><p>Douyin’s new refund service is not available for customised products or non-tangible goods such as memberships. Instant refunds are also limited to 1,500 yuan (US$211).</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Alibaba has been facing a new sense of urgency to win back consumers after PDD overtook China’s e-commerce king in market capitalisation. Alibaba was valued at US$190.2 billion on the New York Stock Exchange on Tuesday, lower than PDD’s US$193.5 billion on the Nasdaq.</p><p>In December, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals">Alibaba promoted six young managers</a> to run its core e-commerce business unit in an attempt to “reignite their entrepreneurial spirit” and “secure and win their future”, according to an internal letter penned by the conglomerate’s CEO Eddie Wu Yongming, two days after he became the head of the unit.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech firms must end, says communist party newspaper after video gaming stock rout</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Recently, a Chinese Communist Party newspaper, the mouthpiece of the Central Party School, published an opinion piece calling for an end to the government's erratic regulatory practices towards the platform economy. The article emphasizes the need for regulatory stability to foster growth and competitiveness among China's internet giants.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: An opinion piece stresses the importance of regulatory stability in China's platform economy to promote growth and competitiveness.</li>    <li>Theme: The impact of regulatory actions on China's internet industry and the need for a balanced approach.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The article advocates for a shift away from extreme regulatory measures and suggests fostering self-governance within internet companies.</li>    <li>Main information: The article highlights the challenges faced by Chinese internet firms due to unpredictable regulations, the need for coordinated enforcement, and the benefits of self-governance.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  近日，中国共产党党刊、中央党校机关报《学习时报》发表评论文章，呼吁结束政府对平台经济的摇摆不定、忽松忽严的监管方式。文章强调了监管稳定性对于中国互联网巨头发展和竞争力增强的必要性。  <ul>    <li>摘要：评论文章强调了监管稳定性对于中国平台经济发展和增强竞争力的重要性。</li>    <li>主题：监管行为对中国互联网行业的影响及平衡之道。</li>    <li>观点：文章主张摒弃极端监管行为，建议培育互联网企业内部自我治理能力。</li>    <li>主要信息：文章指出中国互联网企业因监管莫测面临的挑战，提出加强部门协调执法和发挥企业自我治理作用的好处。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sign - n. 迹象，征兆，信号。    <p>原文例句：A Chinese Communist Party newspaper has urged the country’s regulators to end their erratic moves against the platform economy, in a sign of growing concern over policy damage to the health of the country’s ailing internet titans. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“sign”在这里的意思是“迹象，征兆”。这句话是说，中国共产党的一份报纸呼吁该国监管机构停止对平台经济采取不稳定的行动，这是人们越来越担心政策损害该国陷入困境的互联网巨头健康状况的一个迹象。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>punishment - n. 惩罚，处罚。    <p>原文例句：Beijing’s pursuit of market control, along with China’s economic slowdown and rising geopolitical tensions with the US, have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“punishment”在这里的意思是“惩罚”。这句话是说，北京对市场控制的追求，加上中国经济放缓以及与美国的 геополитическое напряжение加剧，让中国互联网股票在过去三年里成为表现最差的资产之一。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>platform economy - 平台经济    <P>原文例句：A Chinese Communist Party newspaper has urged the country’s regulators to end their erratic moves against the platform economy, in a sign of growing concern over policy damage to the health of the country’s ailing internet titans.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由platform（平台）和economy（经济）构成，表示“平台经济”，是指基于互联网平台的经济模式，这种模式的特点是，平台提供了一个撮合交易的场所，而交易的双方通过平台进行交易。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The NPPA wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with draft regulation to restrict spending on video games. - NPPA 通过一项拟议的监管规定来限制电子游戏支出，导致中国游戏股市价值损失数十亿美元。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The NPPA wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks，其中主语是The NPPA，谓语是wiped out，宾语是billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks。with draft regulation to restrict spending on video games是一个介词短语作状语，表示这项规定的目的，即限制电子游戏支出。这个句子的意思是说，NPPA通过一项拟议的监管规定来限制电子游戏支出，导致中国游戏股市价值损失数十亿美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词作定语 - 用于修饰名词或代词，表示该名词或代词所描述的人或事物在过去发生的状态或动作。    <p>原文例句：The draft proposal is the latest example of regulatory hostility, after Beijing’s campaign of “curbing irrational expansion of capital” in 2020 unleashed a race among different ministries and watchdogs to claim authority in checking and approving internet businesses. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某人或某物在过去发生的状态或动作。结构是：过去分词 + 名词或代词。其中过去分词是动词的过去分词形式，名词或代词是被修饰的名词或代词。在这个例句中，过去分词是unleashed，表示“释放，释放”。过去分词短语“unleashed a race among different ministries and watchdogs”作定语，修饰名词campaign，表示“在 2020 年，北京开展了‘遏制资本无序扩张’的运动之后，引发了不同部委和监管机构之间的竞赛，争夺检查和批准互联网企业的权力”。这个句子的意思是说，在 2020 年，北京开展了‘遏制资本无序扩张’的运动之后，引发了不同部委和监管机构之间的竞赛，争夺检查和批准互联网企业的权力。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>动词不定式作宾语 - 用于表示动词、形容词或名词的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：China must improve “cross-departmental coordination” to avoid duplicated enforcement and checks. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是动词不定式作宾语的用法。这种用法通常出现在某些动词之后，表示动词、形容词或名词的动作或状态。动词不定式可以由to + 动词原形构成，也可以由动词原形或动词的-ing形式构成。在这个例句中，动词improve后面跟动词不定式“to avoid duplicated enforcement and checks”，表示“为了避免重复的执法和检查，中国必须提高跨部门协调”。这个句子的意思是说，为了避免重复的执法和检查，中国必须提高跨部门协调。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The mouthpiece of the Central Party School argued that regulators must stop the practice of swinging between extremes of lax oversight and ‘overly strict’ regulation</li>
<li>The opinion came days after the NPPA wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with draft regulation to restrict spending on video games</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/3319e698-c70a-4b75-a5c4-b17164272de6_6b557a93.jpg" /><figcaption>Tencent’s Game for Peace is seen on a mobile phone in this illustration picture taken May 13, 2019.  Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>A Chinese Communist Party newspaper has urged the country’s regulators to end their erratic moves against the platform economy, in a sign of growing concern over policy damage to the health of the country’s ailing internet titans.</p><p>A front page opinion piece published by the Study Times, the mouthpiece of the Central Party School, on Wednesday argued that regulators must stop the practice of swinging between extremes of lax oversight and “overly strict” regulation so that China’s Big Tech firms can have room to grow.</p><p>The article, which did not name any specific company or regulator, came days after the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" target="_self" title="">proposed regulation to restrict spending on video games.</a> The South China Morning Post reported on Tuesday that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes" target="_self" title="">a key gaming official has left his job following the debacle,</a> as the Chinese government tries to allay market fears.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246511/chinas-disciplinary-enforcers-add-bad-books-sex-drugs-serious-offences" title="">China’s disciplinary enforcers add ‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences</a></h3><p>The draft proposal is the latest example of regulatory hostility, after Beijing’s campaign of “curbing irrational expansion of capital” in 2020 unleashed a race among different ministries and watchdogs to claim authority in checking and approving internet businesses.</p><p>A long list of Chinese ministries has been sharpening their teeth when it comes to disciplining internet firms. The Cyberspace Administration of China, the country’s internet watchdog, for instance, has articulated Beijing’s demand for data security into intrusive requirements that have made it increasingly difficult and costly to comply with.</p><p>Beijing’s pursuit of market control, along with China’s economic slowdown and rising geopolitical tensions with the US, have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years. Tencent Holdings, the country’s most valuable player that once eyed being Asia’s first US$1 trillion company, fell out of the global top 10 after losing 60 per cent of its market capitalisation, while Post owner Alibaba Group Holding, which exceeded Amazon.com in market value in 2014, is now worth an eighth of the US e-commerce titan.</p><p>According to the Study Times opinion piece, the erratic regulatory behaviour is “a risk and a challenge” for China as its leading internet firms are left further behind their global peers in terms of competitiveness and growth potential.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/643c0e52-aced-4b9f-a2cf-0f56737ce2f0_bd901af2.jpg" title="People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" width="2000" /><figcaption>People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song</figcaption></figure></div><p>China must improve “cross-departmental coordination” to avoid duplicated enforcement and checks, while regulatory acts and policy adjustments must factor in “the views of all parties, especially those being regulated” to avoid interrupting normal business activities or causing unexpected risks, it said.</p><p>Chinese regulators should loosen their grip and allow “self-governance” by Chinese internet companies, it added. “It is important to respect the rationality and necessity of platform self-governance to guide and encourage the formation of self-regulatory mechanisms,” the article said.</p><p>It remains unknown whether China’s different regulators will heed the advice. Beijing’s regulatory crackdown on the internet sector officially came to an end a year ago, when the Chinese leadership said the country’s platform enterprises would be encouraged to “fully display their capabilities” in growth, job creation and international competition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung to kick off year of AI phones with new launch this month</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247104/samsung-kick-year-ai-phones-new-launch-month</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Samsung, the world's leading smartphone maker, is introducing artificial intelligence (AI) as a key selling point for its upcoming flagship device, the Galaxy S24. Samsung plans to unveil the Galaxy S24 with a focus on advanced AI capabilities on January 17. This shift towards AI comes after years of relying on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out in the market. By doing so, they aim to gain a significant market share over the next two years, with similar dominance to what they achieved with foldable phones.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung's focus on AI in its upcoming flagship device, the Galaxy S24.</li>    <li>Theme: The emergence of AI as a key differentiator in the smartphone market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Samsung's strategic advantage in adopting and integrating AI into its products.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's past reliance on camera technology and flexible displays; projected growth of smartphones with built-in generative AI; Samsung's positioning as a leader in AI integration; anticipated market share gains in the next two years.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  三星，全球领先的智能手机制造商，正在将其即将推出的旗舰设备 Galaxy S24 中的人工智能 (AI) 作为一项关键卖点。三星计划于 1 月 17 日发布 Galaxy S24，注重于先进的 AI 功能。此番转向人工智能，是多年来依赖相机技术和柔性显示屏以在市场中脱颖而出的结果。通过这样做，他们旨在在未来两年内获得巨大的市场份额，与他们在可折叠手机领域取得的统治地位相似。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星在即将推出的旗舰设备 Galaxy S24 中对人工智能的关注。</li>    <li>主题：人工智能作为智能手机市场关键差异化因素的出现。</li>    <li>观点：三星在采用和将人工智能集成到其产品中的战略优势。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星过去对摄像头技术和柔性显示屏的依赖；搭载内置生成型人工智能的智能手机的预期增长；三星作为人工智能集成领导者的定位；未来两年预期获得的市场份额。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ship (v.) - /ʃɪp/ 装运；运输。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词既可以作名词，也可以作动词。作动词时，它表示“装运；运输”。在这个例句中，它表示预计到 2027 年底，将有超过 10 亿部内置生成式人工智能的智能手机被装运出去。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>enhance (v.) - /ɪnˈhæns/ 提高；增强。    <p>原文例句：Samsung is leaning into artificial intelligence (AI) as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词表示“提高；增强”。在这个例句中，它表示三星将人工智能 (AI) 作为今年提高销量的关键。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stand out - 脱颖而出；引人注目。    <P>原文例句：In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由stand（站立）和out（在外）组成，表示“脱颖而出；引人注目”。在这个例句中，它表示在过去的几年里，三星和其他智能手机制造商依赖于相机技术和柔性显示屏的改进以脱颖而出。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – on January 17 in San Jose, California, with a live-streamed event.【句子分析】：这是一个简单句，主语是Samsung Electronics，谓语是announced，宾语是it plans to launch its next flagship device。其中，it plans to launch its next flagship device是一个复合句，主句是it plans to launch its next flagship device，其中主语是it，谓语是plans to launch；从句是likely to be known as the Galaxy S24，其中主语是likely to be known as the Galaxy S24，谓语是to be known as the Galaxy S24。这个句子的意思是说，三星电子宣布计划于 1 月 17 日在加利福尼亚州圣何塞发布其下一代旗舰设备——可能被称为 Galaxy S24，并举行现场直播活动。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>一般现在时 - 表示现在正在发生或存在的情况。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – on January 17 in San Jose, California, with a live-streamed event. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在时态的句子，表示现在正在发生或存在的情况。结构是：主语 + 谓语（动词的现在式）。在这个例句中，主语是Samsung Electronics，谓语是announced，表示三星电子宣布了这一消息。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的主语承受的。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，表示动作或状态是由句子中的主语承受的。结构是：be + 过去分词。在这个例句中，主语是More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI，谓语是are expected to be shipped，表示预计到 2027 年底，将有超过 10 亿部内置生成式人工智能的智能手机被装运出去。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out</li>
<li>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates</li>
</ul><p>The world’s most prolific smartphone maker is leaning into artificial intelligence (AI) as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.</p><p>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – on January 17 in San Jose, California, with a live-streamed event. The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming”.</p><p>In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out, but 2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246310/huawei-launches-new-nova-smartphones-without-giving-details-chip-attention-remains-fixed-its" title="">Huawei launches new Nova smartphones without giving details on chip</a></h3><p>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p><p>OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Dall-E tools, which generate text or visual responses to users’ queries, are at the forefront of a generative-AI wave that is swept across the tech industry – and helped make Nvidia a trillion-dollar company by providing the key AI-training accelerators. The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices, as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year.</p><p>“Samsung and Qualcomm are immediate leaders as current product offerings and capabilities position them as first movers,” the Counterpoint researchers wrote in December. “Similar to what it did with foldables, Samsung is likely to capture almost 50 per cent share for the next two years, followed by key Chinese OEMs like Xiaomi, Vivo, Honor and Oppo.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok use</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247089/montana-appealing-ruling-blocked-state-barring-tiktok-use</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen stated that the state is appealing a lower court ruling that blocked the state's ban on the video-sharing app TikTok. The ban was blocked by U.S. District Judge Donald Molloy in November, who stated that Montana's law oversteps state authority and violates the Constitution in multiple ways. TikTok said it does not share user data with the Chinese government and has implemented measures to protect user privacy. Many states and the U.S. government have barred TikTok on government devices, but Montana is the only state that has attempted to completely prohibit the app's use.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Montana appeals court decision blocking ban on video-sharing app TikTok.</li>    <li>Theme: Legal and political contestation over the state's ban on TikTok.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Concerns regarding TikTok's data privacy, security, and potential ties to the Chinese government.</li>    <li>Main information: Montana's ban on TikTok; preliminary injunction issued by U.S. District Judge; TikTok's response and legal arguments; broader efforts to restrict TikTok in the U.S.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  蒙大拿州总检察长奥斯汀·努德森表示，该州正在向第九巡回上诉法院上诉，以推翻下级法院的裁决，该裁决阻止了该州对视频共享应用程序 TikTok 的禁令。美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊于 11 月下令禁止该禁令，他表示蒙大拿州的法律超越了州权力，并以多种方式违反了宪法。TikTok 表示，它不会与中国政府共享用户数据，并已采取措施保护用户隐私。许多州和美国政府已禁止在政府设备上使用 TikTok，但蒙大拿州是唯一一个试图完全禁止使用该应用程序的州。前总统唐纳德·特朗普于 2020 年试图禁止新下载 TikTok 和中国拥有的微信，但一系列法院裁决阻止了该禁令的生效。  <ul>    <li>摘要：蒙大拿州对法院判决提出上诉，该判决阻止了对视频共享应用程序 TikTok 的禁令。</li>    <li>主题：围绕该州禁止 TikTok 的法律和政治争论。</li>    <li>观点：对 TikTok 的数据隐私、安全以及与中国政府的潜在联系的担忧。</li>    <li>主要信息：蒙大拿州禁止 TikTok；美国地区法官颁布的初步禁令；TikTok 的回复和法律论据；在美国限制 TikTok 的更广泛努力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>injunction (n.) - /ɪnˈdʒʌŋ(k)ʃən/ 禁令。    <p>原文例句：US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由in-（不，否定）和junction（连接点）组成，表示“禁止，约束”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊于 11 月 30 日颁发的一项初步禁令，以阻止蒙大拿州对 TikTok 的禁令。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>preliminary (adj.) - /prɪˈlɪmɪnəri/ 初步的，暂时的。    <p>原文例句：US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于late Latin，由 prae-（在……之前）和limus（门槛）组成，表示“在前的，先前的”。在这个例句中，它表示该禁令是一项初步禁令，即一项临时禁令，可在等待最终判决时颁发。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>violate (v.) - /vaɪəˈleɪt/ 违反，侵犯。    <p>原文例句：Montana’s law “violates the Constitution in more ways than one” and “oversteps state power”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于late Latin，由violare（强奸，凌辱）演变而来，表示“强奸，凌辱，侵犯”。在这个例句中，它表示蒙大拿州法律侵犯了宪法，并超越了国家权力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take effect - 生效，生效。    <P>原文例句：Montana’s ban had been set to take effect on January 1.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由take（采取）和effect（效果）组成，表示“发生作用，生效”。在这个例句中，它表示蒙大拿州的禁令原定于 1 月 1 日生效。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>citing concerns about - 援引有关……的担忧。</li>    <P>原文例句：TikTok users in Montana also had filed suit last year to block the ban approved by the state legislature, which cited concerns about the personal data of Montana users and potential Chinese spying.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由cite（引用）和concern（担忧）组成，表示“引用，提及担忧”。在这个例句中，它表示蒙大拿州的用户去年也提起了诉讼来阻止该州议会批准的禁令，该禁令援引了对蒙大拿州用户个人数据和潜在中国间谍活动的担忧。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TikTok teams up with fact checkers to stop election disinformation on site - TikTok 与事实核查人员合作，阻止网站上的选举错误信息。<p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是TikTok，谓语是teams up with，宾语是fact checkers。fact checkers是一个名词短语，充当宾语，表示事实核查人员。to stop election disinformation on site是一个不定式短语，作目的状语，表示阻止网站上的选举错误信息。这个句子的意思是说，TikTok 与事实核查人员合作，阻止网站上的选举错误信息。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词结构 - 用于修饰名词或代词。    <p>原文例句：saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词结构是一种非谓语结构，由一个分词和其修饰语组成。它可以用来修饰名词或代词。在这个例句中，分词结构是saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’。它修饰了前面的名词injunction，表示这是一个初步禁令，理由是蒙大拿州法律超越了州权力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>倒装句型 - 把句子中正常的语序颠倒过来。    <p>原文例句：TikTok and Knudsen’s office did not immediately comment.</p>    <p>语法讲解：倒装句型是指把句子中正常的语序颠倒过来。它通常用于强调句子的某个成分或使句子更具文采。在这个例句中，句子中的主语和谓语的顺序被颠倒了。这样做是为了强调句子的主语TikTok和Knudsen’s office。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice that the state is appealing the ruling to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals</li>
<li>US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’</li>
</ul><p>Montana said on Tuesday it was appealing a decision by a US judge in November to block the state's first-of-its kind ban on the use of short-video sharing app TikTok.</p><p>Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice that the state is appealing the ruling to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals.</p><p>Montana’s ban had been set to take effect on January 1, but US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban on the Chinese-owned app, saying Montana’s law “violates the Constitution in more ways than one” and “oversteps state power”.</p><p>TikTok and Knudsen’s office did not immediately comment. Molloy had previously said preliminary pretrial statements were due by January 16.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246313/taiwan-elections-tiktok-teams-fact-checkers-stop-disinformation-site" title="">TikTok teams up with fact checkers to stop election disinformation on site</a></h3><p>TikTok users in Montana also had filed suit last year to block the ban approved by the state legislature, which cited concerns about the personal data of Montana users and potential Chinese spying.</p><p>In earlier court filings, TikTok said it “has not shared, and would not share, US user data with the Chinese government, and has taken substantial measures to protect the privacy and security of TikTok users”. Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government and the state’s action was too sweeping.</p><p>TikTok has faced efforts by some in Congress to ban the app or give the Biden administration's powers to impose restrictions or bar foreign-owned apps, but those efforts have stalled.</p><p>Many states and the US government have barred TikTok on government-owned devices, but only Montana has sought to completely bar the app’s use.</p><p>Former President Donald Trump in 2020 sought to bar new downloads of TikTok and Chinese-owned WeChat, but a series of court decisions blocked the effective ban from taking effect.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple hits 7-week low after Barclays downgrade on demand concerns</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Apple's shares saw a considerable surge in 2023, reaching a record high in mid-December during the dominance of Big Tech companies in the markets. However, the company has faced challenges due to a demand slowdown since early 2022 and has forecasted holiday-quarter sales lower than Wall Street estimates. Barclays downgraded Apple's shares expressing concerns about weak demand for its devices in 2024, leading to a decline in the stock's value.  Meanwhile, analysts generally have a positive view of Apple's prospects, recommending it as a "buy" with a median price target of $200.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's stock experienced a significant rise in 2023 followed by a decline due to concerns about demand and the company's services business.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's stock performance and market trends in 2023 amidst challenges and analyst recommendations.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Barclays' downgrade of Apple's shares due to demand concerns, emphasizing the impact on market capitalization and analyst ratings.</li>    <li>Main information: Apple's share price increase in 2023, Barclays' downgrade to "underweight," holiday-quarter sales forecast below estimates, analysts' "buy" recommendation with a median price target of $200.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  苹果公司股票在 2023 年大幅上涨，在 12 月中旬达到历史高点，当时大型科技公司引领市场。然而，该公司自 2022 年初以来面临需求放缓的挑战，并预测假日季度的销售额低于华尔街的估计。巴克莱将苹果股票评级下调，表达对 2024 年其设备需求疲软的担忧，导致股价下跌。与此同时，分析师普遍对苹果的前景持积极态度，建议将其评级为“买入”，目标价格中值为 200 美元。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果股票在 2023 年经历了大幅上涨，随后下跌，原因是担心需求和公司服务业务。</li>    <li>主题：苹果股票表现和 2023 年市场趋势，面临挑战和分析师建议。</li>    <li>观点：巴克莱将苹果股票评级下调至“减持”，强调对市场资本和分析师评级的重大影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果公司股票在 2023 年上涨、巴克莱下调评级至“减持”、假日季度销售额预测低于估计、分析师建议“买入”，目标价格中值为 200 美元。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Subdued (adj.) - /səbˈdjud/ 抑制的，柔和的。    <p>原文例句：“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long said in a client note, pointing to the China weakness as well as subdued demand in developed markets.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Subdued”表示“抑制的，柔和的”，在这个语境中，它描述了发达市场的需求被抑制，没有达到预期的水平。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Underweight (adj.) - /ˈʌndərweɪt/ 权重较低。    <p>原文例句：Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral” and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Underweight”表示“权重较低”，在这个语境中，它描述了巴克莱将苹果股票的评级从“中性”下调至“减持”，这意味着巴克莱认为苹果股票在投资组合中的权重应该降低。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Holiday-quarter sales - 假日季度销售额。    <p>原文例句：Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Holiday-quarter sales”表示“假日季度销售额”，在这个语境中，它指的是苹果公司在假日季度的销售业绩。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Demand slowdown - 需求放缓。    <p>原文例句：Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Demand slowdown”表示“需求放缓”，在这个语境中，它指的是苹果公司自去年年初以来面临的需求下降。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral” and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160. - 巴克莱将该股票评级从“中性”下调至“减持”，并将 12 个月的价格目标从 1 美元下调至 160 美元。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Barclays downgraded the stock，其中主语是Barclays，谓语是downgraded，宾语是the stock。to “underweight” from “neutral”是一个介词短语作状语，表示从“中性”下调至“减持”。and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160是一个并列句，其中trimmed its 12-month price target是主句，by US$1 to US$160是状语，表示价格目标下调了1美元至160美元。这个句子的意思是说，巴克莱将苹果股票的评级从“中性”下调至“减持”，并将12个月的价格目标从1美元下调至160美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时态 - 表示现在已经完成或开始的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态的常用结构是have/has+过去分词，表示现在已经完成或开始的动作或状态。在这个例句中，has been grappling表示“一直在努力应对”，been是从grapple的过去分词，grapple是一个动词，意思是努力应对。has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year这句话的意思是说，苹果公司自去年年初以来一直在努力应对需求放缓的情况。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子的宾语承受的，而不是主语发出的。    <p>原文例句：Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral” and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态的常用结构是be+过去分词，表示动作或状态是由句子的宾语承受的，而不是主语发出的。在这个例句中，downgraded是动词downgrade的过去分词，这句话的意思是说，巴克莱将股票评级从“中性”下调至“减持”。trim是动词，意思是修剪，trimmed是过去分词，这句话的意思是说，巴克莱将12个月的价格目标修剪了1美元至160美元。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple’s shares rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech firms led the markets</li>
<li>The company has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates</li>
</ul><p>Apple on Tuesday fell nearly 3.6 per cent to a seven-week low after Barclays downgraded the shares of the world’s most valuable company on concerns that demand for its devices, from the iPhone to the Mac, will remain weak in 2024.</p><p>Barclays is the second brokerage to have the equivalent of a “sell” rating on the stock, which now has its most number of bearish recommendations in at least two years, according to LSEG data.</p><p>The stock accounts for a hefty 7 per cent of the S&amp;P 500’s market weight – the broader index was dragged 0.56 per cent lower on Tuesday.</p><p>Apple rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech companies led the markets.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245817/apple-ramps-vision-pro-production-aiming-launch-february" title="">Apple ramps up Vision Pro production, aiming for launch by February</a></h3><p>Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates. Its performance in China has also been a worry after the revival of local rival Huawei Technologies.</p><p>“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long said in a client note, pointing to the China weakness as well as subdued demand in developed markets.</p><p>Long is rated four out of five stars for his recommendation accuracy on Apple, according to LSEG data.</p><p>The brokerage also warned risks were mounting for Apple’s services business, which has come under the scanner in countries including the United States over app store practices.</p><p>The business has often outpaced growth in Apple’s hardware segment in recent years and now accounts for nearly a quarter of the company’s total revenue.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3246322/us-import-ban-certain-apple-watch-models-takes-effect-over-patent-clash" title="">Apple to appeal US watch ban in patent dispute</a></h3><p>The stock rout on Tuesday erased more than US$100 billion of Apple’s market capitalisation, as its shares closed at US$185.64.</p><p>Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral” and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160. Before Tuesday, Itau BBA’s “sell” was the only bearish rating on Apple since July 2022.</p><p>Analysts, on average, rate the iPhone maker “buy”, with a median price target of US$200. The company trades at about 28.7 times its 12-month forward earnings estimates, much higher than the S&amp;P 500’s 19.8.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
