<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s logistics arm Cainiao offers shoppers in US grouped delivery service, cutting shipping times to five days</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247829/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-offers-shoppers-us-grouped-delivery-service-cutting-shipping-times</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Cainiao, a logistics unit of Alibaba Group, has announced a new cross-border shipping service for Chinese customers in the US. This service will enable customers to bundle their purchases from Chinese e-commerce websites and have them shipped together, reducing delivery times and costs. The service is expected to boost the company's cross-border logistics business and contribute to its planned US$1 billion listing in Hong Kong.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Cainiao launches a consolidated shipping service for Chinese consumers in the US.</li>    <li>Theme: Optimizing delivery times and costs for cross-border e-commerce purchases.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: This initiative addresses the growing demand for efficient international shipping services and supports Cainiao's expansion into overseas markets.</li>    <li>Main information: Service covers air and sea transport routes, consolidates online shopping orders from various platforms, and aims to reduce delivery times and costs. Cainiao's recent cross-border parcel deliveries exceeded 1.5 billion, making it a leading logistics provider globally.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  阿里巴巴集团的物流子公司菜鸟，宣布针对美国境内的中国消费者推出跨境运输新服务。这项服务将允许消费者将从中国电子商务网站购买的商品捆绑在一起包装，并一起运输，从而减少交货时间和成本。预计这项服务将提振公司的跨境物流业务，并为其计划在香港进行的 10 亿美元上市做出贡献。  <ul>    <li>摘要：菜鸟为美国中国消费者推出拼箱运输服务。</li>    <li>主题：优化跨境电子商务购物的配送时间和成本。</li>    <li>观点：这项举措满足了对高效国际运输服务日益增长的需求，并支持菜鸟向海外市场扩张。</li>    <li>主要信息：该服务涵盖空运和海运路线，将来自不同平台的在线购物订单集中起来，并旨在减少交货时间和成本。菜鸟最近的跨境包裹配送量超过 15 亿件，使其成为全球领先的物流供应商。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>warehouse (n.) - /ˈweərˌhaʊs/ 仓库，货栈。    <p>原文例句：The so-called “consolidated shipping” service, covering both air and sea transport routes, will collect multiple online shopping orders placed by users on various platforms in a warehouse before shipping them from China. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由ware（货物）和house（房子）组成，表示“仓库，货栈”。在这个例句中，它指的是一个收集用户在不同平台上下的多笔在线购物订单，然后从中国发货的仓库。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>logistics (n.) - /lɔːˈdʒɪstɪks/ 物流学，运输管理学。    <p>原文例句：Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics unit, will open a new service for consumers in the US to allow them to package several items they have bought together, cutting delivery times to as little as five days. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由logo（逻辑）和istics（学问）组成，表示“物流学，运输管理学”。在这个例句中，它指的是菜鸟，阿里巴巴集团的物流子公司，将为美国消费者开通一项新服务，允许他们将购买的多件商品打包在一起，将送货时间缩短至五天。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>delivery (n.) - /dɪˈlɪvəri/ 分娩，交付，递送。    <p>原文例句：If the parcel is sent via air, delivery times may be reduced five days after the items are sent out from the warehouse. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由de-（离开）和livery（交付）组成，表示“分娩，交付，递送”。在这个例句中，它指的是包裹的送达，如果包裹是通过航空运输，在包裹从仓库发出后五天内就可以送达。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>subject to - 受到……的影响，以……为准。    <p>原文例句：Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to a Post report in September that cited people familiar with the situation. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由subject（主体）和to（向）组成，表示“受到……的影响，以……为准”。在这个例句中，它表示菜鸟的目标是筹集至少 10 亿美元，但具体取决于市场状况。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>make up - 组成，构成。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba announced it would spin off Cainiao in the restructuring announced in March.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由make（制造）和up（向上）组成，表示“组成，构成”。在这个例句中，它表示阿里巴巴宣布将在 3 月份宣布的重组中剥离菜鸟。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Prior to its US expansion, Cainiao provided consolidated shipping to shoppers in other markets outside mainland China, including Hong Kong, Singapore and Australia. - 在其美国扩张之前，菜鸟已向中国大陆以外其他市场（包括香港、新加坡和澳大利亚）的消费者提供合单运输服务。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Cainiao provided consolidated shipping to shoppers，其中主语是Cainiao，谓语是provided consolidated shipping，宾语是to shoppers。Prior to its US expansion是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示在菜鸟美国扩张之前。in other markets outside mainland China是一个介词短语作地点状语，表示在中国大陆以外的其他市场，包括香港、新加坡和澳大利亚。这个句子的意思是说，在菜鸟美国扩张之前，菜鸟已向中国大陆以外的其他市场（包括香港、新加坡和澳大利亚）的消费者提供合单运输服务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子中的某一部分。    <p>原文例句：The so-called “consolidated shipping” service covers both air and sea transport routes.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句型，强调了句中的so-called “consolidated shipping” service。结构是：It is/was + 被强调部分 + that/who + 其他部分。在这个例句中，be动词是is，被强调部分是so-called “consolidated shipping” service，that从句是covers both air and sea transport routes。这个句子的意思是说，所谓的“拼箱运输”服务覆盖了空运和海运两种运输方式。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>祈使句 - 用于表示命令、请求或建议。    <p>原文例句：Please don't get us fired. I need this urgently for an important project.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个祈使句，表示说话人对听话人的命令、请求或建议。结构是：Please/Kindly/Would you please + 动词原形 + 其他。在这个例句中，说话人是第一人称，动词原形是get，其他部分是us fired。这个句子的意思是说，请不要让我们被解雇，我急需这个重要的项目。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Cainiao said cross-border shipping service would mainly help Chinese consumers in US who tend to buy lots of goods on Chinese sites</li>
<li>The so-called ‘consolidated shipping’ service covers both air and sea transport routes</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/8c90f6e8-359a-4cee-bbfa-62226abce761_8e97fde8.jpg" /><figcaption>The so-called ‘consolidated shipping’ service covers both air and sea transport routes. Photo: Handout  </figcaption></figure><p>Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics unit, will open a new service for consumers in the US to allow them to package several items they have bought together, cutting delivery times to as little as five days.</p><p>Cainiao said in a statement on Tuesday that the cross-border shipping service would mainly help Chinese consumers and students in the US who tend to buy lots of goods on Chinese e-commerce sites. As of 2020, there were roughly 60 million Chinese living outside the country, according to a report by Huaqiao University.</p><p>If the parcel is sent via air, delivery times may be reduced five days after the items are sent out from the warehouse. If by sea, the new service may cut the cost to as low as 12 yuan (US$1.7), depending on the size of the parcel, according to the statement.</p><p>The new overseas service comes ahead of Cainiao’s planned US$1 billion listing in Hong Kong. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247710/alibabas-aliexpress-pdd-owned-temu-face-supply-chain-challenges-south-korea-amid-rapid-business" title="">Alibaba’s AliExpress, PDD-owned Temu face supply chain challenges in South Korea</a></h3><p>The so-called “consolidated shipping” service, covering both air and sea transport routes, will collect multiple online shopping orders placed by users on various platforms in a warehouse before shipping them from China.</p><p>Prior to its US expansion, Cainiao provided consolidated shipping to shoppers in other markets outside mainland China, including Hong Kong, Singapore and Australia.</p><p>In November, Cainiao and Alibaba were part of a consortium that made a US$57 million offer to buy Chinese logistics company Best. Best is a major courier in China and has a presence in Southeast Asia. In the third quarter of 2023, Best’s global businesses achieved revenue of US$37.7 million, contributing to 12.4 per cent of the total.</p><p>Cainiao has its eye on the overseas market, and recorded more than 1.5 billion cross-border e-commerce parcel deliveries in its recent financial year to March, making it one of the world’s top logistics services providers, according to its prospectus.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to a Post report in September that cited people familiar with the situation. The listing is part of a group-wide restructuring of Alibaba, as the e-commerce titan seeks to free up decision- making amid increased competition.</p><p>Established in 2013, Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s e-commerce empire, handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023. Alibaba announced it would spin off Cainiao in the restructuring announced in March.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China TV makers Hisense and TCL promote AI, live sports at US show</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247808/ces-2024-china-tv-makers-hisense-and-tcl-promote-ai-live-sports-us-show</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In a competitive display at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Chinese television giants Hisense and TCL unveiled their latest line-ups, emphasizing artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities and pushing into new areas like augmented reality (AR) and virtual reality (VR). Both companies touted their in-house production capabilities and supply chain prowess, while showcasing advancements in mini-LED technology and laser TVs. Sports and AI-enhanced picture quality were key themes, as both brands aimed to establish themselves as leading forces in the global television market.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese TV brands Hisense and TCL showcase AI-powered TVs and explore new technologies at CES 2024.</li>    <li>Theme: Competition and innovation among Chinese TV brands in the areas of AI, mini-LEDs, and emerging technologies.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of in-house production and supply chain control in maintaining a competitive edge.</li>    <li>Main information: Unveiling of new TV models with advanced AI features; emphasis on mini-LED technology and laser TVs; exploration of AR glasses, smart glasses, and VR headsets; partnerships with carmakers to integrate technology into vehicles.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国电视巨头海信和TCL在拉斯维加斯举行的2024年国际消费类电子产品展览会（CES）上激烈竞争，展示了各自最新的产品阵容，强调人工智能（AI）功能，并进军增强现实（AR）和虚拟现实（VR）等新领域。两家公司都宣称其拥有自主生产能力和供应链优势，同时展示了在Mini LED技术和激光电视方面的进步。体育和基于AI的画质提升是本次展会的主题，两大品牌都旨在树立其在全球电视市场中的领导地位。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国电视品牌海信和TCL在2024年国际消费类电子产品展览会上展示了搭载人工智能技术的电视，并探索了新技术。</li>    <li>主题：中国电视品牌在人工智能、Mini LED和新兴技术领域的竞争与创新。</li>    <li>观点：自主生产和供应链控制在保持竞争优势中的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：推出搭载先进人工智能功能的新款电视；强调Mini LED技术和激光电视；探索AR眼镜、智能眼镜和VR头盔；与汽车制造商合作，将技术集成到汽车中。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unveil (v.) - /ʌnˈveɪl/ 揭幕，公布。    <p>原文例句：Chinese television set makers Hisense and TCL unveiled their latest line-ups at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday, with an emphasis on artificial intelligence (AI) and making screens the centre of the home, while pushing into new areas like cars.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语dévoiler，表示“揭示，公布”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国电视制造商海信和TCL在拉斯维加斯举行的2024年国际消费类电子产品展览会上公布了他们的最新产品阵容。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>emphasis (n.) - /ˈɛmfəsɪs/ 强调，重点。    <p>原文例句：Both companies offered competing narratives, presenting themselves as the biggest Chinese brands in the US television space. They also boasted about their supply chain prowess and the ability to manufacture leading technologies in-house.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古希腊语émphasis，表示“重视，强调”。在这个例句中，它指的是两家公司对供应链能力和自主制造领先技术的自夸。</p></li>      </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in-house - 内部，本地的。    <p>原文例句：Hisense president David Gold on stage at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday. Photo: Matt Haldane</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“内部的，本地的”。在这个例句中，它指的是Hisense总裁David Gold在拉斯维加斯举行的2024年国际消费类电子产品展览会上的照片。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The companies emphasised their ability to produce much of their technology in-house and how they are branching out into areas like AR. - 这两家公司强调了它们能够在内部生产大量技术的能力，以及它们如何进军增强现实等领域。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The companies emphasised their ability to produce，其中主语是The companies，谓语是emphasised，宾语是their ability to produce。much of their technology in-house是一个定语从句，修饰主语The companies，表示这些公司能够在内部生产大量技术。how they are branching out into areas like AR是一个宾语从句，修饰主语The companies，表示这些公司如何进军增强现实等领域。这个句子的意思是说，这两家公司强调了它们能够在内部生产大量技术的能力，以及它们如何进军增强现实等领域。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TCL referred to itself as a “great global power” with 32 research and development centres and 43 manufacturing sites around the world.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是由have/has和过去分词构成的，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个例句中，TCL referred to itself as a “great global power”是一个现在完成时的句子，表示TCL一直以来都将自己称为一个“伟大的全球力量”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The two biggest Chinese TV brands offered competing narratives about their global stature and AI processing capabilities</li>
<li>The companies emphasised their ability to produce much of their technology in-house and how they are branching out into areas like AR</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/d720b3c6-868e-43ae-b6f8-e7b08d7057b0_128316fa.jpg" /><figcaption>Hisense USA president David Gold on stage at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese television set makers Hisense and TCL unveiled their latest line-ups at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday, with an emphasis on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence">artificial intelligence (AI)</a> and making screens the centre of the home, while pushing into new areas like cars.</p><p>Both companies offered competing narratives, presenting themselves as the biggest Chinese brands in the US television space. They also boasted about their supply chain prowess and the ability to manufacture leading technologies in-house.</p><p>David Gold, president of Hisense USA, said the company’s ability to produce displays and even its own AI chipsets without third parties is something that sets it apart.</p><p>“When you think about global players, I think we are one of less than a handful of companies that have everything that it takes to be able to truly provide a smart home solution,” Gold said after the Hisense presentation. “We have all the ingredients, all the components. There are very few companies out there that can do the same.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>The flagship product from Hisense this year is its new 110-inch ULED X television with a brightness of 10,000 nits and 40,000 backlight zones.</p><p>Not to be outdone, TCL announced what it said is the world’s largest mini-LED TV at 115 inches. TCL referred to itself as a “great global power” with 32 research and development centres and 43 manufacturing sites around the world.</p><p>Mini LEDs featured prominently in the presentations of both Hisense and TCL, as they each presented their brands as the best option for finding this tech in TVs that cost just a few hundred dollars, rather than thousands.</p><p>Hisense said that mini LEDs – which cram more LEDs into a display to offer a greater range of contrast and image quality – are now integrated into all its models, including one for under US$500.</p><p>Hisense also introduced its new so-called laser TVs, which are projectors combined with an ambient-light-rejecting screen. The company said its newest 8K Sonic Laser TV is the “world’s largest sound-emitting screen”, offering a sound bar-like experience built into the projector. It is also offering a new Rollable Laser TV, which is exactly what it sounds like: a projector screen that rolls up and disappears, offering a cleaner look at home when not in use.</p><p>Both companies used sports to draw attention to their new TVs. As more viewers switch to streaming, the focus on live television has largely fallen to sports, a major reason households remain subscribed to cable and satellite TV packages.</p><p>TCL leaned into this heavily, inviting sportscasters including Charissa Thompson and former National Football League player Charles Woodson on stage for nearly the entire duration of the presentation.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/e0266ca3-3156-4fd7-af77-61200f190c62_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Hisense highlighted the ability of its AI chips to enhance picture quality by identifying whether the video is coming from streaming, cable or another source.</p><p>“[Our AI is] about recognising what content it is, the quality, the factor in which it’s being displayed – whether it’s streaming, cable, DVDs, Blu-ray – and finding the way to enhance that picture quality,” Gold said. “Usually you put in one setting and never change it again. What we’re trying to do with AI is automatically detect, ‘Oh, now you’re watching football, let’s move to a sport setting’.”</p><p>Seemingly omnipresent at CES 2024, AI was mentioned repeatedly during both presentations, as it has been by rivals like Samsung and LG.</p><p>TCL talked of enhancing access to its AI processing with three levels of its AIPQ processors, which include “pro” and “ultra” versions. The AI processors are now offered in its cheaper S Class series.</p><p>While TVs are typically the highlight for these events from the Chinese display giants, they are also chasing other trends in the industry. TCL mentioned the latest version of the RayNeo X2 smart glasses, which can display images on the lenses to do things like offer real-time text translation. TCL incubated RayNeo.</p><p>The company also highlighted its newest smartphones and tablets with an emphasis on its Nxtpaper display, which is meant to be easier on the eyes like e-reader displays.</p><p>Hisense is working on its own augmented reality (AR) glasses and a virtual reality headset, but both are just prototypes for now.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1229" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/5dbb9d8d-418e-45e8-ade6-ea407301ebfc_dc8aec28.jpg" title="Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>It has also followed many of its Chinese peers – like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a> – into the auto sector. It is working on bringing its projector technology into cars to, among other things, turn the windscreen into an AR display. The company said this enhances safety because drivers do not need to take their eyes off the road when getting information like navigation.</p><p>“If you’re on the road and your smart refrigerator can tell you, ‘hey, you’re out of eggs; so on your way home, stop by and pick up some eggs,’ that’s the idea that we’re going for,” Gold said.</p><p>Many tech firms are betting on cars as the next big area of growth. As leaders in electric vehicles, Chinese companies are benefiting from the trend. Carmakers <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto">Li Auto</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/great-wall-motors" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/great-wall-motors">Great Wall Motor</a>, Zeekr and Xiaomi will all <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector">use Nvidia’s Drive tech</a> for autonomous driving, the chip firm announced on Monday.</p><p>Samsung and Sony also discussed their own partnerships with carmakers in their presentations on Monday. Sony has partnered with Honda on its Afeela joint venture, while Samsung is partnering with Hyundai to bring its SmartThings platform to cars.</p><p>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>JD.com’s on-demand delivery unit, Dada Nexus, loses 46 per cent of US stock value overnight amid internal inquiry into potential fraud</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247804/jdcoms-demand-delivery-unit-dada-nexus-loses-46-cent-us-stock-value-overnight-amid-internal-inquiry</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  - Dada Nexus, a Chinese on-demand delivery firm affiliated with JD.com, lost 46% of its stock value after an internal audit revealed 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) in questionable revenue and costs.  - The audit, conducted during the first three quarters of 2023, raised concerns about the company's financial integrity and led to the resignation of several top executives, including the chairman and chief financial officer.  - The incident has further eroded investor confidence in Chinese tech stocks and highlights the need for stronger corporate governance and internal controls in the sector.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Internal audit reveals questionable financial data at Dada Nexus, causing stock plunge and executive departures.</li>    <li>Theme: Financial irregularities at a Chinese tech company raise concerns about corporate governance and investor confidence.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The need for transparency and accountability in the Chinese tech sector to rebuild investor trust.</li>    <li>Main information: Identification of questionable revenue and costs during internal audit; resignations of top executives; impact on investor confidence in Chinese tech stocks.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  - 与京东关联的中国即时配送公司达达快送在内部审计中发现10亿元人民币（1.4亿美元）可疑收入和成本，股价暴跌46%。  - 在2023年前三个季度的审计中，公司财务出现问题，导致多位高管辞职，包括董事长和首席财务官。  - 该事件进一步侵蚀了投资者对中国科技股的信心，凸显了该行业加强公司治理和内部控制的必要性。  <ul>    <li>摘要：内部审计发现达达快送财务数据可疑，导致股价暴跌和高管离职。</li>    <li>主题：中国科技公司财务违规，引发对公司治理和投资者信心的担忧。</li>    <li>观点：中国科技行业需要透明度和问责制，以重建投资者信任。</li>    <li>主要信息：内部审计中发现可疑收入和成本；高管辞职；对中国科技股投资者信心的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>audit (n.) - /ˈɑːdɪt/ 审计    <p>原文例句：A routine internal audit at Dada found US$140 million worth of questionable revenue and costs in the firm’s books for the first three quarters of 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词源于拉丁语audire（倾听），表示“对财务记录或账户进行检查和核实”。在这个例句中，它指的是达达公司在2023年前三个季度对其财务账目进行的例行内部审计。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fraud (n.) - /frɔːd/ 欺诈    <p>原文例句：A potential case of fraud at JD.com-affiliated, on-demand delivery firm Dada Nexus could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese tech stocks.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词来源于古法语fraude，表示“欺骗或不诚实的行为”。在这个例句中，它指的是京东旗下的即时配送公司达达快送可能存在欺诈行为，这可能会进一步损害投资者对中国科技股的信心。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>internal audit - 内部审计    <p>原文例句：A routine internal audit at Dada found US$140 million worth of questionable revenue and costs in the firm’s books for the first three quarters of 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由internal（内部的）和audit（审计）组成，表示“对组织或公司的财务记录和账户进行审查”。在这个例句中，它指的是达达公司对2023年前三个季度的财务账目进行的例行内部审计。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Dada Nexus, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit, according to its corporate filing. - 达达快送在2023年前三个季度的例行内部审计中发现，其财务账目中有10亿元人民币（1.4亿美元）的可疑收入和成本，根据其公司文件显示。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Dada Nexus found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books，其中主语是Dada Nexus，谓语是found，宾语是1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs。which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰Dada Nexus，表示达达快送运营京东到家和达达快送。during a routine internal audit是一个介词短语作状语，表示审计的时间，即在例行内部审计中。according to its corporate filing是一个介词短语作状语，表示消息来源，即根据其公司文件显示。这个句子的意思是说，达达快送在2023年前三个季度的例行内部审计中发现，其财务账目中有10亿元人民币（1.4亿美元）的可疑收入和成本，根据其公司文件显示。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作定语 - 用于修饰名词或代词，提供更多信息。    <p>原文例句：The audit, conducted during the first three quarters of 2023, raised concerns about the company's financial integrity and led to the resignation of several top executives, including the chairman and chief financial officer.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，conducted during the first three quarters of 2023是一个过去分词短语，作定语，修饰audit，表示审计是在2023年前三个季度进行的。这个短语提供了更多关于审计的信息，包括审计的时间范围。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>动名词短语作主语 - 用于构成主句的主语，表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The investigation at Dada comes nearly a month since the company’s chairman, Xin Lijun, stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” effective on December 19.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，The investigation at Dada是一个动名词短语，作主语，表示对达达的调查。这个短语表示了一个动作或状态，即对达达的调查。需要注意的是，动名词短语作主语时，动词通常采用现在分词形式。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>A routine internal audit at Dada found US$140 million worth of questionable revenue and costs in the firm’s books for the first three quarters of 2023</li>
<li>Shanghai-based Dada has reported the potential case of fraud to police, according to local media</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/c047f84e-6340-412a-9bce-843911227d91_14f4c464.jpg" /><figcaption>A potential case of fraud at JD.com-affiliated, on-demand delivery firm Dada Nexus could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese tech stocks. Image: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>An on-demand delivery firm affiliated with Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> lost 46 per cent of its stock value in New York on Monday, following an inquiry into “suspicious” data during an internal audit, dealing a fresh blow to confidence in China’s tech stocks.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3195587/jdcoms-logistics-arm-pushes-ahead-unmanned-robotic-grocery-deliveries" target="_self" title="">Dada Nexus</a>, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit, according to its corporate filing. Parent JD.com’s share price tumbled 3 per cent on Tuesday in Hong Kong.</p><p>Nasdaq-listed Dada said an estimated 500 million yuan of online advertising and marketing service revenue plus another 500 million yuan of operations and support costs for the first three quarters of 2023 may have been overstated.</p><p>While the amount that is subject of the inquiry makes up just about a third of Dada’s total revenue in the September quarter, a potential fraud in the company’s books could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> stocks.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/933378cf-3ccc-42bf-a060-3d2efc2145c7_55c83460.jpg" title="Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The investigation at Dada comes nearly a month since the company’s chairman, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241791/chinese-e-commerce-giant-jdcom-removes-veteran-executive-retail-ceo-after-brutal-singles-day-price" target="_self" title="">Xin Liju</a>n, stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” effective on December 19. In that same corporate announcement of management changes at Dada, Chen Zhaoming resigned as the firm’s chief financial officer.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a>-based Dada, according to a report by Chinese news outlet The Paper, has reported the potential fraud case to local police.</p><p>A JD.com representative referred the South China Morning Post to Dada’s US filing and declined to provide further details. Dada did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Tuesday.</p><p>Dada had earlier said it was working with third-party agencies, including an accounting company and a law firm, to conduct an independent review of the case.</p><p>In separate filings with regulators, both JD.com and Dada said they are committed to maintaining high corporate-governance standards and internal controls.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246715/chinese-e-commerce-giant-jdcom-wins-antitrust-lawsuit-against-alibaba-which-was-ordered-beijing" title="">Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com wins antitrust lawsuit against Alibaba</a></h3><p>Founded in Shanghai in 2014, Dada runs two core businesses: parent JD.com’s on-demand retail platform JD Daojia and its own Dada Now. Both these operations work with bricks-and-mortar retailers and merchants on fulfilment, including delivery of online orders to consumers in under roughly an hour.</p><p>JD Daojia operates in more than 1,700 counties, districts and cities across mainland China, while Dada Now does business in 2,700 domestic locations.</p><p>In November, Dada reported that total third-quarter revenue rose 20.4 per cent year on year to 2.9 billion yuan.</p><p>On-demand delivery is a hotly contested field on the mainland, where Dada competes against the likes of food delivery giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> and JD.com rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, which owns the Post.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance confirms talks with Tencent, other potential buyers over sale of video game operations</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  ByteDance, the owner of TikTok, is in talks with several potential buyers, including Tencent, for the sale of its video game operations. This decision comes after the company failed to achieve returns from its gaming investments despite spending heavily on game development. ByteDance has been restructuring its gaming business and focusing on long-term strategic growth areas.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: ByteDance is selling its video game operations after failing to generate returns from its gaming investments.</li>    <li>Theme: ByteDance's unsuccessful venture into the video game industry and its decision to restructure its gaming business.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The challenges faced by tech companies in the video game industry; the importance of focusing on core competencies.</li>    <li>Main information: Negotiations with potential buyers; restructuring of the gaming business; ByteDance's previous investments in video games.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  字节跳动，也就是 TikTok 的所有者，正在与多家潜在买家谈判，其中包括腾讯，以出售其视频游戏业务。做出这个决定是因为字节跳动在游戏开发上投入巨资，但未能从其游戏投资中获得回报。字节跳动一直在重组其游戏业务，并专注于长期的战略增长领域。  <ul>    <li>摘要：字节跳动在未能从其游戏投资中获得回报后，正在出售其视频游戏业务。</li>    <li>主题：字节跳动在视频游戏行业的失败尝试，以及其决定重组游戏业务。</li>    <li>观点：科技公司在视频游戏行业面临的挑战；专注于核心能力的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：与潜在买家的谈判；游戏业务的重组；字节跳动以前在视频游戏上的投资。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.njuː/ 收入，营业额。    <p>原文例句：Tencent Holdings, the world’s biggest gaming company by revenue.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于法语，表示“收入，营业额，收益”。在这个例句中，它指的是腾讯公司通过其游戏业务获得的收入。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>lay-off (n.) - /ˈleɪ ɔːf/ 暂时解雇，裁员。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance also started lay-offs at its games unit, which employs nearly 2,000 people.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由lay（躺下）和off（离开）构成的，表示“暂时解雇，裁员”。在这个例句中，它指的是字节跳动对其游戏部门进行裁员。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>enthusiast (n.) - /ɪnˈθjuːziæst/ 爱好者，热情者。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance founder Zhang Yiming, who stepped down as chairman and CEO in 2021, was never a video gaming enthusiast before dipping his toe in the market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于希腊语，表示“爱好者，热情者”。在这个例句中，它指的是字节跳动创始人张一鸣，他并不是一个视频游戏爱好者。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>shut down - 关闭，停业。    <p>原文例句：The company told employees that it would shut down most game projects that had not been released online.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由shut（关闭）和down（向下）构成的，表示“关闭，停业”。在这个例句中，它指的是字节跳动关闭其大部分尚未发布的游戏项目。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>strategic move - 战略举措，策略性行动。    <p>原文例句：Some workers who want to remain at ByteDance could be allowed to transfer to other teams, the Post reported.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由strategic（战略的）和move（行动）构成的，表示“战略举措，策略性行动”。在这个例句中，它指的是字节跳动允许一些员工转到其他团队。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>regulatory move - 监管举措，监管行动。    <p>原文例句：China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech must end, party paper says</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由regulatory（监管的）和move（行动）构成的，表示“监管举措，监管行动”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国政府对大型科技公司的监管行动。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance also started lay-offs at its games unit, which employs nearly 2,000 people, although the exact number of affected employees was not clear. - 字节跳动还对其游戏部门开始了裁员，该部门雇佣了近 2,000 人，尽管受影响的员工的确切数量尚不清楚。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是ByteDance also started lay-offs at its games unit，其中主语是ByteDance，谓语是started lay-offs，宾语是at its games unit。which employs nearly 2,000 people是一个限制性定语从句，修饰先行词ByteDance，表示字节跳动对其游戏部门开始了裁员，该部门雇佣了近 2,000 人。although the exact number of affected employees was not clear是一个让步状语从句，修饰谓语started lay-offs，表示尽管受影响的员工的确切数量尚不清楚。这个句子的意思是说，字节跳动还对其游戏部门开始了裁员，该部门雇佣了近 2,000 人，尽管受影响的员工的确切数量尚不清楚。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>时间状语从句 - 表示时间，说明句子中所述动作或事件发生的时间。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance also started lay-offs at its games unit, which employs nearly 2,000 people, although the exact number of affected employees was not clear. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时间状语从句，位于主句之前，由when引导，表示“当……”或“在……的时候”。在这个句子中，它表示“当字节跳动在其游戏部门开始裁员时”。時間狀語從句裡面有從句的主詞The exact number of affected employees，謂語was not clear，可以分析成名詞子句，在從句中作主語。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>让步状语从句 - 表示句子中所述动作或事件尽管受到阻碍或限制，但仍然发生。    <p>原文例句：Tencent Holdings, the world’s biggest gaming company by revenue.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个让步状语从句，由although引导，表示“尽管……”或“即使……”。在这个例句中，它表示“尽管腾讯公司是世界上最大的游戏公司，但它仍然面临着挑战”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Local media reported that ByteDance was lowering the valuation of its gaming studios to try and make a deal after spending more than US$14 million developing titles</li>
<li>Despite its huge success with short video app TikTok and its Chinese version Douyin, ByteDance has failed to achieve returns from its gaming investments</li>
</ul><p>TikTok owner ByteDance has confirmed that it is in talks with multiple potential buyers for its video game operations, including Tencent Holdings, the world’s biggest gaming company by revenue.</p><p>The confirmation from a ByteDance representative on Tuesday came after local media outlet LatePost reported that the company's gaming unit Nuverse was in negotiations with Tencent regarding the disposal of its operations. According to the report, ByteDance was lowering the valuation of its video gaming studios to try and make a deal after spending more than 100 million yuan (US$14 million) developing various titles.</p><p>The representative said that the company has not reached an agreement with Tencent.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242972/tiktok-owner-bytedance-retreats-video-gaming-cuts-main-studio-amid-stagnating-market-dominated" target="_self" title="">In November, the South China Morning Post reported</a> that the Beijing-based company told employees that it would shut down most game projects that had not been released online, and sell rights to at least two of its titles – the anime-style role-playing game <em>Crystal of Atlan</em> and sci-fi survival game <em>Earth: Revival.</em></p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after" title="">China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech must end, party paper says</a></h3><p>ByteDance also started lay-offs at its games unit, which employs nearly 2,000 people, although the exact number of affected employees was not clear. Some workers who want to remain at ByteDance could be allowed to transfer to other teams, the Post reported.</p><p>A ByteDance representative said at the time that it decided to “restructure its gaming business” and “make adjustments to focus on long-term strategic growth areas”.</p><p>Despite its huge success with short video app TikTok and its Chinese version Douyin, ByteDance has failed to achieve returns from its video gaming investments. The company spent around 30 billion yuan on video game acquisitions and investments involving more than 20 studios between 2019 and 2022, according to local media outlet DingjiaoOne.</p><p>“While the company made US$54 billion in the first half of 2023, less than 1 per cent of that came from their video games business,” said Lisa Hanson, chief executive of gaming industry consultancy Niko Partners.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Crystal of Atlan, the action role-playing game developed by ByteDance’s Nuverse studio, is up for sale. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1037" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/1b444be4-f8e0-4989-bcc0-6ad82a22dc7a_d4f55384.jpg" title="Crystal of Atlan, the action role-playing game developed by ByteDance’s Nuverse studio, is up for sale. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Crystal of Atlan, the action role-playing game developed by ByteDance’s Nuverse studio, is up for sale. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>ByteDance founder Zhang Yiming, who stepped down as chairman and CEO in 2021, was never a video gaming enthusiast before dipping his toe in the market.</p><p>Yan Shou, head of ByteDance’s video gaming unit, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246294/after-tiktok-owner-bytedance-cuts-fat-focus-fundamentals-social-commerce-challenges-and-us-election" target="_self" title="">spent most of his career in strategic investments</a> and hired several people with a consulting and strategy background to help him run the unit, the Post reported.</p><p>Zhang had grown impatient with the slow development, complaining in 2022 about the lack of progress at the gaming division during a video call with executives, saying that its Moonton studio had not grown despite doubling its headcount, tech media outlet The Information reported in December. Reuters reported a month earlier that ByteDance was in talks to sell Moonton.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia rolls out new chips, claims leadership of &#39;AI PC&#39; race</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247752/nvidia-rolls-out-new-chips-claims-leadership-ai-pc-race</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia unveiled new products at the CES trade show in Las Vegas, including three new desktop graphics chips with extra components for AI use.</li>    <li>The company claims its new graphics chips are the best engines to power the new types of laptops and desktops, offering an order-of-magnitude improvement over Intel-powered machines.</li>    <li>Nvidia also unveiled an RTX 4070 Ti Super and a 4070 Super, priced at US$799 and US$599 respectively.</li>    <li>The new chips are expected to attract laptop owners and corporate buyers to upgrade their equipment, as they offer more realistic gaming, improved dialogue, and more responsive image-editing tools.</li>    <li>Nvidia said its new products will not trigger the US government's rules on AI-related chips export to China, unlike the top-of-the-line GTX 4090.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia在拉斯维加斯的CES贸易展上发布了多款新产品，其中包括三款带有额外AI组件的桌面图形芯片。</li>    <li>该公司宣称，其新型图形芯片是驱动新型笔记本和台式机电脑的最佳引擎，比英特尔驱动的机器提供了数量级提升。</li>    <li>Nvidia还公布了RTX 4070 Ti Super和4070 Super，售价分别为799美元和599美元。</li>    <li>预计新芯片将吸引笔记本电脑用户和企业购买者升级他们的设备，因为它们提供更逼真的游戏、改进的对话和更灵敏的图像编辑工具。</li>    <li>Nvidia表示，其新产品不会触发美国政府对AI相关芯片对中国的出口限制，而顶级GTX 4090会受到此类限制。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>touted (v.) - /taʊt/ 宣扬，大力宣传。    <p>原文例句：Intel and AMD have already touted AI PCs as a new era for the industry, arguing that AI software is more secure and responsive on the PC than over the internet.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由tout（吹嘘，夸耀）构成的，表示“宣扬，大力宣传”。在这个例句中，它指的是英特尔和AMD已经宣扬人工智能电脑是行业的新时代，认为人工智能软件在电脑上比在互联网上更安全、更灵敏。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>magnitude (n.) - /ˈmægnɪˌtjuːd/ 大小，程度。    <p>原文例句：Paired with new software and optimisations of AI models that Nvidia is also releasing, the products will offer an “order-of-magnitude” improvement over machines that are powered by Intel chips, according to Justin Walker, an Nvidia vice-president.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由拉丁语magnitudo（大小）构成的，表示“大小，程度”。在这个例句中，它指的是Nvidia的副总裁贾斯汀·沃克认为，与Nvidia即将发布的新软件和人工智能模型优化相结合，这些产品将比英特尔芯片驱动的机器提供数量级提升。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fall afoul of - 违反，触犯。    <P>原文例句：The top-of-the-line GTX 4090 already fell afoul of those restrictions, requiring Nvidia to produce a less-capable version for that market. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由fall（跌倒）和afoul（错误，过错）构成的，表示“违反，触犯”。在这个例句中，它指的是顶级的GTX 4090已经违反了这些限制，要求Nvidia为此市场生产一个功能较弱的版本。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia, whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software, announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”. - Nvidia whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software, announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”.<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Nvidia announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”。其中Nvidia是主语，announced 是谓语，new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”是宾语。whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software是一个定语从句，修饰Nvidia，表示Nvidia的芯片技术在用于创建人工智能软件的数据中心中占主导地位。这个句子的意思是说，Nvidia凭借其在数据中心中用于创建人工智能软件的主导地位，宣布了新产品以帮助个人电脑行业以“人工智能电脑”吸引消费者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia has avoided the worst of the PC plunge by owning the market for accelerator chips used to create AI software in data centres. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示Nvidia通过拥有用于在数据中心创建人工智能软件的加速器芯片市场来避免了个人电脑暴跌的最坏情况。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去进行时 - 表示过去正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia’s stock rose as much as 5 per cent in New York trading on Monday, taking it back above US$500 a share to a record high. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：was/were + 现在分词。其中was/were要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间正在进行，强调动作或状态的延续性。在这个例句中，it表示Nvidia的股票在纽约星期一的交易中上涨了5%，使其回升至每股500美元以上，创历史新高。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Intel and AMD have already touted AI PCs as a new era for the industry, arguing that AI software is more secure and responsive on the PC than over the internet</li>
<li>The new GeForce RTX 4080 Super&nbsp;can run Stable Diffusion XL image generation software 1.7 times faster than the equivalent model from the previous generation</li>
</ul><p>Nvidia, whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software, announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”.</p><p>Nvidia unveiled three new desktop graphics chips with extra components that will let gamers, designers and other computer users make better use of AI on their personal machines, without having to rely on remote services accessed over the internet. The chips, updated versions of existing offerings, will be offered at a “great new price”, the company said on Monday in a presentation at the CES trade show in Las Vegas.</p><p>The company's major rivals, Intel and Advanced Micro Devices, have already touted what they say is a new era for the industry: AI PCs. The companies argue that AI software is more secure and responsive when it is run on the PCs themselves rather than over the internet.</p><p>Nvidia now claims its graphics chips are the best engines to power the new types of laptops and desktops.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector" title="">Nvidia expands its reach in China’s electric vehicle sector</a></h3><p>The new GeForce RTX 4080 Super will get more processing cores and faster memory. It can run Stable Diffusion XL image generation software 1.7 times faster than the equivalent model from the previous generation of Nvidia technology, the company said. The new chip will also power games with ray tracing – building an image by calculating the path of individual rays of light – at 4K resolution.</p><p>The product is scheduled to go on sale from January 31 for US$999. The company also unveiled an RTX 4070 Ti Super for US$799 and a 4070 Super for US$599, which will be available later this month.</p><p>Paired with new software and optimisations of AI models that Nvidia is also releasing, the products will offer an “order-of-magnitude” improvement over machines that are powered by Intel chips, according to Justin Walker, an Nvidia vice-president.</p><p>Nvidia’s stock rose as much as 5 per cent in New York trading on Monday, taking it back above US$500 a share to a record high. The stock more than tripled last year, giving the company a market value of more than US$1 trillion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>After a spike in sales during the pandemic, PC shipments have fallen steeply, leaving makers and component suppliers burdened with inventory and little growth. Nvidia has avoided the worst of the PC plunge by owning the market for accelerator chips used to create AI software in data centres. The explosion in demand for that more expensive type of chip has pushed Nvidia’s market value past US$1 trillion, making it the most valuable company in the history of the semiconductor industry.</p><p>For chip makers in general, though, the majority of the volume they ship still goes into PCs. They are searching for a way to persuade laptop owners and corporate buyers to upgrade their equipment and have begun touting AI capabilities as a reason for new purchases.</p><p>Nvidia said the new chips will provide more realistic gaming with high-definition images enhanced by AI, which will also generate improved dialogue by in-game characters. In another example, the products will provide more responsive tools for image-editing software from companies such as Adobe. There are currently 500 applications that are tuned to work better with AI and Nvidia’s RTX technology, the company said.</p><p>Separately, Nvidia said the capabilities of its new products will not trigger rules put in place by the US government to limit the export of AI-related chips to China. The top-of-the-line GTX 4090 already fell afoul of those restrictions, requiring Nvidia to produce a less-capable version for that market.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s Vision Pro headset launches next month, as US tech giant seeks to expand mixed-reality market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247747/apples-vision-pro-headset-launches-next-month-company-seeks-expand-mixed-reality-market</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  苹果公司表示，全新发布的眼镜操作系统将兼容超过100万款专为iPhone和iPad设计的应用程序，预购将于1月19日开始。行业分析师认为，这款产品亮相或将为头显技术带来更广泛的用户群体，不仅仅局限于占比更大的电子游戏玩家和科技爱好者人群。苹果公司定价3500美元的高端头显设备将于2月2日起在商店正式开售，这是苹果首次开始尝试将小众技术推向更广阔的受众群体。为鼓励开发者为这款AR头显设备量身打造应用程序，苹果公司于八个月前在加州总部举办了软件发布会，首次面向公众发布这款时尚的AR头显设备。苹果公司选择发布新品的日子恰逢年度拉斯维加斯国际消费类电子展（CES）举行期间，而往年苹果公司并未出现于此活动。苹果公司还表示，其头显系统将与超过100万款为iPhone和iPad设计的应用程序兼容。预购将于1月19日开始，但消费者需要到线下实体店进行设备调试和佩戴以确保合适的佩戴方式，该款眼镜可以通过眼睛和简单的手势进行控制。高通推出混合现实芯片，旨在与苹果公司的Vision Pro头显设备一较高下。尽管脸书母公司元宇宙平台和其他公司多年来一直在致力于虚拟现实头戴设备的开发，但收效甚微。众多行业分析师认为，苹果公司有能力将头显技术的用户群体扩展到电子游戏玩家和科技爱好者的圈层之外。苹果Vision Pro头显设备在受控良好的媒体测试体验情境下，获得了相当数量媒体的高度赞扬，但设备的高昂售价或意味着其在市场的第一年销售业绩整体上相对疲软。这款设备于苹果2023年全球开发者大会上公开亮相，这是自十年前其智能手表发布以来的首款全新产品，这可能为未来为更广泛的受众群体推出更加实惠的头显设备奠定基础。如今，Vision Pro的定价是Meta旗下的最新虚拟现实头显设备，Quest 3的七倍左右。苹果公司希望Vision Pro能够为更大的市场铺平道路，其最新款高端iPhone，15 Pro和15 Pro Max支持拍摄可以通过头显设备进行观看的3D视频，这也表明了苹果对此的期望。这些视频非常逼真，视频中的人物和图像仿佛就在观影者的眼前。苹果公司正在寻求办法提振销量，此前在截至2022年9月的最近一个财年，其收入略有下降。苹果公司的整体收入仍达到3,830亿美元，其中iPhone销售额占一半以上。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple announces Vision Pro headset with 1 million compatible iPhone/iPad apps, aiming to broaden the technology's audience beyond gamers and tech nerds.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's strategy to expand the appeal of virtual reality technology and introduce a new product category.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Analysts anticipate Apple's potential to diversify the headwear technology's user base, while the high price may limit initial sales.</li>    <li>Main information: The Vision Pro headset, compatible with numerous iPhone/iPad apps, will be available for pre-order from January 19th. Apple targets a broader audience, including media who gave positive reviews in controlled demonstrations.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果公司表示，全新发布的眼镜操作系统将兼容超过100万款专为iPhone和iPad设计的应用程序，预购将于1月19日开始。行业分析师认为，这款产品亮相或将为头显技术带来更广泛的用户群体，不仅仅局限于占比更大的电子游戏玩家和科技爱好者人群。苹果公司定价3500美元的高端头显设备将于2月2日起在商店正式开售，这是苹果首次开始尝试将小众技术推向更广阔的受众群体。为鼓励开发者为这款AR头显设备量身打造应用程序，苹果公司于八个月前在加州总部举办了软件发布会，首次面向公众发布这款时尚的AR头显设备。苹果公司选择发布新品的日子恰逢年度拉斯维加斯国际消费类电子展（CES）举行期间，而往年苹果公司并未出现于此活动。苹果公司还表示，其头显系统将与超过100万款为iPhone和iPad设计的应用程序兼容。预购将于1月19日开始，但消费者需要到线下实体店进行设备调试和佩戴以确保合适的佩戴方式，该款眼镜可以通过眼睛和简单的手势进行控制。高通推出混合现实芯片，旨在与苹果公司的Vision Pro头显设备一较高下。尽管脸书母公司元宇宙平台和其他公司多年来一直在致力于虚拟现实头戴设备的开发，但收效甚微。众多行业分析师认为，苹果公司有能力将头显技术的用户群体扩展到电子游戏玩家和科技爱好者的圈层之外。苹果Vision Pro头显设备在受控良好的媒体测试体验情境下，获得了相当数量媒体的高度赞扬，但设备的高昂售价或意味着其在市场的第一年销售业绩整体上相对疲软。这款设备于苹果2023年全球开发者大会上公开亮相，这是自十年前其智能手表发布以来的首款全新产品，这可能为未来为更广泛的受众群体推出更加实惠的头显设备奠定基础。如今，Vision Pro的定价是Meta旗下的最新虚拟现实头显设备，Quest 3的七倍左右。苹果公司希望Vision Pro能够为更大的市场铺平道路，其最新款高端iPhone，15 Pro和15 Pro Max支持拍摄可以通过头显设备进行观看的3D视频，这也表明了苹果对此的期望。这些视频非常逼真，视频中的人物和图像仿佛就在观影者的眼前。苹果公司正在寻求办法提振销量，此前在截至2022年9月的最近一个财年，其收入略有下降。苹果公司的整体收入仍达到3,830亿美元，其中iPhone销售额占一半以上。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果发布Vision Pro头显设备，兼容百万款iPhone/iPad应用，旨在将技术用户群体拓展至游戏玩家和科技爱好者以外的人群。</li>    <li>主题：苹果公司的策略是扩展虚拟现实技术的吸引力，推出新产品类别。</li>    <li>观点：分析师预计苹果公司有可能使头戴技术的用户群多样化，然而高昂的价格可能会限制头显设备的初期销量。</li>    <li>主要信息：Vision Pro头显设备兼容众多iPhone/iPad应用，将于1月19日开始预购。苹果的目标是更广泛的用户群体，包括在受控演示中给予积极评价的媒体。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>compatible (adj.) - /kəmˈpatəbəl/ 兼容的，相容的。    <p>原文例句：Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad. </p>    <p>例句讲解：兼容（compatible）是指两个或多个系统、设备或软件能够一起工作，相互配合，而不会出现问题。在这个例子中，“compatible”表示苹果公司的眼镜操作系统将能够与超过100万款专为iPhone和iPad设计的应用程序一起使用，不会出现兼容性问题。</p></li>    <li>headset (n.) - /ˈhɛdsɛt/ 头戴式耳机，头戴式装置。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s high-priced headset for toggling between the real and digital world will be available in its stores beginning February 2. </p>    <p>例句讲解：头戴式耳机或头戴式装置（headset）是一种戴在头上的电子设备，通常包括耳机和麦克风，用于免提通话或听音乐。在这个例子中，“headset”指的是苹果公司将从2月2日起在其商店出售的高价头戴式设备，可以用于在现实世界和数字世界之间切换。</p></li>    <li>immersive (adj.) - /ɪˈmɜːsɪv/ 沉浸式的，身临其境的。    <p>原文例句：The Vision Pro already has got largely enthusiastic reviews among the media who were able to test it in tightly controlled demonstrations monitored by Apple. </p>    <p>例句讲解：沉浸式（immersive）是指一种让你感觉完全沉浸在某个环境或体验中的东西。在这个例子中，“immersive”表示媒体对Vision Pro头戴式设备的评论大多是积极的，他们在苹果公司严密控制的演示中测试了这款设备，并感到非常身临其境。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>potential audience - 潜在受众，潜在观众。    <p>原文例句：Industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“potential audience”  <ul><li>Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad, with pre-orders beginning January 19</li>
<li>Industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far</li>
</ul><p>Apple’s high-priced headset for toggling between the real and digital world will be available in its stores beginning February 2, launching the trendsetting company’s push to broaden the appeal of what so far has been a niche technology.</p><p>Apple unveiled the sleek US$3,500 goggles at a software conference held at its Cupertino, California, headquarters eight months ago – an event that was designed to encourage developers to make apps tailored for a device that projects users into three-dimensional simulations of reality.</p><p>Apple’s announcement coincides with the annual CES trade show in Las Vegas, where the company has long been conspicuously absent.</p><p>Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad. Pre-orders begin January 19, but buyers will have to go to a store to be properly fitted for the goggles, which are controlled with the eyes and a few simple hand gestures.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247367/qualcomm-unveils-chip-mixed-reality-compete-apples-vision-pro" title="">Qualcomm unveils chip for mixed reality to compete with Apple’s Vision Pro</a></h3><p>Although Facebook owner Meta Platforms and other companies have been making virtual-reality headsets for years with limited success, many industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far.</p><p>The Vision Pro already has got largely enthusiastic reviews among the media who were able to test it in tightly controlled demonstrations monitored by Apple, but the device’s price tag probably means relatively few unit sales during its first year on the market.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" class="image-inline caption" height="1271" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/c20a30fc-1af5-4a7c-af6e-4132fe5d819a_b9343cec.jpg" title="Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" width="2000" /><figcaption>Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even so, Apple’s first new product since its smartwatch debuted a decade ago could set the stage for the introduction of more affordable versions for a broader audience. Right now, the Vision Pro will cost seven times more than Meta’s latest virtual-reality headset, the Quest 3.</p><p>In a sign that Apple is expecting the Vision Pro to pave the way to a bigger market, the company included the ability to take 3D videos that can be viewed through the goggles on its latest premium iPhones, the 15 Pro and 15 Pro Max. These videos are so realistic that the people and other images in them appear to be right in front of the viewer watching them.</p><p>Apple is looking for ways to juice its sales after suffering a slight decline in revenue during its last fiscal year ended September. Apple still raked in US$383 billion in sales, with the iPhone accounting for more than half that amount.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung profit tumbles 35% as chip weakness persists</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  South Korean tech giant Samsung Electronics reported a decline in its operating income for the sixth consecutive quarter, primarily due to weak global demand for consumer electronics. The company aims to boost its presence in the high-density memory chip market and plans to increase its production capacity by 2.5 times in 2024. Samsung hopes to counteract the slowdown in smartphone and memory chip demand by introducing new devices and foldable smartphones.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung Electronics faces challenges due to declining demand for consumer electronics, leading to a reduction in operating income.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's strategic focus on high-density memory chips and new devices to drive growth in challenging market conditions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of weak consumer demand and economic uncertainty on the electronics industry; Samsung's efforts to navigate these challenges.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's financial results for the quarter, including revenue and operating income; the company's plans to increase production capacity for memory chips; the introduction of new devices and foldable smartphones.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  韩国科技巨头三星电子连续六个季度运营利润下降，主要原因是全球对消费电子的需求疲软。公司旨在提高其在高密度存储芯片市场的地位，并计划在 2024 年将其生产能力提高 2.5 倍。三星希望通过推出新设备和可折叠智能手机来抵消智能手机和存储芯片需求的放缓。这家韩国科技巨头准备在本月晚些时候在美国推出其最新产品，当时投资者担心苹果的 iPhone 15 可能在发布后短短几个月内就会失去动力。  <ul>    <li>摘要：由于对消费电子的需求下降，三星电子面临挑战，导致营业收入减少。</li>    <li>主题：三星在具有挑战性的市场条件下战略性地专注于高密度存储芯片和新设备来推动增长。</li>    <li>观点：疲软的消费者需求和经济不确定性对电子行业的影响；三星应对这些挑战的努力。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星当季财务业绩，包括收入和营业收入；公司计划增加存储芯片的产能；推出新设备和可折叠智能手机。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Underscore (v.) —— 记号，强调，强调。    <p>原文例句：The results underscore how demand for smartphones and the memory chips that power modern electronics remains sluggish given economic uncertainty.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由under（在……以下）和score（分数，评级）组成，表示“划线，强调，强调”。在这个例句中，它的意思是强调スマートフォン和为现代电子设备供电的内存芯片的需求在经济不确定性的情况下仍然低迷。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Sluggish (adj.) —— 缓慢的，迟钝的，不景气的。    <p>原文例句：In December, rival Micron Technology delivered a better-than-projected revenue outlook that suggested data centre construction may make up for the lukewarm computing and mobile devices markets.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由slug（鼻涕虫）和-ish（形容词后缀）组成，表示“缓慢的，迟钝的，不景气的”。在这个例句中，它的意思是计算和移动设备市场的低迷。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the field of —— 在……领域。    <P>原文例句：Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），the（限定词）和field（领域）组成的，表示“在……领域”。在这个例句中，它的意思是三星现在计划在 2024 年在高密度存储芯片领域追赶竞争对手 SK Hynix，计划将产能提高 2.5 倍。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Revenue came to 67 trillion won, compared with projections for 70.31 trillion won. —— 收入达到 67 万亿韩元，而预计为 70.31 万亿韩元。<p>句子分析：这个句子是一个简单的句子，主语是Revenue，谓语是came，宾语是to 67 trillion won。compared with projections for 70.31 trillion won是一个介词短语，作状语，修饰谓语came，表示收入达到 67 万亿韩元，而预计为 70.31 万亿韩元。这个句子的意思是收入达到 67 万亿韩元，而预计为 70.31 万亿韩元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是被动的，强调动作或状态的承受者。    <p>原文例句：Prices should start climbing out of troughs around the latter part of 2023, executives said at the time.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则变化形式。这种语态表示动作或状态是被动的，强调动作或状态的承受者。在这个例句中，它表示价格应该在 2023 年下半年开始从低谷中爬升。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>South Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates</li>
<li>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024</li>
</ul><p>Samsung Electronics posted its sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit, reflecting stubbornly weak demand for consumer electronics globally.</p><p>South Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates. Revenue came to 67 trillion won, compared with projections for 70.31 trillion won.</p><p>The results underscore how demand for smartphones and the memory chips that power modern electronics remains sluggish given economic uncertainty.</p><p>In December, rival Micron Technology delivered a better-than-projected revenue outlook that suggested data centre construction may make up for the lukewarm computing and mobile devices markets.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>“I think this shows that the rebound is slower than we all thought,” said Tom Kang, research director at Counterpoint Technology. “Prices are not rising that fast and the demand from certain sectors is not that strong.”</p><p>Samsung in October predicted the long-depressed US$160 billion memory market will bounce back gradually in 2024, driven by a boom in artificial intelligence (AI) development. Prices should start climbing out of troughs around the latter part of 2023, executives said at the time.</p><p>The company will release a full earnings report, with divisional breakdowns, on January 31.</p><p>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024. HBM, an advanced chip that handles data more quickly, works with hardware such as Nvidia’s accelerators to speed up data processing for intensive tasks like training AI models.</p><p>Samsung is also counting on a new line-up of devices and foldable smartphones to drive growth in 2024. The Korean tech conglomerate is preparing to unveil its latest gadgets in the US later this month, at a time investors worry Apple’s iPhone 15 may be running out of steam mere months after launch.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s AliExpress, PDD-owned Temu face supply chain challenges in South Korea amid rapid business expansion</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247710/alibabas-aliexpress-pdd-owned-temu-face-supply-chain-challenges-south-korea-amid-rapid-business</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>AliExpress and Temu, two popular Chinese online shopping platforms in South Korea, struggle with long delivery times and product quality issues, despite their fast growth.</li>    <li>Korean consumers are hesitant to replace local platforms due to these challenges and the prevalence of copycat products on AliExpress and Temu.</li>    <li>To address these concerns, AliExpress and Temu have implemented initiatives to enhance supply chain efficiency and product authenticity.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>阿里速卖通和拼多多，两个在中国流行的在线购物平台，尽管在韩国发展迅速，但依然面临着交货时间长和产品质量不足的问题。</li>    <li>韩国消费者由于这些挑战以及阿里速卖通和拼多多上的仿冒产品盛行，因而犹豫是否要替换本地的平台。</li>    <li>为了解决这些问题，阿里速卖通和拼多多已经开始实施提高供应链效率和产品真实性的举措。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>grappling - (v.) 努力对付或处理。    <p>原文例句：China’s e-commerce giants are now the fastest-growing online platforms for Korean shoppers, but they are still grappling with problems of long delivery time and unstable product quality, according to consumers and retail industry officials.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古诺斯语，意思是“抓握、搏斗”。在这个例句中，它表示中国电子商务巨头现在是韩国购物者增长最快的在线平台，但他们仍在努力解决消费者和零售业官员报告的交货时间长和产品质量不稳定的问题。</p></li>    <li>cautious - (adj.) 小心的，谨慎的。    <p>原文例句：But on the flip side, some consumers in Korea remain cautious about replacing local online retail sites, such as Coupang and Gmarket, owing to the Chinese platforms’ supply chain problems that include long delivery time and unstable product quality.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语，意思是“小心、谨慎”。在这个例句中，它表示但另一方面，由于中国平台的供应链问题包括交货时间长和产品质量不稳定，韩国一些消费者仍然谨慎地对待替换本地在线零售网站，例如Coupang和Gmarket。</p></li>    <li>authenticity - (n.) 真实性，可靠性。    <p>原文例句：He suggested that these platforms set up a “patrol system” to punish counterfeiters.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自希腊语，意思是“真实的、可靠的”。在这个例句中，它表示他建议这些平台建立一个“巡逻系统”来惩罚造假者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>long delivery time - 交货时间长。    <p>原文例句：AliExpress Group Holding and PDD, two of the largest e-commerce companies in China, have been aggressively expanding their foothold in South Korea, offering prices as low as US$1 for some small gadgets on their overseas shopping platforms AliExpress and Temu, respectively.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由long（长的）和delivery time（交货时间）组成，表示交货时间长。</p></li>    <li>unstable product quality - 产品质量不稳定。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba Group Holding and PDD, two of the largest e-commerce companies in China, have been aggressively expanding their foothold in South Korea, offering prices as low as US$1 for some small gadgets on their overseas shopping platforms AliExpress and Temu, respectively.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由unstable（不稳定的）和product quality（产品质量）组成，表示产品质量不稳定。</p></li>    <li>copycat products - 仿冒产品。    <p>原文例句：Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由copycat（模仿）和products（产品）组成，表示仿冒产品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>To address these concerns, AliExpress and Temu have implemented initiatives to enhance supply chain efficiency and product authenticity. - 为了解决这些问题，阿里速卖通和拼多多已经开始实施提高供应链效率和产品真实性的举措。    <p>句子解析：这是一个复合句，主句是AliExpress and Temu have implemented initiatives to enhance supply chain efficiency and product authenticity.，其中主语是AliExpress and Temu，谓语是have implemented，宾语是initiatives to enhance supply chain efficiency and product authenticity.。To address these concerns是一个状语从句，表示为了解决这些问题。这个句子的意思是说，阿里速卖通和拼多多为了解决这些问题，已经开始实施提高供应链效率和产品真实性的举措。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示两个事物或情况之间的差异。    <p>原文例句：South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是形容词或副词的一种形式，表示两个事物或情况之间的差异。它通常通过在形容词或副词的词尾加上-er或more来形成。在这个例句中，fourth-largest是形容词largest的比较级，表示韩国是世界上第四大电子商务市场。</p></li>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Despite those challenges, both AliExpress and Temu have pushed initiatives to improve supply chain efficiency in South Korea.</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去完成时是一种时态，表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。它通常通过在have/has后面加上过去分词来形成。在这个例句中，have pushed是动词push的过去完成时，表示尽管面临着这些挑战，AliExpress和Temu都已采取措施来提高韩国的供应链效率。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Despite their popularity, AliExpress and Temu lag behind the competition in South Korea in terms of fast delivery and product quality assurance</li>
<li>Korean consumers find that proliferation of copycat merchandise is a major problem for Chinese online shopping platforms</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/429e5290-226a-46f7-b76d-3c56e51b65b3_f7ecc5a8.jpg" /><figcaption>Online retail platforms AliExpress and Temu ranked as the two fastest-growing apps in South Korea in 2023, according to market research firm WiseApp. Photos: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giants are now the fastest-growing online platforms for Korean shoppers, but they are still grappling with problems of long delivery time and unstable product quality, according to consumers and retail industry officials.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3243140/discount-e-commerce-giant-pdd-nearly-doubles-quarterly-revenue-closing-alibaba-meituan-also-chalks" target="_self" title="">PDD</a>, two of the largest e-commerce companies in China, have been aggressively expanding their foothold in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a>, offering prices as low as US$1 for some small gadgets on their overseas shopping platforms <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3213632/alibabas-aliexpress-steps-investment-spain-and-south-korea-chinas-e-commerce-players-look-growth" target="_self" title="">AliExpress</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244193/chinese-budget-e-commerce-app-temu-snatching-business-us-dollar-stores-ahead-lucrative-holiday" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>, respectively. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Launched in South Korea in 2018, AliExpress saw its monthly active users surpass 7 million as of last November, nearly doubling the number recorded a year earlier, according to mobile market research firm WiseApp. Temu, which started Korean operations in July, averages 3.5 million users per month. WiseApp ranked the two Chinese platforms as the fastest-growing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">apps</a> in Korea in 2023.</p><p>But on the flip side, some consumers in Korea remain cautious about replacing local online retail sites, such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/2174243/softbank-doubles-down-korean-online-retailer-coupang-us2-billion" target="_self" title="">Coupang</a> and Gmarket, owing to the Chinese platforms’ supply chain problems that include long delivery time and unstable product quality.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/a4611340-1803-40fa-8f74-caa324044017_1126e908.jpg" title="South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Lawrence Woo, a 38-year-old office worker in Seoul, started using AliExpress a year ago after he was lured by the platform’s low prices. Woo found, for example, a laptop stand on AliExpress that costs 30,000 won (US$23) and comes with free shipping, which was a deal around 50 per cent cheaper than those offered by local retail sites.</p><p>Still, Woo said he was confused about the delivery time of merchandise he bought on AliExpress. For instance, it took AliExpress two months to deliver a smartphone camera protector film that he bought last autumn.</p><p>“The delivery time is too long,” Woo said. “I tried to cancel the order, but the customer service was not working.”</p><p>On Temu, product shipping times would range from six to 20 days, according to the Chinese budget shopping app’s website.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3108619/south-korea-some-couriers-are-paying-same-day-deliveries-their" title="">In South Korea, couriers crack under the weight of same-day deliveries</a></h3><p>By comparison, Korean e-commerce giant Coupang is capable of shortening delivery times to within a day through its signature Rocket Delivery service.</p><p>Both AliExpress and Temu work with domestic logistics service providers such as CJ Logistics Corp, the oldest and largest parcel delivery firm in South Korea.</p><p>“It depends on [these companies’] supply chain,” said Zhuang Shuai, founder and chief analyst at Chinese market consultancy Bailian. “For instance, whether the sellers are local merchants or Chinese merchants, and whether the platforms have their own warehouses.”</p><p>Zhuang indicated that Chinese shopping platforms face both policy and cultural barriers in their overseas expansion. “Just like how <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon</a> did not succeed in China, it is also not easy for Chinese companies to operate overseas,” he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235863/alibabas-cainiao-and-aliexpress-start-5-day-global-delivery-service-consumers-uk-spain-netherlands" title="">Alibaba’s Cainiao and AliExpress start ‘5-day global delivery’ service</a></h3><p>Despite those challenges, both AliExpress and Temu have pushed initiatives to improve supply chain efficiency in South Korea.</p><p>The Alibaba unit last March launched a new service called AliExpress Choice that aims to provide Korean consumers with “delivery guarantees and more affordable prices”, touting up to a “three-day delivery window”. AliExpress also expanded the capacity of its warehouses in Weihai and Yantai, two cities in eastern Shandong province, which is close to the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/korean-peninsula-0" target="_self" title="">Korean peninsula</a>.</p><p>Long-time AliExpress user Lee Ye-seul, a 35-year-old resident of Seoul, said the platform’s delivery speed has improved, pointing out that some products she recently ordered arrived within four days of her online purchase. Still, she lamented another major problem: copycat designs widely seen on Chinese e-commerce platforms.</p><p>Lee indicated that there were many merchants on AliExpress selling smartphone cases designed with characters from popular Korean or Japanese brands, such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/article/3131357/hello-kitty-story-how-sanrio-went-silk-sandals-global-superstar" target="_self" title="">Sanrio</a>. “It’s hard to tell if the product you’re buying is plagiarised or an original design,” she said.</p><p>Echoing Lee’s view on copycat merchandise, office worker Woo said it was tough to determine the authenticity of branded products on Chinese shopping platforms. He suggested that these platforms set up a “patrol system” to punish counterfeiters.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" title="">How Temu, an app for US shoppers, helped PDD catch up with Alibaba in market value</a></h3><p>Products bought from AliExpress are “unknowingly circulating” on Korean second-hand sales sites as counterfeits, according to Kang Hyoung-goo, a professor of finance at Hanyang University in Seoul.</p><p>“It is a stumbling block to expanding global outreach through K-fashion exports,” Kang said.</p><p>South Korea has become one of the major battlefields for Alibaba and PDD, as both count on overseas markets to maintain their business momentum amid sluggish user growth and weak spending in their home market.</p><p>Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, followed by Japan, according to a report from online database ECDB.</p><p>Although Chinese platforms have paved the way for many Korean consumers to gain direct access to China-made goods at extremely low prices, Woo and Lee both indicated that these online marketplaces would not become their prime destinations for shopping.</p><p>“I will keep using such platforms, but I’d rather turn to Coupang or Naver Shopping for daily necessities or fashion items,” Woo said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia expands its reach in China’s electric vehicle sector</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Nvidia, a US-based chip maker, announced that four Chinese electric vehicle brands, including Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr, and the new EV unit of Xiaomi, will use its DRIVE technology for automated driving systems. This move highlights Nvidia's determination to expand in China despite tighter US export restrictions on advanced semiconductors.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese EV brands adopt Nvidia's technology for automated driving.</li>    <li>Theme: Nvidia expands its presence in China's automotive market amid US-China trade tensions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of Chinese EV market for Nvidia's growth; the impact of US export controls on Nvidia's business.</li>    <li>Main information: The four Chinese EV brands that will use Nvidia's technology; Nvidia's partnership with WPP and other companies for online shopping tools.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  美国芯片制造商英伟达宣布，四家中国电动汽车品牌，包括理想汽车、长城汽车、极氪和小米汽车，将使用其DRIVE技术用于自动驾驶系统。此举凸显了英伟达在中美贸易争端中扩大在中国市场份额的决心。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国电动汽车品牌采用英伟达技术实现自动驾驶。</li>    <li>主题：英伟达在美国与中国贸易紧张局势中扩大其在中国汽车市场的存在。</li>    <li>观点：中国电动汽车市场对英伟达增长的重要性；美国出口管制对英伟达业务的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：将使用英伟达技术的四家中国电动汽车品牌；英伟达与WPP等公司在网络购物工具方面的合作。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>automated (adj.) - /ˈɔːtəˌmeɪtɪd/ 自动化的。    <p>原文例句：Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Automated的意思是“自动化的，不用人工干预的”。在这个例句中，它修饰driving，表示自动驾驶，即无需人工驾驶的车辆。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rival (n.) - /ˈraɪvəl/ 竞争对手。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips, while complying with US controls on semiconductor exports to China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Rival的意思是“竞争对手，敌手”。在这个例句中，它指的是英伟达在中国的竞争对手，包括英特尔、高通和其他半导体制造商。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in compliance with - 遵守，符合。    <P>原文例句：Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</P>    <p>例句讲解：In compliance with的意思是“遵守，符合”。在这个例句中，它表示英伟达及其美国竞争对手在满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求时面临挑战，同时还要遵守美国对向中国出口先进半导体更严格的控制。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>keep pace with - 跟上，保持同步。    <P>原文例句：Chinese carmakers are racing each other to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays and automated driving functions.</P>    <p>例句讲解：Keep pace with的意思是“跟上，保持同步”。在这个例句中，它表示中国汽车制造商正在相互竞争，以推出更先进的车载信息娱乐显示器和自动驾驶功能。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday at the CES technology conference in Las Vegas. - 在拉斯维加斯举行的 CES 技术大会上，英伟达于周一表示，理想汽车、长城汽车、极氪和小米汽车的新电动汽车部门将使用英伟达的 DRIVE 技术来实现自动驾驶。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Li Auto、Great Wall Motor、Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving，其中主语是Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi，谓语是will use，宾语是Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving。Nvidia said on Monday at the CES technology conference in Las Vegas是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示这一消息是在拉斯维加斯举行的 CES 技术大会上，英伟达于周一表示的。这个句子的意思是说，理想汽车、长城汽车、极氪和小米汽车的新电动汽车部门将使用英伟达的 DRIVE 技术来实现自动驾驶，这一消息是在拉斯维加斯举行的 CES 技术大会上，英伟达于周一表示的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>一般现在时 - 表示现在发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips.</p>    <p>语法讲解：一般现在时用来表示现在发生的动作或状态，结构是：主语 + 谓语（动词原形或第三人称单数）。在这个例句中，主语是Nvidia and US rivals，谓语是face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips，表示英伟达及其美国竞争对手面临满足中国对强大芯片的需求的挑战。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在进行时用来表示正在进行的动作或状态，结构是：主语 + be + 现在分词。在这个例句中，主语是Nvidia and its US-based rivals，谓语是face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips，表示英伟达及其美国竞争对手面临满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求的挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday</li>
<li>Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips, while complying with US controls on semiconductor exports to China</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/ca10cd80-a417-41ba-821c-f909879abb0a_5739d5f7.jpg" /><figcaption>A Nvidia logo at the company’s headquarters in Taipei, Taiwan. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia said four Chinese electric vehicle brands will use its technology as the brains for automated driving systems, underscoring the US chip maker’s determination to expand in China despite Washington’s tighter export rules.</p><p>Chinese carmakers Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Chinese telecommunications company Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday at the CES technology conference in Las Vegas.</p><p>China’s rising EV brands are a key market for Nvidia’s automotive technology business. Chinese carmakers are racing each other to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays and automated driving functions. That has created a growth opportunity for Nvidia, Intel, Qualcomm and other semiconductor manufacturers.</p><p>Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>In related CES announcements, Nvidia said it is working with advertising giant WPP, Lotus and six other companies to develop more advanced online shopping tools. Using Nvidia technology, carmakers and dealers hope to create online shopping sites with three dimensional graphics and more lifelike graphics, said Danny Shapiro, Nvidia’s vice-president for automotive.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tencent’s Pony Ma says 2021 WeChat photo privacy controversy was ‘misunderstanding’ that was fixed with update</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247704/tencents-pony-ma-says-2021-wechat-photo-privacy-controversy-was-misunderstanding-was-fixed-update</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Tencent CEO Pony Ma addressed a 2021 privacy controversy involving WeChat's access to user photo galleries without authorization. Ma explained the issue as a misunderstanding caused by image cache acceleration. The problem was resolved through an update to the app's programming interface. Tencent emphasized that the app only accessed the gallery when authorized by the user and has since introduced stricter data protection measures in compliance with China's new data security laws.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tencent CEO clarifies the 2021 WeChat photo privacy issue, citing cache acceleration as the cause and subsequent resolution.</li>    <li>Theme: Addressing privacy concerns and implementing data protection measures in response to government regulations.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Ma's explanation highlights the importance of transparent communication and adherence to data protection laws.</li>    <li>Main information: Ma's description of the issue as a cache acceleration misunderstanding; resolution through a programming interface update; Tencent's emphasis on user authorization and stricter data protection measures.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  腾讯CEO马化腾对2021年以来一直困扰微信的一项隐私问题做出了回应，这项隐私问题是：用户未授权的情况下，微信会访问他们的照片库。马化腾解释道，这些问题是由于图像缓存加速而引起的，并且通过更新应用程序编程接口来解决此问题。腾讯强调，应用程序只会在用户授权的情况下访问图库，而且还引入了更严格的数据保护措施，以遵守中国新的数据安全法。  <ul>    <li>摘要：腾讯CEO澄清了2021年以来困扰微信的照片隐私问题，并引用缓存加速作为该问题的成因和解决方案。</li>    <li>主题：为了应对政府法规，解决隐私问题并实施数据保护措施。</li>    <li>观点：马化腾的解释强调了透明沟通和遵守数据保护法的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：马化腾将该问题描述为缓存加速的误解；通过编程接口更新来解决该问题；腾讯强调用户授权和更严格的数据保护措施。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>reassurance (n.) - /ˌriːəˈʃʊərəns/ 保证，使放心。    <p>原文例句：That year, a tech influencer found that WeChat, China’s largest social media app with 1.3 billion monthly active users (MAUs), was frequently accessing user photo galleries even when not in use, which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由re-（重新）和assurance（保证，使放心）构成的，表示“使放心，保证”。在这个例句中，它指的是微信频繁访问用户照片库而引起了广泛的隐私担忧。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>screenplay  (n.) - /ˈskriːnpleɪ/ 剧本。    <p>原文例句：In a novel twist, WhatsApp is developing its first podcast series to be adapted into a screenplay.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由screen（屏幕）和play（戏剧）构成的，表示“电影或电视的剧本”。在这个例句中，它指的是WhatsApp正在开发其第一个播客系列并将其改编成剧本。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>handle personal data - 处理个人数据。    <p>原文例句：China has introduced new laws in recent years that tighten scrutiny over how tech companies handle personal data.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由handle（处理）和personal data（个人数据）构成的，表示“处理个人数据”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国近年来出台了新的法律，加强了对科技公司处理个人数据的方式的审查。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The activity was discovered using Apple’s “Record App Activity” feature on its iOS 15 operating system at that time. - 此项活动是当时使用苹果iOS 15操作系统上的“记录应用程序活动”功能发现的。<p>句子分析：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是The activity，谓语是被动语态的was discovered，宾语是using Apple’s “Record App Activity” feature on its iOS 15 operating system。at that time是一个时间状语，表示当时。这个句子的意思是说，此项活动是当时使用苹果iOS 15操作系统上的“记录应用程序活动”功能发现的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 将句子中句子的正常语序（主-谓-宾）颠倒过来。    <p>原文例句：Up to 40% off on selected styles while stocks last.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，将句子中句子的正常语序（主-谓-宾）颠倒过来。在倒装句中，句子的谓语部分（动词）通常放在句子的第一位，而主语部分（名词或代词）放在谓语部分之后。在这个例句中，谓语部分是Up to 40% off，主语部分是selected styles while stocks last。这个句子的意思是说，精选款式最高可享40%的折扣，售完即止。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，并且这个动作或状态可能已经完成也可能还没有完成。    <p>原文例句：We’ve been working on this project for months.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态的句子，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，并且这个动作或状态可能已经完成也可能还没有完成。在这个例句中，它表示我们从几个月前就开始一直致力于这个项目，并且现在可能已经完成也可能还没有完成。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Ma described the issue as ‘a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images’</li>
<li>The 2021 WeChat photo issue sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time despite reassurances that the glitch had been fixed</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/daec20ec-0fa7-42e0-ad58-197447fdda39_11d7714e.jpg" /><figcaption>Ma described the WeChat issue as “a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images”. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Pony Ma Huateng, founder, chairman and CEO of Tencent Holdings, has described a 2021 privacy controversy sparked by a photo issue with its all-purpose super app WeChat as a “misunderstanding”, according to a local media report.</p><p>That year, a tech influencer found that WeChat, China’s largest social media app with 1.3 billion monthly active users (MAUs), was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3151762/tencents-wechat-stop-routine-scans-photos-after-tech-influencer" target="_self" title="">frequently accessing user photo galleries even when not in use</a>, which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time.</p><p>Ma described the issue as “a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images”, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Yicai on Monday.</p><p>He said the matter was solved by the roll-out of a new application programming interface within the operating system to fix the lag.</p><p>Tencent said at the time that the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”, and it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user. The company also said it would cancel the scanning in a new version of the app.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Yicai picked up Ma’s comments from CSDNnews, a tech news outlet run by the Chinese Software Developer Network.</p><p>Ma told CSDNnews in a private WeChat message last Friday that this “old incident” in 2021 had been fixed, according to a screenshot shared by the outlet.</p><p>Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment by the Post on Monday.</p><p>China has introduced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3147040/what-chinas-new-data-laws-are-and-their-impact-big-tech?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">new laws in recent years</a> that tighten scrutiny over how tech companies handle personal data.</p><p>The Data Security Law and the Personal Information Protection Law, some of the world’s toughest data protection laws, went into effect in 2021 with strict penalties for the unauthorised collection, processing, storage and use of data generated in the country.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245623/chinas-finance-influencers-face-stricter-rules-tencents-live-streaming-channels-beijing-moves-shore" title="">China’s finance live streamers face stricter rules on Tencent</a></h3><p>Tencent faced intense scrutiny in 2021 when tech influencer Hackl0us said on social media platform Weibo that the app periodically accessed user photos while running in the background.</p><p>The activity was discovered using Apple’s “Record App Activity” feature on its iOS 15 operating system at that time.</p><p>The influencer also said in 2021 that Tencent’s QQ messaging app and Taobao, Alibaba Group Holding’s top online shopping marketplace with roughly 900 million MAUs, had also been found routinely accessing user photos. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tightening noose: Hong Kong joins EU, US, South Korea and Singapore in tightening crypto rules, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247684/hong-kong-joins-eu-us-south-korea-and-singapore-tightening-crypto-regulations-2023-report-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In 2023, 17 jurisdictions, including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, have toughened cryptocurrency regulations. About 80% of the investigated 21 jurisdictions enhanced consumer protection measures in the volatile cryptocurrency sector. This move follows a series of meltdowns and market turmoil, such as the collapse of major platforms like TerraUSD and FTX.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Global tightening of cryptocurrency regulations in 2023.</li>    <li>Theme: Governments worldwide strengthen consumer protection and regulatory frameworks for cryptocurrencies.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The necessity of regulation to ensure market stability and investor protection in the cryptocurrency industry.</li>    <li>Main information: 17 jurisdictions' regulatory actions; focus on consumer protection; significant events like the FTX collapse; international organizations' involvement.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023年，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币法规。根据TRM Labs的数据，收紧加密货币监管的21个司法管辖区中约80%加强了对波动的加密货币行业的消费者保护措施。此举是在一系列崩溃和市场动荡之后进行的，例如TerraUSD和FTX等主要平台的崩溃。    <ul>    <li>摘要：2023年全球加密货币监管趋严。</li>    <li>主题：全球政府加强对加密货币的消费者保护和监管框架。</li>    <li>观点：监管的必要性，以确保加密货币行业的市场稳定和投资者保护。</li>    <li>主要信息：17个司法管辖区的监管行动；专注于消费者保护；FTX崩盘等重大事件；国际组织的参与。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>eatery (n.) - /ˈiːtəri/ 餐馆，饭店。    <p>原文例句：One can dine on local specialties at eateries in the village.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由eat（吃）和-ery（表示从事某事的地方或事物）组成，表示“餐馆，饭店”。在这个例句中，它指的是村子里可以吃到当地特色的餐馆。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>scrutiny (n.) - /ˈskruːtɪni/ 审查，仔细检查。    <p>原文例句：Research findings can also come under scrutiny in a peer review process.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由scrutari（搜索，检查）而来，表示“审查，仔细检查”。在这个例句中，它指的是同行评审过程中对研究结果的审查。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Hong Kong to push retail access to spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示香港将推动散户进入现货加密货币交易所交易基金。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms, including the stablecoin TerraUSD and exchange FTX, led to a market rout that wiped out trillions of dollars in value. - 几个主要的加密货币平台的崩盘，包括稳定币TerraUSD和交易所FTX，导致市场暴跌，损失了数万亿美元的价值。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms led to a market rout，其中主语是The collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms，谓语是led to，宾语是a market rout。that wiped out trillions of dollars in value是一个定语从句，修饰market rout，表示市场暴跌造成了数万亿美元的损失。在这个例句中，it表示市场暴跌，that wiped out trillions of dollars in value是一个定语从句，修饰market rout，表示市场暴跌造成了数万亿美元的损失。这个句子的意思是说，几个主要的加密货币平台的崩盘，包括稳定币TerraUSD和交易所FTX，导致市场暴跌，损失了数万亿美元的价值。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are two major theories of how the universe began.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是two major theories，表示有两个主要的理论。这个句子的意思是说，宇宙如何开始的，有两个主要的理论。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been providing quality products for over 50 years.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示这家公司一直在提供优质产品，over 50 years是一个时间状语，表示超过50年。这个句子的意思是说，这家公司一直提供优质产品，超过50年了。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, tightened cryptocurrency regulations</li>
<li>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures, according to TRM Labs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/70965061-8587-4332-9ba0-361c7665e6c9_67fe6e02.jpg" /><figcaption>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US tightened cryptocurrency regulations. Photo: Bloomberg </figcaption></figure><p>Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p><p>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the European Union, South Korea, Singapore, and the United States, tightened cryptocurrency regulations, according to a report published on Monday by blockchain analytics firm TRM Labs.</p><p>Those strengthening protection accounted for 80 per cent of the 21 jurisdictions studied by the firm, with the latter representing 70 per cent of global exposure to cryptocurrencies, said TRM Labs.</p><p>In 2022, the collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms, including the stablecoin TerraUSD and exchange FTX, led to a market rout that wiped out trillions of dollars in value.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" title="">Hong Kong to push retail access to spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a></h3><p>While 2023 began with the crypto ecosystem “reeling from the collapse of FTX”, the subsequent 12 months “saw an extraordinary boom in regulation across the globe”, the report says.</p><p>Among prominent moves, the European Union’s Markets in Crypto Assets Regulation came into force in June last year, and Hong Kong’s new licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges went live, the firm noted.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>Singapore, which the report described as “an early adopter of crypto regulation”, in November last year issued a set of rules aimed at curbing retail speculation in cryptocurrencies, and finalised its rules for stablecoins.</p><p>Meanwhile, South Korea and Australia also increased scrutiny of the cryptocurrency sector last year, the report says.</p><p>In the US, the Securities and Exchange Commission ramped up its enforcement actions against crypto firms in 2023, and the House Financial Services Committee also advanced bills last July aimed at creating a federal regulatory framework for the crypto market, with specific attention to stablecoins.</p><p>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures, according to TRM Labs.</p><p>It also noted that international organisations, including the G20, the Financial Action Task Force, the Financial Stability Board, International Monetary Fund, and the International Organization of Securities Commissions, all laid out global frameworks and policy recommendations for regulating cryptocurrencies.</p><p>Hong Kong, which in October 2022 announced a major initiative to support the virtual asset sector with the goal of becoming a global hub for such businesses, has implemented a mandatory licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges that allow them to accept retail investors.</p><p>Eleven companies have so far submitted applications for the licence in the city, including OKX, one of the largest exchanges by trading volume.</p><p>In December, the Asian financial hub also <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246415/hong-kong-regulators-propose-tougher-rules-sale-stablecoins-retail-investors?module=hard_link&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">proposed rules for stablecoin issuers</a>, which would ban companies without a licence from selling stablecoins to Hong Kong’s retail investors through regulated channels, or from actively marketing their tokens to the city.</p><p>The rules have been deemed as “extremely challenging” for stablecoin issuers, potentially deterring operators of the world’s biggest stablecoins, such as Tether and USDC, from entering the city, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246692/hong-kongs-proposed-stablecoin-rules-would-be-extremely-challenging-global-issuers-tether-and-usdc" target="_self" title="">experts told the Post last month</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Shanghai explainer on taxation of digital currency transaction drives speculation on potential easing of China’s crypto ban</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247683/shanghai-explainer-taxation-digital-currency-transaction-drives-speculation-potential-easing-chinas</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In China, an article by the Shanghai Municipal Tax Service initially caused speculation of cryptocurrency legitimacy due to mentions of digital currency transaction taxation. </li>    <li>The article was subsequently deleted, indicating no shift in the country's anti-cryptocurrency stance.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>上海市税务局发布文章解释中国数字货币交易征税政策，引发当地加密货币爱好者猜测中国或将放松针对加密货币的严厉管制。</li>    <li>然而，该文章随后被税务局删除，说明中国对加密货币的抵制态度并无改变。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>speculation (n.) - /ˌspekjʊˈleɪʃən/ 推测，猜测。    <p>原文例句：An online article posted by the Shanghai Municipal Tax Service, explaining levies imposed on digital currency transactions in China, has fanned speculation among local cryptocurrency enthusiasts that it signals a potential relaxation of the country’s draconian ban on crypto operations.</p>    <p>例句讲解：本词由speculate（猜测，推测）派生而来，表示“猜测，预测”。在句中，它指的是上海市税务局发布的文章引发了当地加密货币爱好者对中国放松对加密货币管制的猜测。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>enthusiasts (n.) - /ɪnˈθjuːziæst/ 爱好者，热衷者。    <p>原文例句：The explainer became widely circulated on Sunday after some local crypto enthusiasts suggested that it acknowledged cryptocurrencies’ legitimacy.</p>    <p>例句讲解：本词源于希腊语，由en（在……里面）和theos（神）组成，意为“被神附体的人，狂热者”。在句中，它表示一些当地的加密货币爱好者在文章中看到了中国承认加密货币合法性的信号。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>financial stability - 金融稳定。    <p>原文例句：China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks.</p>    <p>例句讲解：本词组由financial（金融的）和stability（稳定）组成，意为“金融稳定”。在句中，它被用作名词，表示中国以金融稳定为由，近年来加强了对所有加密货币相关活动的打击。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>draconian ban - 严厉的禁令。    <p>原文例句：The explainer became widely circulated on Sunday after some local crypto enthusiasts suggested that it acknowledged cryptocurrencies’ legitimacy</p>    <p>例句讲解：本词组由draconian（严厉的）和ban（禁令）组成，意为“严厉的禁令”。在句中，它被用作名词，表示中国对加密货币的严厉禁令。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Shanghai Municipal Tax Service has since deleted the article from its public WeChat account. - 上海市税务局随后从其公共微信账号中删除了该文章。<p>句子分析：本句由主语The Shanghai Municipal Tax Service和谓语has deleted组成，其中The Shanghai Municipal Tax Service由名词Shanghai Municipal Tax Service（上海市税务局）和形容词Municipal（市的）组成，has deleted由助动词has和过去分词deleted组成。介词since引导时间状语since deleted（随后删除），表示动作发生在某个时间点之后。from its public WeChat account是介词短语，表示从其公共微信账号中。整句的意思是：上海市税务局随后从其公共微信账号中删除了该文章。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作是由句子中的承受者承受的。    <p>原文例句：The article was subsequently deleted, indicating no shift in the country's anti-cryptocurrency stance.</p>    <p>语法讲解：本句使用了被动语态，其中was deleted是被动语态的过去式，表示文章被删除了。该结构由助动词was和过去分词deleted组成。在句中，文章是动作的承受者，被税务局删除了。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示一个动作或状态从过去开始一直持续到现在。    <p>原文例句：China has denied legal-tender status for cryptocurrencies, but has not opposed its attribution as property or commodity, according to an article published on Friday by Jin Jianzhi of the Shanghai Mankun Law Firm.</p>    <p>语法讲解：本句使用了现在完成时，其中has denied是现在完成时的肯定式，表示中国拒绝了加密货币的法定货币地位。该结构由助动词has和过去分词denied组成。在句中，has denied表示中国从过去开始一直到现在都拒绝了加密货币的法定货币地位。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The explainer became widely circulated on Sunday after some local crypto enthusiasts suggested that it acknowledged cryptocurrencies’ legitimacy</li>
<li>The Shanghai Municipal Tax Service has since deleted the article from its public WeChat account</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/dd38a0bb-3bd5-4e5f-aee4-d25bc7d830f4_a5b28db7.jpg" /><figcaption>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>An online article posted by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a> Municipal Tax Service, explaining levies imposed on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/digital-currencies" target="_self" title="">digital currency</a> transactions in China, has fanned speculation among local cryptocurrency enthusiasts that it signals a potential relaxation of the country’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3208481/chinese-economist-calls-review-rigid-cryptocurrency-ban-digital-yuan-fails-take?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">draconian ban on crypto operations</a>.</p><p>The explainer, “Common Misunderstandings Regarding Personal Income Tax on Business Income and Categorised Income”, became widely circulated on Sunday after it was published on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> by the Shanghai tax service on Thursday. It cited a 2008 statement by the State Taxation Administration (STA).</p><p>That prompted some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies. The Shanghai tax service subsequently deleted the explainer on Sunday from its public WeChat account.</p><p>The wide attention received by the Shanghai tax service’s explainer reflects the lingering hope among Chinese crypto circles that the country’s rigid ban on cryptocurrencies would be reviewed amid Beijing’s drive to expand adoption of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/china-digital-currency/news" target="_self" title="">digital yuan</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology last month announced plans to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" target="_self" title="">draft a national Web3 development plan</a> to suit the country’s needs, although it did not specifically mention cryptocurrencies.</p><p>Mainland legal experts, however, pointed out that the Shanghai tax service’s explainer does not suggest any potential change in the country’s cryptocurrency policy.</p><p>The published article is not an official policy document, and the STA statement it cited concerns virtual tokens used in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video games</a>, according to Guo Zhihao, a partner at Beijing-based Yingke Law Firm, in an article he posted on WeChat on Sunday.</p><p>The explainer had indicated that individuals who obtain virtual currencies from other players through online transactions and generate revenue by selling them at a higher price must pay income tax on such earnings. The Shanghai tax agency’s article detailed taxation in four scenarios, including loans obtained by individual investors from their investee companies and online monetary gifts.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3208481/chinese-economist-calls-review-rigid-cryptocurrency-ban-digital-yuan-fails-take" title="">Chinese economist calls for review of rigid crypto ban amid slow e-CNY adoption</a></h3><p>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. It maintains that stance even though it <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3216894/chinese-officials-pledge-support-hong-kongs-tech-web3-ambitions-digital-economy-summit?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">supports Hong Kong’s ambitions to become a major hub for virtual assets</a>, including cryptocurrencies.</p><p>While there is no official sign from Beijing about changing its position on cryptocurrencies, local crypto circles expect increased regulatory oversight on the taxation of virtual asset-related income on the mainland.</p><p>China has denied legal-tender status for cryptocurrencies, but has not opposed its attribution as property or commodity, according to an article published on Friday by Jin Jianzhi of the Shanghai Mankun Law Firm. The lawyer said the government can levy taxes on relevant transactions under the law.</p><p>The global cryptocurrency market, meanwhile, appears to be slowly recovering from a prolonged slump last year. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bitcoin" target="_self" title="">Bitcoin</a> prices gained more than 150 per cent from a year earlier on the back of expectations that the US Securities and Exchange Commission will soon approve <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" target="_self" title="">bitcoin exchange-traded funds</a>, which would make these virtual assets more attractive to mainstream investors.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: Chinese tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to premier consumer electronics show in Las Vegas</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese tech giants made a strong return to the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in Las Vegas this year, with a significant increase in the number of exhibitors compared to last year. This surge in participation reflects companies' efforts to overcome the challenges posed by the Covid-19 era and expand their overseas growth. Artificial intelligence (AI) emerged as the major trend at the show, with many companies showcasing their integration of AI technology into their products.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese tech giants return to CES in Las Vegas with a focus on AI and international growth.</li>    <li>Theme: The resurgence of Chinese tech companies at CES and the prominence of AI technology as a driving force in the industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: CES provides a platform for Chinese companies to showcase their latest innovations and connect with global partners, despite ongoing geopolitical tensions.</li>    <li>Main Information: Increased presence of Chinese companies at CES; Emphasis on AI and emerging technologies; Challenges faced by Chinese companies due to geopolitical tensions and restrictions; Representation of companies from various sectors, including e-commerce, smart lighting, and electric vehicles.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国科技巨头今年强势回归拉斯维加斯举办的消费电子展（CES），参展商数量较去年大幅增加。这一参展热潮反映出企业克服新冠疫情时代挑战并扩大海外增长的努力。人工智能 (AI) 成为展会上的主要趋势，许多公司展示了将其 AI 技术集成到产品中的成果。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国科技巨头带着对人工智能和国际增长的关注重返拉斯维加斯的 CES。</li>    <li>主题：中国科技公司在 CES 上的复苏以及人工智能技术作为行业驱动力的显着地位。</li>    <li>观点：CES 为中国企业提供了一个展示其最新创新并与全球合作伙伴建立联系的平台，尽管地缘政治紧张局势仍然存在。</li>    <li>主要信息：CES 上中国企业参展数量的增加；对人工智能和新兴技术的高度关注；中国企业面临的地缘政治紧张局势和限制所带来的挑战；来自电子商务、智能照明和电动汽车等多个行业的代表性企业。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>       <li>specific (adj.) - /spəˈsɪfɪk/ 具体的，详细的，明确的。    <p>原文例句：Govee is advertising the use of generative AI to help people create specific moods, like asking for a backdrop that is evocative of the Hong Kong skyline or Barbie Dreamhouse. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由拉丁语specificus（明确的）演变而来的，它包含了“指定，明确”的意思。在这个例句中，specific表示“特定的，明确的”，指用户可以通过生成式人工智能来创建特定的心情或场景，比如要求一个背景是香港天际线或芭比娃娃梦之屋。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>     <li>autonomous (adj.) - /ɔːˈtɒnəməs/ 自主的，自治的，独立的。    <p>原文例句：Wuhan-based autonomous driving chip maker Black Sesame.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由希腊语autos（自己）和nomos（法律）构成的，它表示“自我管理，自我控制”。在这个例句中，autonomous driving chip maker是指自动驾驶芯片制造商，即生产自动驾驶汽车所用芯片的公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>     <li>national security (n.) - /ˈnæʃ(ə)nəl sɪˈkjʊərəti/ 国家安全，国家安全。    <p>原文例句：TikTok and its Beijing-based owner ByteDance have been under intense political scrutiny in Washington over data privacy and national security concerns. </p>    <p>例句讲解：national security这个词由national（国家的）和security（安全）组成，表示“国家安全”。在这个例句中，national security concerns是指数据隐私和国家安全问题。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Xpeng is among the major electric vehicle makers at the show, where it will be demonstrating its new “flying car”, the AeroHT.    <p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是Xpeng，谓语是will be demonstrating，宾语是its new “flying car”, the AeroHT。其中Xpeng是一个中国电动汽车制造商，will be demonstrating表示将要展示，its new “flying car”, the AeroHT是指小鹏汽车的新款“飞行汽车”AeroHT。这个句子的意思是说，小鹏汽车是展会上主要的电动汽车制造商之一，它将在展会上展示其新款“飞行汽车”AeroHT。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在并且已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TikTok and its Beijing-based owner ByteDance have been under intense political scrutiny in Washington over data privacy and national security concerns.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是由have/has been + 过去分词构成的。have/has been要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在并且已经完成的动作或状态，强调动作或状态已经结束或完成。在这个例句中，it have been under intense political scrutiny表示TikTok和字节跳动自一段时间以来一直受到华盛顿的严格政治审查，到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态的承受者。    <p>原文例句：TikTok and its Beijing-based owner ByteDance have been under intense political scrutiny in Washington over data privacy and national security concerns. </p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是由be + 过去分词构成的。be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种语态表示动作或状态的承受者，强调动作或状态的承受者而不是动作或状态的执行者。在这个例句中，TikTok and its Beijing-based owner ByteDance have been under intense political scrutiny中的TikTok and its Beijing-based owner ByteDance是动作或状态的承受者，表示TikTok和字节跳动一直受到华盛顿的严格政治审查。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>AI is the major trend this year in the wake of ChatGPT, with many companies touting how they are integrating the tech into their products</li>
<li>The return of Chinese tech giants comes even as geopolitical tensions have barely budged from where they were last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/2545b743-77c1-45e1-83aa-b5a50e2cd69e_8fe19122.jpg" /><figcaption>Attendees arrive at the CES Unveiled event before the start of the CES tech show, January 7, 2024, in Las Vegas. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese companies have returned to Las Vegas for CES in full force this year, with more than double the number of exhibitors compared with last year, including big names like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance">ByteDance</a> and Alibaba.com, as companies try to shake off Covid-era blues with overseas growth.</p><p>CES lists 1,115 companies registered from China on its website, a 126 per cent increase over the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial">493 listed</a> at the beginning of the 2023 show. That does not include many of the biggest names on the list, which joined using international addresses.</p><p>ByteDance and its subsidiary <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a>, along with big hardware brands from last year like TCL and Lenovo are registered under their US offices. Even <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, owner of the South China Morning Post, has a presence through its subsidiary Alibaba.com Singapore.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247219/tiktok-eyes-us175-billion-shopping-business-amazons-turf" title="">TikTok eyes US$17.5 billion shopping business on Amazon’s turf</a></h3><p>“You have big exhibitors coming back, really showcasing that this is a platform that really pushes for consumers and enterprises and maybe [can] combat some of these major challenges that we’re facing,” Brian Comiskey, director of consumer programmes at the CTA, said after his opening remarks on Sunday afternoon.</p><p>This marks a stark reversal from 2023, when China had just started to reopen its borders but restrictions did not fall fast enough for many companies to make it to the show in the first week of January.</p><p>“Some of the largest Chinese companies that have signed up for participation this year … will all have a large presence at the show,” John Kelley, vice-president and show director for CES at the Consumer Technology Association (CTA), told the Post in an interview on November 29. “But where we’re really seeing growth on the Chinese side is smaller companies.”</p><p>Kelley said the CTA was anticipating numbers to reach pre-Covid levels, and it looks like the show has pulled it off. The number of Chinese companies is more than the 1,000 that state-run tabloid Global Times reported for the 2020 show. CTA said the show has attracted around 4,000 exhibitors, although numbers are not final yet. Kelley said CES expects to see 130,000 attendees.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence">Artificial intelligence (AI)</a> is expected to be the major trend at the show this year, playing an even larger role since ChatGPT ignited a generative AI arms race over the past year. Smart homes, green tech and electric vehicles were other areas highlighted during the show’s opening remarks to the media.</p><p>Alibaba was highlighted as one of the exhibitors using machine learning platforms to “power e-commerce”.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1306" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/d1856897-2d66-43bf-b0ad-271970378ed9_da47af5a.jpg" title="Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even much smaller companies are touting their use of AI. Govee, a smart lighting maker from Shenzhen, is advertising the use of generative AI to help people create specific moods, like asking for a backdrop that is evocative of the Hong Kong skyline or Barbie Dreamhouse.</p><p>Some fabless chip design firms are also exhibiting, such as Fuzhou-based mobile chip maker Rockchip and Wuhan-based autonomous driving chip maker Black Sesame, which contracts with electric car companies Geely and BYD. Black Sesame chips are manufactured by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a>, it said.</p><p>Xpeng is among the major electric vehicle makers at the show, where it will be demonstrating its new “flying car”, the AeroHT.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1067" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/b8c16129-faf2-4eac-924a-4824d9f25c14_5368aac5.jpg" title="XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>The return of Chinese tech giants comes even as geopolitical tensions have barely budged from where they were last year. US President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping may have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3241692/joe-biden-xi-jinping-meet-person-first-time-year-apec-sidelines" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3241692/joe-biden-xi-jinping-meet-person-first-time-year-apec-sidelines">met in November</a>, but there have been no major policy shifts around escalating restrictions on technology such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors">semiconductors</a> and AI.</p><p>TikTok and its Beijing-based owner ByteDance have been under intense political scrutiny in Washington over data privacy and national security concerns. This may not have deterred TikTok from showing up to the largest consumer electronics shows in its largest market.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial" title="">Number of Chinese tech firms at CES 2023 less than half of pre-pandemic level</a></h3><p>Representatives from the company will join two panels at the show to discuss sports and entertainment. Beyond entertainment, though, ByteDance makes much of its money through advertising and has been trying to grow its e-commerce business.</p><p>Other Chinese companies cannot exhibit at the show even if they want to because they have been listed on Washington’s Entity List. This includes the world’s largest drone maker DJI and a number of semiconductor companies.</p><p>“From a show management perspective, we welcome participation from every company,” CTA’s Kelley said. “As a US-based trade association, we cannot allow participation if they are on some sort of Entity List. That’s really the only place where we will not allow participation.”</p><p>Still, CES may be more important for the many small firms that make up the bulk of the show’s exhibition floor. It remains the premier event of its kind.</p><p>“We like to make the case that the four days you spend in Las Vegas is some of the most efficient use of your time in the sense that you don’t have to necessarily travel the world to meet with individual business partners on six different continents,” said Kelley. “Instead, you can come to Las Vegas and meet everybody that you need to meet from the global technology industry over the course of a week.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
