<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>This year, prepare for the magic wand of generative AI to transform our world</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3247183/year-prepare-magic-wand-generative-ai-transform-our-world</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Generative AI, capable of generating text, images, videos, codes, etc., is gaining popularity and will become a powerful assistant across various industries by the end of 2024.</li>    <li>The trend of generative AI is shifting towards multi-modal expression, enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data, enhancing creative capabilities and improving efficiency.</li>    <li>Auto agents, capable of both generating and responding to prompts, are emerging, leading to the development of personalized generative AI systems.</li>    <li>Federated learning enables generative AI applications to operate locally on personal computers and smartphones, ensuring higher privacy protection and security.</li>    <li>Generative AI will play a significant role in 6G mobile technology, enabling the realization of connective intelligence and decentralized, evolving intelligence.</li>    <li>Governments need to address ethical, privacy, and copyright issues to ensure the positive development of generative AI and prevent malicious exploitation.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>生成式人工智能能够生成文本、图像、视频、代码等，正变得越来越普及，并将在 2024 年底前成为各个行业不可或缺的助手。</li>    <li>生成式人工智能的发展趋势正转向多模态表达，能够同时处理多种形式的数据，从而增强创造力和提高效率。</li>    <li>能够生成和响应提示的自动代理正在涌现，促使个性化生成式人工智能系统的开发。</li>    <li>联邦学习使生成式人工智能应用程序能够在个人电脑和智能手机上本地运行，确保更高的隐私保护和安全性。</li>    <li>生成式人工智能将在 6G 移动技术中发挥重要作用，实现连接智能和分散、不断演进的智能。</li>    <li>政府需要解决伦理、隐私和版权问题，以确保生成式人工智能的积极发展并防止恶意利用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>federated learning - 联合学习。      <p>原文例句：Generative AI applications that operate locally on personal computers and smartphones are built upon the concept of “federated learning”.</p>      <p>例句讲解：“联合学习”是指一种机器学习方法，其中多个参与者共同训练一个模型，而无需共享他们的原始数据。这种方法可以保护数据隐私，同时允许模型从所有参与者的数据中学习。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>connective intelligence - 连接智能。      <p>原文例句：Generative AI can be applied to various aspects of 6G, such as … connetive intelligence for new technologies.</p>      <p>例句讲解：“连接智能”是指一种新的智能形式，它将人类、物理世界和数字世界连接起来，实现实时、可靠和无处不在的交互和通信。这种智能可以帮助我们更好地理解世界，并解决一些复杂的问题。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>real-time solutions - 实时解决方案。      <p>原文例句：By the end of 2024, generative AI will become an invaluable assistant, providing support and help across different industries. Its powerful analysis and predictive capabilities will enable people to handle complex tasks and problems more efficiently, offering real-time solutions and recommendations.</p>      <p>例句讲解：“实时解决方案”是指能够立即提供解决方案或建议的方法或技术。这种解决方案通常需要使用实时数据和分析来做出决策，以便快速应对不断变化的情况。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The trend of generative AI is shifting towards multi-modal expression, enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data, enhancing creative capabilities and improving efficiency. - 生成式人工智能的发展趋势正转向多模态表达，能够同时处理多种形式的数据，从而增强创造力和提高效率。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，包含两个并列结构。第一个并列结构是“enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data, enhancing creative capabilities”，其中“enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data”是一个现在分词短语，作状语，表示生成式人工智能能够同时处理多种形式的数据；“enhancing creative capabilities”是一个现在分词短语，作目的状语，表示生成式人工智能能够增强创造力。第二个并列结构是“and improving efficiency”，其中“and”是并列连词，连接两个动词短语；“improving efficiency”是一个现在分词短语，作目的状语，表示生成式人工智能能够提高效率。</p><p>这个句子的意思是：生成式人工智能的发展趋势正转向多模态表达，能够同时处理多种形式的数据，从而增强创造力和提高效率。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由分词和修饰语组成的短语，在句中可作状语、表语、定语等。      <p>原文例句：The trend of generative AI is shifting towards multi-modal expression, enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data, enhancing creative capabilities and improving efficiency.</p>      <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，有三个分词短语：“enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data”，“enhancing creative capabilities”和“improving efficiency”。这些分词短语在句中都作状语，表示生成式人工智能能够同时处理多种形式的数据、增强创造力和提高效率。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>并列结构 - 由两个或多个并列的成分组成的结构，在句中可作主语、谓语、宾语等。      <p>原文例句：The trend of generative AI is shifting towards multi-modal expression, enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data, enhancing creative capabilities and improving efficiency.</p>      <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，有两个并列结构：“enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data, enhancing creative capabilities”和“and improving efficiency”。这两个并列结构在句中都作目的状语，表示生成式人工智能能够同时处理多种形式的数据、增强创造力和提高效率。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Generative AI is becoming active, multimodal and being embedded in PCs and smartphones, penetrating our daily lives in profound ways</li>
<li>Governments must pay attention to ethical, privacy and copyright issues to ensure the positive development of the technology</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/993c33b7-d303-46f3-9fa7-b02b2516d087_73af80ad.jpg" /><figcaption>Customs inspector Hui Ka-hei explains how XiaoHui, a virtual ambassador introduced at Hong Kong’s airport and three control points, works to to handle public enquiries, on December 29. Photo: Dickson Lee</figcaption></figure><p>Since the debut of ChatGPT at the end of 2022, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243449/chatgpt-one-year-how-openais-chatbot-brought-generative-artificial-intelligence-public-consciousness" target="_self" title="">generative artificial intelligence</a> (AI) has gained popularity globally. Various industries are eagerly adopting generative AI for diverse applications including the creation of text, images, videos, computer codes and more.</p><p>The output of generative AI in these domains has proliferated, presenting a diverse array of creative work. According to Gartner, an information technology (IT) research and consulting company in the United States, use of generative AI will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245217/chinese-generative-ai-account-third-industrys-economic-value-2035-beijing-think-tank-says" target="_self" title="">increase substantially</a> by 2026. It projects that more than 80 per cent of businesses will have integrated generative AI application programming interfaces (APIs), models and/or applications into their operations by then, from less than 5 per cent now.</p><p>IT experts believe that generative AI will play a transformative role this year, akin to a magic wand that changes the world. In light of these developments, what major trends in generative AI can we expect this year?</p><p>Last year, most generative AI tools, algorithms and large language models were primarily focused on a single media type: text, images, speech or video, with limited emphasis on the simultaneous processing of multiple media. But with the emergence of models like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238197/baidu-says-ai-chatbot-ernie-now-matches-openais-gpt-4-unveils-new-enterprise-tools" target="_self" title="">GPT-4</a>, generative AI is shifting towards multi-modal expression, enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data.</p><p>This suggests that human-machine communication will one day effortlessly incorporate mixed media, as ChatGPT is starting to do. Users can input non-textual cues, such as images, making the conversation more convenient and natural.</p><p>Furthermore, multi-modal generative AI is poised to enhance the creative capabilities of artists and improve the efficiency of professionals in fields such as writing, journalism and music. When appropriately used, multi-modal generative AI can spark artistic inspiration, generate work drafts or even fully automate content creation.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>In 2024, there is likely to be a proliferation of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224924/ai-challenging-us-rethink-distinction-between-real-and-fake" target="_self" title="">AI-generated art</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3227291/ai-generated-hits-hong-kong-stars-surprise-fans-bring-dead-singers-back-life-and-raise-questions" target="_self" title="">music</a>, videos and stories. Experts believe that through generative AI’s artistic contributions, content will become more diverse, innovative and distinctive, ushering in a new era for creative industries.</p><p>Last year, generative AI operated primarily through user-driven prompts. Taking <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> as an example, interactions were conducted in a “question and answer” format and were purely passive. In response to this limitation, scientists are researching “auto agent” technology.</p><p>Auto agents can both generate and respond to prompts, performing tasks more rapidly and efficiently. A recent example is the AutoGPT system, which recently raised US$12 million in a funding round. The goal is to develop AutoGPT into a large-scale open-source AI platform, serving various industries.</p><p>Also set to thrive is the development of personalised generative AI systems. Computer companies are researching and developing AI personal computers capable of running generative AI applications locally, while chip companies have developed AI-embedded mobile processors, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236845/google-unveils-pixel-8-smartphones-pixel-watch-2-new-ai-features-mobile-processor" target="_self" title="">enabling smartphones</a> to execute generative AI models.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>A plethora of intelligent devices with diverse generative AI functionalities is emerging.</p><p>Generative AI applications that operate locally on personal computers and smartphones are built upon the concept of “federated learning”. This approach can afford consumers higher levels of privacy protection and security since these platforms do not need to send user data to the cloud for tasks such as searches or information organisation.</p><p>Meanwhile, by analysing user-specific data such as preferences, behaviours and conversations, this type of generative AI can optimise its performance based on individual characteristics and requirements, providing tailored content and task execution. This not only addresses concerns regarding privacy and security but also saves consumers time and effort.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3213160/how-ai-could-free-us-return-pursuit-wisdom" title="">Could AI free us to return to the pursuit of wisdom?</a></h3><p>Generative AI is also expected to play a significant role in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/6g" target="_self" title="">6G mobile technology</a>. This year, work to set and agree on 6G standards will continue with the anticipation that the first standards could be introduced between 2027 and 2028, and the technology could reach commercialisation by 2030. Generative AI can be applied to various aspects of 6G, such as network resource management, spectrum allocation and network topology optimisation.</p><p>It is also capable of meeting the demands of “connective intelligence” for new technologies. Connective intelligence is a key force driving the development of the 6G network, enabling real-time, reliable and ubiquitous interaction and communication between humans, the physical world and the digital world. This results in the creation of a decentralised and continually evolving intelligence, making it easier for users to share their discoveries and experiences with each other.</p><p>In summary, by the end of 2024, generative AI will become an invaluable assistant, providing support and help across different industries. Its powerful analysis and predictive capabilities will enable people to handle complex tasks and problems more efficiently, offering real-time solutions and recommendations.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3242417/fears-over-ai-dangers-are-hindering-chance-create-better-future" title="">How cooperation on AI governance can curb risks and create a better future</a></h3><p>Whether in fielding queries about professional knowledge or optimising and automating business processes, generative AI will play a crucial role. It will also become the ideal companion in consumption, leisure and entertainment.</p><p>Through personalised recommendation systems and intelligent assistant features, generative AI will gain a deep understanding of user preferences and needs, providing customised product and service suggestions. Whether in shopping, travel, music, film and television entertainment or social interaction, generative AI will enhance our experiences.</p><p>Generative AI has become an irreversible trend, penetrating our daily lives in profound ways. Governments must pay attention to ethical, privacy and copyright issues to ensure the positive development of the technology. Otherwise, there is a risk of unintended consequences, allowing malicious individuals to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246612/chatgpt-aided-ransomware-china-results-four-arrests-ai-raises-cybersecurity-concerns" target="_self" title="">exploit</a> generative AI’s capabilities.</p><p><strong>Wong Kam-fai is a legislative councillor, associate dean (external affairs) of the Faculty of Engineering at Chinese University and vice-president of the Hong Kong Professionals And Senior Executives Association</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple supplier Foxconn sees revenue decline in first quarter of 2024 amid weak global consumer electronics demand, sluggish iPhone sales</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Foxconn's Q1 outlook reflects Apple's concerns about sluggish iPhone sales.</li>    <li>Weak demand and protests at Zhengzhou plant impacted Q4 results.</li>    <li>Huawei's resurgence in China adds to competition for Apple.</li>    <li>Foxconn diversifies supply chain and plans new factories in China and India.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>富士康第一季度业绩展望反映出苹果对 iPhone 销售疲软的担忧。</li>    <li>弱劲需求和郑州工厂抗议活动影响了第四季度业绩。</li>    <li>华为在中国的复苏加剧了与苹果的竞争。</li>    <li>富士康在中印两国进行多元化布点，计划建设新工厂。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>off-peak (adj.) - 淡季的，非高峰期的。    <p>原文例句：The world’s largest electronics contract manufacturer also indicated that the year’s first quarter is typically an off-peak season for the industry. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“off-peak”意为“淡季的，非高峰期的”，指一年中业务或活动较少的时候。在这个例句中，“off-peak season”指淡季。</p></li>    <li>sluggish (adj.) - 疲软的，缓慢的。    <p>原文例句：The company’s dim first-quarter outlook reflects concerns raised by investors of major client Apple about sluggish iPhone sales.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“sluggish”意为“疲软的，缓慢的”，指经济或销售增长缓慢。在这个例句中，“sluggish iPhone sales”指 iPhone 销售疲软。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>provide an estimate - 提供估计</li>    <li>raise concerns - 提出担忧</li>    <li>be hit by - 受到打击</li>    <li>face intense competition - 面临激烈竞争</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Foxconn Technology Group, the world’s biggest iPhone assembler, expects revenue to decline in the first quarter of 2024 amid weak global consumer electronics demand, extending a decrease in sales in the past three months. - 富士康科技集团，全球最大的 iPhone 组装商，预计 2024 年第一季度收入将下降，因为全球消费电子产品需求疲软，过去三个月的销售额下降将持续下去。</li>    <li>Revenue for the company’s December quarter fell 5.4 per cent year on year to NT$1.85 trillion (US$60 billion), but was up by 20 per cent from the previous quarter. - 该公司 12 月季度的收入同比下降 5.4%，至 1.85 万亿新台币（600 亿美元），但较上一季度增长了 20%。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子中的某个成分。</li>    <p>原文例句：It was Huawei that saw strong demand for its new 5G handsets in the world’s largest smartphone market. </p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句型的基本结构是：It is/was + 被强调成分 + that + 其他（句子成分）。在这个例句中，被强调的成分是Huawei，强调的是华为对新 5G 手机的强劲需求。</p>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。</li>    <p>原文例句：Foxconn has stepped up efforts to diversify its manufacturing supply chain for Apple and other clients amid the weak post-pandemic economic recovery in mainland China and rising geopolitical tensions between Beijing and Washington.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时的基本结构是：has/have + 过去分词。在这个例句中，has stepped up表示富士康加强了努力，diversify表示多元化，diversify its manufacturing supply chain表示多元化其制造供应链，for Apple and other clients表示针对苹果和其他客户，amid the weak post-pandemic economic recovery in mainland China and rising geopolitical tensions between Beijing and Washington表示在中国大陆疫情后的经济复苏疲软和北京与华盛顿之间不断加剧的地缘政治紧张局势中。这个句子的意思是，富士康加强了努力，在疫情后的经济复苏疲软和北京与华盛顿之间不断加剧的地缘政治紧张局势中，为苹果和其他客户多元化其制造供应链。</p>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Foxconn did not provide an estimate of the quarterly drop, but said the year’s first three months represent an off-peak season for the industry</li>
<li>The world’s largest electronics contract manufacturer reported total 2023 revenue was down 7 per cent year on year to US$198.9 billion</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/e222829d-56dc-48eb-b8cb-9a2ea658a625_cee121ea.jpg" /><figcaption>Foxconn Technology Group’s dim first-quarter outlook reflects concerns raised by investors of major client Apple about sluggish iPhone sales. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foxconn?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Foxconn Technology Group</a>, the world’s biggest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> assembler, expects revenue to decline in the first quarter of 2024 amid weak global consumer electronics demand, extending a decrease in sales in the past three months.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>-based Foxconn, formally known as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hon-hai-precision-industry?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Hon Hai Precision Industry</a>, did not provide an estimate on the quarterly revenue drop, but said the first three months will be compared to a high base in the same period last year, when its factories in mainland China resumed normal operations after disruptive pandemic controls were relaxed by the government, according to the company’s statement on Friday.</p><p>The world’s largest electronics contract manufacturer also indicated that the year’s first quarter is typically an off-peak season for the industry.</p><p>Revenue for the company’s December quarter fell 5.4 per cent year on year to NT$1.85 trillion (US$60 billion), but was up by 20 per cent from the previous quarter. Total 2023 revenue was US$198.9 billion, down 7 per cent from 2022.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen" class="image-inline caption" height="1243" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/09a87505-ea2a-40a2-91f3-d3980a90b343_8f795096.jpg" title="People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen" width="2000" /><figcaption>People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen</figcaption></figure></div><p>Foxconn on Friday blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, even though the company went through a bumpy period a year ago when its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3225783/worlds-largest-iphone-factory-zhengzhou-ramps-hiring-foxconn-chairman-reassures-china-supply-chain" target="_self" title="">biggest iPhone plant in Zhengzhou</a>, capital of central Henan province, was rocked by an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3197909/coronavirus-iphone-factory-exodus-shows-how-chinas-covid-narrative-still-strikes-fear-public?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">exodus of tens of thousands of employees</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3200747/violence-erupts-foxconn-zhengzhou-plant-workers-protest-over-benefits-and-covid-19-controls-worlds?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">violent workers’ protests</a> amid a Covid-19 outbreak that began in late October.</p><p>The company’s dim first-quarter outlook reflects concerns raised by investors of major client Apple about sluggish iPhone sales, which prompted the US tech giant to be <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">hit by two ratings downgrades</a> this week.</p><p>“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">said in a client note</a>, which pointed to weakness in China and subdued demand in developed markets.</p><p>Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247501/apples-reign-worlds-most-valuable-stock-market-value-jeopardy-bumpy-2024-start" title="">Apple’s lofty status as world’s most valuable stock at risk from bumpy 2024 start</a></h3><p>Apple, which has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022, has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.</p><p>The company’s iPhones also face intense competition on the mainland against a resurgent <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, which is seeing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" target="_self" title="">strong demand for its new 5G handsets</a> in the world’s largest smartphone market.</p><p>While Apple <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" target="_self" title="">continues to lead the global premium smartphone market</a>, where handsets are priced from US$600, Huawei has gained ground in this segment on the back of its new Mate 60 series.</p><p>Foxconn is also <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234562/foxconn-offers-higher-hourly-rates-workers-shenzhen-its-huawei-production-unit-its-iphone-operation" target="_self" title="">offering higher rates for workers that make Huawei’s handsets</a> in southern tech hub <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shenzhen" target="_self" title="">Shenzhen</a> than those that make iPhones, according to a South China Morning Post report last September.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions" title="">Foxconn ramps up investment in giant Apple plant in India</a></h3><p>Still, Foxconn has stepped up efforts to diversify its manufacturing supply chain for Apple and other clients amid the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246222/chinas-middle-class-does-not-dare-spend-until-post-covid-economy-shows-clear-signs-recovery" target="_self" title="">weak post-pandemic economic recovery</a> in mainland China and rising geopolitical tensions between Beijing and Washington.</p><p>Foxconn won approval to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions" target="_self" title="">invest at least US$1 billion more in a plant</a> it is building in India that will make Apple products, on top of the US$1.6 billion it earlier pledged, according to a report by Bloomberg last month.</p><p>On the mainland, Foxconn continues to invest in central Henan province, where it employs 200,000 workers in the firm’s Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p><p>The Taiwanese firm, which was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239113/china-says-investigation-apple-supplier-foxconns-operations-mainland-normal-law-enforcement" target="_self" title="">put under investigation in October by mainland regulators</a>, this year plans to start building new factories for smartphones and other electronics products in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of 520 major construction projects for 2024 released this week by the province’s Development and Reform Commission.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s reign as world’s most valuable stock by market value in jeopardy from bumpy 2024 start</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247501/apples-reign-worlds-most-valuable-stock-market-value-jeopardy-bumpy-2024-start</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  On Friday, Apple's stock price dropped by 0.4% after news that the US Justice Department is near to filing an antitrust lawsuit against the company. Bloomberg data shows that the tech giant has lost about US$177 billion in market value this year, making it the most challenging start to a year in recent history. Investors are reacting to growing pressures on Apple, including slowing iPhone sales and patent concerns related to the Apple Watch.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple stock declines due to antitrust case and market value loss.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple faces challenges and risks as investors react to mounting pressures.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of antitrust lawsuit threats, slowing iPhone sales, and patent issues on Apple's market dominance.</li>    <li>Main information: The decline in Apple's stock price; analyst perspectives on the company's situation; its shrinking lead over Microsoft; and the rotation of investor portfolios at the start of the year.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  周五，苹果公司股票下跌0.4%，此前有报道称，美国司法部即将对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。根据彭博社汇编的数据，这家科技巨头今年到目前为止已损失了约1,770亿美元的市值，使其成为近年来最具挑战性的开年。投资者正在对苹果公司日益增长的压力做出反应，包括iPhone销售放缓以及与Apple Watch相关的专利问题。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果股票因反垄断案和市值损失而下跌。</li>    <li>主题：苹果面临挑战和风险，因为投资者对不断增长的压力做出反应。</li>    <li>观点：反垄断诉讼威胁、iPhone销售放缓以及专利问题对苹果市场主导地位的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果股价下跌；分析师对公司状况的看法；其对微软的领先优势缩小；以及年初投资者投资组合的轮换。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>antitrust (n.) - 反垄断，反托拉斯。    <p>原文例句：Apple just had its worst start to the year by one measure, as investors react to mounting pressures on the company, putting its long-standing status as the world’s most valuable stock by market value in jeopardy.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由anti-（反对）和trust（信托，托拉斯）组成，表示“反垄断，反托拉斯”。在这个例句中，它指的是对苹果公司提起反垄断诉讼，因为苹果公司被指控滥用市场权力，损害消费者的利益。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>plummet (v.) - /ˈplʌmɪt/ 暴跌，直线下降。    <p>原文例句：Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由plummet（铅垂线）演变而来的，表示“暴跌，直线下降”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司的股票价格在周五下跌了0.4%，至每股181美元左右，原因是《纽约时报》报道称美国司法部即将对苹果公司提起反垄断诉讼。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>by one measure - 按照一种衡量标准。    <P>原文例句：Apple just had its worst start to the year by one measure, as investors react to mounting pressures on the company, putting its long-standing status as the world’s most valuable stock by market value in jeopardy.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由by（通过，按照）和one measure（一种衡量标准）构成的，表示“按照一种衡量标准”。在这个例句中，它指的是根据一种衡量标准，苹果公司今年开局最差。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The tech giant has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg - 根据彭博社汇编的数据，这家科技巨头今年到目前为止已损失了约1,770亿美元的市值。<p>句子分析：这是一个陈述句，主语是The tech giant，谓语是has seen，宾语是about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year。according to data compiled by Bloomberg是一个介词短语作原因状语，表示根据彭博社汇编的数据。这个句子的意思是说，根据彭博社汇编的数据，这家科技巨头今年到目前为止已损失了约1,770亿美元的市值。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态正在进行，强调动作或状态的持续性。在这个例句中，it表示苹果公司的股票在周五下跌了0.4%，收于每股181美元左右，原因是《纽约时报》报道称美国司法部即将对苹果公司提起反垄断诉讼。显然，苹果股票下跌的动作正在进行。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设或愿望的情况。    <p>原文例句：Apple just had its worst start to the year by one measure, as investors react to mounting pressures on the company, putting its long-standing status as the world’s most valuable stock by market value in jeopardy.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语气，结构是：would/could/should/might + 动词原形。这种语气表示假设或愿望的情况，不表示事实。在这个例句中，it表示苹果公司今年开局最差，因为投资者对公司日益增长的压力做出反应，使其作为全球市值最高股票的长期地位岌岌可危。显然，苹果公司开局最差是假设的情况。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Shares of Apple fell 0.4 per cent on Friday after a report that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company</li>
<li>The tech giant has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/0bab1060-0f68-4b59-b625-ee8f62b7b778_cec54c59.jpg" /><figcaption>People walk past an Apple Store in the Glendale Galleria shopping mall in California on December 26, 2023. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> just had its worst start to the year by one measure, as investors react to mounting pressures on the company, putting its long-standing status as the world’s most valuable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/stocks" target="_self" title="">stock</a> by market value in jeopardy.</p><p>Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.</p><p>The decline notched the fifth consecutive negative day for Apple, its longest losing streak since October.</p><p>The potential antitrust case against Apple “would add to the plethora of problems it faces, from slowing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> sales to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246452/apple-resumes-sale-watches-after-appeals-court-lifts-us-ban" target="_self" title="">Apple Watch patent issues</a>”, Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Anurag Rana wrote in a note. “The suit could attack Apple’s business model of tightly integrating its devices and services.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/bdba7b4d-2eef-4fae-a196-1d3cd943fe89_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Cupertino, California-based company has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022, but has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.</p><p>While the stock has suffered bigger percentage declines in the first week of January, the losses are the biggest market value destruction at the start of any year on record.</p><p>The downturn began earlier in the week after the technology giant was hit by two <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" target="_self" title="">ratings downgrades</a>, with analysts flagging a weak macro environment in China pressuring demand for iPhones.</p><p>That has shrunk its lead over fellow technology juggernaut <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft Corp</a> – whose shares have seen a less pronounced decline to begin the year – to less than US$100 billion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247211/apple-leads-us383-billion-tech-rout-reversal-groups-2023-rally" title="">Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</a></h3><p>“Investors realise how rare it is to have two people go negative,” said Gene Munster, managing partner of Deepwater Asset Management. “I’ve been covering this company for a long time and I’ve never seen two downgrades before an earnings report.”</p><p>Apple is also likely under pressure as investors rotate their portfolios at the start of the year.</p><p>“Everybody’s selling their winners and buying losers,” said Brian Mulberry, client portfolio manager at Zacks Investment Management. “There’s a big rebalance going on.”</p><p>The losses have pushed Apple’s market value down to about US$2.8 trillion, nearing Microsoft’s US$2.7 trillion. Shares of Microsoft fell less than 0.1 per cent Friday to close at about US$368.</p><p>The Windows software maker has benefited from the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> trade that has mesmerised Wall Street over the past year. The company is <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content" target="_self" title="">OpenAI</a>’s largest shareholder and has invested about US$13 billion into the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> parent.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech trade group representing TikTok, Snapchat and Meta sues Ohio over state’s new law limiting children’s use of social media apps</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247497/tech-trade-group-representing-tiktok-snapchat-and-meta-sues-ohio-over-states-new-law-limiting</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  俄亥俄州一项要求社交媒体公司在 16 岁以下儿童注册社交媒体和视频游戏应用时获得父母许可的新法律引起了争议。该法律的目的是保护儿童的心理健康，但 NetChoice 贸易组织认为该法律违反宪法，过于宽泛和模糊。他们已向俄亥俄州南部地区联邦地区法院提起诉讼，寻求阻止该法律生效。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Ohio's new law requiring parental consent for children's social media use is challenged as unconstitutional.</li>    <li>Theme: The conflict between protecting children's mental health and preserving free speech in the digital age.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: NetChoice's argument that the law violates the First Amendment and is overly broad and vague; Husted's defense of the law as necessary to protect children from harmful content.</li>    <li>Main information: The provisions of the law, including obtaining parental permission, providing privacy guidelines, and potential consequences for tech companies; NetChoice's previous legal victories in similar cases; Husted's criticism of the tech companies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  A new law in Ohio requiring social media companies to obtain parental consent for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps has drawn a legal challenge. The law, part of a state budget bill signed by Republican Governor Mike DeWine in July, is set to take effect on January 15. The NetChoice trade group, representing major tech companies including TikTok, Snapchat, and Facebook and Instagram operator Meta Platforms, sued Ohio on Friday over the pending law. The lawsuit argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps – unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Ohio's new law requiring parental consent for children's social media use is challenged as unconstitutional.</li>    <li>Theme: The conflict between protecting children's mental health and preserving free speech in the digital age.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: NetChoice's argument that the law violates the First Amendment and is overly broad and vague; Husted's defense of the law as necessary to protect children from harmful content.</li>    <li>Main information: The provisions of the law, including obtaining parental permission, providing privacy guidelines, and potential consequences for tech companies; NetChoice's previous legal victories in similar cases; Husted's criticism of the tech companies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>pending (adj.) - /ˈpɛndɪŋ/ 悬而未决的，未决的。    <p>原文例句：A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由pend（悬挂，悬而未决）构成的，表示“悬而未决的，未决的”。在这个例句中，它指的是一项要求儿童在使用社交媒体应用程序之前获得父母同意的俄亥俄州待定法律，该法律是共和党州长迈克·德温于 2023 年 7 月签署成为法律的一部分，并将于 1 月 15 日生效。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>vague (adj.) - /veɪg/ 模糊的，含糊的。    <p>原文例句：The litigation argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps – unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语vague，表示“模糊的，含糊的”。在这个例句中，它指的是一项要求社交媒体公司在 16 岁以下儿童注册社交媒体和视频游戏应用程序时获得父母许可的俄亥俄州法律，该法律被指控违宪地阻碍言论自由，并且过于宽泛和模糊。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take effect - 生效，有效。    <P>原文例句：It is set to take effect on January 15.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，接受）和effect（效果，效力）构成的，表示“生效，有效”。在这个例句中，它表示该法律将于 1 月 15 日生效。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The law was part of an US$86.1 billion state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July. - 这项法律是共和党州长迈克·德温去年 7 月签署成为法律的 861 亿美元州预算法案的一部分。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The law was part of a state budget bill，其中主语是The law，谓语是was part of，宾语是a state budget bill。that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July是一个定语从句，修饰state budget bill，表示这是共和党州长迈克·德温去年 7 月签署成为法律的。这个句子的意思是说，这项法律是共和党州长迈克·德温去年 7 月签署成为法律的 861 亿美元州预算法案的一部分。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由主语承受的。    <p>原文例句：The law was signed into law last July by Republican Governor Mike DeWine. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态句，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词形式。这个例句中，be用的是was，表示过去时态，过去分词是signed，表示签署。这个句子的意思是说，这项法律是共和党州长迈克·德温去年 7 月签署成为法律的。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人对某件事的假设、愿望或建议。    <p>原文例句：They said in a statement that “With NetChoice v Yost, we will fight to ensure all Ohioans can embrace digital tools without their privacy, security and rights being thwarted.” </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气句，结构是：would/could/should/might + 动词原形。这个例句中，would用的是will，表示将来时态，动词原形是fight。这个句子的意思是说，他们在一份声明中说，“我们将致力于确保所有俄亥俄州人能够使用数字工具，而不会损害他们的隐私、安全和权利”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The law forms part of a state budget bill that Ohio Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July and is set to take effect on January 15</li>
<li>The NetChoice trade group argues that Ohio’s law unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/0827334f-9aca-4109-b4e2-813fa20ac5b8_06ce695b.jpg" /><figcaption>Ohio’s new law requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps. Photo: TNS</figcaption></figure><p>A trade group representing major tech companies including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/snapchat" target="_self" title="">Snapchat</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/facebook" target="_self" title="">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/instagram" target="_self" title="">Instagram</a> operator <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226704/meta-takes-aim-twitter-launch-rival-app-threads" target="_self" title="">Meta Platforms</a> sued Ohio on Friday over the state’s pending law that requires children to get parental consent to use <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">apps</a>.</p><p>The law was part of an US$86.1 billion state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July. It is set to take effect on January 15.</p><p>The administration pushed the measure as a way to protect children’s mental health, with Republican Lieutenant Governor Jon Husted saying at the time that social media was “intentionally addictive” and harmful to kids.</p><p>The NetChoice trade group filed its lawsuit against Republican Attorney General Dave Yost in US District Court for the Southern district of Ohio. It seeks to block the law from taking effect.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP" class="image-inline caption" height="1410" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/8d380f8f-5e87-4f75-add2-ca49bea0915b_3ad8b242.jpg" title="A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP" width="2000" /><figcaption>A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The litigation argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> apps – unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p><p>The law also requires social media companies to provide parents with their privacy guidelines, so that families can know what content will be censored or moderated on their child’s profile.</p><p>“We at NetChoice believe families equipped with educational resources are capable of determining the best approach to online services and privacy protections for themselves,” Chris Marchese, director of the organisation’s litigation centre, said in a statement.</p><p>“With NetChoice v Yost, we will fight to ensure all Ohioans can embrace digital tools without their privacy, security and rights being thwarted.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247089/montana-appealing-ruling-blocked-state-barring-tiktok-use" title="">Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok use</a></h3><p>The group has won lawsuits against similar restrictions in California and Arkansas.</p><p>Husted, who leads Ohio’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> initiatives and championed the law, called Friday’s lawsuit “cowardly but not unexpected”.</p><p>“In filing this lawsuit, these companies are determined to go around parents to expose children to harmful content and addict them to their platforms,” Husted said in a statement.</p><p>He also alleged the tech companies know their algorithms are harming children “with catastrophic health and mental health outcomes”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China needs ‘groundbreaking’ policy changes to embrace disruptive technologies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247450/china-needs-groundbreaking-policy-changes-embrace-disruptive-technologies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  China needs to adjust its industrial policymaking for disruptive technologies that may significantly change the way consumers, industries, and businesses operate. The selective industrial policy, which led to China's success, may not be suitable for these technologies. China should promote innovation and entrepreneurship, relax market access, and support small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) to drive innovation.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China needs to adjust its industrial policy for disruptive technologies.</li>    <li>Theme: The impact of disruptive technologies on China's economy and the need for policy changes.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: China should make groundbreaking changes to its industrial policymaking and focus on functional policies to embrace disruptive technologies.</li>    <li>Main information: The shift from selective industrial policy to functional policy; importance of innovation, entrepreneurship, and SMEs; the role of small market players; challenges in resource allocation and decision-making.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  中国需要调整其产业政策来应对颠覆性技术，这些技术可能极大地改变消费者、行业和企业运作方式。促成中国取得成功的选择性产业政策可能不适用于这些技术。中国应该促进创新和创业精神，放松市场准入，并支持中小型企业 (SME) 以推动创新。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国需要调整其针对颠覆性技术的产业政策。</li>    <li>主题：颠覆性技术对中国经济的影响和政策变革的必要性。</li>    <li>观点：中国应该对其产业政策制定做出开创性的变革，并专注于职能性政策以接纳颠覆性技术。</li>    <li>主要信息：从选择性产业政策转变为职能政策；创新、创业精神和中小型企业的重要性；小型市场参与者的作用；资源分配和决策的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>paradigm (n.) - /ˈpærədaɪm/ 范式，模式。    <p>原文例句：Huang Shaoqing, a professor of economics at the Antai College of Economics and Management at Shanghai Jiao Tong University, said in a report. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“paradigm”源自希腊语“paradeigma”，意为“模式、样板”，指“被认为或被接受为模型或模式的事物”。在这个例子中，“paradigm”指的是“模式、范式”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>disruptive (adj.) - /dɪsˈrʌptɪv/ 破坏性的，颠覆性的。    <p>原文例句：Disruptive technologies, including artificial intelligence and quantum computing, will significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“disruptive”源自拉丁语“disrumpere”，意为“打破、分裂”，形容词形式为“disruptive”，指“破坏性的、颠覆性的”。在这个例子中，“disruptive technologies”指的是“颠覆性技术”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make a shift - 作出转变。    <p>原文例句：“How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgent,” he wrote in the report, which had earlier been published in Mandarin by the Journal of Comparative Studies in February 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“make a shift”意为“作出转变”，强调从一种状态或情况转变到另一种状态或情况。在这个例子中，“make a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm”指的是“从选择性产业政策范式转变到职能政策范式”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China should make ‘groundbreaking changes’ to its industrial policymaking, otherwise, it will never be a global technological and economic leader,” Peng said. - 彭说，中国需要对其产业政策制定做出“开创性的变革”，否则它将永远不会成为全球技术和经济领导者。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是China should make ‘groundbreaking changes’ to its industrial policymaking，其中主语是China，谓语是should make，宾语是‘groundbreaking changes’ to its industrial policymaking。otherwise, it will never be a global technological and economic leader是一个结果状语，表示“否则，它将永远不会成为全球技术和经济领导者”。这个句子的意思是说，中国需要对其产业政策制定做出“开创性的变革”，否则它将永远不会成为全球技术和经济领导者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“there be”句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Disruptive technologies, including artificial intelligence and quantum computing, will significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate</li>
<li>China should make ‘groundbreaking changes’ to its industrial policymaking amid its push to become a global technological and economic leader, analysts said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/df3b6f4b-498c-4140-80f2-8b42e0ebe9ed_9f02ea50.jpg" /><figcaption>China’s HL-2M reactor in Sichuan could provide a long-term solution to the world’s energy needs by generating power without producing nuclear waste. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China needs to adjust its industrial policymaking to brace for possible revolutionary changes to its economy by disruptive technologies, analysts said.</p><p>From artificial intelligence (AI) to quantum computing, and from room-temperature superconductivity to controllable nuclear fusion, disruptive technologies are set to significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate.</p><p>China’s economic miracle over the past four decades has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs.</p><p>This model has been adopted by other economies in East Asia during their development in the second half of 20th century.</p><blockquote>How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgentHuang Shaoqing</blockquote><p>“As frontier technologies, no one knows what technology truly has promising prospects, which could ultimately be screened out by the market through competition,” Huang Shaoqing, a professor of economics at the Antai College of Economics and Management at Shanghai Jiao Tong University, said in a report.</p><p>“Therefore, in the early development stage of disruptive technologies, economies of scale are not important and even dangerous.”</p><p>Huang said in the report published by the English-language Asian Review of Political Economy in October 2022 that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”.</p><p>“How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgent,” he wrote in the report, which had earlier been published in Mandarin by the Journal of Comparative Studies in February 2022.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>The urgency has become more prominent for Beijing, which views innovation and technological advancement as key to countering the heightened containment efforts by the United States, and also crucial for its ambition to become an economic and tech superpower by the middle of the century.</p><p>Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, said China needs to plan areas where matured technologies can be applied, including sectors influenced by US export bans, and that involve more markets.</p><p>“China needs to make groundbreaking changes to its industrial policymaking, otherwise, it will never be a global technological and economic leader,” Peng said.</p><p>“Decision makers need to listen more to private companies, give them enough funding for industrial research, and place them at the front role of disruptive industrial exploration.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies" title="">‘More, better’: premier urges China to focus on application of core technologies</a></h3><p>But as it is impossible to determine in advance which technology would prevail, a country can gain an advantage only if it develops enough small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) to offer sufficient diversified technological routes, Huang added.</p><p>“Only by promoting innovation and entrepreneurship, relaxing market access, improving the business environment, and allowing as many as SMEs as possible to grow rapidly can these SMEs play an important role in economic development driven by innovation,” he said.</p><p>In 2016 when mapping out a national scientific and technology plan, Beijing vowed to improve tracking revolutionary industrial development to be capable of prejudging “the turning point” of possible replacements for traditional industries.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>At the time it added that it would make a timely plan for research into disruptive technologies, such as AI, quantum information, genome editing, unmanned driving, hydrogen power and nanotechnology.</p><p>Li Yangwei, a technical consultant in the computing sector in Shenzhen, said disruptive technologies may lead to bigger tech and economic gaps among regions within China, but when there are more participants, the cost of any potential failures can be lowered.</p><p>He also said small market players can offer advice to the central government about industrial policies, but amid hefty external pressure and geopolitical complications, Beijing may still allocate resources to big companies or state-owned enterprises.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3243101/chinas-ai-aspirations-will-fuel-economy-drive-investment-trillions-dollars-mckinsey" title="">China’s AI gains will fuel economy as windfall swells into trillions: McKinsey</a></h3><p>“It also requires technocrats to be socially, economically and politically insightful, as well as having strong communication skills and being given central decision-making power,” Li said.</p><p>China’s basic research accounted for more than 6 per cent of its total research and development (R&amp;D) expenditure in the last four years, lower than the 16 to 18 per cent in the US and 22 per cent in France over the last 10 years.</p><p>Basic research from enterprises only accounted for 0.78 per cent of China’s overall R&amp;D expenditure, behind over 6 per cent in developed countries, according to a report in February by the Science and Technology Daily, a newspaper backed by the Ministry of Science and Technology.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
