<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Nvidia’s China customers to get hobbled version of gaming chip</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3246591/nvidias-china-customers-get-hobbled-version-gaming-chip</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Nvidia is selling a less powerful version of its GTX 4090 D graphics card in China due to US export restrictions. The Chinese version has about 10% fewer processing cores and fewer processing sub units for AI workloads compared to the global version. Nvidia says it worked closely with the US government to develop this compliant product, which will be available in January. The company's CEO has stated that they will produce versions of their products that comply with US export rules for China.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Nvidia's customized graphics card for China meets US export regulations.</li>    <li>Theme: Nvidia adapts its top graphics product for China in response to US restrictions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of US export controls on Nvidia's business and the global semiconductor industry.</li>    <li>Main information: The technical differences between the Chinese and global versions of the GTX 4090 D; Nvidia's engagement with the US government; the broader context of US-China tensions and export restrictions.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  英伟达公司因美国出口限制而在中国销售功能较弱的版本 GTX 4090 D 显卡。与全球版本相比，中国版本少了大约 10% 的处理核心，还减少了用于 AI 工作负载的处理子单元。英伟达表示，他们与美国政府密切合作开发了这款符合规定的产品，将于 1 月份上市。该公司首席执行官表示他们将生产符合美国针对中国出口规则的产品版本。  <ul>    <li>摘要：英伟达为中国定制显卡满足美国出口管制。</li>    <li>主题：英伟达为应对美国限制调整其顶级显卡产品以适应中国市场。</li>    <li>观点：美国出口管制对英伟达业务和全球半导体行业的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国版和全球版 GTX 4090 D 之间的技术差异；英伟达与美国政府的沟通；中美紧张关系和出口限制的更广泛背景。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>engage (v.) - /ɪnˈgeɪdʒ/ 从事，卷入，交战。    <p>原文例句：The company said it “extensively engaged” with the US government while developing the graphics product, which will be available in January.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语engagier，由en-（使）和gage（誓约，质押）组成，表示“使卷入，使从事，使交战。”它可以用于正式和非正式的语境中。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>accelerate (v.) - /ækˈsɛlərˌeɪt/ 加快。    <p>原文例句：Compared with the 4090 sold elsewhere, the China model will also have fewer processing sub units that are useful for accelerating artificial intelligence workloads, Nvidia said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语accelerare，由ad-（向）和celer（快）组成，表示“向快的方向变化”。它可以用于正式和非正式的语境中。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>artificial intelligence capabilities - 人工智能能力    <p>原文例句：The US, seeking to slow down the advancement of China’s artificial intelligence capabilities, is limiting access to specialised chips in that market.</p>    <p>词组讲解：这个词组由artificial intelligence（人工智能）和capabilities（能力）组成，表示“人工智能的能力”。它可以用于正式和非正式的语境中。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>processing sub units - 处理子单元    <p>原文例句：Compared with the 4090 sold elsewhere, the China model will also have fewer processing sub units that are useful for accelerating artificial intelligence workloads, Nvidia said.</p>    <p>词组讲解：这个词组由processing（处理）和sub units（子单元）组成，表示“处理子单元”。它可以用于正式的语境中。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>US officials, who have cited national security concerns, are more interested in Nvidia’s AI accelerators, a range that is currently topped by the H100. - 美国官员出于国家安全考虑，对英伟达的人工智能加速器更感兴趣，目前该系列的顶级产品是 H100。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是US officials are more interested in Nvidia’s AI accelerators，其中主语是US officials，谓语是are more interested，宾语是Nvidia’s AI accelerators。who have cited national security concerns是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰US officials，表示这些官员出于国家安全考虑。a range that is currently topped by the H100是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰AI accelerators，表示这一系列的人工智能加速器目前由 H100 占据领先地位。这个句子的意思是说，美国官员出于国家安全考虑，对英伟达的人工智能加速器更感兴趣，目前该系列的顶级产品是 H100。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 被动语态用于强调动作的承受者，而主动语态则强调动作的执行者。    <p>原文例句：The version of the GTX 4090 D chip that is listed for sale on Nvidia’s China website has about 10 per cent fewer processing cores than the 4090 that is sold in other countries.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，强调动作的承受者。句子的结构是：The version of the GTX 4090 D chip is listed for sale，其中The version of the GTX 4090 D chip是主语，is listed for sale是谓语，than the 4090 that is sold in other countries是一个介词短语作状语，修饰is listed for sale，表示该版本的产品在中国网站上被列为待售，而其他国家销售的产品则不是。这个句子的意思是说，在中国网站上列为待售的 GTX 4090 D 芯片版本比其他国家销售的 4090 芯片版本少约 10% 的处理核心。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态一直延续到现在，或者对过去发生的动作或状态的结果或影响感兴趣。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia’s stock has more than tripled this year, making it by far the best performing semiconductor stock.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时的句子，表示过去发生的动作或状态一直延续到现在。句子的结构是：Nvidia’s stock has tripled，其中Nvidia’s stock是主语，has tripled是谓语，this year是一个时间状语，表示动作发生在今年。这个句子的意思是说，英伟达的股票今年上涨了三倍多，使其成为迄今为止表现最好的半导体股票。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The GTX 4090 D chip listed for sale on Nvidia’s China website has about 10 per cent fewer processing cores than the version sold in other countries</li>
<li>The company said it ‘extensively engaged’ with the US government while developing the graphics product, which will be available in January</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2023/12/29/6aeb4486-fe29-4117-8dfc-c6e2ca0846a1_86b52e64.jpg" /><figcaption>A view of Nvidia’s headquarters in Taipei, Taiwan May 31, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia, the world’s most valuable chip maker, is selling a less-capable version of its best graphics product for video gamers in China, after the US government tightened restrictions on what the company can market in that country.</p><p>The version of the GTX 4090 D chip that is listed for sale on Nvidia’s China website has about 10 per cent fewer processing cores than the 4090 that is sold in other countries.</p><p>“The GeForce RTX 4090 D has been designed to comply with US government export controls and will only be available at retail in China,” a Nvidia spokesperson said in an email.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246524/chinese-ai-champion-sensetime-introduces-go-playing-robot-japan-south-korea" title="">Chinese AI champion SenseTime introduces Go playing robot to Japan, South Korea</a></h3><p>Chief Executive Officer Jensen Huang has said he would produce versions of his market-leading products for China that comply with rules imposed by the Biden administration on exports to that country. The US, seeking to slow down the advancement of China’s artificial intelligence capabilities, is limiting access to specialised chips in that market.</p><p>The company said it “extensively engaged” with the US government while developing the graphics product, which will be available in January.</p><p>Compared with the 4090 sold elsewhere, the China model will also have fewer processing sub units that are useful for accelerating artificial intelligence workloads, Nvidia said.</p><p>US officials, who have cited national security concerns, are more interested in Nvidia’s AI accelerators, a range that is currently topped by the H100. That type of chip, which is based on technology used in graphics cards, has become the basis of an explosion in AI-capable hardware by owners of large data centres.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Nvidia’s CEO Jensen Huang attends a media roundtable meeting in Singapore December 6, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1415" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2023/12/29/b07f1415-9721-4c74-bbd2-58815bd15117_7dba929e.jpg" title="Nvidia’s CEO Jensen Huang attends a media roundtable meeting in Singapore December 6, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Nvidia’s CEO Jensen Huang attends a media roundtable meeting in Singapore December 6, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>When US export rules were tightened in 2022, Nvidia introduced less capable versions of its chips for China. The US clamped down again in October by further reducing performance thresholds. Nvidia’s leadership responded by saying the company would again redo its offerings for the Asian country, the largest market for chips, to make them compliant with the new rules.</p><p>Nvidia’s stock has more than tripled this year, making it by far the best performing semiconductor stock in 2023 and the industry’s first company with a market value of US$1 trillion.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei sees 9 per cent sales growth in 2023 as it bounces back from US sanctions, but cautions on ‘serious challenges’ ahead</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei saw a 9% year-on-year increase in sales in 2023, surpassing 700 billion yuan (US$99.1 billion).</li>    <li>Chairman of Huawei, Ken Hu, highlighted the company's improved performance but cautioned against complacency in the face of upcoming challenges.</li>    <li>Huawei has been forced to diversify its revenue sources by expanding into new areas such as smart car systems and software services.</li>    <li>The company's intelligent automotive solutions business witnessed growing competitiveness but requires further monetization.</li>    <li>Huawei's joint venture with Changan Automobile and plans to transfer its smart-car system business are part of its broader strategy to become a leading provider of software and hardware solutions.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>华为2023年销售额超过7000亿元人民币（991亿美元），同比增长9%。</li>    <li>华为轮值董事长胡厚崑指出公司业绩改善，但告诫员工不要自满，未来挑战依然严峻。</li>    <li>华为通过进军智能汽车系统和软件服务等新领域，被迫实现收入来源多样化。</li>    <li>华为智能汽车解决方案业务竞争力增强，但需要进一步实现盈利。</li>    <li>华为与长安汽车的合资企业和计划中的智能汽车系统业务转移，是其成为软件和硬件解决方案领先供应商的战略的一部分。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>diversify (v.) - /dɪˈvɜːsɪfaɪ/ 多样化，使多样化。    <p>原文例句：Huawei has been forced to diversify its revenue sources by venturing into new areas such as smart car systems.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由di-（分开）和versus（转向）组成，意为“使变化，使多样化”。在这个例句中，它描述了华为通过进军智能汽车系统等新领域，被迫对其收入来源进行多样化。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>monetization (n.) - /ˌmɑːnɪtʌɪˈzeɪʃən/ 货币化，变现。    <p>原文例句：However, the business needs to generate more money. “Our Intelligent Automotive Solution business needs to keep working closely with partners to translate its technological advantages into business success,” Hu urged. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由monetize（货币化，变现）构成的，表示“货币化，变现”。在这个例句中，它描述了华为智能汽车解决方案业务需要与合作伙伴紧密合作，将其技术优势转化为商业成功，即实现货币化。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take an equity stake - 持有股权，入股。    <P>原文例句：Huawei has been making a deeper push into the automotives sector and last month announced a new joint venture with Changan Automobile, a major state-owned carmaker, while also extending its invitation to other domestic carmakers to take an equity stake. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，取）和equity stake（股权）构成的，表示“拥有，持有股权”。在这个例句中，它描述了华为与长安汽车的合资企业，并邀请其他国内汽车制造商持股。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei’s intelligent automotive solutions business, in which the company works with carmakers and supplies its own components and software, became more competitive in the past year, said Hu. - 华为智能汽车解决方案业务，即华为与汽车制造商合作并提供其组件和软件的业务，胡说，在过去一年变得更具竞争力。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huawei’s intelligent automotive solutions business became more competitive in the past year，其中主语是Huawei’s intelligent automotive solutions business，谓语是became more competitive，宾语是in the past year。in which the company works with carmakers and supplies its own components and software是一个定语从句，修饰主句的主语，表示华为智能汽车解决方案业务是指华为与汽车制造商合作并提供其组件和软件的业务。said Hu是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示这句话的主体是胡说。这个句子的意思是说，华为智能汽车解决方案业务，即华为与汽车制造商合作并提供其组件和软件的业务，胡说，在过去一年变得更具竞争力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直延续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Huawei has been making a deeper push into the automotives sector and last month announced a new joint venture with Changan Automobile, a major state-owned carmaker, while also extending its invitation to other domestic carmakers to take an equity stake. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示华为一直致力于汽车行业，并在上个月宣布与长安汽车成立新合资企业，同时还邀请其他国内汽车制造商入股。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、愿望或可能性的语气。    <p>原文例句：Huawei’s intelligent automotive solutions business, in which the company works with carmakers and supplies its own components and software, became more competitive in the past year, said Hu.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语气，表示假设、愿望或可能性的语气。结构是：should + 动词原形。这种语气常用于建议、请求或命令。在这个例句中，它表示华为智能汽车解决方案业务，即华为与汽车制造商合作并提供其组件和软件的业务，胡说，在过去一年变得更具竞争力。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Huawei has been forced to diversify its revenue sources by venturing into new areas such as smart car systems</li>
<li>Rotating chairman says intelligent automotive solutions business became more competitive in the past year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2023/12/28/6687b12e-bbf0-4fe5-ae7a-114d18fa70be_1b010a4e.jpg" /><figcaption>Huawei’s Hu says intelligent automotive solutions business became more competitive in the past year. Photo: Handout </figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> expects its sales to surpass 700 billion yuan (US$99.1 billion) in 2023 after the US-sanctioned Chinese telecommunications giant launched a new 5G smartphone and amid multiple efforts to diversify its revenue streams.</p><p>This would mark a 9 per cent year-on-year increase in total sales for the full year from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3215553/huaweis-meng-wanzhou-faces-uphill-battle-reversing-flat-revenue-plummeting-profits" target="_self" title="">642.3 billion yuan in 2022</a>, better than the slim 0.9 per cent increase then and an improvement from 2021 when revenue plunged 28.6 per cent.</p><p>The achievement shows that the Shenzhen-based firm is “pretty much back on track”, according to a new year’s message from Huawei’s rotating chairman Ken Hu Houkun on Friday.</p><p>However, Hu also warned of “serious challenges” ahead in 2024 and urged employees to avoid “blind optimism”.</p><p>“Geopolitical and economic uncertainties abound, while technology restrictions and trade barriers continue to have an impact on the world. Together, these forces are reshaping business models and the global value chain,” Hu said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246414/huawei-and-xiaomi-launch-new-ev-models-china-reigniting-worries-about-price-wars-worlds-largest-ev" title="">New EVs from Huawei, Xiaomi could renew price wars in China’s car market</a></h3><p>Huawei, which briefly <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/3095328/huawei-wrests-crown-worlds-biggest-smartphone-vendor-samsung-strong-china?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">surpassed Samsung Electronics to lead global smartphone shipments</a> in early 2020, has been battling US sanctions that hit its smartphone business and overseas sales hard in the past few years. It has been forced to diversify its revenue sources by venturing into new areas such as smart car systems, while looking to revive its handset businesses.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Huawei EV Aito, M7, featuring cutting edge, autonomous driving technology, is displayed in a Huawei shop in Beijing, China, on Sep. 17, 2023. Photo: SCMP/Simon Song" class="image-inline caption" height="1492" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2023/12/28/94cbbb63-0c49-446d-9dea-b1afd7acec31_6b3e03da.jpg" title="Huawei EV Aito, M7, featuring cutting edge, autonomous driving technology, is displayed in a Huawei shop in Beijing, China, on Sep. 17, 2023. Photo: SCMP/Simon Song" width="2000" /><figcaption>Huawei EV Aito, M7, featuring cutting edge, autonomous driving technology, is displayed in a Huawei shop in Beijing, China, on Sep. 17, 2023. Photo: SCMP/Simon Song</figcaption></figure></div><p>In late August, the company surprised the industry with the launch of the Mate 60 Pro smartphone, which is powered by a home-grown advanced processor, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233520/tech-war-top-chinese-chip-maker-smic-under-spotlight-breakthrough-5g-processor-used-huaweis-latest?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Kirin 9000s</a>. This was Huawei’s first 5G smartphone since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">US trade sanctions</a> barred the firm from accessing advanced American technology.</p><p>Its devices unit, which includes the smartphone business, “surpassed expectations” in 2023, Hu said in the new year message, without elaborating on specific figures.</p><p>Huawei’s intelligent automotive solutions business, in which the company works with carmakers and supplies its own components and software, became more competitive in the past year, said Hu.</p><p>However, the business needs to generate more money. “Our Intelligent Automotive Solution business needs to keep working closely with partners to translate its technological advantages into business success,” Hu urged.</p><p>Huawei has been making a deeper push into the automotives sector and last month announced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242954/us-sanctioned-huawei-forms-smart-vehicle-joint-venture-state-owned-changan-automobile-amid-effort" target="_self" title="">a new joint venture with Changan Automobile</a>, a major state-owned carmaker, while also <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243139/huawei-accelerates-smart-car-ambitions-invitation-four-carmakers-invest-changan-joint-venture" target="_self" title="">extending its invitation to other domestic carmakers</a> to take an equity stake.</p><p>Huawei said it plans to transfer its smart-car system business to the new unit with investments from Changan. The firm’s car unit achieved <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3215866/huaweis-carmaking-ambitions-face-challenges-under-us-sanctions-and-concerns-over-brand-identity?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">2.1 billion yuan in sales in 2022</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230769/growth-returns-huaweis-consumer-business-smartphone-sales-rise-again-despite-us-sanctions?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">1 billion yuan in revenue in the first half of this year</a>.</p><p>Huawei’s nascent car business forms part of its efforts to reposition itself as a software and hardware provider to industrial and government clients.</p><p>Joining the artificial intelligence (AI) craze in China, Huawei <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226981/huawei-taps-computing-power-shortage-china-touts-self-developed-ai-tech-amid-chatgpt-craze" target="_self" title="">unveiled the 3.0 version of its Pangu AI model in July</a>, with a sharpened focus on industrial uses in various sectors including coal mines, finance and government. It has also touted in-house processors as alternatives to advanced American AI chips to satisfy the hunger for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a>-style services in the country.</p><p>Huawei’s information and communications technology business, in which it supplies data centre servers and other tech infrastructure to clients, has remained solid, while its digital power and cloud businesses reported steady growth, according to Hu.</p><p>In the coming year, Hu said the company should sharpen its focus on the trend of digital, intelligent, and low-carbon transformation as its strategic direction. “In 2024, all business units should focus on creating value and growing the harvest,” Hu said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China, Myanmar revive hopes for Bay of Bengal deep water port in Kyaukphyu under Belt and Road Initiative</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3246551/china-myanmar-revive-hopes-bay-bengal-deep-water-port-kyaukphyu-under-belt-and-road-initiative</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  China and the Myanmar military government signed a supplementary agreement for the Kyaukphyu deep water port, part of the Belt and Road Initiative, aiming to boost cooperation and economic development. However, progress is hampered by ongoing clashes between ethnic rebel groups and the junta.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Renewed push for China-backed Kyaukphyu port project amid ethnic conflicts in Myanmar.</li>    <li>Theme: The signing of a supplementary agreement between China and Myanmar for the Kyaukphyu deep water port, highlighting the significance of the project for economic cooperation despite ongoing security challenges.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Importance of the Kyaukphyu port for China's Belt and Road Initiative and energy security, concerns about project delays due to ethnic conflicts, and China's efforts to promote stability and cooperation in Myanmar.</li>    <li>Main information: Signing of the addendum to the project concession agreement, Citic Group's commitment to promote project implementation, ongoing ethnic violence hampering progress, China's security warnings, and the strategic importance of the port for China's energy imports.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国与缅甸军政府签署了若开邦皎漂深水港的补充协议，该港口是“一带一路”倡议的一部分，旨在促进合作和经济发展。然而，进展受到民族叛乱组织与军政府之间持续冲突的阻碍。  <ul>    <li>摘要：在缅甸民族冲突中，中国支持的皎漂港项目重新启动。</li>    <li>主题：中国与缅甸签署皎漂深水港项目补充协议，强调该项目对经济合作的重要性，尽管存在持续的安全挑战。</li>    <li>观点：皎漂港对中国“一带一路”倡议和能源安全的意义，由于民族冲突导致项目延误的担忧，以及中国在缅甸促进稳定与合作的努力。</li>    <li>主要信息：项目特许经营协议附件的签署，中信集团致力于促进项目的实施，持续的民族暴力阻碍了项目的进展，中国发出的安全警告，以及该港口对中国能源进口的战略重要性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>initiative (n.) - /ɪˈnɪʃətɪv/ 主动权，倡议。    <p>原文例句：China sees Myanmar as stepping stone to Indian Ocean, energy security</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由in-（进入）和itio（去，运动）构成的，表示“进入行动，主动权，倡议”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国的“一带一路”倡议，该倡议旨在加强中国与其他国家的经济联系和合作。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>stake (n.) - /steɪk/ 股份，利害关系。    <p>原文例句：Chinese state-owned Citic Group will, as agreed in 2018, maintain a 70 per cent stake in the port, which is expected to give China access to the Bay of Bengal as an alternative route for oil imports.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由古英语staca（木桩）演变而来，表示“木桩，柱子，股份，利害关系”。在这个例句中，它指的是中信集团在皎漂港的股份，该股份预计将使中国获得孟加拉湾作为石油进口的替代路线。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>agreement for - 关于……的协议。    <p>原文例句：China and the Myanmese military government have signed a supplementary agreement for the Kyaukphyu deep water port, as both sides seek to get the stalled Belt and Road Initiative project off the ground.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由agreement（协议）和for（关于）构成的，表示“关于……的协议”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国和缅甸军政府签署的皎漂深水港补充协议，该协议旨在推进陷入停滞的“一带一路”倡议项目。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>It is also a key section of the 1,700km China-Myanmar Economic Corridor, a planned network of railway, roads and oil and natural gas pipelines running from Kunming in China’s Yunnan province to the Indian Ocean. - 它也是连接中国云南省昆明至印度洋，长达1700公里的中缅经济走廊的主要部分，该走廊规划建设铁路、公路和石油天然气管道网络。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是It is also a key section，其中主语是It，谓语是is，宾语是a key section。of the 1,700km China-Myanmar Economic Corridor是一个介词短语作定语，修饰a key section，表示该路段属于1700公里长的中缅经济走廊。a planned network of railway, roads and oil and natural gas pipelines running from Kunming in China’s Yunnan province to the Indian Ocean是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰network，表示该网络由铁路、公路和石油天然气管道组成，从中国云南省昆明一直延伸到印度洋。这个句子的意思是说，该路段也是连接中国云南省昆明至印度洋，长达1700公里的中缅经济走廊的主要部分，该走廊规划建设铁路、公路和石油天然气管道网络。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>插入句 - 插入一个解释性或描述性句子。    <p>原文例句：Chinese President Xi Jinping with then Myanmar state counsellor Aung San Suu Kyi in Naypyidaw in January 2020. Photo: EPA-EFE</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句子结构，用于在句子中间插入一个解释性或描述性句子。插入句通常用括号、破折号或逗号分隔。在这个例句中，插入句是Chinese President Xi Jinping with then Myanmar state counsellor Aung San Suu Kyi in Naypyidaw in January 2020，它提供了有关习近平主席与缅甸国务资政昂山素季在2020年1月在内比都会面的信息。这个句子可以省略，但它的存在可以为读者提供更多信息，使句子更具可读性。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Renewed push for Citic-led project in Rakhine state comes amid continued clashes between ethnic rebel groups and the ruling Myanmar junta</li>
<li>Port expected to allow Beijing to bypass South China Sea for oil imports is cited as ‘major part’ of 1,700km China-Myanmar Economic Corridor</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2023/12/28/dabccf5b-9b0f-45ff-95a3-13c0caf4165f_67383b8a.jpg" /><figcaption>Kyaukphyu port will offer China an alternative route for energy imports from the Middle East, avoiding the Strait of Malacca. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China and the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/myanmars-changing-ties-china" target="_self" title="">Myanmese military government</a> have signed a supplementary agreement for the Kyaukphyu deep water port, as both sides seek to get the stalled <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/belt-and-road-initiative?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Belt and Road Initiative</a> project off the ground.</p><p>The renewed push for the project in Myanmar’s restive western Rakhine state comes amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3239976/risks-ahead-china-northern-myanmar-clashes-near-border-analyst-says" target="_self" title="">escalating violence</a> between ethnic rebel groups and the ruling junta, which has prompted repeated security warnings from the Chinese mission.</p><p>Chinese state-owned Citic Group will, as agreed in 2018, maintain a 70 per cent stake in the port, which is expected to give China access to the Bay of Bengal as an alternative route for oil imports.</p><p>Top Citic executives, Chinese diplomats and junta officials attended the signing of an addendum to the project concession agreement, in Myanmar’s capital Naypyidaw on Tuesday.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3046218/china-sees-myanmar-stepping-stone-indian-ocean-energy-security" title="">China sees Myanmar as stepping stone to Indian Ocean, energy security</a></h3><p>The Kyaukphyu deep-sea port is a “major part” of Beijing’s belt and road strategy as well as the China-Myanmar Economic Corridor, and of “great significance to practical cooperation” between the two countries, Citic Group president Xi Guohua said during the ceremony.</p><p>“Citic Group will make every effort to promote the implementation of the Kyaukphyu project,” Xi pledged, according to a readout from the Chinese embassy in Myanmar.</p><p>Details of the addendum were not made public, but it is viewed as the latest sign that the key China-backed infrastructure project, which had made little progress since the military seized power in a coup in early 2021, is now back on track.</p><p>However, it comes as resource-rich Myanmar is in the throes of some of the worst ethnic violence since the coup, with intense clashes between military and an alliance of powerful ethnic armed groups, sometimes in coordination with anti-junta groups, erupting across the country.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Citing sources close to the ethnic rebel groups, Myanmese news portal The Irrawaddy reported on Wednesday that the junta and an alliance of three ethnic armies had failed to reach a peace deal at a second round of China-brokered peace talks last week in Kunming, capital of China’s southwestern Yunnan province bordering Myanmar.</p><p>The continued clashes prompted a fresh security warning on Thursday from the Chinese embassy, urging citizens to “evacuate as soon as possible” from Laukkai, a major town in the Kokang Self-Administered Zone near Myanmar’s northern border with China.</p><p>The fighting has also raised fears about the future of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3047557/chinese-companies-investing-myanmar-have-lot-work-do-convince" target="_self" title="">Chinese-backed</a> infrastructure projects in Myanmar.</p><p>The US$1.3 billion port project, sitting on Maday Island off the fishing village of Kyaukphyu on the Bay of Bengal, is part of the Kyaukphyu Special Economic Zone, a scheme aiming to draw textile and oil refining industries that is at the heart of China’s relationship with Myanmar.</p><p>It is also a key section of the 1,700km China-Myanmar Economic Corridor, a planned network of railway, roads and oil and natural gas pipelines running from Kunming in China’s Yunnan province to the Indian Ocean.</p><p>During a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3046694/chinese-president-xi-jinping-wraps-myanmar-visit-string" target="_self" title="">state visit to Myanmar</a> in early 2020, Chinese President Xi Jinping hailed the economic corridor as “priority among priorities” for the belt and road, a global infrastructure drive that has become a cornerstone of Beijing’s foreign policy.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Chinese President Xi Jinping with then Myanmar state counsellor Aung San Suu Kyi in Naypyidaw in January 2020. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1495" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2023/12/28/3129a716-4290-44c8-8402-c02d472564fa_6f2fa68f.jpg" title="Chinese President Xi Jinping with then Myanmar state counsellor Aung San Suu Kyi in Naypyidaw in January 2020. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping with then Myanmar state counsellor Aung San Suu Kyi in Naypyidaw in January 2020. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>Kyaukphyu port is expected to give Beijing strategic access to the Indian Ocean while offering China an alternative energy route to the Strait of Malacca, a narrow waterway between the Indian Ocean and the South China Sea that now transports some 80 per cent of China’s oil imports from the Middle East.</p><p>Beijing-based Citic, one of China’s biggest and the oldest financial conglomerates, was chosen to take the lead in the Kyaukphyu Special Economic Zone and deep seaport projects in 2015.</p><p>However, little progress was made until Citic and the then Myanmese government, led by Aung San Suu Kyi’s National League for Democracy, reached a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3047557/chinese-companies-investing-myanmar-have-lot-work-do-convince" target="_self" title="">framework agreement</a> in 2018 to scale back the port investment from US$7.3 billion to US$1.3 billion.</p><p>A joint management committee was also set up between Citic and the Myanmar government on a 70:30 holding basis, with a 50-year lease for the Chinese company.</p><p>But regulatory issues have stalled progress on the project. This has frustrated Beijing, with Chinese officials publicly urging the Myanmar government to push forward infrastructure plans under the China-Myanmar Economic Corridor.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3245278/myanmar-grapples-chinas-ire-amid-rising-anti-junta-offensive" title="">Rebel fire and China’s ire: inside Myanmar’s anti-junta offensive</a></h3><p>As the domestic conflict in Myanmar continues, there are growing signs that the military government – increasingly isolated by international sanctions since its 2021 coup – is looking to bring China-backed projects back on track.</p><p>In February, Citic said it had completed a 10-month field survey for the port project. A report was released in September, paving the way for construction, with the SEZ committee starting to invite bids last month.</p><p>Earlier this month, Aung Naing Oo, the Myanmese commerce minister, announced the conclusion of negotiations with Citic Group over the deep seaport business licence agreement signed by the previous government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mexico targets Chinese steel imports with increased tariff of nearly 80 per cent</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3246576/mexico-targets-chinese-steel-imports-increased-tariff-nearly-80-cent</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In response to criticism from local producers who believe that Chinese steelmakers are stifling their production, Mexico has imposed a significant tariff of nearly 80% on certain steel imports, specifically cold-rolled steel sheets from Vietnam.</li>    <li>The Mexican government has exempted companies that can prove that the steel they export originates from a country other than China, illustrating the complex global trade landscape in the steel industry.</li>    <li>Currently, Mexico, the United States, Brazil, and other nations have voiced concerns about the impact of Chinese steel imports on their industries, accusing China of engaging in dumping practices and circumventing anti-dumping measures.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>墨西哥政府针对本地生产商关于中国钢厂扼杀他们生产的批评，宣布对中国的钢铁进口征收约80%的关税，特别是来自越南的冷轧钢板。</li>    <li>墨西哥政府豁免了那些能够证明他们出口的钢材来自中国以外的公司的关税，这反映了钢铁行业内复杂的全球贸易格局。</li>    <li>目前，墨西哥、美国、巴西等国均对中国钢铁进口对本国产业的影响表示担忧，指责中国从事倾销行为并规避反倾销措施。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>threshold (n.) - /ˈθrɛʃhoʊld/ 门槛，界限。    <p>原文例句：Accelerating vaccination rates would undoubtedly be a huge step in crossing the threshold of herd immunity, but it’s not the only factor under consideration.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，由thresh（打谷）和hold（握住）构成，意为“打谷场的门槛”。在这个例句中，它指的是群体免疫的门槛，即达到群体免疫所需的人口疫苗接种率。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>imposition (n.) - /ɪm.pəˈzɪʃən/  征收，强加。    <p>原文例句：Mexico imposed a nearly 80 per cent tariff on some steel imports on Thursday, following criticism from local producers that Chinese steelmakers have strangled their production.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由im-（向内）、ponere（放置）和-tion（结果）构成，意为“加在上面的东西”。在这个例句中，它指的是墨西哥政府对某些钢材进口征收的关税。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>circumvent (v.) - /ˌsɜːrkəmˈvɛnt/ 规避，绕过。    <p>原文例句：A number of nations have in recent years raised alarm at Chinese steel producers selling their surplus abroad at below-market rates, a practice known as dumping, with some attempting to circumvent “anti-dumping” measures by first shipping the steel to other countries.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由circum-（周围）和venire（来）构成，意为“从周围走来”。在这个例句中，它指的是一些国家试图通过先将钢材运往其他国家来规避“反倾销”措施的行为。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>behemoth (n.) - /bɪˈhɛməθ/ 巨兽，庞然大物。    <p>原文例句：The country has been a steel behemoth for decades.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于希伯来语，意为“巨大的野兽”。在这个例句中，它指的是一个钢铁巨头，即一个非常大的钢铁生产国或公司。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in accordance with - 根据，按照。    <p>原文例句：The court ruled in accordance with the law.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），accordance（一致，符合）和with（与……一起）构成的，表示“按照某种规则或标准”。在这个例句中，它表示法院根据法律作出了判决。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In August, Mexico hiked a tariff to 25 per cent on some steel imports from countries with which it does not have a free-trade agreement, including China. - 8月份，墨西哥对没有自由贸易协定的国家的钢铁进口征收25%的关税，包括中国。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是Mexico hiked a tariff to 25 per cent on some steel imports from countries with which it does not have a free-trade agreement, 其中主语是Mexico，谓语是hiked，宾语是a tariff，介词短语on some steel imports from countries with which it does not have a free-trade agreement作状语，表示墨西哥对没有自由贸易协定的国家的钢铁进口征收25%的关税。including China是一个并列连词，表示包括中国。这个句子的意思是说，8月份，墨西哥对没有自由贸易协定的国家的钢铁进口征收25%的关税，包括中国。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The Mexican government has exempted companies that can prove that the steel they export originates from a country other than China, illustrating the complex global trade landscape in the steel industry. - 墨西哥政府豁免了那些能够证明他们出口的钢材来自中国以外的公司的关税，这反映了钢铁行业内复杂的全球贸易格局。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The Mexican government has exempted companies that can prove that the steel they export originates from a country other than China, 其中主语是The Mexican government，谓语是has exempted，宾语是companies，定语从句that can prove that the steel they export originates from a country other than China作定语，表示墨西哥政府豁免了那些能够证明他们出口的钢材来自中国以外的公司的关税。illustrating the complex global trade landscape in the steel industry是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示墨西哥政府豁免这些公司的关税的原因或目的，即反映了钢铁行业内复杂的全球贸易格局。这个句子的意思是说，墨西哥政府豁免了那些能够证明他们出口的钢材来自中国以外的公司的关税，这反映了钢铁行业内复杂的全球贸易格局。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式 - 表示动词的名称或动作。    <p>原文例句：The government is not in the mood to create friction with the Chinese.</p>    <p>语法讲解：动词不定式是由to和动词原形构成的，表示动词的名称或动作。在这个例句中，动词不定式是to create friction，表示制造摩擦或矛盾的动作。动词不定式可以作主语、宾语、补语或状语。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>动词-ing形式 - 表示正在进行或将要进行的动作。    <p>原文例句：China is the region’s number one steel supplier, accounting for nearly a third of what is brought into Latin America, according to Alacero. </p>    <p>语法讲解：动词-ing形式是由动词原形加上-ing构成的，表示正在进行或将要进行的动作。在这个例句中，动词-ing形式是accounting，表示占……比例的动作。动词-ing形式可以作主语、宾语、补语或状语。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The declaration from Mexico’s economy ministry follows criticism from local producers that Chinese steelmakers have strangled their production</li>
<li>Brazilian steelmakers have also requested their government impose a 25 per cent tariff on Chinese steel imports, though little action has been taken</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2023/12/29/327b7908-8be2-4c66-bb78-e42783cd487f_c72fd6f5.jpg" /><figcaption>Piles of steel pipes to be exported at a port in Lianyungang in China’s Jiangsu province. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Mexico announced a nearly 80 per cent tariff on some steel imports on Thursday, following criticism from local producers that Chinese steelmakers have strangled their production.</p><p>The tariff applies to some Vietnamese exports of cold-rolled steel sheets, although if the groups can prove the steel comes from a country other than China, they are exempt from the tariff, according to a declaration from the economy ministry published in Mexico’s official gazette.</p><p>Vietnam’s largest steelmaker, Hoa Phat, is subject to a nearly 12 per cent tariff while Posco Vietnam will face a 26 per cent tariff, though the country of origin exemption also applies to them.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3246573/joe-biden-extends-eu-steel-aluminium-tariff-exemption-2-years" title="">Joe Biden extends EU steel, aluminium tariff exemption for 2 years</a></h3><p>A number of nations have in recent years raised alarm at Chinese steel producers selling their surplus abroad at below-market rates, a practice known as dumping, with some attempting to circumvent “anti-dumping” measures by first shipping the steel to other countries.</p><p>In August, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mexico" target="_self" title="">Mexico</a> hiked a tariff to 25 per cent on some steel imports from countries with which it does not have a free-trade agreement, including China.</p><p>The tariff published on Thursday brings a government anti-dumping investigation opened at the behest of steelmaker Ternium’s local unit nearly two years ago to a close. Ternium declined a request for comment.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> has also expressed concern about its own imports of steel and aluminium products from Mexico, where the US alleges a “lack of transparency” regarding their country of origin.</p><p>Steel production in Latin America has dropped in recent years as imports have grown. The region is expected to produce 83 per cent of the steel it consumes this year, according to November data by regional association Alacero.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3244421/china-bans-new-steel-plants-drive-defend-blue-sky-and-cut-atmospheric-pollution" title="">China bans new steel plants in ‘blue skies’ plan to cut pollution</a></h3><p>China is the region’s number one steel supplier, accounting for nearly a third of what is brought into Latin America, according to Alacero.</p><p>Brazilian steelmakers also have requested their country’s government impose a 25 per cent tariff on Chinese steel imports, though little action has been taken.</p><p>“The government is not in the mood to create friction with the Chinese,” industry group head Carlos Loureiro said earlier this month, as China is one of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/brazil" target="_self" title="">Brazil’s</a> largest trading partners.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China urges ‘prudent’ yuan internationalisation as pace of adoption remains slow</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3246528/china-urges-prudent-yuan-internationalisation-pace-adoption-remains-slow</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China is taking a cautious and incremental approach to promoting the international use of the yuan.</li>    <li>The focus is now on risk management and ensuring that the yuan's broader use serves the real economy.</li>    <li>China is leveraging its trade relationships and exploring tools such as yuan swap mechanisms and currency swap deals to encourage wider use of the yuan.</li>    <li>The yuan's overseas use has increased but still lags behind the US dollar and the Euro in terms of global payments, foreign exchange markets, and reserves.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国正在谨慎而渐进地推进人民币的国际化进程。</li>    <li>目前的重点是风险管理，确保人民币的广泛使用服务于实体经济。</li>    <li>中国正在利用其贸易关系，并探索人民币掉期机制和货币互换交易等工具，以鼓励人民币的更广泛使用。</li>    <li>人民币的海外使用有所增加，但仍落后于美元和欧元，无论是从全球支付、外汇市场还是外汇储备来看。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>prudent (adj.) - /ˈprudnt/ 谨慎的，审慎的。      <p>Original sentence: Beijing should promote the yuan’s use abroad next year by tapping deeper into emerging markets with loans and swap deals, but must also remain prudent and prepared to head off risks, former officials and analysts have urged.</p>      <p>Example explanation: This word is often used to describe someone who is careful and makes wise decisions, especially in financial matters. In this sentence, it means that China should be careful and take a cautious approach in promoting the yuan's use abroad.</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>incremental (adj.) - /ɪŋˈkrɛmənt(ə)l/ 渐进的，逐渐增加的。      <p>Original sentence: Beijing now appears to favour an incremental approach, tapping direct yuan financing tools to encourage wider use in all manner of transactions, from trade settlements to loans.</p>      <p>Example explanation: This word is used to describe a process or change that happens in small, gradual steps. In this sentence, it means that China is taking a step-by-step approach to promoting the use of the yuan, rather than trying to do it all at once.</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>leverage (v.) - /ˈlɛv(ə)rɪdʒ/ 利用（优势、资源等）      <p>Original sentence: China is either the largest trading partner or among the major economic partners for 140 countries, so we should leverage this for the yuan.</p>      <p>Example explanation: This word means to use something to your advantage. In this sentence, it means that China should use its strong trading relationships with other countries to promote the use of the yuan.</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>denominated (adj.) - /dɪˈnɑːmɪneɪtɪd/ 以……计价的。      <p>Original sentence: Most of China’s emergency loans to developing countries are denominated in the yuan, like the Export-Import Bank of China’s deal with debt-ridden Sri Lanka.</p>      <p>Example explanation: This word describes something that is expressed in a particular currency or unit of measure. In this sentence, it means that China's loans to developing countries are expressed in yuan, which is the Chinese currency.</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>for internationalisation’s sake - 为了国际化而进行。</li>    <p>Original sentence: “It’s nonsensical to push it merely for internationalisation’s sake, or for the frivolity of pursuing high rankings or bigger scale,” said Guan Tao, chief economist at BOC International, a Bank of China investment arm.</p>    <p>Example explanation: This phrase is used to criticize actions or policies that are motivated solely by the desire to achieve international recognition or status, without considering the actual benefits or consequences.</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China, ‘pummelled’ yuan could feel ripple effects as Fed signals 2024 rate cuts - 中国，“备受打击”的人民币可能会感受到涟漪效应，因为美联储暗示2024年降息。</li>    <p>Sentence analysis: This is a complex sentence with a main clause and a subordinate clause. The main clause is "China, 'pummelled' yuan could feel ripple effects". The subordinate clause is "as Fed signals 2024 rate cuts". The main clause states that China and the yuan could be affected by the Fed's decision to cut interest rates in 2024. The subordinate clause provides more information about the Fed's decision and its potential impact on China and the yuan.</p>    </li>    <li>It received broader attention as de-dollarisation – reduction of dependency on the US dollar – has become an area of interest, with Brazilian President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva calling for an alternative currency to be used by emerging economies. - 当去美元化——减少对美元的依赖——成为一个受关注的领域时，它受到了更广泛的关注，巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦呼吁新兴经济体使用替代货币。</li>    <p>Sentence analysis: This is a complex sentence with a main clause and a subordinate clause. The main clause is "It received broader attention". The subordinate clause is "as de-dollarisation – reduction of dependency on the US dollar – has become an area of interest". The main clause states that the yuan received broader attention. The subordinate clause provides more information about the reason for the increased attention, which is the growing interest in de-dollarization.</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Parallel Structure - 并列结构，指的是在一个句子中，使用相同或类似的句法结构来连接两个或多个元素。</li>    <p>Original sentence: With risk prevention the overall economic watchword, rash moves ‘for internationalisation’s sake’ discouraged by ex-officials, analysts.</p>    <p>Grammar analysis: This sentence uses parallel structure to connect the two phrases "risk prevention" and "rash moves 'for internationalisation's sake'". The two phrases are both in the gerund form, which is a verbal noun ending in "-ing". This parallelism creates a sense of balance and symmetry in the sentence.</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Conditional Sentences (Type 2) - 第二类条件句，用于表示与某一假设相反的事实。</li>    <p>Original sentence: If risk prevention wasn’t the overall economic watchword, rash moves ‘for internationalisation’s sake’ would not be discouraged by ex-officials, analysts.</p>    <p>Grammar analysis: This sentence is an example of a Type 2 conditional sentence. The if-clause "If risk prevention wasn't the overall economic watchword" expresses a hypothetical situation that is contrary to the actual situation. The main clause "rash moves 'for internationalisation's sake' would not be discouraged by ex-officials, analysts" expresses the result of the hypothetical situation. Type 2 conditional sentences are often used to express hypothetical situations or to make predictions about what would happen if a certain condition were different.</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China’s efforts to boost international use of the yuan are still in progress, but prudence and caution have been advised</li>
<li>With risk prevention the overall economic watchword, rash moves ‘for internationalisation’s sake’ discouraged by ex-officials, analysts</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2023/12/28/6c63954f-c4fe-4042-a22d-c7fe331acd94_9c68c34b.jpg" /><figcaption>Beijing appears to favour an incremental approach, tapping direct yuan financing tools to encourage wider use in all manner of transactions, from trade settlements to loans. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Beijing should promote the yuan’s use abroad next year by tapping deeper into emerging markets with loans and swap deals, but must also remain prudent and prepared to head off risks, former officials and analysts have urged.</p><p>The assessment came as financial regulators look to implement Beijing’s risk-prevention mandate and take a more pragmatic approach to expand the overseas influence of the Chinese currency.</p><p>“It’s nonsensical to push it merely for internationalisation’s sake, or for the frivolity of pursuing high rankings or bigger scale,” said Guan Tao, chief economist at BOC International, a Bank of China investment arm.</p><p>At a forum last month, he said the emphasis going forward had shifted to risk management and Beijing would not rush the process.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3245073/fed-interest-rate-stance-could-help-pummelled-yuan-china-could-feel-ripple-effects-2024-cuts" title="">China, ‘pummelled’ yuan could feel ripple effects as Fed signals 2024 rate cuts</a></h3><p>Guan, a former official with the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, added China’s financial opening must go hand in hand with the yuan’s broader use overseas and serve the real economy – those sectors that produce or trade in goods and services.</p><p>These remarks echoed statements made by the country’s leadership at <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3239873/xi-jinping-says-preventing-resolving-chinas-financial-risks-are-eternal-theme-beijing" target="_self" title="">October’s central financial work conference,</a> which designated risk prevention and mitigation as an “eternal, overarching theme” for the entire financial sector.</p><p>This rhetoric marks a shift on how the pace of the yuan’s internationalisation has been addressed, from an “orderly process” laid out in the political report from the Communist Party’s 20th national congress in October 2022 to a “steady, prudent and solid” one in the readout from the financial conference.</p><p>Beijing now appears to favour an incremental approach, tapping direct yuan financing tools to encourage wider use in all manner of transactions, from trade settlements to loans.</p><blockquote>China is either the largest trading partner or among the major economic partners for 140 countries, so we should leverage this for the yuanHu Xiaolian</blockquote><p>Hu Xiaolian, former deputy governor of the People’s Bank of China (PBOC), the country’s central bank, suggested last month that Beijing could explore a yuan swap mechanism to convert loans and debt denominated in US dollars.</p><p>“China is either the largest trading partner or among the major economic partners for 140 countries, so we should leverage this for the yuan,” she said.</p><p>At October’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3238398/china-russia-pledge-belt-and-road-infrastructure-integration-xi-jinping-vladimir-putin-lay-out" target="_self" title="">Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation,</a> 700 billion yuan (US$98.6 billion) in loans were slated for distribution from two policy banks to countries taking part in the broad-based infrastructure initiative.</p><p>Most of China’s emergency loans to developing countries are denominated in the yuan, like the Export-Import Bank of China’s deal with debt-ridden Sri Lanka.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>The PBOC has also accelerated currency swap deals and designation of clearing banks overseas.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3244387/china-singapore-let-each-others-tourists-pay-digital-yuan-beijing-seeks-globalise-its-e-cny-currency" target="_self" title="">This month, China and Singapore</a> agreed on a pilot plan to enable visitors from either side to use the digital yuan, another step forward as Project mBridge, the multinational trial system for the use of digital currencies to make cross-border payments, moves closer to commercialisation.</p><p>The yuan’s overseas use has increased rapidly after its initial internationalisation in trade settlements began in 2009.</p><p>It received broader attention as de-dollarisation – reduction of dependency on the US dollar – has become an area of interest, with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3216961/china-cosies-brazils-lula-state-visit-full-deals-diplomacy-and-south-american-inroads" target="_self" title="">Brazilian President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva</a> calling for an alternative currency to be used by emerging economies.</p><p>Brazil and the others in the Brics trading bloc – Russia, India, China and South Africa- have been using the yuan more frequently to conduct trade and investment.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>This has been of particular benefit to Russia, as sanctions levied against it in the wake of the invasion of Ukraine make use of the US dollar or Euro all but impossible.</p><p>However, the yuan was still far behind the two currencies in all dimensions – proportional representation in payment, foreign exchange markets, commodity pricing and foreign exchange reserves.</p><p>Data from global interbank messaging service Swift showed that in November, the yuan edged past the Japanese yen to the fourth-most active currency for global payments by value, with a share of 4.61 per cent. But this was a mere fraction of the US dollar’s 47.08 per cent and the Euro’s 22.95 per cent.</p><p>In terms of reserve holdings by foreign central banks, yuan-denominated reserves accounted for 2.45 per cent of the global total by the end of June, according to the International Monetary Fund, lower than 58.9 per cent for the US dollar and 20 per cent for the Euro.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Taiwan elections: mainland China accuses Democratic Progressive Party of ‘hyping’ up military threat to win votes</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246564/taiwan-elections-mainland-china-accuses-democratic-progressive-party-hyping-military-threat-win</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Taiwan will hold presidential and legislative elections in January, with independence-leaning candidate William Lai currently leading in the polls.</li>    <li>Beijing has accused Taiwan's ruling party of hyping up military threats from the mainland to gain votes.</li>    <li>Taiwan has accused Beijing of interfering in the elections through various actions, including flying spy balloons and sending warplanes into its air defense zone.</li>    <li>Beijing denies the accusations and views Taiwan as a breakaway province that should be reunited with the mainland.</li>    <li>Most countries do not officially recognize Taiwan as independent, but many oppose a forcible change in the status quo.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>台湾将于1月举行总统和立法机关选举，目前支持独立的候选人赖清德在民意调查中领先。</li>    <li>北京指责台湾执政党在选举前夕夸大渲染大陆的军事威胁以赢得选票。</li>    <li>台湾指责北京通过各种行动干预选举，包括飞越台湾海峡中线并向其防空识别区派遣军机。</li>    <li>北京否认这些指责，并视台湾为一个应该与大陆统一的分裂省份，必要时可以武力统一。</li>    <li>大多数国家不正式承认台湾为独立国家，但许多国家，包括美国，反对强行改变现状。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>independence-leaning（adj.） - 支持独立的，倾向于独立的。    <p>原文例句：Taiwan is set to hold presidential and legislative elections in less than three weeks. Vice-President William Lai Ching-te, the independence-leaning DPP’s presidential candidate, is currently leading in the polls.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“independence-leaning”由“independence”（独立）和“leaning”（倾向）两个词组成，意为“支持独立的，倾向于独立的”。在这个例句中，它用来形容台湾执政党民进党，表示民进党是一个支持台湾独立的政党。</p></li>    <li>interference（n.） - 干预，干涉。    <p>原文例句：Beijing has accused Taiwan’s ruling Democratic Progressive Party of “hyping up” the People’s Liberation Army’s activities ahead of next month’s elections to win votes.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“interference”由“inter”（互相）和“ference”（携带）两个词组成，意为“干预，干涉”。在这个例句中，它用来形容北京指责台湾执政党民进党在选举前夕夸大渲染大陆的军事威胁以赢得选票。</p></li>    <li>sovereignty（n.） - 主权，独立。    <p>原文例句：“As for the Taiwan military’s capabilities, the PLA is in absolute full control. As always, we will adopt all necessary measures to resolutely defend national sovereignty and territorial integrity.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：“sovereignty”由“sov”（统治）和“reign”（统治）两个词组成，意为“主权，独立”。在这个例句中，它用来形容大陆解放军对台湾军事力量的绝对控制和捍卫国家主权和领土完整的决心。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>provocate confrontation - 挑起对抗。    <p>原文例句：“The DPP authorities’ hyping up the so-called ‘mainland interference in the election’ is nothing more than their usual election tactics, which are aimed at provoking confrontation and gaining votes with lies. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“provocate confrontation”由“provocate”（挑起）和“confrontation”（对抗）两个词组成，意为“挑起对抗”。在这个例句中，它用来形容民进党夸大渲染大陆干预选举是其惯用选举伎俩，目的是挑起对抗并通过谎言赢得选票。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Senior Colonel Wu Qian, a PLA spokesman, told a press briefing in Beijing: “The Democratic Progressive Party has purposely hyped up the so-called ‘military threats by the mainland military’ to exaggerate tensions.” - 解放军发言人吴谦上校在北京的一次新闻发布会上表示：“民进党当局蓄意夸大所谓‘大陆军机威胁’，渲染两岸紧张气氛。”    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是“The Democratic Progressive Party has purposely hyped up the so-called ‘military threats by the mainland military’”，其中主语是“The Democratic Progressive Party”，谓语是“has hyped up”，宾语是“the so-called ‘military threats by the mainland military’”。“to exaggerate tensions”是一个不定式作目的状语，表示夸大渲染的目的。“Senior Colonel Wu Qian, a PLA spokesman, told a press briefing in Beijing”是一个先行状语，表示这句话是解放军发言人吴谦上校在北京的一次新闻发布会上说的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：“Taiwan has accused Beijing of interfering in the elections by flying spy balloons across the Taiwan Strait’s median line and sending PLA warplanes into its air defence identification zone.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态的句子，结构是：“have/has + been + 现在分词”。在这个例句中，“has accused”是现在完成时的形式，表示台湾一直指责北京干预选举。现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。</p></li>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设或不真实的情况。    <p>原文例句：“Beijing views Taiwan as a breakaway province to be reunited with the mainland, by force if necessary.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气的句子，结构是：“would/could/should/might + have + 过去分词”。在这个例句中，“to be reunited”是虚拟语气，表示北京认为台湾是一个应该与大陆统一的分裂省份。虚拟语气表示假设或不真实的情况，强调说话者的主观判断或猜测。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The island will elect its next president in January, with William Lai, the independence-leaning party’s candidate, currently ahead in the polls</li>
<li>PLA spokesman Wu Qian said accusations was interfering in the election were an attempt to ‘gain votes through lies’</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2023/12/28/389ddd58-5844-4fdf-9922-0caa502f0f30_76dae35b.jpg" /><figcaption>Beijing has accused William Lai’s DPP of hyping up the threat from the mainland. Photo:  EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>Beijing has accused Taiwan’s ruling Democratic Progressive Party of “hyping up” the People’s Liberation Army’s activities ahead of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-election-2024" target="_self" title="">next month’s elections</a> to win votes.</p><p>Taiwan is set to hold presidential and legislative elections in less than three weeks. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246417/taiwan-election-hopeful-william-lai-says-kmts-embrace-one-china-dividing-island" target="_self" title="">Vice-President William Lai Ching-te, the independence-leaning DPP’s presidential candidate</a>, is currently leading in the polls.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246302/chinese-leader-xi-jinping-leads-tributes-mao-zedong-chairmans-130th-birthday" title="">Xi says Taiwan unification will ‘surely’ happen as he marks Mao anniversary</a></h3><p>“The Democratic Progressive Party has purposely hyped up the so-called ‘military threats by the mainland military’ to exaggerate tensions,” Senior Colonel Wu Qian, a PLA spokesman, told a press briefing in Beijing. “They do that so they can make gains in the elections.”</p><p>In response to questions about Taiwan keeping tabs on the PLA, Wu said: “As for the Taiwan military’s capabilities, the PLA is in absolute full control. As always, we will adopt all necessary measures to resolutely defend national sovereignty and territorial integrity.”</p><p>In recent weeks, Taiwan has accused Beijing of interfering in the elections by flying spy balloons across the Taiwan Strait’s median line and sending PLA warplanes into its air defence identification zone.</p><p>Wu dismissed the accusations as election rhetoric by the DPP and denied that the median line exists, saying Taiwan was part of China.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>“The DPP authorities’ hyping up the so-called ‘mainland interference in the election’ is nothing more than their usual election tactics, which are aimed at provoking confrontation and gaining votes with lies. The same old trick has been recognised by more and more Taiwanese people,” he said.</p><p>Last week, Beijing announced a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245816/mainland-china-suspends-tariff-cuts-12-taiwanese-imports-january-response-discriminatory-measures?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">suspension of tariff cuts on 12 petrochemical products from Taiwan</a> and accused the island of putting up “barriers” on mainland imports against the spirit of a key cross-strait trade pact, the Economic Cooperation Framework Agreement.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246313/taiwan-elections-tiktok-teams-fact-checkers-stop-disinformation-site" title="">TikTok teams up with fact checkers to stop election disinformation on site</a></h3><p>The Taiwan Affairs Office in Beijing also <a href="https://collaborate-next.scmp.work/groups/CHINA/boards/7f5ae7cc-93ca-40f1-aed4-58e846ad4f6a/38dd4950-c1f7-4972-a128-3606cfff91f7/5027fbac-fe4c-439b-8ee0-cee97e3254ef/article_viewer?userId=5b5625bb83e37f0001c4a4f9&amp;viewMode=false" target="_self" title="">blamed it on the DPP’s stance on independence</a> and warned that more trade penalties could be on the way.</p><p>Beijing views Taiwan as a breakaway province to be reunited with the mainland, by force if necessary. Most countries do not officially recognise Taiwan as an independent state, but many, including the United States, oppose a forcible change in the status quo.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s economic, social development under 14th 5-year plan on track despite ‘extremely unusual’ time</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3246545/chinas-economic-social-development-under-14th-5-year-plan-track-despite-extremely-unusual-time</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China's top economic planner assesses progress on the 14th five-year plan and reports that most goals are being met or exceeded.</li>    <li>Some areas like energy consumption, carbon emission, air quality, and childcare services are lagging behind due to economic challenges.</li>    <li>Investor and consumer confidence remains low due to a weak property sector and subdued external demand.</li>    <li>China is expected to meet its 2023 GDP growth target but faces challenges in maintaining steady expansion, reducing unemployment, and attracting foreign investment.</li>    <li>China is facing technological constraints from Western countries and needs to boost consumer spending and address risks in food, energy, and finance.</li>    <li>Weak confidence also stems from negative media portrayals of China's national security law and economic growth potential.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国顶级经济规划者评估了十四五规划的进展，报告称大部分目标已经实现或超预期。</li>    <li>能源消耗、碳排放、空气质量和儿童保育服务等领域由于经济挑战而落后。</li>    <li>由于房地产行业疲软和外部需求低迷，投资者和消费者信心依然低迷。</li>    <li>中国有望实现2023年“约5%”的GDP增长目标，但决策者仍面临着艰巨的挑战，需要保持稳定增长，解决失业压力，振兴私营部门并留住外资。</li>    <li>国家发改委的评估指出，国内外“重大深刻变化”阻碍了中国完全实现十四五规划的目标。</li>    <li>国家发改委表示，中国仍被西方国家“卡脖子”于关键技术，缺乏长期机制刺激消费，并面临粮食、能源、金融等领域风险上升的局面。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>economic planner (n.) - 经济规划者。    <p>原文例句：China’s top economic planner has sent out an upbeat message about China’s growth prospects in an assessment of a key economic plan amid growing calls to lift expectations for expansion.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“economic planner”是一个复合名词，由“economic”和“planner”组成，分别表示“经济的”和“规划者”，合起来表示“经济规划者”。在这个例子中，它指的是中国最高级别的经济规划机构——国家发展和改革委员会。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>consumption (n.) - 消费。    <p>原文例句：Energy consumption, carbon emission, air quality and childcare service goals are lagging amid a bumpy economic recovery.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“consumption”是一个名词，表示“消费”。在这个例子中，它指的是能源消耗。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：While Western media doubts whether China is still investible, and “demonises” its national security law, China has greater potential for growth compared to Western countries in terms of GDP per capita. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示从人均GDP的角度来看，中国比西方国家有更大的增长潜力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>take a different perspective - 采取不同的观点。    <P>原文例句：She said at the China Wealth Management 50 Forum, noting a combination of reasons, including increased competition from domestic companies and higher labour costs.“It’s an adjustment to adapt to a new development phase – let’s bear this in mind first.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（采取），a（一个），different（不同的），perspective（观点）构成的，表示“采取不同的观点”。在这个例句中，它表示以不同的观点看待问题。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The world’s second-largest economy has advanced as expected in most aspects outlined in its 14th five-year plan covering economic and social development for 2021-25, according to a midterm assessment from the National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC). - 根據國家發展和改革委員會(NDRC)的中期評估，世界第二大經濟體在第十四個五年規劃所概述的經濟和社會發展的大多數方面已按預期推進，該規劃涵蓋2021-25 年。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The world’s second-largest economy has advanced as expected，其中主语是The world’s second-largest economy，谓语是has advanced，宾语是as expected。in most aspects outlined in its 14th five-year plan covering economic and social development for 2021-25是一个介词短语作定语，修饰The world’s second-largest economy，表示世界第二大经济体在第十四个五年规划所概述的经济和社会发展的大多數方面已按預期推進。according to a midterm assessment from the National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC)是一个介词短语作状语，表示根據國家發展和改革委員會(NDRC)的中期評估。这个句子的意思是说，根据国家发展和改革委员会(NDRC)的中期评估，世界第二大经济体在第十四个五年规划所概述的经济和社会发展的大多數方面已按預期推進。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子中的某一部分。    <p>原文例句：China is, though, expected to meet its 2023 GDP growth goal of “around 5 per cent”, but decision makers are still facing an uphill battle to maintain steady expansion, address unemployment pressures, revive the private sector and retain foreign investment.</p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句型是一个常见的句型，用于强调句子中的某一部分。结构是：It is/was + 被强调的部分 + that/who + 其他。其中it is/was是强调句的标志，被强调的部分可以是名词、代词、形容词、副词等。在这个例句中，被强调的部分是China is expected to meet its 2023 GDP growth goal of “around 5 per cent”，表示中国有望实现2023年“约5%”的GDP增长目标。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Zheng Shanjie said in his report to the country’s top legislature on Tuesday.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词形式。在这个例句中，have/has been + been修饰了said，表示郑栅洁在周二向全国最高立法机关所做的报告中一直持续到现在的动作或状态。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>16 of the 20 major goals included in China’s 14th five-year plan for 2021-25 are within expectation or better than anticipated, according to Beijing’s top economic planner</li>
<li>But energy consumption, carbon emission, air quality and childcare service goals are lagging amid a bumpy economic recovery</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2023/12/28/fe05d087-9e17-4814-a8b9-b1afa8224626_60092395.jpg" /><figcaption>Investor and consumer confidence in China has remained low amid a bumpy economic recovery after reopening, mainly due to an ailing property sector and subdued external demand. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>Beijing’s top economic planner has sent out an upbeat message about China’s growth prospects in an assessment of a key economic plan amid growing calls to lift expectations for expansion.</p><p>The world’s second-largest economy has advanced as expected in most aspects outlined in its 14th five-year plan covering economic and social development for 2021-25, according to a midterm assessment from the National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC).</p><p>Despite several challenges, including technological chokepoints, 16 of the 20 major goals included in the plan are within expectation or better than anticipated, NDRC head Zheng Shanjie said in his report to the country’s top legislature on Tuesday.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/series/3243741/what-expect-chinas-economy-2024" title="">What to expect from China’s economy in 2024</a></h3><p>The evaluation followed the central economic work conference earlier this month, when the top leadership set <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3244856/chinas-development-biggest-political-priority-key-econ-meeting-leaders-vow-counter-risks-lift" target="_self" title="">development as a political priority</a> and ordered officials to strengthen public opinion guidance and “trumpet the bright prospects of the Chinese economy”.</p><p>Calling the past couple of years “extremely unusual”, Zheng said China has “basically met expectations” in terms of gross domestic product (GDP) growth and residents’ income despite Western-led containment efforts and shocks from the coronavirus pandemic.</p><p>However, energy consumption, carbon emission, air quality and childcare service goals, which are high on the agenda for China’s green transition and efforts to counter <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3246037/china-population-reward-grandparents-ban-antinatalist-content-boost-tumbling-births-demographers-say" target="_self" title="">demographic challenges,</a> are lagging, the report added.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>Investor and consumer confidence has remained low amid a bumpy economic recovery after reopening, mainly due to an ailing property sector and subdued external demand.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3238309/china-gdp-economic-recovery-regains-momentum-third-quarter-rises-13-quarter-quarter" target="_self" title="">China is, though, expected to meet</a> its 2023 GDP growth goal of “around 5 per cent”, but decision makers are still facing an uphill battle to maintain steady expansion, address unemployment pressures, revive the private sector and retain foreign investment.</p><p>The NDRC’s assessment pointed out that “significant and deep changes” at home and abroad are hindering China’s efforts to completely meet its 14th five-year plan goals.</p><p>China is, the NDRC said, still being “choked” by Western countries on key technologies, lacking a long-term mechanism to spur consumer spending and facing rising risks in key areas, including food, energy and finance.</p><blockquote>In many cases, it’s the narrative that’s exerting an influenceZheng Yongnian</blockquote><p>The economy is also still suffering from “Covid scars”, represented by stagnant income growth, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3245207/china-jobs-suspended-production-extended-unpaid-leave-embody-woes-private-businesses-under-pressure" target="_self" title="">insufficient jobs</a> and weak confidence, meaning the recovery is lagging behind developed nations, former finance minister Lou Jiwei said at the China Wealth Management 50 Forum at the weekend.</p><p>Weak confidence also occurs as Western media plays up China’s national security law and plays down China’s dedication to economic growth, said Zheng Yongnian, a prominent political scientist at the Chinese University of Hong Kong, Shenzhen.</p><p>“In many cases, it’s the narrative that’s exerting an influence,” he said.</p><p>While Western media doubts whether China is still investible, and “demonises” its national security law, China has greater potential for growth compared to Western countries in terms of GDP per capita, he added.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>“Beijing should respond with emphasis on three most important things – reform, opening-up and innovation,” he said.</p><p>Jiang Xiaojuan, former deputy secretary general of the State Council, also urged people to take a different perspective when looking at the withdrawal of foreign businesses <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3229739/china-exports-us-eu-de-risking-isnt-going-away-worst-yet-come" target="_self" title="">from China amid de-risking efforts.</a></p><p>“Don’t interpret the coming and going of foreign firms into whether they have confidence in China,” she said at the China Wealth Management 50 Forum, noting a combination of reasons, including increased competition from domestic companies and higher labour costs.</p><p>“It’s an adjustment to adapt to a new development phase – let’s bear this in mind first.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
