<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China rich list compiler Hurun clarifies Tsinghua graduate Zhang Zetian’s ranking to quell online controversy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247956/china-rich-list-compiler-hurun-clarifies-tsinghua-graduate-zhang-zetians-ranking-quell-online</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Zhejiang University and Tsinghua University have produced the most graduates to become the billionaires.</li>    <li>30-year-old Zhang was ranked as the third-richest graduate from Tsinghua, with a net worth of US$8.4 billion.</li>    <li>However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</li>    <li>Hurun issued a statement to clarify its methodology for the ranking of rich Chinese alumni.</li>    <li>Chinese tech billionaires move up Hurun 2023 Rich List amid internet rebound.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>浙江大学和清华大学培养出最多的毕业生成为亿万富翁。</li>    <li>30岁的张兰被评为清华大学第三富有毕业生，净资产84亿美元。</li>    <li>然而，许多中国网民在社交媒体平台上质疑张是否真的拥有如此庞大的财富。</li>    <li>胡润百富发布声明，澄清其对中国富豪校友的排名方法。</li>    <li>中国科技亿万富翁在互联网反弹中登上胡润2023年富豪榜。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>entrepreneurship (n.) - /ˌɒntrəprə'nɜːʃɪp/   创业，企业家精神。    <p>原文例句：Hurun defined the “most successful alumni” to include former full-time undergraduates, postgraduates and those entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由entreprendre（承担，着手）和-ship（状态，地位）构成，表示“企业家精神，创业”。在这个例句中，它指的是胡润中国富豪榜2023年榜单中拥有博士学位的全日制本科生、研究生和企业家，即最成功的校友。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>undergraduate (n.) - /ˌʌndərˈgrædʒuət/   大学生，本科生。    <p>原文例句：Hurun defined the “most successful alumni” to include former full-time undergraduates, postgraduates and those entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由under（在……之下）和graduate（毕业生）构成，表示“本科生”。在这个例句中，它指的是胡润中国富豪榜2023年榜单中的全日制本科生，即最成功的校友。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>postgraduate (n.) - /ˌpəʊstˈgrædʒuət/   研究生，硕士生。    <p>原文例句：Hurun defined the “most successful alumni” to include former full-time undergraduates, postgraduates and those entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由post（在……之后）和graduate（毕业生）构成，表示“研究生”。在这个例句中，它指的是胡润中国富豪榜2023年榜单中的研究生，即最成功的校友。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li> such massive wealth - 如此庞大的财富。    <p>原文例句：However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由such（如此）和massive wealth（庞大的财富）构成，表示“如此庞大的财富”。在这个例句中，它指的是张是否真的拥有如此庞大的财富。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Zhejiang University and Tsinghua University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China. - 浙江大学和清华大学培养出最多的毕业生成为亿万富翁。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Zhejiang University and Tsinghua University，谓语是have produced，宾语是the most graduates，状语是to become billionaires in China。这句话的意思是，浙江大学和清华大学培养出最多的毕业生成为亿万富翁。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去的某个时间之前已经发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：A total of 58 universities, 45 Chinese and 13 overseas, have at least three alumni on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个时态结构是：had + been + 过去分词。其中had是have的过去式，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词形式。这个时态表示在过去的某个时间之前已经发生的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示截至2023年胡润中国富豪榜，共有58所大学，其中45所是中国大学，13所是海外大学，至少有三位校友登上榜单。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>According to Hurun, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China</li>
<li>Zhang ranked behind Meituan founder Wang Xing and Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/22f80ee8-51eb-4f11-94d0-38c9096e305d_32c40a21.jpg" /><figcaption>JD.com chairman Richard Liu Qiangdong and wife Zhang Zetian at Princess Eugenie’s wedding. Photo: YouTube </figcaption></figure><p>The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.</p><p>According to a list published by Hurun last Friday, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China. And 30-year-old Zhang was ranked as the third-richest graduate from Tsinghua, with a net worth of 60 billion yuan (US$8.4 billion).</p><p>Zhang ranked behind 44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan and 62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group. However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p><p>Hurun issued a statement on Monday to clarify its methodology for the ranking of rich Chinese alumni. “In the case of Tsinghua’s Zhang, her 60 billion yuan worth falls under her and [husband] Liu jointly.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239156/chinese-tech-founders-bounce-back-huruns-2023-rich-list-number-and-overall-wealth-billionaires-drop" title="">Chinese tech billionaires move up Hurun 2023 Rich List amid internet rebound</a></h3><p>The controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China. According to a separate rich list published by Forbes in November 2023, the net worth of Liu, founder and chairman of e-commerce giant JD.com, was US$4.7 billion, ranking No. 69 in China’s top 100 rich list.</p><p>Liu’s celebrity-style marriage to Zhang is also rare among Chinese tech billionaires, with many maintaining a low profile when it comes to family matters.</p><p>The Tsinghua alumni rich list was part of a Hurun Most Successful University Alumni 2023 ranking the research firm released. Hurun defined the “most successful alumni” to include former full-time undergraduates, postgraduates and those entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</p><p>A total of 58 universities, 45 Chinese and 13 overseas, have at least three alumni on the Hurun China Rich List 2023. Tsinghua and Zhejiang University topped the list, each with 32 alumni on the list.</p><p>Peking University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, and Wuhan University came in third, fourth and fifth with 22, 21, and 17 alumni respectively on the list.</p><p>Robin Li Yanhong, founder, chairman and CEO of Baidu, and Xiaomi chairman and CEO Lei Jun are two of the most high-profile and richest graduates to have come from Peking University and Wuhan University, respectively, according to the list.</p><p>Outside China, Stanford University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, University of California, Yale University and Harvard University from the US were the top five institutions with the most Hurun China Rich listers.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China augmented reality start-up Rokid gets US$70 million in new funding round led by Hefei government</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247968/china-augmented-reality-start-rokid-gets-us70-million-new-funding-round-led-hefei-government</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese augmented reality firm Rokid has secured 500 million yuan in funding, led by the municipal government of Hefei, to establish its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub, and R&D center in Hefei's New Station Hi-Tech Zone, aligning with local development strategies. This funding reflects the growing support from Chinese authorities for tech startups, who in return are expected to make local investments and contribute to the local economy.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Rokid receives funding for metaverse development in Hefei.</li>    <li>Theme: Chinese government's support for AR technology and metaverse industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of local government involvement in tech investments; the importance of public-private partnerships for advancing technology.</li>    <li>Main information: Rokid's investment agreement with Hefei; establishment of industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub, and R&D center in Hefei; focus on cutting-edge R&D and user experience optimization.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国增强现实技术公司Rokid在最新一轮融资中获得了5亿元人民币，由合肥市政府领投，将在合肥新站高新区建立其工业元宇宙总部、生态中心和研发中心，与地方发展战略保持一致。这笔资金反映出中国政府对科技初创企业的支持力度越来越大，作为回报，这些初创企业有望进行地方投资并为地方经济做出贡献。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Rokid获得资金用于合肥元宇宙发展。</li>    <li>主题：中国政府对AR技术和元宇宙产业的支持。</li>    <li>观点：地方政府参与科技投资的重要性；政府和私营部门合作对技术进步的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：Rokid与合肥的投资合作协议；在合肥建设工业元宇宙总部、生态中心和研发中心；专注于前沿研发和用户体验优化。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>augmented reality (AR) - /ˌɔːɡˈmɛntɪd riˈæləti/ 增强现实。    <p>原文例句：Chinese augmented reality (AR) technology firm Rokid has raised nearly half a billion yuan in its latest round of funding led by a local Chinese government, in a fresh indication of the backing from authorities for tech start-ups. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“增强现实”一词源于英语“augment（增加，增强）”和“reality（现实）”的组合，意为“在现实中添加虚拟信息”。在这个例句中，它特指一种通过技术手段将虚拟信息叠加到真实世界中，从而增强用户体验的技术。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>metaverse - /ˈmɛtəvəːs/ 元宇宙。    <p>原文例句：Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and R&D centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone </p>    <p>例句讲解：“元宇宙”一词源于英语“meta（元，超）”和“universe（宇宙）”的组合，意为“超越现实的虚拟世界”。在这个例句中，它特指一种利用数字技术构建的虚拟环境，在这个环境中，人们可以以数字形式进行社交、工作、娱乐等活动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>micro-displays - /ˌmaɪkrəu dɪˈspleɪz/ 微型显示器。    <p>原文例句：“We are honoured to contribute to advancements in science/technology … through our innovations,” said Misa Zhu, founder and CEO of Rokid, adding that the company will focus on cutting-edge R&D and user experience optimisation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“微型显示器”一词源于英语“micro（小，微）”和“display（显示，展示）”的组合，意为“非常小的显示设备”。在这个例句中，它特指一种尺寸极小的显示器，通常用于智能眼镜、智能手表等可穿戴设备中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>industrial metaverse - /ɪnˈdʌstriəl mɛtəvəːs/ 工业元宇宙。    <p>原文例句：Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and R&D centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone, tapping into the Chinese city’s emerging ecosystem including micro-displays, the metaverse and other areas.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“工业元宇宙”一词由“industrial（工业的）”和“metaverse（元宇宙）”组合而成，意为“将元宇宙技术应用于工业领域”。在这个例句中，它特指一种利用元宇宙技术，将物理世界和数字世界相融合，从而实现工业生产、制造等活动的数字化和智能化。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese authorities have increasingly stepped up as private equity investors in projects in line with local development strategies. - 中国当局已逐渐加大对符合地方发展战略项目的私募股权投资。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Chinese authorities，谓语是have stepped up，宾语是private equity investors in projects in line with local development strategies。have stepped up是一个现在完成时态的动词，表示一个动作从过去开始一直持续到现在，并且尚未完成。private equity investors in projects in line with local development strategies是一个介词短语，作宾语，表示中国当局投资的对象是符合地方发展战略的项目。这个句子的意思是说，中国当局已逐渐加大对符合地方发展战略项目的私募股权投资。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时态 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，并且尚未完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Chinese authorities have increasingly stepped up as private equity investors in projects in line with local development strategies. </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态的结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has是助动词，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。现在完成时态表示一个动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，并且尚未完成。在这个例句中，have stepped up是一个现在完成时态的动词，表示中国当局加大对符合地方发展战略项目的私募股权投资这一动作从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，并且尚未完成。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Rokid said it has raised 500 million yuan in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei as a lead investor</li>
<li>Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and R&amp;D centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/f677fbfd-346b-4b28-a3ab-89b2e076e79f_2f7ce20d.jpg" /><figcaption>Rokid Glass, augmented reality glasses, at the Rokid booth during CES 2018, Las Vegas. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese augmented reality (AR) technology firm Rokid has raised nearly half a billion yuan in its latest round of funding led by a local Chinese government, in a fresh indication of the backing from authorities for tech start-ups.</p><p>Rokid said in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor. As part of the deal, Rokid signed an investment and cooperation agreement with Hefei to advance the local metaverse industry.</p><p>Chinese authorities have increasingly stepped up as private equity investors in projects in line with local development strategies. As a quid pro quo for funding, local governments generally require these start-ups to make local investments.</p><p>Under the Hefei deal, Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and research and development (R&amp;D) centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone, tapping into the Chinese city’s emerging ecosystem including micro-displays, the metaverse and other areas.</p><p>“We are honoured to contribute to advancements in science/technology … through our innovations,” said Misa Zhu, founder and CEO of Rokid, adding that the company will focus on cutting-edge R&amp;D and user experience optimisation.</p><p>“Looking ahead, we will maintain a focus on achieving technological milestones and enriching our ecosystem to empower developers and deliver superior products that benefit consumers and enterprises globally”, Zhu said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3233933/china-wants-metaverse-firms-global-influence-and-plans-five-industrial-clusters-2025" title="">China wants up to 5 metaverse companies with ‘global influence’ by 2025</a></h3><p>Hong Fan, chairman of Hefei New Venture Investment Control, an investment vehicle under the Hefei government, added that the cooperation aligns with Rokid and the city’s efforts to drive innovation on metaverse applications and technologies.</p><p>“The cooperation between Rokid and Hefei builds on a shared vision to cultivate extended reality [XR]/metaverse industry development, ” Hong said.</p><p>XR is an overarching term that includes AR, virtual reality, and mixed reality technologies that seek to combine or mirror the physical and digital worlds to allow consumers, equipped with XR equipment, to traverse between and interact with them.</p><p>Founded in 2014, Rokid has made AR equipment for a variety of consumer, travel, and industrial uses, counting companies such as the State Grid Corporation of China and home appliance giant Midea among its clients.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Can Beethoven, Bach and Mozart help iPhone sales in China? Apple to launch classical music app on mainland amid sluggish demand for its flagship produ...</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247961/can-beethoven-bach-and-mozart-help-iphone-sales-china-apple-launch-classical-music-app-mainland-amid</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Apple Music Classical音乐app将于1月24日在中国大陆首次发布，这将扩大苹果公司在全球最大的智能手机市场里提供的数字音乐服务。此举可能提振公司在中国的数字服务业务，中国是其最大的App Store收入市场。2022年，中国创造了5700亿美元的App Store收入，占总收入的51%。尽管iPhone销量有所下降，但中国的智能手机市场竞争激烈，苹果公司是否能通过发布音乐应用来提振销量还有待观察。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple Music Classical音乐应用将于1月24日在中国大陆首次发布。</li>    <li>Theme: Apple Music Classical的推出将扩大苹果公司在中国的数字服务业务，中国是其最大的App Store收入市场。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Apple Music Classical的推出是否能在一定程度上提振iPhone销量，还有待观察。</li>    <li>Main information: iPhone销量下滑，中国市场竞争激烈，Apple Music Classical的推出可能会提振数字服务业务。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果音乐中的Classical音乐app将于1月24日在全球大多数市场同时发布，同时将在中国香港、澳门、台湾、日本和韩国等五个东亚市场发布。该音乐应用号称是全球最大的古典音乐目录，拥有超过五百万首曲目。与此同时，iPhone用户可以在中国大陆地区进行预订。根据苹果在X(前身为Twitter)上的帖子，1月24日，该独立应用还将登陆中国香港、澳门、台湾、日本和韩国的App Store。预计该应用的发布将提振苹果在中国的数字服务业务，中国仍是苹果最大的App Store收入市场。根据咨询公司Analysis Group 2023年5月发布的研究报告，中国在2022年通过苹果App Store生态系统创造的总计帐单和销售额为5700亿美元，占总额的51%。根据去年5月咨询公司Analysis Group在苹果网站上发布的一项研究，中国2022年通过App Store生态系统创造的总计帐单和销售额为5700亿美元，占总额的51%。相比之下，美国在2022年通过App Store生态系统创造的总计帐单和销售额为2730亿美元，占25%；欧洲占11%。鉴于全国消费疲软以及在中国的智能手机市场面对中国主要竞争对手的激烈竞争，目前尚不清楚古典音乐应用的本地发布是否能提升iPhone的销量。根据周日公布的Jefferies研究报告，本年度第一周，iPhone在大陆的销量同比下降30%。这家经纪公司表示，iPhone 14 和 14 Plus 型号的“折扣力度很大”，而较新的 iPhone 15 和 15 Plus 型号的折扣力度“适中”。苹果供应商富士康在2024年第一季度面临需求疲软，销售额下降。以华为技术、小米和荣耀为首的中国智能手机供应商在这一期间拥有“更强劲”的势头，销量同比实现“持平增长”，由Edison Lee领导的Jefferies分析师在报告中写道。根据Jefferies的报告，去年iPhone在中国大陆地区的总销量较2022年下降3%，导致苹果的市场份额下降0.4%。该报告估计，竞争对手华为在12月季度的中国大陆市场份额环比增长2%，同比增长6%。由于iPhone销量放缓，Jefferies预计苹果在2024年在中国大陆将面临“更大的收入压力”。尽管如此，苹果仍继续向投资者保证，即使iPhone销量有所下降。在11月的公司财报电话会议上，苹果首席执行官蒂姆·库克表示：“从长期来看，我认为中国是一个非常重要的市场，我对此非常乐观。”库克去年两次访问中国大陆，会见了高级政府官员、中国开发商和苹果的合同制造合作伙伴。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果音乐Classical音乐应用将于1月24日在中国大陆首次发布。</li>    <li>主题：Apple Music Classical的推出将扩大苹果公司在中国的数字服务业务，中国是其最大的App Store收入市场。</li>    <li>观点：Apple Music Classical的推出是否能在一定程度上提振iPhone销量，还有待观察。</li>    <li>主要信息：iPhone销量下滑，中国市场竞争激烈，Apple Music Classical的推出可能会提振数字服务业务。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>slump (n.) - /slʌmp/ 下降，下跌。    <p>原文例句：iPhone sales on the mainland were down 30 per cent year year, according to a Jefferies research note published on Sunday. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由slap（打击）构成的，表示“突然或大幅下降”。在这个例句中，它指的是iPhone在大陆的销量下降了30%。。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>disruption (n.) - /dɪsˈrʌpʃən/ 中断，破坏。    <p>原文例句：The disruption was caused by the earthquake and tsunami.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由dis-（剥离，分离）和rupt（断裂，突然中断）构成的，表示“突然的中断或破坏”。在这个例句中，它指的是地震和海啸造成的破坏。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：China is Apple’s largest market in terms of App Store revenue. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示中国是苹果公司在App Store收入方面最大的市场。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Sales of the iPhone have been declining in China, which is the world’s largest smartphone market. - iPhone的销售在中国，这个全球最大的智能手机市场上，一直在下降。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Sales of the iPhone have been declining，其中主语是Sales of the iPhone，谓语是have been declining。in China, which is the world’s largest smartphone market是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰主句，表示iPhone的销售在中国，这个全球最大的智能手机市场上的情况。这个句子的意思是说，iPhone的销售在中国，这个全球最大的智能手机市场上，一直在下降。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词结构 - 用于修饰名词或代词，相当于一个形容词或副词。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词结构是在动词词干后加上-ing或-ed形成，具有形容词和副词的双重性质，可以修饰名词或代词，相当于一个形容词或副词。在这个例句中，making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15是一个现在分词结构，修饰名词the company，表示该公司已经在印度生产iPhone和其他产品好几年了，包括最新的iPhone 15。这个句子的意思是说，该公司已经在印度生产iPhone和其他产品好几年了，包括最新的iPhone 15。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较级 - 用于比较两个或多个名词、代词或形容词的程度。    <p>原文例句：The iPhone 15 and 15 Plus models saw “a moderate rise” in discounts. </p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是在形容词或副词后加上-er或more形成，用于比较两个或多个名词、代词或形容词的程度。在这个例句中，moderate rise是一个形容词的比较级，修饰名词discounts，表示折扣的程度是适中的。这个句子的意思是说，iPhone 15和15 Plus机型的折扣程度是适度的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Apple Music Classical app, which was launched in most markets globally in March last year, will make its mainland debut on January 24</li>
<li>On the same date, the app will also be available in five other East Asian markets that include Hong Kong, Macau, Taiwan, Japan and South Korea</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/5bfc68e8-e24d-446d-84dd-b98d8c4fe639_56cadcbe.jpg" /><figcaption>The Apple Music Classical app’s launch in China is likely to bolster the firm’s major digital services business in the country, which is its largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> will soon make its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/classical-music" target="_self" title="">classical music</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">app</a> available in mainland China, expanding the US tech giant’s digital services offering in the world’s largest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> market where sales of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> are seeing a deepening decline.</p><p>The Apple Music Classical app, which was launched in most markets globally in March last year, will make its mainland debut on January 24, according to the company’s online China App Store. The app – touted by Apple as the world’s largest classical music catalogue, with more than five million tracks – can now be pre-ordered by iPhone users in the country.</p><p>On the same date, the stand-alone app will also be available in five other East Asian markets that include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/macau-0" target="_self" title="">Macau</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a>, according to a post on Tuesday by Apple on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/twitter-x" target="_self" title="">X, formerly Twitter</a>.</p><p>The app’s launch is likely to bolster Apple’s major digital services business in China, which remains the company’s largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse" class="image-inline caption" height="1330" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/8163ba04-0fe9-402a-937d-975263f7c4ad_f67d3284.jpg" title="China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse" width="2000" /><figcaption>China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse</figcaption></figure></div><p>China accounted for US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of the total US$1.1 trillion in billings and sales facilitated by the App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published on Apple’s website in May last year.</p><p>By comparison, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> generated US$273 billion, or almost 25 per cent, of the App Store ecosystem’s overall billings and sales in 2022. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/europe" target="_self" title="">Europe</a> accounted for US$119 billion, or 11 per cent, of that year’s total.</p><p>Whether the classical music app’s local release would somehow help lift iPhone sales on the mainland remains to be seen, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247712/chinas-retail-sales-weaken-year-falling-home-prices-jobs-outlook-feed-consumer-insecurity-ubs" target="_self" title="">consumption remains weak</a> across the country and Apple faces stiff competition from major Chinese smartphone rivals.</p><p>In the first week of the year, iPhone sales on the mainland were down 30 per cent year on year, according to a Jefferies research note published on Sunday. The brokerage indicated that there was “a big rise in discounts” for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3192215/apples-iphone-14-sees-surging-pre-orders-china-enthusiastic-consumers" target="_self" title="">iPhone 14</a> and 14 Plus models, while the newer <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3235981/apple-iphone-15-review-faster-cheaper-new-standard-models-are-big-jump-over-their-predecessors" target="_self" title="">iPhone 15</a> and 15 Plus models saw “a moderate rise” in discounts.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics" title="">Apple supplier Foxconn sees sales decline in first quarter of 2024 amid weak demand</a></h3><p>Chinese smartphone vendors, with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honor" target="_self" title="">Honor</a> leading the pack, had “much stronger” momentum during the period, with sales delivering “flattish growth” year on year, Jefferies analysts led by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/enterprises/article/2113581/chinas-chance-lead-global-innovation-may-lie-5g-mobile-technology" target="_self" title="">Edison Lee</a> wrote in the note.</p><p>The iPhone’s total sales volume last year on the mainland was down 3 per cent from 2022, which translated to a 0.4 per cent decline in Apple’s market share, according to Jefferies. It estimated that rival Huawei saw its mainland market share in the December quarter gain 2 per cent from the previous quarter, and 6 per cent year on year.</p><p>Apple is expected to see “even higher revenue pressure” on the mainland in 2024, according to Jefferies.</p><p>Still, Apple has continued to reassure investors even though iPhone sales have been slowing. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240278/apples-ceo-cook-sees-china-bright-spot-after-record-iphone-sales-country-despite-overall-revenue" target="_self" title="">In the firm’s earnings call in November</a>, Apple chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tim-cook" target="_self" title="">Tim Cook</a> said: “Over the long term, I view China as an incredibly important market, and I’m very optimistic about it.”</p><p>Cook made two visits to the mainland last year, meeting senior government officials, Chinese developers and Apple’s contract manufacturing partners.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Foxconn pushes into electric vehicle production near its biggest iPhone plant amid slow smartphone sales</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247941/foxconn-pushes-electric-vehicle-production-near-its-biggest-iphone-plant-amid-slow-smartphone-sales</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary:</h2>  Taiwanese tech giant Foxconn establishes a new venture in Zhengzhou, China, to focus on the electric vehicle industry amid declining smartphone sales. The new company, Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co., will engage in car component manufacturing, motor production, and NEV sales, among other areas. Foxconn aims to expand its presence in the electric vehicle market, complementing its role as a prominent Apple supplier.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Foxconn diversifies into the electric vehicle sector with a new venture in Zhengzhou.</li>    <li>Theme: Foxconn's strategic shift towards electric vehicles due to declining smartphone demand.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The company's efforts to consolidate its position in the automotive industry and reduce reliance on consumer electronics.</li>    <li>Main information: Establishment of Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co.; focus on car component manufacturing, motor production, and NEV sales; expansion into EV market to counterbalance smartphone sales decline.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  台湾科技巨头富士康在中国郑州成立新合资企业，专注于电动汽车行业，以应对智能手机销量下降。新公司富士康新能源汽车产业发展（河南）有限公司将从事汽车零部件制造、电机生产和新能源汽车销售等领域。富士康的目标是扩大其在电动汽车市场的存在，以补充其作为苹果主要供应商的角色。  <ul>    <li>摘要：富士康成立郑州新合资企业，进军电动汽车领域。</li>    <li>主题：富士康因智能手机需求下降而将战略重点转向电动汽车。</li>    <li>观点：富士康巩固其在汽车行业地位并减少对消费电子产品依赖的努力。</li>    <li>主要信息：成立富士康新能源汽车产业发展（河南）有限公司；专注于汽车零部件制造、电机生产和新能源汽车销售；进军电动汽车市场，以弥补智能手机销量下降的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>accelerate (v.) - 加速，加速发展。    <p>原文例句：Foxconn is accelerating its move into the automobile industry amid weakening demand for smartphones and consumer gadgets. </p>    <p>例句讲解：accelerate源自拉丁语adcelerare，意为“增加速度，加速”。在这个例句中，它表示富士康在智能手机和消费电子产品需求疲软的情况下，正在加快向汽车行业的转型。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>contract (n.) - 合同，契约。    <p>原文例句：The world’s largest contract electronics manufacturer is accelerating its move into the automobile industry amid weakening demand for smartphones and consumer gadgets. </p>    <p>例句讲解：contract源自拉丁语contractus，意为“协议，契约”。在这个例句中，它表示富士康作为全球最大的电子合同制造商，正在加快向汽车行业的转型。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>forthcoming (adj.) - 将要发生的，即将到来的。    <p>原文例句：It blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, while expecting continuing decline in the first quarter of this year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：forthcoming源自古英语forthcuman，意为“即将到来”。在这个例句中，它表示富士康将第四季度消费电子产品业务的停滞归咎于市场需求疲软，并预计今年第一季度将继续下滑。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>exodus (n.) - 大量迁出，大量外流。    <p>原文例句：In 2022, that facility was rocked by violent workers’ protests and an exodus of tens of thousands of employees that Apple CEO Tim Cook later blamed for a decline in the US company’s quarterly revenue. </p>    <p>例句讲解：exodus源自希腊语exodos，意为“离开，离去”。在这个例句中，它表示2022年，富士康郑州工厂发生了工人抗议和数万名员工离职事件，苹果公司CEO蒂姆·库克后来将这起事件归咎于该公司季度收入下降的原因之一。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>amid (prep.) - 在……之中，在……期间。    <p>原文例句：Foxconn is accelerating its move into the automobile industry amid weakening demand for smartphones and consumer gadgets. </p>    <p>例句讲解：amid源自拉丁语amidus，意为“在……中间”。在这个例句中，它表示富士康在智能手机和消费电子产品需求疲软的情况下，正在加快向汽车行业的转型。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>put under investigation - 接受调查。    <p>原文例句：The company, which was put under a tax and land use investigation in October by mainland authorities, employs 200,000 workers in its Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p>    <p>例句讲解：put under investigation是一个动词短语，意为“接受调查”。在这个例句中，它表示富士康在去年10月接受了大陆当局的税收和土地使用调查。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Foxconn Technology Group has set up a new car venture in Zhengzhou city, capital of central China’s Henan province and home to the world’s largest iPhone factory, as the Apple supplier steps up its efforts in the new energy vehicle (NEV) sector amid declining smartphone sales. - 富士康科技集团在中国中部河南省省会郑州市成立了一家新的汽车合资企业，这家全球最大的iPhone工厂所在地，因为苹果供应商在新能源汽车（NEV）领域的努力加大了，而智能手机销售额却在下降。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，有多个従句，主句是Foxconn Technology Group has set up a new car venture in Zhengzhou city。其中Foxconn Technology Group是主语，has set up a new car venture in Zhengzhou city是谓语，Zhengzhou city是宾语。capital of central China’s Henan province and home to the world’s largest iPhone factory是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰Zhengzhou city。as the Apple supplier steps up its efforts in the new energy vehicle (NEV) sector amid declining smartphone sales是一个时间状语从句，表示富士康在智能手机销售额下降的情况下，加大了在新能源汽车（NEV）领域的努力。这个句子的意思是说，富士康科技集团在中国中部河南省省会郑州市成立了一家新的汽车合资企业，这家全球最大的iPhone工厂所在地，因为苹果供应商在新能源汽车（NEV）领域的努力加大了，而智能手机销售额却在下降。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>非限制性定语从句 - 提供额外信息，不限制先行词的指代范围，可以用逗号分隔。    <p>原文例句：Foxconn Technology Group has set up a new car venture in Zhengzhou city, capital of central China’s Henan province and home to the world’s largest iPhone factory, as the Apple supplier steps up its efforts in the new energy vehicle (NEV) sector amid declining smartphone sales. </p>    <p>语法讲解：非限制性定语从句通常用逗号分隔，提供有关先行词的额外信息，但并不限制先行词的指代范围。在这个例句中，capital of central China’s Henan province and home to the world’s largest iPhone factory是一个非限制性定语从句，它提供了关于Zhengzhou city的额外信息，即它是中国中部河南省的省会，也是全球最大的iPhone工厂的所在地。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>主谓一致 - 动词必须与主语在人称和数上保持一致。    <p>原文例句：Foxconn Technology Group has set up a new car venture in Zhengzhou city, capital of central China’s Henan province and home to the world’s largest iPhone factory, as the Apple supplier steps up its efforts in the new energy vehicle (NEV) sector amid declining smartphone sales.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：主谓一致是指动词必须与主语在人称和数上保持一致。在这个例句中，主语是Foxconn Technology Group，是一个单数第三人称主语，所以动词has set up也是单数第三人称形式。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Apple supplier has set up a new venture in Zhengzhou to sharpen its focus on the electric vehicle industry</li>
<li>The new project will involve car component manufacturing and development, motor production and car sales</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/aad49844-fb12-4001-aa76-72cbfe6b99d4_f04766b4.jpg" /><figcaption>A Foxconn building in Taipei. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foxconn" target="_self" title="">Foxconn Technology Group</a> has set up a new car venture in Zhengzhou city, capital of central China’s Henan province and home to the world’s largest iPhone factory, as the Apple supplier steps up its efforts in the new energy vehicle (NEV) sector amid declining smartphone sales.</p><p>The new firm, named Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co, was established on January 4 with a registered capital of 500 million yuan (US$70 million), according to public records in the National Enterprise Credit Information Publicity System.</p><p>Its business covers car component manufacturing and development, motor production and NEV sales, among other areas.</p><p>Foxconn, known formally as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hon-hai-precision-industry" target="_self" title="">Hon Hai Precision Industry</a>, said the new venture belongs to Foxconn Innovation Industry Development Group Co and aims to sharpen the company’s focus on the electric vehicle industry, according to a report by the Securities Times on Tuesday.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Foxconn confirmed the report, adding that the Henan subsidiary was disclosed in December 2023 to the Taiwan Stock Exchange.</p><p>The world’s largest contract electronics manufacturer is accelerating its move into the automobile industry amid weakening demand for smartphones and consumer gadgets.</p><p>The Taiwanese giant last week reported US$198.9 billion in preliminary revenue for 2023, down 7 per cent from 2022. It blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, while <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics" target="_self" title="">expecting continuing decline in the first quarter of this year</a>.</p><p>In October, Foxconn <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238352/apple-supplier-foxconn-build-ai-factories-using-nvidias-chips-and-software-range-applications" target="_self" title="">announced a new electric cargo van called Model N</a> and announced plans to mass produce its compact SUV Model B. Jun Seki, its chief strategy officer for electric vehicles, said the company was in touch with about 14 potential customers and saw India and Japan as promising countries for EV development.</p><p>To help push the company towards its new direction, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3218313/apple-supplier-foxconn-sets-global-business-base-iphone-city-show-commitment-china" target="_self" title="">Foxconn opened a new global business base in Zhengzhou</a> last April and reaffirmed its commitment to the Chinese market, even as the firm and other Apple suppliers move to diversify their supply chain.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/853102cf-b84f-499d-9b72-8c24ea357fde_a66cec46.jpg" title="A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Foxconn plans to start building new factories for smartphones and electronics goods in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of major construction projects in 2024 released last week by the provincial Development and Reform Commission.</p><p>The company, which was put under <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239113/china-says-investigation-apple-supplier-foxconns-operations-mainland-normal-law-enforcement" target="_self" title="">a tax and land use investigation</a> in October by mainland authorities, employs 200,000 workers in its Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p><p>In 2022, that facility was rocked by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3200747/violence-erupts-foxconn-zhengzhou-plant-workers-protest-over-benefits-and-covid-19-controls-worlds?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">violent workers’ protests</a> and an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3197909/coronavirus-iphone-factory-exodus-shows-how-chinas-covid-narrative-still-strikes-fear-public?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">exodus of tens of thousands of employees</a> that Apple CEO Tim Cook later <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3208974/apples-tim-cook-blames-supply-disruption-chinas-pandemic-controls-revenue-drop" target="_self" title="">blamed for a decline in the US company’s quarterly revenue</a>.</p><p>Separately, Foxconn plans to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">invest at least US$2.6 billion in a plant</a> it is building in India to make Apple products, according to a report by Bloomberg last month.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China EV maker Xpeng accepts pre-orders for flying car but notes urban use is far off</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Xpeng, a leading electric vehicle manufacturer in China, unveiled two models of flying cars at the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in Las Vegas. One of the models, the sportier AeroHT eVTOL, made its international debut at the event. Despite ongoing conversations with Chinese authorities for regulatory approval, Xpeng aims to deliver the first batch of flying cars by the fourth quarter of 2025. The modular Land Aircraft Carrier, featuring a separate aircraft launched from the car, will begin accepting pre-orders later this year. Pricing and availability information for the AeroHT, which was showcased but not flown at CES, has not been disclosed. Xpeng president Brian Gu highlighted the company's focus on a consumer market rather than urban transportation, emphasizing the need for regulatory frameworks before widespread city use can be realized. The company distinguishes its products from competitor EHang, which targets enterprise use with aerial vehicles lacking road-driving capabilities. While Gu mentioned discussions with Chinese regulators, the company acknowledges that international expansion may face challenges due to geopolitical tensions and potential regulatory hurdles.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Xpeng introduces flying car concepts at CES, aiming for initial deliveries in 2025, subject to regulatory approvals.</li>    <li>Theme: Xpeng's innovative approach to the flying car market, focusing on consumer appeal and addressing regulatory hurdles.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The potential of flying cars to revolutionize transportation, the need for regulatory frameworks, and the geopolitical considerations impacting the industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Unveiling of two flying car models, target delivery timeline, modular design of Land Aircraft Carrier, focus on consumer market, discussions with Chinese regulators, and potential international expansion challenges.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  中国电动汽车制造商小鹏汽车在拉斯维加斯举行的消费电子展 (CES) 上展示了两种型号的飞行汽车。其中一款名为 AeroHT eVTOL 的运动型飞行汽车在本次展会上首次亮相。小鹏汽车虽然正在与中国当局就监管审批进行沟通，但仍计划在 2025 年第四季度交付首批飞行汽车。模块化陆地航空母舰配有一架从汽车上发射的独立飞机，将于今年晚些时候开始接受预订，并于一年后开始交付。AeroHT 在 CES 上进行了展示，但并未进行飞行，其价格和供货信息尚未公布。小鹏汽车总裁顾宏地强调，公司专注于消费市场，而非城市交通，并强调在城市实现广泛使用之前需要建立监管框架。该公司将自己的产品与竞争对手亿航区分开来，亿航专注于企业使用，其飞行器不具备在道路上行驶的能力。虽然顾宏地提到正在与中国监管机构进行讨论，但该公司承认，由于地缘政治紧张局势和潜在的监管障碍，国际扩张可能会面临挑战。  <ul>    <li>摘要：小鹏汽车在 CES 上推出飞行汽车概念，计划于 2025 年交付首批产品，但需获得监管部门的批准。</li>    <li>主题：小鹏汽车开创性的飞行汽车市场战略，着眼于消费者的吸引力并解决监管障碍。</li>    <li>观点：飞行汽车对变革交通运输的潜力、建立监管框架的必要性以及影响该行业的地缘政治因素。</li>    <li>主要信息：推出两款飞行汽车型号、目标交付时间表、陆地航空母舰的模块化设计、对消费市场的关注、与中国监管机构的讨论以及潜在的国际扩张挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>modular (adj.) - /ˈmɑːdjələr/ 模块化的，由模块组成的。    <p>原文例句：Its modular Land Aircraft Carrier will start taking pre-orders in the fourth quarter this year, with deliveries to start a year later. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由module（模块）和-ar（形容词后缀）构成的，表示“模块化的，由模块组成的”。在这个例句中，它指的是小鹏汽车的模块化陆地航空母舰，即由多个模块组成的飞行汽车。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>propeller (n.) - /prəˈpɛlər/ 螺旋桨，推进器。    <p>原文例句：It has propellers that pop out of the back.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由propel（推进）和-er（名词后缀）构成的，表示“螺旋桨，推进器”。在这个例句中，它指的是小鹏汽车飞行汽车的后部弹出式螺旋桨。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take flight - 起飞，腾飞。    <P>原文例句： It did not take flight at CES.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（采取，进行）和flight（飞行）组成的，表示“起飞，腾飞”。在这个例句中，它表示小鹏汽车的飞行汽车在 CES 上并没有起飞。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Xpeng distanced itself from the EHang comparison, saying its products are different and target different buyers. - 小鹏汽车否认了与亿航的比较，称其产品不同且目标客户不同。<p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，主句是Xpeng distanced itself from the EHang comparison，其中主语是Xpeng，谓语是distanced，宾语是itself，状语是from the EHang comparison。saying its products are different and target different buyers是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示小鹏汽车否认与亿航的比较的原因，即其产品不同且目标客户不同。这个句子的意思是说，小鹏汽车否认了与亿航的比较，称其产品不同且目标客户不同。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>否定虚拟祈使句 - 表示请求或建议不要做某事。    <p>原文例句：I’m not even thinking about that right now … This business is purely focused on the China market right now.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个否定虚拟祈使句，结构是：否定词 + be + 现在分词 + 其他。其中否定词为not，be为am，现在分词是thinking，其他是about that right now。这种句型表示请求或建议不要做某事。在这个例句中，它表示小鹏汽车总裁顾宏地说，他甚至不想考虑国际扩张的问题，因为他们的业务目前只关注中国市场。这个句子的意思是说，小鹏汽车总裁顾宏地说，他甚至不想考虑国际扩张的问题，因为他们的业务目前只关注中国市场。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>分词短语的两种方式 - 分词短语在句中可以作定语或状语。    <p>原文例句：The sportier AeroHT eVTOL car made its international debut at the show, having previously conducted flying tests in China. - 携此前已在华进行飞行的测试，更具运动风格的 AeroHT eVTOL 车型在展会上首次亮相。</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中含有两个分词短语，分别是having previously conducted flying tests in China和made its international debut at the show。having previously conducted flying tests in China是一个过去分词短语，作定语，修饰car，表示这辆车此前已经在中国进行了飞行测试。made its international debut at the show是一个现在分词短语，作状语，修饰car，表示这辆车在展会上首次亮相。这个句子的意思是说，携此前已在华进行飞行的测试，更具运动风格的 AeroHT eVTOL 车型在展会上首次亮相。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The company’s subsidiary AeroHT presented two types of flying cars at CES, including a sportier eVTOL that made its international debut</li>
<li>Xpeng president Brian Gu said the company is in talks with regulators in China to allow use of the vehicle, but international expansion ‘takes time’</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/407dea1a-dbe1-45b0-ac41-d295e42b8239_80ccf63e.jpg" /><figcaption>Brian Gu Hongdi, vice-chairman and president of Xpeng, discusses the company’s new flying car at CES on January 9, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Seven years after EHang debuted its first passenger drone, Chinese electric vehicle maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng">Xpeng</a> entered the market with its own “flying car”, with the goal of delivering the first batch by the fourth quarter of 2025, whether regulations are ready or not.</p><p>The company’s subsidiary AeroHT presented two types of flying cars at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Tuesday. Its modular Land Aircraft Carrier will start taking pre-orders in the fourth quarter this year, with deliveries to start a year later. The sportier AeroHT eVTOL (electric vertical take-off and landing) car made its international debut at the show, having previously conducted flying tests in China.</p><p>There is no information on pricing or availability for the AeroHT, which has propellers that pop out of the back. It has been demoed for flying in China, but it did not take flight at CES. Brian Gu Hongdi, vice-chairman and president of Xpeng, suggested it could launch before regulations are in place for city use, but that people could eventually buy one and fly it in areas where the use of aircraft is not regulated.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247808/ces-2024-china-tv-makers-hisense-and-tcl-promote-ai-live-sports-us-show" title="">Hisense and TCL push AI in TVs, chase industry trends like smart cars</a></h3><p>“The design of our vehicles is not targeted for urban transportation … [which] requires an extensive regulatory approval process,” Gu said. “That’s why we’re targeting a consumer market, for people to first enjoy the experience of flying and then obviously with the regulatory framework in place, we gradually can move towards urban transportation.”</p><p>While Gu said it was too early to say what pricing might be, he expects it to be “similar to buying a luxury performance car”.</p><p>Similar products have been in the works for years. EHang made a splash when it debuted the EHang 184 at CES in 2016. In the years since, it has <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/innovation/article/3024726/nerves-waiver-screaming-lift-joy-two-minute-test-ride-passenger" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/innovation/article/3024726/nerves-waiver-screaming-lift-joy-two-minute-test-ride-passenger">invited journalists to take rides</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/3030521/chinese-drone-maker-ehang-said-file-ipo-nasdaq" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/3030521/chinese-drone-maker-ehang-said-file-ipo-nasdaq">went public on the Nasdaq</a>.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="AeroHT’s modular Land Aircraft Carrier comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/22700ac5-f38a-4718-b5a7-2df12b039468_00d05c81.jpg" title="AeroHT’s modular Land Aircraft Carrier comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>AeroHT’s modular Land Aircraft Carrier comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Xpeng distanced itself from the EHang comparison, saying its products are different and target different buyers. The EV company, which made its debut at CES two years after EHang with its first car, noted that EHang’s products are just aerial vehicles without the ability to be driven on roads. EHang is also targeting enterprise use, while Xpeng is targeting a wider consumer base.</p><p>“We are targeting the consumer market, which is very different,” Gu said. “I don’t see another company that’s doing that right now.”</p><p>While Xpeng has also highlighted how the Land Aircraft Carrier could be used for public services like emergency rescue, the new eVTOL car is a more stylish option that can conceal its rotors. This will presumably make it more appealing for people to buy, whenever it becomes available, even if they cannot fly it to work every morning.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3247413/ai-will-be-spotlight-consumer-electronics-show-2024-glasses-blind-shoes-make-you-walk-faster-and" title="">AI to dominate CES 2024, with glasses for blind, shoes to walk faster</a></h3><p>Gu said the company is already in talks with regulators in China but international expansion “takes time”.</p><p>Xpeng’s ambitions could face some challenges with current geopolitical tensions, though. Chinese drone tech has been caught in the cross hairs before. Washington put DJI, the world’s largest consumer drone maker, on its Entity List that bars US companies from doing business with it without express approval.</p><p>When asked whether this could present some hurdles, Gu said, “I’m not even thinking about that right now … This business is purely focused on the China market right now.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TSMC halts revenue drop, beats expectations on brisk demand for AI chips from Nvidia, Advanced Micro Devices</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247936/tsmc-halts-revenue-drop-beats-expectations-brisk-demand-ai-chips-nvidia-advanced-micro-devices</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Despite a decrease in smartphone and laptop chip sales, Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co. (TSMC), the world's largest contract chipmaker, reported a steady revenue in the fourth quarter, surpassing analyst estimates but falling short of growth. The demand from artificial intelligence (AI) players helped offset declining sales in other sectors. TSMC's sales reached NT$625.5 billion, matching the previous year's results. However, the company's overall revenue for 2023 declined by 4.5 percent due to industry-wide challenges. TSMC's top management remains optimistic about growth this year due to the increasing demand for AI chips.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: TSMC's steady revenue in Q4 despite a challenging market environment, lifted by AI demand.</li>    <li>Theme: TSMC's revenue stability in Q4 amid industry-wide decline, highlighting the impact of AI demand.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of AI in driving semiconductor demand; TSMC's potential for continued growth amidst market uncertainty.</li>    <li>Main information: TSMC's Q4 revenue meeting estimates; overall decline in revenue for 2023; optimism for AI-driven growth; industry headwinds in consumer electronics.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  全球最大芯片代工巨头台积电发布四季度营收，在智能手机和笔记本芯片销售低迷的情况下，受人工智能（AI）需求推动，营收依然稳健，超过分析师预期，但未能实现增长。台积电的销售额达到 6255 亿新台币，与去年同期持平。然而，由于整个行业的挑战，该公司 2023 年的整体营收下降了 4.5%。面对严峻的市场环境，台积电高层仍然对今年的增长持乐观态度，原因是 AI 芯片的需求不断增加。  <ul>    <li>摘要：AI 需求支撑，台积电第四季度营收稳健，尽管市场环境具有挑战性。</li>    <li>主题：台积电第四季度营收稳定，行业整体下滑，凸显 AI 需求的影响。</li>    <li>观点：AI 在推动半导体需求方面的重要性；台积电在市场不确定性中持续增长的潜力。</li>    <li>主要信息：台积电第四季度营收符合预期；2023 年整体营收下降；对 AI 驱动的增长持乐观态度；消费电子行业面临阻力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>luggish (adj.) - /ˈslʌɡɪʃ/ 迟缓的，不活跃的。    <p>原文例句：While demand from artificial intelligence (AI) players helped offset sluggish smartphone and laptop chip sales.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于slog（慢慢走），表示“缓慢移动的，迟缓的，不活跃的”。在这个例句中，它用来形容智能手机和笔记本电脑芯片销售的低迷状态。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>surge (v.) - /sɜːdʒ/ 激增，猛增。    <p>原文例句：Still, the latest report from the Semiconductor Industry Association showed the first growth in chip sales in over a year came in November, suggesting momentum is gathering for a resurgence in 2024.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle French的surger（涌起），表示“突然或快速增加”。在这个例句中，它用来形容芯片销售在 11 月出现的一年多来的首次增长。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>chip maker - 芯片制造商。    <P>原文例句：Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), the world's largest contract chip maker, saw its fourth-quarter revenue beat estimates of a decline, as demand from artificial intelligence (AI) players helped offset sluggish smartphone and laptop chip sales. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由chip（芯片）和maker（制造商）构成的，表示“芯片制造商”。在这个例句中，它表示台积电是世界上最大的芯片制造商。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), the world's largest contract chip maker, saw its fourth-quarter revenue beat estimates of a decline, as demand from artificial intelligence (AI) players helped offset sluggish smartphone and laptop chip sales. - 全球最大芯片代工巨头台积电发布四季度营收，在智能手机和笔记本芯片销售低迷的情况下，受人工智能（AI）需求推动，营收依然稳健，超过分析师预期。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是TSMC saw its fourth-quarter revenue beat estimates of a decline，其中主语是TSMC，谓语是saw beat，宾语是estimates of a decline。as demand from artificial intelligence (AI) players helped offset sluggish smartphone and laptop chip sales是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示造成这一结果的原因，即人工智能（AI）玩家的需求帮助抵消了智能手机和笔记本电脑芯片销售疲软的影响。这个句子的意思是说，全球最大芯片代工巨头台积电发布四季度营收，在智能手机和笔记本芯片销售低迷的情况下，受人工智能（AI）需求推动，营收依然稳健，超过分析师预期。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 表示原因或条件。    <p>原文例句：as demand from artificial intelligence (AI) players helped offset sluggish smartphone and laptop chip sales.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示动作或状态与主句动作或状态之间的关系。结构是：现在分词 + ing + 其他。其中现在分词表示动作或状态，其他部分表示动作或状态的具体情况。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能（AI）玩家的需求帮助抵消了智能手机和笔记本电脑芯片销售疲软的影响。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Hsinchu-based company reported a NT$625.5 billion quarter, matching earnings from the same period a year earlier</li>
<li>While it outdid analyst expectations and its own guidance, TSMC’s US$20.2 billion quarter still fell short of delivering growth</li>
</ul><p>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), the world's largest contract chip maker, saw its fourth-quarter revenue beat estimates of a decline, as demand from artificial intelligence (AI) players helped offset sluggish smartphone and laptop chip sales.</p><p>Hsinchu-based TSMC, the main chip supplier to Apple and Nvidia, reported December sales of NT$176.3 billion (US$5.7 billion), completing a NT$625.5 billion quarter.</p><p>That matched earnings from the same period a year earlier, which was among TSMC’s highest quarterly results. The average analyst estimate for sales over the last three months was NT$616.2 billion.</p><p>Over the course of 2023, TSMC moderated its capital expenditure plans as the consumer electronics industry grappled with a glut of unsold inventory. The chip maker signalled the trough in demand had been reached in the summer and recovery would begin to take hold in the months leading up to 2024.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Overall revenue declined 4.5 per cent last year, to NT$2.16 trillion.</p><p>While it outdid analyst expectations and its own guidance, TSMC’s US$20.2 billion quarter still fell short of delivering growth. December sales were down 8.4 per cent on the same month a year earlier, offering a mixed outlook for the year ahead.</p><p>Top management including chief executive CC Wei have said they expect overall business to grow this year, and the company has seen its high-performance computing business boosted by demand for AI chips from Nvidia and Advanced Micro Devices.</p><p>Earlier in the week, fellow chip maker Samsung Electronics posted <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" target="_self" title="">its sixth successive quarter of declining operating profit</a>, as it weathered the impact of muted consumer demand in its smartphone and memory businesses.</p><p>Still, the latest report from the Semiconductor Industry Association showed the first growth in chip sales in over a year came in November, suggesting momentum is gathering for a resurgence in 2024.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247835/china-persist-ai-development-efforts-2024-despite-setbacks-rigid-us-semiconductor-restrictions-ubs" title="">China to persist with AI development in 2024 despite US chip curbs: UBS</a></h3><p>Upgrades to AI server farms and on-device AI applications are likely to drive an information technology replacement cycle, according to HSBC analysts Ricky Seo and Hankil Chang.</p><p>“For US cloud service providers, we expect capex to grow significantly, about 65 per cent in 2024e. Additionally, AI server purchases will likely total 57 per cent of their investments in 2024e, up from 8 per cent in 2022,” they wrote in a research note on Wednesday.</p><p>Apple, arguably TSMC’s most important customer, has faced headwinds with its latest iPhone generation in China, the world’s biggest smartphone market. Several analysts have downgraded Apple this year on expectations of soft demand, and this week Jefferies said the iPhone sales slump in China is likely to deepen.</p><p>The US company has also been hit by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3233603/china-orders-government-workers-stop-using-iphones-amid-heightened-tensions-us" target="_self" title="">an expanded ban by Chinese agencies and state-owned companies</a> ordering staff to keep iPhones and other foreign devices away from work premises.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Amazon’s Twitch to cut 500 employees, or 35% of staff, as soon as January 10 as business remains unprofitable</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247877/amazons-twitch-cut-500-employees-or-35-staff-soon-january-10-business-remains-unprofitable</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Twitch, a live-streaming site owned by Amazon, is reportedly cutting 35% of its workforce, around 500 employees, due to concerns over losses and recent departures of top executives. Despite relying on Amazon's infrastructure, running a large-scale website with 1.8 billion hours of monthly live video content is very expensive. The company had previously cut over 400 positions in two rounds of layoffs in 2023.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Twitch to lay off 35% of its staff amid concerns over losses and executive departures.</li>    <li>Theme: The business challenges and restructuring efforts at Twitch, a leading live-streaming platform.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Impact of high operational costs and a series of executive exits on Twitch's operations.</li>    <li>Main information: Scale of job cuts; reliance on Amazon's infrastructure; previous layoffs in 2023; focus on advertising; challenges in addressing user concerns.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Twitch，一家由亚马逊拥有的直播网站，据报道将裁员35%，大约500名员工，原因是对亏损和高管离职的担忧。尽管依赖亚马逊的基础设施，但运行一个每月拥有18亿小时直播视频内容的大型网站是非常昂贵的。该公司此前在2023年的两轮裁员中已削减了400多个职位。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Twitch在对亏损和高管离职的担忧中裁员35%。</li>    <li>主题：领先的直播平台Twitch的业务挑战和重组工作。</li>    <li>观点：运营成本高昂和一系列高管离职对Twitch运营的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：裁员规模；对亚马逊基础设施的依赖；2023年之前的裁员；对广告的关注；在解决用户关切方面的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>cross-country (adj.) - /ˌkrɒsˈkʌntri/ 跨越国家的，全国性的。    <p>原文例句：Since he took the position in March 2023, Clancy has been on a cross-country charm offensive to mend relations with the video gaming celebrities who make a living streaming on Twitch. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词由cross（穿过）和country（国家）组成，表示“跨越国家的，全国性的”。在这个例句中，它描述了Clancy自2023年3月上任以来一直在进行的全国性魅力攻势，以修复与在Twitch上直播为生的视频游戏名人的关系。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>mend (v.) - /mend/ 修复，改正。    <p>原文例句：Since he took the position in March 2023, Clancy has been on a cross-country charm offensive to mend relations with the video gaming celebrities who make a living streaming on Twitch. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个动词表示“修复，改正”。在这个例句中，它描述了Clancy自2023年3月上任以来一直在进行的修复与在Twitch上直播为生的视频游戏名人的关系的努力。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>lay-offs (n.) - /ˈleɪɒf/ 裁员。    <P>原文例句：The cuts, which could be announced as soon as Wednesday, come amid concerns over losses at Twitch and after several top executives left the company in the span of a few months.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词是由lay（放下）和off（离开）构成的，表示“裁员”。在这个例句中，它指的是因担忧亏损和高管离职而可能在星期三宣布的裁员。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in the wake of - 在……之后。    <P>原文例句：Running a large-scale website supporting 1.8 billion hours of live video content a month is enormously expensive, company executives have said</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），wake（唤醒）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“在……之后”。在这个例句中，它表示运行一个每月支持18亿小时直播视频内容的大型网站是非常昂贵的。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Many of them chafed at Twitch’s original approach to ads, which the company reworked after criticism. - 许多人对Twitch最初的广告方式感到不满，公司在收到批评后进行了重做。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company reworked after criticism，其中主语是The company，谓语是reworked，宾语是after criticism。Many of them chafed at Twitch’s original approach to ads是一个过去时态的动词短语作状语，表示许多人对Twitch最初的广告方式感到不满。在这个例句中，它表示许多人对Twitch最初的广告方式感到不满，公司在收到批评后进行了重做。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>插入语 - 插入语是在句中插入的非限制性成分，通常用逗号隔开。    <p>原文例句：In the final months of 2023, several top executives announced their departures, including Twitch’s chief product officer, chief customer officer and chief content officer. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个插入语是several top executives announced their departures，其中包括Twitch’s chief product officer, chief customer officer and chief content officer。它在句中起了补充说明的作用，提供了有关几位高管离职的信息。需要注意的是，插入语在句中不构成句子成分，不影响句子的结构，可以用逗号将其与句子其他部分隔开。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>祈使语 - 祈使语是用来发出命令、请求或建议的句子。    <p>原文例句：Take a deep breath and think step by step. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个祈使语，其中Take a deep breath and think step by step是一个并列结构，表示“深呼吸并一步一步思考”。这个句子是用来发出命令或建议的，要求对方深呼吸并一步一步思考。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The cuts come after Twitch’s chief product officer, chief customer officer and chief content officer left in the final months of 2023</li>
<li>Running a large-scale website supporting 1.8 billion hours of live video content a month is enormously expensive, company executives have said</li>
</ul><p>Amazon.com’s live-streaming site Twitch is poised to cut 35 per cent of its staff, or about 500 workers, according to people familiar with the plans, the latest in a series of job reductions there.</p><p>The cuts, which could be announced as soon as Wednesday, come amid concerns over losses at Twitch and after several top executives left the company in the span of a few months. A Twitch representative declined to comment.</p><p>Running a large-scale website supporting 1.8 billion hours of live video content a month is enormously expensive, despite Twitch’s reliance on Amazon’s infrastructure, company executives have said.</p><p>In December, Twitch chief executive Dan Clancy said the company would cease operations in South Korea, where the costs are “prohibitively expensive”, according to a blog post he wrote.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Twitch has increased its focus on advertising in recent years. Nine years after Amazon’s acquisition of the company, the business remains unprofitable, according to the people, who asked not to be identified discussing private information.</p><p>In the final months of 2023, several top executives announced their departures, including Twitch’s chief product officer, chief customer officer and chief content officer. Twitch also lost its chief revenue officer, who worked on Twitch from within Amazon’s ads unit.</p><p>“It’s always bittersweet when talented leaders move on to pursue new opportunities,’’ a Twitch spokesman said at the time. “We are incredibly grateful for their contributions to Twitch and our community, and wish them all the best.”</p><p>The former employees all declined to comment.</p><p>Since he took the position in March 2023, Clancy has been on a cross-country charm offensive to mend relations with the video gaming celebrities who make a living streaming on Twitch.</p><p>Many of them chafed at Twitch’s original approach to ads, which the company reworked after criticism. Streamers have praised Clancy’s desire to listen to their concerns after years of complaints that the service was out of touch with its users.</p><p>The new chief has struggled to stem losses, however. Twitch undertook two rounds of lay-offs last year, cutting over 400 positions, part of wider job reductions at Amazon.</p><p>The online retail giant initiated its biggest-ever corporate job cuts in 2022, which it expanded to 27,000 positions across the company. It continued in October with a new round of cuts to its music division, which encompasses the company’s audio streaming platform and digital storefront for songs.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US SEC says its X account was compromised to falsely say bitcoin ETFs approved</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247873/us-sec-says-its-x-account-was-compromised-falsely-say-bitcoin-etfs-approved</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>On Tuesday, a fake post on the SEC's official Twitter account claimed that the agency had approved a spot-Bitcoin ETF, causing a surge in Bitcoin's price and triggering a cybersecurity investigation.</li>    <li>The SEC clarified that the post was fake and no decision had been made regarding the approval of spot-Bitcoin ETFs.</li>    <li>SEC Chairman Gary Gensler, known for his skepticism towards cryptocurrency, emphasized the severity of cyberattacks and expressed sympathy for companies that have experienced such incidents.</li>    <li>The incident highlighted the irony of a cybersecurity breach affecting an agency that has warned about the vulnerabilities of cryptocurrencies.</li>    <li>The SEC faces a deadline of January 10 to take action on at least one Bitcoin ETF application, and traders speculate that a slew of decisions may be announced soon.</li>    <li>Approval of spot-backed Bitcoin ETFs requires both the SEC's approval of exchange filings and the approval of registration applications from issuers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>周二，美国证券交易委员会 (SEC) 的官方 Twitter 账号上的一篇虚假帖子声称机构已经批准了现货比特币 ETF，导致比特币价格飙升并引发网络安全调查。</li>    <li>美国证券交易委员会澄清，该帖子是虚假的，尚未就批准现货比特币 ETF 作出决定。</li>    <li>美国证券交易委员会主席加里·金斯勒以其对加密货币的怀疑态度而闻名，他强调了网络攻击的严重性，并对经历过此类事件的公司表示同情。</li>    <li>这一事件凸显了负责警告加密货币漏洞的监管机构发生网络安全漏洞的讽刺意味。</li>    <li>美国证券交易委员会面临 1 月 10 日的最后期限，必须对至少一项比特币 ETF 申请采取行动，交易员猜测可能很快就会宣布一系列决定。</li>    <li>获得现货支持的比特币 ETF 的批准，需要得到美国证券交易委员会对交易所文件的批准，以及得到发行人的注册申请的批准。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>morphed (v.) - 变成，演变成。    <p>原文例句：A highly anticipated decision by the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) on whether to approve a spot-bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF) quickly morphed into a major cybersecurity incident on Tuesday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“morphed”意思是“变成，演变成”。在这个例句中，它指的是一个高度预期的决定，即美国证券交易委员会是否批准现货比特币交易所交易基金 (ETF)，迅速演变成了周二发生的一起重大网络安全事件。</p></li>    <li>irony (n.) - 讽刺。    <p>原文例句：The irony of a cybersecurity incident befalling a regulator that has repeatedly warned of crypto’s online vulnerabilities was not lost on critics who have spent years waiting for the SEC to approve a bitcoin ETF.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“irony”意思是“讽刺”。在这个例句中，它指的是一个负责警告加密货币在线漏洞的监管机构自己发生了网络安全事件，这个讽刺之处并没有被那些多年来一直等待美国证券交易委员会批准比特币 ETF 的批评者忽视。</p></li>    <li>speculation (n.) - 推测，猜测。    <p>原文例句：Traders have been speculating for weeks that the agency could approve several of the products as soon as Wednesday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“speculation”意思是“推测，猜测”。在这个例句中，它指的是交易员们已经猜测数周，该机构可能最早在周三就批准几种产品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take action - 采取行动。    <p>原文例句：In statements late on Tuesday, the regulator said that it would work with law enforcement to investigate the incident, the unauthorized access had been terminated, and that the post was not made by the SEC or its staff.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“take action”意思是“采取行动”。在这个例句中，它指的是监管机构在周二的晚些时候发表声明表示，将与执法部门合作调查事件，未经授权的访问已被终止，该帖子并非美国证券交易委员会或其员工发布的。</p></li>    <li>sign off - 批准，通过。    <p>原文例句：First, the SEC must sign off on so-called 19b-4 filings by the exchanges that would list the ETFs.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“sign off”意思是“批准，通过”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国证券交易委员会首先必须批准交易所为上市 ETF 而提交的所谓 19b-4 文件。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The SEC’s X account was compromised and a fake post claiming that the agency had greenlit plans for the products fuelled a brief surge in the price of the world’s biggest cryptocurrency. - SEC 的 X 账户遭到入侵，一个虚假帖子声称该机构已批准了这些产品的计划，导致全球最大加密货币的价格短暂飙升。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是A fake post claiming that the agency had greenlit plans for the products fuelled a brief surge in the price of the world’s biggest cryptocurrency.，其中主语是A fake post，谓语是fuelled，宾语是a brief surge in the price of the world’s biggest cryptocurrency。The SEC’s X account was compromised是一个过去分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示SEC 的 X 账户遭到入侵。claiming that the agency had greenlit plans for the products是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰A fake post，表示声称该机构已批准了这些产品的计划。这个句子的意思是说，SEC 的 X 账户遭到入侵，一个虚假帖子声称该机构已批准了这些产品的计划，导致全球最大加密货币的价格短暂飙升。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式作主语 - 不定式可以作主语，表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：To approve a spot-bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF) quickly morphed into a major cybersecurity incident on Tuesday.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，不定式To approve a spot-bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF)作主语，表示批准现货比特币交易所交易基金 (ETF)的动作。这个句子的意思是说，批准现货比特币交易所交易基金 (ETF) 的决定迅速演变成周二发生的一起重大网络安全事件。</p></li>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：In statements late on Tuesday, the regulator said that it would work with law enforcement to investigate the incident, the unauthorised access had been terminated, and that the post was not made by the SEC or its staff.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，现在完成时态had been terminated表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的状态，即未经授权的访问已被终止。这个句子的意思是说，监管机构在周二的晚些时候发表声明表示，将与执法部门合作调查事件，未经授权的访问已被终止，该帖子并非美国证券交易委员会或其员工发布的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>US authorities are investigating how the @SECGov’s account was compromised by ‘an unknown party’</li>
<li>The regulator has clarified that no decision on spot bitcoin ETFs had been made</li>
</ul><p>A highly anticipated decision by the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) on whether to approve a spot-bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF) quickly morphed into a major cybersecurity incident on Tuesday.</p><p>The SEC’s X account was compromised and a fake post claiming that the agency had greenlit plans for the products fuelled a brief surge in the price of the world’s biggest cryptocurrency. It also has sparked an investigation by US authorities into how a social media account at Wall Street’s main regulator was compromised.</p><p>“It really shows the breadth and frequency of cyberattacks,” said Kurt Gottschall, a partner at law firm Haynes Boone and former SEC regional director. “The irony here is that the SEC has not shown much sympathy to public companies and asset managers that have experienced cybersecurity incidents.”</p><p>The breach gave fodder to crypto faithful who have long viewed the commission’s chairman, Gary Gensler, as an enemy due to his zeal to rein in the industry.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="SEC chairman Gary Gensler at a congress hearing in September. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/74063e72-ef97-4ab1-9293-377cc070fd84_57e2bc2f.jpg" title="SEC chairman Gary Gensler at a congress hearing in September. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>SEC chairman Gary Gensler at a congress hearing in September. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>The irony of a cybersecurity incident befalling a regulator that has repeatedly warned of crypto’s online vulnerabilities was not lost on critics who have spent years waiting for the SEC to approve a bitcoin ETF. Traders have been speculating for weeks that the agency could approve several of the products as soon as Wednesday.</p><p>In statements late on Tuesday, the regulator said that it would work with law enforcement to investigate the incident, the unauthorised access had been terminated, and that the post was not made by the SEC or its staff. In a separate statement, Gensler clarified that no decision on ETFs had been made.</p><p>The SEC said that there was unapproved activity on the @SECGov X account “by an unknown party for a brief period of time shortly after 4pm ET” on Tuesday. After the fake post was removed, Joe Benarroch, head of business operations at X, said in a statement that the “account is secure and we are investigating the root cause”.</p><p>About a dozen companies have applied to list ETFs backed by bitcoin in the US. The SEC has until January 10 to take action on at least one of those applications, and crypto insiders have speculated the regulator will use that date to announce a slew of decisions at once.</p><p>There are two technical requirements that must be fulfilled before a spot-backed bitcoin ETF can start trading. First, the SEC must sign off on so-called 19b-4 filings by the exchanges that would list the ETFs. Second, the regulator must approve the relevant S-1 forms, which are the registration applications from the would-be issuers – a list that includes BlackRock and Fidelity.</p><p>The SEC is planning to vote on the exchanges’ filings, the 19b-4s, this week, Bloomberg News has reported. The regulator may or may not take action on the issuers’ applications, the S-1s, around the same time. If the SEC grants both sets of required approvals, the ETFs could start trading as soon as the next business day.</p><p>The SEC under Gensler and his Trump-era predecessor, Jay Clayton, has previously refused to allow such a product to launch, citing concerns about investor protection and the potential for market manipulation. However, speculation has been mounting since August, when the SEC lost a key legal fight against crypto asset manager Grayscale Investments, that the regulator will have to acquiesce to the growing clamour for the product.</p><p>Hype about an approval has been rampant on social media. Bitcoin surged as much as 10 per cent on October 16 when a crypto news site incorrectly posted on X that BlackRock had been approved to list a spot ETF. About US$85 million of mostly bearish trading positions were liquidated during the surge, which quickly reversed.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
