<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Apple supplier Foxconn sees revenue decline in first quarter of 2024 amid weak global consumer electronics demand, sluggish iPhone sales</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Foxconn, the world's largest electronics contract manufacturer, expects revenue to decline in the first quarter of 2024 due to weak global consumer electronics demand, influenced by Apple's sluggish iPhone sales. The company's revenue for the December quarter fell 5.4% year-on-year, but annual revenue reached US$198.9 billion, with the first quarter being an off-peak season. Foxconn is diversifying its manufacturing supply chain in response to geopolitical tensions with the US and weak economic recovery in China, with plans to invest in plants for Apple products in India and Henan province.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Foxconn anticipates a revenue decline in Q1 2024 due to sluggish consumer electronics demand, influenced by Apple's iPhone sales.</li>    <li>Theme: Foxconn's dim first-quarter outlook and revenue decline due to weak demand, Apple's status as the world's most valuable stock, and Foxconn's efforts to diversify its manufacturing supply chain.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of weak iPhone sales on Apple and Foxconn; Foxconn's strategic moves to address geopolitical tensions and economic recovery in China.</li>    <li>Main information: Foxconn's revenue decline in Q1 2024; sluggish iPhone sales impacting Apple's valuation; Foxconn's expansion in India and ongoing investments in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  富士康作为全球最大的电子合约制造商，预计 2024 年第一季度的收入将下降，原因是苹果iPhone销售疲软导致全球消费电子需求疲软。该公司 12 月季度的收入同比下降 5.4%，但年收入达到 1989 亿美元，第一季度通常是非高峰期。富士康正在针对与美国的紧张地缘政治局势以及中国经济复苏乏力进行供应链多元化，计划投资建设印度和河南省的苹果产品工厂。  <ul>    <li>摘要：富士康因消费者电子需求低迷（受苹果 iPhone 销售影响）预计 2024 年第一季度收入下降。</li>    <li>主题：受需求低迷影响，富士康第一季度预期黯淡和收入下降、苹果作为全球最具价值股票的地位以及富士康为应对地缘政治紧张局势和中国经济复苏而进行的供应链多元化努力。</li>    <li>观点：苹果和富士康受 iPhone 销售疲软影响；富士康为应对地缘政治紧张局势和中国经济复苏而采取的战略举措。</li>    <li>主要信息：富士康2024年第一季度收入下降；iPhone销售疲软影响苹果估值；富士康在印度扩张并持续投资中国。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>analyst (n.) - /ˈæn(ə)lɪst/ 分析师，评论家。    <p>原文例句：Barclays analyst Tim Long said in a client note, which pointed to weakness in China and subdued demand in developed markets. </p>    <p>例句讲解：分析师是指对某一领域或行业进行分析和研究的人，他们通常拥有丰富的知识和经验，可以对市场、经济或行业趋势做出专业的判断。在这个例句中，巴克莱分析师蒂姆·朗在客户报告中指出中国疲软和发达市场需求低迷。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>plummet (v.) - /ˈplʌmɪt/ 急剧下降，暴跌。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s lofty status as world’s most valuable stock at risk from bumpy 2024 start    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词指价格或数量急剧、大幅度下降，常用来形容股票、商品价格等在短时间内的剧烈下跌。在这个例句中，它表示苹果公司作为全球最具价值的股票的地位可能会因为2024年充满挑战的开局而面临风险。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>bump period - 颠簸时期。    <P>原文例句：Foxconn on Friday blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, even though the company went through a bumpy period a year ago when its biggest iPhone plant in Zhengzhou, capital of central Henan province, was rocked by an exodus of tens of thousands of employees and violent workers’ protests amid a Covid-19 outbreak that began in late October. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由bump（颠簸）和period（时期）组成的，表示一段充满挑战、坎坷或动荡的时期。在这个例句中，它指的是富士康在去年经历的一段颠簸时期，当时该公司位于河南省郑州市的最大iPhone工厂因数万名员工离职和工人生气抗议而受到冲击。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Foxconn Technology Group, the world’s biggest iPhone assembler, expects revenue to decline in the first quarter of 2024 amid weak global consumer electronics demand, extending a decrease in sales in the past three months. - 富士康科技集团是全球最大的 iPhone 组装厂，预计 2024 年第一季度收入将下降，因全球消费电子需求疲软，这将延续过去三个月来的销售下降趋势。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Foxconn Technology Group expects revenue to decline in the first quarter of 2024，其中主语是Foxconn Technology Group，谓语是expects，宾语是revenue to decline in the first quarter of 2024。amid weak global consumer electronics demand是一个介词短语，作状语，表示在全球消费电子需求疲软的情况下。extending a decrease in sales in the past three months是一个现在分词短语，作状语，表示延续过去三个月来的销售下降趋势。这个句子的意思是说，富士康科技集团预计2024年第一季度收入将下降，原因是全球消费电子需求疲软，这将延续过去三个月来的销售下降趋势。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式 - 表示一种动作或状态，可以作名词、形容词或副词。    <p>原文例句：Foxconn on Friday blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, even though the company went through a bumpy period a year ago when its biggest iPhone plant in Zhengzhou, capital of central Henan province, was rocked by an exodus of tens of thousands of employees and violent workers’ protests amid a Covid-19 outbreak that began in late October. - 富士康周五将第四季度其静态消费类电子产品业务的需求疲软归咎于市场需求疲软，尽管该公司一年前经历了一段颠簸时期，当时其位于河南省郑州市的最大 iPhone 工厂因数万名员工离职和工人生气抗议而受到冲击，抗议始于 10 月底的 Covid-19 爆发期间。</p>    <p>语法讲解：动词不定式是指动词的非限定形式，即在动词词干后加-ing。动词不定式有主动和被动两种形式。主动不定式表示主动的动作或状态，被动不定式表示被动的动作或状态。动词不定式在句中可以作名词、形容词或副词。在这个例句中，动词不定式for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter作状语，表示富士康第四季度其静态消费电子产品业务的需求疲软的原因。动词不定式amid a Covid-19 outbreak that began in late October作状语，表示在10月底开始的Covid-19爆发期间。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>情态动词 - 表示说话者的态度、能力、意愿等。    <p>原文例句：“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long said in a client note, which pointed to weakness in China and subdued demand in developed markets. - “iPhone 15 表现不佳，我们相信 iPhone 16 也会如此，”巴克莱分析师蒂姆·朗在客户报告中表示，报告指出了中国疲软和发达市场需求低迷。</p>    <p>语法讲解：情态动词是指表示说话者的态度、能力、意愿、建议或可能性的助动词。情态动词有can、could、may、might、must、shall、should、will、would等。在这个例句中，情态动词should表示说话者的建议或意见，即iPhone 16 应该和iPhone 15一样表现不佳。</p  <ul><li>Foxconn did not provide an estimate of the quarterly drop, but said the year’s first three months represent an off-peak season for the industry</li>
<li>The world’s largest electronics contract manufacturer reported total 2023 revenue was down 7 per cent year on year to US$198.9 billion</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/e222829d-56dc-48eb-b8cb-9a2ea658a625_cee121ea.jpg" /><figcaption>Foxconn Technology Group’s dim first-quarter outlook reflects concerns raised by investors of major client Apple about sluggish iPhone sales. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foxconn?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Foxconn Technology Group</a>, the world’s biggest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> assembler, expects revenue to decline in the first quarter of 2024 amid weak global consumer electronics demand, extending a decrease in sales in the past three months.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>-based Foxconn, formally known as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hon-hai-precision-industry?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Hon Hai Precision Industry</a>, did not provide an estimate on the quarterly revenue drop, but said the first three months will be compared to a high base in the same period last year, when its factories in mainland China resumed normal operations after disruptive pandemic controls were relaxed by the government, according to the company’s statement on Friday.</p><p>The world’s largest electronics contract manufacturer also indicated that the year’s first quarter is typically an off-peak season for the industry.</p><p>Revenue for the company’s December quarter fell 5.4 per cent year on year to NT$1.85 trillion (US$60 billion), but was up by 20 per cent from the previous quarter. Total 2023 revenue was US$198.9 billion, down 7 per cent from 2022.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen" class="image-inline caption" height="1243" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/09a87505-ea2a-40a2-91f3-d3980a90b343_8f795096.jpg" title="People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen" width="2000" /><figcaption>People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen</figcaption></figure></div><p>Foxconn on Friday blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, even though the company went through a bumpy period a year ago when its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3225783/worlds-largest-iphone-factory-zhengzhou-ramps-hiring-foxconn-chairman-reassures-china-supply-chain" target="_self" title="">biggest iPhone plant in Zhengzhou</a>, capital of central Henan province, was rocked by an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3197909/coronavirus-iphone-factory-exodus-shows-how-chinas-covid-narrative-still-strikes-fear-public?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">exodus of tens of thousands of employees</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3200747/violence-erupts-foxconn-zhengzhou-plant-workers-protest-over-benefits-and-covid-19-controls-worlds?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">violent workers’ protests</a> amid a Covid-19 outbreak that began in late October.</p><p>The company’s dim first-quarter outlook reflects concerns raised by investors of major client Apple about sluggish iPhone sales, which prompted the US tech giant to be <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">hit by two ratings downgrades</a> this week.</p><p>“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">said in a client note</a>, which pointed to weakness in China and subdued demand in developed markets.</p><p>Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247501/apples-reign-worlds-most-valuable-stock-market-value-jeopardy-bumpy-2024-start" title="">Apple’s lofty status as world’s most valuable stock at risk from bumpy 2024 start</a></h3><p>Apple, which has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022, has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.</p><p>The company’s iPhones also face intense competition on the mainland against a resurgent <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, which is seeing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" target="_self" title="">strong demand for its new 5G handsets</a> in the world’s largest smartphone market.</p><p>While Apple <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" target="_self" title="">continues to lead the global premium smartphone market</a>, where handsets are priced from US$600, Huawei has gained ground in this segment on the back of its new Mate 60 series.</p><p>Foxconn is also <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234562/foxconn-offers-higher-hourly-rates-workers-shenzhen-its-huawei-production-unit-its-iphone-operation" target="_self" title="">offering higher rates for workers that make Huawei’s handsets</a> in southern tech hub <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shenzhen" target="_self" title="">Shenzhen</a> than those that make iPhones, according to a South China Morning Post report last September.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions" title="">Foxconn ramps up investment in giant Apple plant in India</a></h3><p>Still, Foxconn has stepped up efforts to diversify its manufacturing supply chain for Apple and other clients amid the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246222/chinas-middle-class-does-not-dare-spend-until-post-covid-economy-shows-clear-signs-recovery" target="_self" title="">weak post-pandemic economic recovery</a> in mainland China and rising geopolitical tensions between Beijing and Washington.</p><p>Foxconn won approval to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions" target="_self" title="">invest at least US$1 billion more in a plant</a> it is building in India that will make Apple products, on top of the US$1.6 billion it earlier pledged, according to a report by Bloomberg last month.</p><p>On the mainland, Foxconn continues to invest in central Henan province, where it employs 200,000 workers in the firm’s Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p><p>The Taiwanese firm, which was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239113/china-says-investigation-apple-supplier-foxconns-operations-mainland-normal-law-enforcement" target="_self" title="">put under investigation in October by mainland regulators</a>, this year plans to start building new factories for smartphones and other electronics products in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of 520 major construction projects for 2024 released this week by the province’s Development and Reform Commission.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s reign as world’s most valuable stock by market value in jeopardy from bumpy 2024 start</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247501/apples-reign-worlds-most-valuable-stock-market-value-jeopardy-bumpy-2024-start</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  苹果公司股价周五下滑0.4%，此前有报道称美国司法部即将对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。彭博数据显示，今年以来，这家科技巨头已损失约1770亿美元的市值。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's stock falls on news of potential antitrust case.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's challenges, including antitrust issues, declining iPhone sales, and patent disputes, weigh on its stock performance.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of antitrust concerns and market pressures on Apple's status as the world's most valuable company.</li>    <li>Main information: Apple's stock decline, analyst downgrades, and investors' portfolio adjustments contribute to the loss in market value.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果公司股票在周五下跌了 0.4%，此前有报道称美国司法部即将对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。彭博数据显示，今年以来，这家科技巨头已经损失了约 1770 亿美元的市值。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果公司股票因潜在的反垄断案件消息而下跌。</li>    <li>主题：苹果公司面临的反垄断问题、iPhone 销量下降和专利争议等挑战对其股票表现产生了负面影响。</li>    <li>观点：反垄断担忧和市场压力对苹果作为全球市值最高公司的影响和地位。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果公司股价下跌、分析师下调评级和投资者投资组合调整导致其市值损失。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>decline (n.) - /dɪˈklaɪn/ 下降。    <p>原文例句：The downturn began earlier in the week after the technology giant was hit by two ratings downgrades. </p>    <p>例句讲解：decline 这个单词可以作为名词或动词使用。作为名词时，它表示“下降，减少”。在这个例句中，它表示苹果公司股价的下跌。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>mesmerise (v.) - /ˈmɛzməraɪz/ 使入迷。    <p>原文例句：The Windows software maker has benefited from the artificial intelligence trade that has mesmerised Wall Street over the past year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：mesmerise 这个单词来源于德国的催眠术师弗兰茨·梅斯默的名字，意思是“使入迷，使着迷”。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能行业的发展吸引了华尔街的关注。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in jeopardy - 处于危险之中。    <p>原文例句：putting its long-standing status as the world’s most valuable stock by market value in jeopardy. </p>    <p>例句讲解：in jeopardy 这个词组是由in（在……里面）和jeopardy（危险）构成的，意思是“处于危险之中”。在这个例句中，它表示苹果公司作为世界上市值最高的股票的地位正处于危险之中。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>at the start of - 在……开始时。    <p>原文例句：While the stock has suffered bigger percentage declines in the first week of January, the losses are the biggest market value destruction at the start of any year on record. </p>    <p>例句讲解：at the start of 这个词组是由at（在）和start（开始）构成的，意思是“在……开始时”。在这个例句中，它表示苹果公司今年第一周的股价跌幅虽然较大，但从年初开始的市值损失却是历史上最大的。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company. - 周五，这家科技巨头的股价下跌了0.4%，收于大约181美元，此前《纽约时报》报道称，美国司法部即将对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。<p>句子分析：这是一个复句，主句是Shares of the technology giant fell，其中主语是Shares of the technology giant，谓语是fell。to close at about US$181是一个不定式作状语，表示苹果公司股价下跌的结果或目的。after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company是一个时间状语从句，表示苹果公司股价下跌的原因或背景。这个句子的意思是说，周五，这家科技巨头的股价下跌了0.4%，收于大约181美元，此前《纽约时报》报道称，美国司法部即将对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：It is OpenAI’s largest shareholder and has invested about US$13 billion into the ChatGPT parent. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句型，主要结构是：It is / was + 被强调成分 + that + 其他部分。其中It is / was是句子的主语，被强调成分是句子中需要强调的部分，that + 其他部分是句子的谓语。在这个例句中，被强调成分是largest shareholder，表示微软是OpenAI最大的股东。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态，主要结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示苹果公司从2022年7月以来一直是世界上市值最高的公司。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Shares of Apple fell 0.4 per cent on Friday after a report that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company</li>
<li>The tech giant has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/0bab1060-0f68-4b59-b625-ee8f62b7b778_cec54c59.jpg" /><figcaption>People walk past an Apple Store in the Glendale Galleria shopping mall in California on December 26, 2023. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> just had its worst start to the year by one measure, as investors react to mounting pressures on the company, putting its long-standing status as the world’s most valuable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/stocks" target="_self" title="">stock</a> by market value in jeopardy.</p><p>Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.</p><p>The decline notched the fifth consecutive negative day for Apple, its longest losing streak since October.</p><p>The potential antitrust case against Apple “would add to the plethora of problems it faces, from slowing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> sales to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246452/apple-resumes-sale-watches-after-appeals-court-lifts-us-ban" target="_self" title="">Apple Watch patent issues</a>”, Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Anurag Rana wrote in a note. “The suit could attack Apple’s business model of tightly integrating its devices and services.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/bdba7b4d-2eef-4fae-a196-1d3cd943fe89_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Cupertino, California-based company has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022, but has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.</p><p>While the stock has suffered bigger percentage declines in the first week of January, the losses are the biggest market value destruction at the start of any year on record.</p><p>The downturn began earlier in the week after the technology giant was hit by two <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" target="_self" title="">ratings downgrades</a>, with analysts flagging a weak macro environment in China pressuring demand for iPhones.</p><p>That has shrunk its lead over fellow technology juggernaut <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft Corp</a> – whose shares have seen a less pronounced decline to begin the year – to less than US$100 billion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247211/apple-leads-us383-billion-tech-rout-reversal-groups-2023-rally" title="">Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</a></h3><p>“Investors realise how rare it is to have two people go negative,” said Gene Munster, managing partner of Deepwater Asset Management. “I’ve been covering this company for a long time and I’ve never seen two downgrades before an earnings report.”</p><p>Apple is also likely under pressure as investors rotate their portfolios at the start of the year.</p><p>“Everybody’s selling their winners and buying losers,” said Brian Mulberry, client portfolio manager at Zacks Investment Management. “There’s a big rebalance going on.”</p><p>The losses have pushed Apple’s market value down to about US$2.8 trillion, nearing Microsoft’s US$2.7 trillion. Shares of Microsoft fell less than 0.1 per cent Friday to close at about US$368.</p><p>The Windows software maker has benefited from the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> trade that has mesmerised Wall Street over the past year. The company is <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content" target="_self" title="">OpenAI</a>’s largest shareholder and has invested about US$13 billion into the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> parent.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech trade group representing TikTok, Snapchat and Meta sues Ohio over state’s new law limiting children’s use of social media apps</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247497/tech-trade-group-representing-tiktok-snapchat-and-meta-sues-ohio-over-states-new-law-limiting</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  俄亥俄州一项要求儿童在使用社交媒体应用程序前获得父母同意的新法律因违宪而面临法律挑战。该法律于去年7月由共和党州长迈克·德温签署成为法律，将于2023年1月15日生效。净选择贸易团体认为该法律侵犯了言论自由，过于宽泛且含糊不清。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 俄亥俄州一项要求儿童使用社交媒体应用需要获得父母同意的法律因违宪而受到质疑。</li>    <li>Theme: 新法律引发了社交媒体公司和家长之间的矛盾，双方对该法律的合理性各执一词。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 净选择贸易团体认为该法律侵犯了言论自由，过于宽泛且含糊不清；政府则认为该法律可以保护儿童的心理健康。</li>    <li>Main information: 该法律由共和党州长迈克·德温签署，将于2023年1月15日生效；净选择贸易团体已对该法律提起诉讼，称其违反了宪法第一修正案；共和党副州长乔恩·哈斯蒂德为该法律辩护，认为社交媒体对儿童有害且会上瘾。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  俄亥俄州一项要求儿童在使用社交媒体应用程序前获得父母同意的新法律因违宪而面临法律挑战。该法律于去年7月由共和党州长迈克·德温签署成为法律，将于2023年1月15日生效。净选择贸易团体认为该法律侵犯了言论自由，过于宽泛且含糊不清。  <ul>    <li>摘要：俄亥俄州一项要求儿童使用社交媒体应用需要获得父母同意的法律因违宪而受到质疑。</li>    <li>主题：新法律引发了社交媒体公司和家长之间的矛盾，双方对该法律的合理性各执一词。</li>    <li>观点：净选择贸易团体认为该法律侵犯了言论自由，过于宽泛且含糊不清；政府则认为该法律可以保护儿童的心理健康。</li>    <li>主要信息：该法律由共和党州长迈克·德温签署，将于2023年1月15日生效；净选择贸易团体已对该法律提起诉讼，称其违反了宪法第一修正案；共和党副州长乔恩·哈斯蒂德为该法律辩护，认为社交媒体对儿童有害且会上瘾。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>impugn (v.) - /ɪmˈpjuːn/ 质疑，攻击。    <p>原文例句：The litigation argues that Ohio’s law unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，意为“攻击，质疑”。在这个例句中，它表示净选择贸易团体认为俄亥俄州的新法律侵犯了言论自由，过于宽泛且含糊不清。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>censor (v.) - /ˈsɛnsər/ 审查，禁止。    <p>原文例句：The law also requires social media companies to provide parents with their privacy guidelines, so that families can know what content will be censored or moderated on their child’s profile.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，意为“监督，检查”。在这个例句中，它表示该法律要求社交媒体公司向父母提供其隐私指南，以便家庭了解哪些内容将在其孩子的个人资料上被审查或调整。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>harmful (adj.) - /ˈhɑːrmfʊl/ 有害的，伤人的。    <p>原文例句：He also alleged the tech companies know their algorithms are harming children “with catastrophic health and mental health outcomes”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语hearm（伤害），意为“伤害，损害”。在这个例句中，它表示共和党副州长哈斯蒂德指控科技公司知道他们的算法对儿童有害，并导致了灾难性的健康和心理健康后果。</p>    </li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>on the grounds (that) - 根据（……的理由）。    <p>原文例句：The litigation argues that Ohio’s law is unconstitutional on the grounds that it impedes free speech.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组通常用于法律或政治语境，表示“根据（……的理由）”。在这个例句中，它表示净选择贸易团体认为俄亥俄州的新法律违宪，理由是它侵犯了言论自由。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The law was part of an US$86.1 billion state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July. - 该法律是共和党州长迈克·德温去年7月签署成为法律的861亿美元州预算法案的一部分。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The law was part of a state budget bill，其中主语是The law，谓语是was part of。an US$86.1 billion state budget bill是定语从句，修饰名词The law，表示该法律是861亿美元州预算法案的一部分。that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July是定语从句，修饰名词state budget bill，表示该预算法案是由共和党州长迈克·德温签署成为法律的。    </p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示违背事实的假设或愿望。    <p>原文例句：The group has won lawsuits against similar restrictions in California and Arkansas. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气结构，其中has won lawsuits是虚拟语气的现在完成时态，表示过去的事情在现在仍然有效或有影响。在这个例句中，它表示该组织已经赢得了针对加利福尼亚州和阿肯色州类似限制的诉讼。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The law forms part of a state budget bill that Ohio Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July and is set to take effect on January 15</li>
<li>The NetChoice trade group argues that Ohio’s law unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/0827334f-9aca-4109-b4e2-813fa20ac5b8_06ce695b.jpg" /><figcaption>Ohio’s new law requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps. Photo: TNS</figcaption></figure><p>A trade group representing major tech companies including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/snapchat" target="_self" title="">Snapchat</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/facebook" target="_self" title="">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/instagram" target="_self" title="">Instagram</a> operator <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226704/meta-takes-aim-twitter-launch-rival-app-threads" target="_self" title="">Meta Platforms</a> sued Ohio on Friday over the state’s pending law that requires children to get parental consent to use <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">apps</a>.</p><p>The law was part of an US$86.1 billion state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July. It is set to take effect on January 15.</p><p>The administration pushed the measure as a way to protect children’s mental health, with Republican Lieutenant Governor Jon Husted saying at the time that social media was “intentionally addictive” and harmful to kids.</p><p>The NetChoice trade group filed its lawsuit against Republican Attorney General Dave Yost in US District Court for the Southern district of Ohio. It seeks to block the law from taking effect.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP" class="image-inline caption" height="1410" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/8d380f8f-5e87-4f75-add2-ca49bea0915b_3ad8b242.jpg" title="A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP" width="2000" /><figcaption>A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The litigation argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> apps – unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p><p>The law also requires social media companies to provide parents with their privacy guidelines, so that families can know what content will be censored or moderated on their child’s profile.</p><p>“We at NetChoice believe families equipped with educational resources are capable of determining the best approach to online services and privacy protections for themselves,” Chris Marchese, director of the organisation’s litigation centre, said in a statement.</p><p>“With NetChoice v Yost, we will fight to ensure all Ohioans can embrace digital tools without their privacy, security and rights being thwarted.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247089/montana-appealing-ruling-blocked-state-barring-tiktok-use" title="">Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok use</a></h3><p>The group has won lawsuits against similar restrictions in California and Arkansas.</p><p>Husted, who leads Ohio’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> initiatives and championed the law, called Friday’s lawsuit “cowardly but not unexpected”.</p><p>“In filing this lawsuit, these companies are determined to go around parents to expose children to harmful content and addict them to their platforms,” Husted said in a statement.</p><p>He also alleged the tech companies know their algorithms are harming children “with catastrophic health and mental health outcomes”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China needs ‘groundbreaking’ policy changes to embrace disruptive technologies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247450/china-needs-groundbreaking-policy-changes-embrace-disruptive-technologies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China needs to make fundamental changes to its industrial policymaking to become a global technological and economic leader.</li>    <li>Disruptive technologies like artificial intelligence and quantum computing will significantly alter consumer, industry, and business operations.</li>    <li>China's economic success resulted from carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies, a model adopted by other Asian economies.</li>    <li>The shift from selective industrial policy to functional policy is critical, as disruptive technologies' potential is uncertain.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国需要对产业政策制定进行颠覆性改变，以成为全球科技和经济领袖。</li>    <li>人工智能、量子计算等颠覆性技术将极大地改变消费者、工业和商业运作方式。</li>    <li>中国经济奇迹源于精心设计的产业政策和引进技术，这一模式也被其他亚洲经济体采用。</li>    <li>从选择性产业政策范式向功能性政策范式的转变至关重要且紧迫，因为颠覆性技术的潜力尚不确定。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>groundbreaking (adj.) - 里程碑式的，开创性的。    <p>原文例句：China should make ‘groundbreaking changes’ to its industrial policymaking amid its push to become a global technological and economic leader. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词由ground（地面）和breaking（打破）构成，表示“突破性的，开创性的”。在这个例句中，它描述了中国在努力成为全球科技和经济领导者的过程中，需要对产业政策制定进行根本性的改变。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>disruptive (adj.) - 破坏性的，颠覆性的。    <p>原文例句：From artificial intelligence (AI) to quantum computing, and from room-temperature superconductivity to controllable nuclear fusion, disruptive technologies are set to significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词由disrupt（破坏，扰乱）和-ive（形容词后缀）构成，表示“破坏性的，颠覆性的”。在这个例句中，它描述了一系列技术，包括人工智能、量子计算等，这些技术将会对消费者、工业和商业运作方式产生重大影响。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>economic miracle - 经济奇迹。    <p>原文例句：China’s economic miracle over the past four decades has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由economic（经济的）和miracle（奇迹）构成，表示“经济奇迹”。在这个例句中，它描述了中国在过去四十年里取得的经济成就，这一成就基于精心设计的产业政策和引进技术，实现了规模经济和降低了生产成本。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China’s economic miracle over the past four decades has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs. - 中国在过去四十年里的经济奇迹是基于精心设计的产业政策和引进的技术，实现了规模经济和降低了生产成本。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是China’s economic miracle has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies，其中主语是China’s economic miracle，谓语是has been based on，宾语是carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies。over the past four decades是一个介词短语作时间状语，修饰主句，表示在过去的四十年里。to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs是一个不定式短语作目的状语，修饰主句，表示实现规模经济和降低生产成本的目的。这个句子的意思是说，中国在过去四十年里的经济奇迹是基于精心设计的产业政策和引进的技术，实现了规模经济和降低了生产成本。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列连词 - 表示并列关系。    <p>原文例句：From artificial intelligence (AI) to quantum computing, and from room-temperature superconductivity to controllable nuclear fusion, disruptive technologies are set to significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate. </p>    <p>语法讲解：并列连词是用来连接两个或多个词、词组或句子，表示并列关系。常见的并列连词有and、or、but等。在这个例句中，并列连词and连接了四个并列成分，分别是from artificial intelligence (AI) to quantum computing，from room-temperature superconductivity to controllable nuclear fusion，disruptive technologies，和the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate。这个句子的意思是说，从人工智能到量子计算，从室温超导到可控核聚变，颠覆性技术将极大地改变消费者、工业和商业运作方式。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式 - 表示动作、状态或过程。    <p>原文例句：China needs to make groundbreaking changes to its industrial policymaking to become a global technological and economic leader. </p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式是指动词的非限定形式，可以表示动作、状态或过程。不定式有两种形式，一种是带to的不定式，另一种是不带to的不定式。在这个例句中，不定式make groundbreaking changes to its industrial policymaking是一个带to的不定式，作目的状语，表示实现成为全球科技和经济领导者的目的。这个句子的意思是说，中国需要对产业政策制定进行颠覆性改变，以成为全球科技和经济领袖。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Disruptive technologies, including artificial intelligence and quantum computing, will significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate</li>
<li>China should make ‘groundbreaking changes’ to its industrial policymaking amid its push to become a global technological and economic leader, analysts said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/df3b6f4b-498c-4140-80f2-8b42e0ebe9ed_9f02ea50.jpg" /><figcaption>China’s HL-2M reactor in Sichuan could provide a long-term solution to the world’s energy needs by generating power without producing nuclear waste. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China needs to adjust its industrial policymaking to brace for possible revolutionary changes to its economy by disruptive technologies, analysts said.</p><p>From artificial intelligence (AI) to quantum computing, and from room-temperature superconductivity to controllable nuclear fusion, disruptive technologies are set to significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate.</p><p>China’s economic miracle over the past four decades has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs.</p><p>This model has been adopted by other economies in East Asia during their development in the second half of 20th century.</p><blockquote>How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgentHuang Shaoqing</blockquote><p>“As frontier technologies, no one knows what technology truly has promising prospects, which could ultimately be screened out by the market through competition,” Huang Shaoqing, a professor of economics at the Antai College of Economics and Management at Shanghai Jiao Tong University, said in a report.</p><p>“Therefore, in the early development stage of disruptive technologies, economies of scale are not important and even dangerous.”</p><p>Huang said in the report published by the English-language Asian Review of Political Economy in October 2022 that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”.</p><p>“How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgent,” he wrote in the report, which had earlier been published in Mandarin by the Journal of Comparative Studies in February 2022.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>The urgency has become more prominent for Beijing, which views innovation and technological advancement as key to countering the heightened containment efforts by the United States, and also crucial for its ambition to become an economic and tech superpower by the middle of the century.</p><p>Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, said China needs to plan areas where matured technologies can be applied, including sectors influenced by US export bans, and that involve more markets.</p><p>“China needs to make groundbreaking changes to its industrial policymaking, otherwise, it will never be a global technological and economic leader,” Peng said.</p><p>“Decision makers need to listen more to private companies, give them enough funding for industrial research, and place them at the front role of disruptive industrial exploration.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies" title="">‘More, better’: premier urges China to focus on application of core technologies</a></h3><p>But as it is impossible to determine in advance which technology would prevail, a country can gain an advantage only if it develops enough small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) to offer sufficient diversified technological routes, Huang added.</p><p>“Only by promoting innovation and entrepreneurship, relaxing market access, improving the business environment, and allowing as many as SMEs as possible to grow rapidly can these SMEs play an important role in economic development driven by innovation,” he said.</p><p>In 2016 when mapping out a national scientific and technology plan, Beijing vowed to improve tracking revolutionary industrial development to be capable of prejudging “the turning point” of possible replacements for traditional industries.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>At the time it added that it would make a timely plan for research into disruptive technologies, such as AI, quantum information, genome editing, unmanned driving, hydrogen power and nanotechnology.</p><p>Li Yangwei, a technical consultant in the computing sector in Shenzhen, said disruptive technologies may lead to bigger tech and economic gaps among regions within China, but when there are more participants, the cost of any potential failures can be lowered.</p><p>He also said small market players can offer advice to the central government about industrial policies, but amid hefty external pressure and geopolitical complications, Beijing may still allocate resources to big companies or state-owned enterprises.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3243101/chinas-ai-aspirations-will-fuel-economy-drive-investment-trillions-dollars-mckinsey" title="">China’s AI gains will fuel economy as windfall swells into trillions: McKinsey</a></h3><p>“It also requires technocrats to be socially, economically and politically insightful, as well as having strong communication skills and being given central decision-making power,” Li said.</p><p>China’s basic research accounted for more than 6 per cent of its total research and development (R&amp;D) expenditure in the last four years, lower than the 16 to 18 per cent in the US and 22 per cent in France over the last 10 years.</p><p>Basic research from enterprises only accounted for 0.78 per cent of China’s overall R&amp;D expenditure, behind over 6 per cent in developed countries, according to a report in February by the Science and Technology Daily, a newspaper backed by the Ministry of Science and Technology.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s ‘king of software’, Wang Wenjing, steps down as president of enterprise management systems firm Yonyou amid mounting losses</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247446/chinas-king-software-wang-wenjing-steps-down-president-enterprise-management-systems-firm-yonyou</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese tech billionaire Wang Wenjing, the founder of enterprise management systems provider Yonyou Network Technology, has stepped down as president to focus on his roles as chairman and chief executive. The move comes amid the company's struggles with weak sales and mounting losses, as well as its efforts to turnaround its business after two years of stagnant revenue growth. Veteran Yonyou executive Chen Qiangbin takes over as president, with a focus on operations and management.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tech billionaire Wang Wenjing steps down as president of Yonyou Network Technology.</li>    <li>Theme: Yonyou's efforts to revive its business amidst weak sales and mounting losses.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of restructuring and strategic changes in driving business turnaround.</li>    <li>Main information: Wang's resignation, Chen's appointment, Yonyou's recent revenue growth and widening losses, the company's shift to a service fee model, and the impact of China's digitalisation drive.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国科技亿万富翁，用友网络科技的创始人王文京辞去总裁职务，专注于董事长和首席执行官的角色。此举适逢该公司销售疲软、亏损加剧以及努力扭转其两年来停滞不前的收入增长的情况。资深用友高管陈强斌接任总裁职务，重点关注运营和管理。  <ul>    <li>摘要：科技亿万富翁王文京辞去用友网络科技总裁职务。</li>    <li>主题：用友努力复苏其在销售疲软和亏损加剧中的业务。</li>    <li>观点：重组和战略变革在推动企业扭亏为盈中的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：王文京的辞职，陈强斌的任命，用友最近的收入增长和亏损扩大，公司转向服务费模式，以及中国数字化浪潮的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sluggish (adj.) - /ˈslʌɡɪʃ/ 迟缓的，缓慢的。    <p>原文例句：Yonyou Network Technology founder Wang Wenjing retains his roles as chairman and chief executive at the Beijing-based enterprise management systems company. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由sluggard（懒汉）和-ish（构成形容词后缀）组成，表示“懒惰的，迟缓的，缓慢的”。在这个例句中，它指的是Yonyou Network Technology的销售情况不佳，业绩不振。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>restructure (v.) - /ˈriːˌstrʌktʃər/ 重组，改组。    <p>原文例句：Yonyou initiated one of its largest organizational changes last year, when it set up 23 industry client and solution business units to cover a range of industries including manufacturing, consumer products, energy, logistics and the public sector. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由re-（重新）和structure（结构）组成，表示“重新组合，改组，重组”。在这个例句中，它指的是用友去年进行的组织调整，旨在提高企业的运营效率和业绩。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>turn around - 扭转，改变。    <P>原文例句：Yonyou's effort to turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由turn（转，扭转）和around（周围，反面）组成，表示“扭转，改变”。在这个例句中，它表示用友努力扭转其过去两年收入停滞不前的局面。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>widening losses - 亏损扩大。    <P>原文例句：Yonyou saw its losses widen 91 per cent year on year to 1 billion yuan.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由widen（扩大）和losses（损失）组成，表示“亏损扩大”。在这个例句中，它表示用友的亏损从去年同期10亿元人民币扩大到100亿元人民币。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Yonyou currently has more than 230 branch offices worldwide – including in the mainland, Hong Kong, Macau, Australia, New Zealand and a number of countries in Southeast Asia. - 用友目前在全球拥有 230 多个分支机构——包括中国大陆、香港、澳门、澳大利亚、新西兰和东南亚多个国家。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是Yonyou currently has more than 230 branch offices worldwide，其中主语是Yonyou，谓语是has，宾语是more than 230 branch offices worldwide。including in the mainland, Hong Kong, Macau, Australia, New Zealand and a number of countries in Southeast Asia是一个介词短语作状语，表示用友在全球的分支机构包括中国大陆、香港、澳门、澳大利亚、新西兰和东南亚多个国家。这个句子的意思是说，用友目前在全球拥有230多个分支机构，包括在中国大陆、香港、澳门、澳大利亚、新西兰和东南亚多个国家。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Yonyou initiated one of its largest organizational changes last year, when it set up 23 industry client and solution business units to cover a range of industries including manufacturing, consumer products, energy, logistics and the public sector.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态正在进行中。在这个例句中，它表示用友去年进行了一次重大的组织调整，目的是提高企业的运营效率和业绩。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去的某个时间之前就已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Wang, who was 24 when he founded Yonyou after leaving a job in government, initially provided accounting software to businesses and quickly became a dominant player in that market. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的第三种形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去的某个时间之前就已经完成。在这个例句中，它表示王文京24岁时创办用友之前在政府工作，他最初为企业提供会计软件，并迅速成为该市场的领导者。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Tech billionaire Wang, 60, will remain in his roles as Yonyou chairman and chief executive, overseeing corporate strategy and product development</li>
<li>The senior management shuffle at Yonyou reflects the firm’s effort to turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/6c7f31d3-f7f3-4577-a795-008077b768f9_4bcd59c9.jpg" /><figcaption>Yonyou Network Technology founder Wang Wenjing retains his roles as chairman and chief executive at the Beijing-based enterprise management systems company. Photo: Weibo</figcaption></figure><p>Tech billionaire <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/347601/ufsoft-creates-fast-fortune-and-billion-dollar-goal" target="_self" title="">Wang Wenjing</a>, who was once known as China’s “king of software”, has stepped down as president of enterprise management systems provider Yonyou Network Technology, as the company he founded in 1988 continues to struggle with sluggish sales and mounting losses amid the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3241783/chinas-2023-gdp-forecasts-twisted-and-turned-prognosticators-puzzled-over-countrys-future" target="_self" title="">weak post-pandemic economic recovery</a>.</p><p>Wang had tendered his resignation with immediate effect, according to Yonyou’s filing with the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai-stock-index" target="_self" title="">Shanghai Stock Exchange</a> on Wednesday. “The company’s board expresses its sincere gratitude to Wang for his contribution,” the Beijing-based firm said.</p><p>The 60-year-old Wang – with a net worth of US$3.1 billion as of January 5, according to Forbes – will remain in his roles as Yonyou chairman and chief executive, overseeing corporate strategy and product development, according to a separate statement released by the firm.</p><p>Veteran Yonyou executive Chen Qiangbin, 48, takes over as company president, with a focus on operations and management, according to the company. After joining Yonyou in 2000, Chen was involved in software development, sales and then served as general manager at the firm’s branch offices in Beijing, northern Hebei province and southwestern Sichuan province.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/9f56e087-6a3a-4e69-b9a6-4ca4b123727b_b201e52d.jpg" title="Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Yonyou, ranked by research firm Gartner as one of the world’s top 10 enterprise resource planning (ERP) software providers, saw its shares close down 2.48 per cent to 16.49 yuan (US$2.32) on Friday.</p><p>ERP refers to software designed to automate business processes, as well as provide insights and internal controls, often in real time. It manages operations including accounting and finance, procurement, supply chain, manufacturing, human resources and collaboration.</p><p>In recent years, Yonyou changed its focus from selling licences of its ERP and other enterprise management software to collecting service fees by providing these systems via a software-as-a-service model called Yonyou BIP. By 2022, cloud-based services accounted for nearly 70 per cent of the firm’s revenue.</p><p>Still, the senior management shuffle at Yonyou reflects the company’s effort to try and turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth and widening losses, as fresh opportunities beckon from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" target="_self" title="">Beijing’s digitalisation drive</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" title="">China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms</a></h3><p>Yonyou initiated one of its largest organisational changes last year, when it set up 23 industry client and solution business units to cover a range of industries including manufacturing, consumer products, energy, logistics and the public sector. The move was expected to make its operations more focused on vertical industries, instead of regional markets.</p><p>Even as China’s weak macroeconomic environment has driven a round of poor earnings from cybersecurity and finance software stocks, Yonyou’s third-quarter results last year – with “positive revenue growth across all segments” – “indicate that ERP demand has been resilient”, according to a November research note by Jefferies.</p><p>While it reported 2 per cent revenue growth in the first three quarters of last year, Yonyou saw its losses widen 91 per cent year on year to 1 billion yuan.</p><p>Wang, who was 24 when he founded Yonyou <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/242891/software-rewards-u-turn-decision" target="_self" title="">after leaving a job in government</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/496999/software-firm-hopes-name-will-score-goal" target="_self" title="">initially provided accounting software</a> to businesses and quickly became a dominant player in that market. When Yonyou – first known as Ufsoft and then Ufida – expanded into ERP and other enterprise management systems, it surpassed the performance of major foreign ERP players like Oracle and SAP in the Chinese market.</p><p>Yonyou currently has more than 230 branch offices worldwide – including in the mainland, Hong Kong, Macau, Australia, New Zealand and a number of countries in Southeast Asia.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>McDonald’s China and Cainiao partner on RFID chips to improve supply chain efficiencies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247447/mcdonalds-china-and-cainiao-partner-rfid-chips-improve-supply-chain-efficiencies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>麦当劳中国与菜鸟合作，利用射频识别技术提升供应链效率。</li>    <li>双方合作旨在减少库存盘点时间，提高库存数据的准确性，提升供应链管理的整体效率。</li>    <li>菜鸟正在准备在香港进行首次公开募股，麦当劳中国与菜鸟的合作也为菜鸟的首次公开募股做好了铺垫。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>麦当劳中国与菜鸟合作，利用射频识别技术提升供应链效率。</li>    <li>双方合作旨在减少库存盘点时间，提高库存数据的准确性，提升供应链管理的整体效率。</li>    <li>菜鸟正在准备在香港进行首次公开募股，麦当劳中国与菜鸟的合作也为菜鸟的首次公开募股做好了铺垫。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>RFID 射频识别。    <p>原文例句：Under a deal signed on Thursday, McDonald’s China will deploy Cainiao’s RFID technology in its supply chain with built-in tags on food packages, allowing the company to track products from factories to restaurants, according to a statement by the Hangzhou-based logistics firm.</p>    <p>例句讲解：RFID 射频识别技术是一种通过射频信号进行识别的技术，它有这広い用途，例如，在供应链管理、库存管理和资产管理等领域。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stocktaking 盘点，清点。    <p>原文例句：A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants</p>    <p>例句讲解：Stocktaking 盘点是指对库存进行清点，以核实库存的准确性。Stocktaking 盘点可以帮助企业了解库存的实际情况，并做出相应的调整。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>McDonald’s China has a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year. - 麦当劳中国拥有超过 5,500 家餐厅和超过 200,000 名员工，年均服务超过 10 亿客户。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是McDonald's China，谓语是has，宾语是a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year。这个句子的意思是，麦当劳中国拥有超过5500家餐厅和超过20万名员工，年均服务超过10亿顾客。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式 - 表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong.</p>    <p>语法讲解：动词不定式是由to加动词原形构成，表示动作或状态。它在句中可以作主语、宾语、表语、定语或状语。在这个例句中，动词不定式是prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong，它作状语，表示菜鸟准备在香港首次公开募股。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants</li>
<li>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/d5e1a0a3-a5e3-492f-b311-a67d3c5f12ec_d1186b0d.jpg" /><figcaption>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong. Photo: Reuters </figcaption></figure><p>McDonald’s China unit has partnered with Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics business, to improve supply chain efficiency using radio frequency identification (RFID) chips and other technologies.</p><p>Under a deal signed on Thursday, McDonald’s China will deploy Cainiao’s RFID technology in its supply chain with built-in tags on food packages, allowing the company to track products from factories to restaurants, according to a statement by the Hangzhou-based logistics firm.</p><p>A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants while improving the accuracy of inventory data by 30 per cent, according to the statement.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240676/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-will-enhance-its-overseas-presence-proposed-buyout-local-rival-best" title="">Alibaba logistics spin-off Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout</a></h3><p>RFID is a third-generation identification technology, after bar codes and QR codes, and has been widely adopted in supply chain tracking. With a built-in microchip, data is transmitted through radio frequency signals.</p><p>Apart from deploying RFID technology to improve efficiency in inventory and logistics, McDonald’s and Cainiao will also explore digitisation and automation technologies in the supply chain, Cainiao said.</p><p>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3235860/alibabas-cainiao-files-us1-billion-ipo-helping-hong-kong-land-worlds-second-biggest-listing-2023" target="_self" title="">an initial public offering (IPO) in Hong Kong</a> after submitting its A1 filing to the city’s stock exchange last September.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month. The listing is part of a group-wide restructuring of Alibaba as the e-commerce titan seeks to free up decision- making amid increased competition across its businesses. Alibaba also owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Established in 2013, Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s huge e-commerce empire, handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023. Alibaba announced it would spin Cainiao off in the restructuring announced in March.</p><p>Cainiao moved into the RFID field with the launch of its own tags in 2021, which it said could achieve 99.9 per cent recognition accuracy. The company announced in April last year that it had produced and sold over 100 million RFID tags in just two years.</p><p>McDonald’s China has a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year. It has also been stepping up efforts to digitise its operations in the country, which is the fast-food giant’s second-largest market globally.</p><p>Last month, McDonald’s China said it would work with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> to build a native app based on the next iteration of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3136017/will-huaweis-harmony-operating-system-end-global-duopoly-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS</a>, the Chinese telecommunications equipment and smartphone giant’s self-developed mobile platform.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
