<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Apple supplier Foxconn sees revenue decline in first quarter of 2024 amid weak global consumer electronics demand, sluggish iPhone sales</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Foxconn, the world's largest iPhone assembler, anticipates a decline in revenue during the initial quarter of 2024, citing weak consumer electronics demand globally. This forecast aligns with the observed decrease in sales witnessed over the past three months.<br>  <ul>    <li>Quarterly revenue drop estimation withheld.</li>    <li>First-quarter comparison with high base in 2023.</li>    <li>Typically an off-peak season for the industry.</li>    <li>Dim outlook in line with Apple investors' concerns.</li>    <li>iPhone 15 and 16 sales seen as lackluster.</li>    <li>Apple's share price affected by antitrust case prospects.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  富士康，全球最大的 iPhone 组装商，预计 2024 年第一季度收入将下降，原因是全球消费电子需求疲软。这一预测与过去三个月观察到的销售下降的情况一致。<br>  <ul>    <li>季度收入下降估计被扣留。</li>    <li>第一季度与 2023 年的高基数进行比较。</li>    <li>通常是行业的淡季。</li>    <li>黯淡的前景与苹果投资者的担忧一致。</li>    <li>iPhone 15 和 16 的销售额被视为乏善可陈。</li>    <li>苹果的股价受到反垄断案前景的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>antitrust (n.) - /ˈæntɪtrʌst/ 反托拉斯（法）、反垄断法、反不正当竞争法。    <p>原文例句：Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company. </p>    <p>例句讲解：本单词由anti-（反对）和trust（信托）构成，表示“反对垄断法，反托拉斯法”。在例句中，它指的是美国司法部准备对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。</p></li>    <li>bumpy (adj.) - /'bʌmpi/ 颠簸的，崎岖的。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s lofty status as world’s most valuable stock at risk from bumpy 2024 start </p>    <p>例句讲解：本单词由bump（碰撞，撞击）构成，表示“颠簸的，崎岖的，不平坦的”。在例句中，它指的是苹果公司在2024年初面临的颠簸开局。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Firefox is also very competitive in terms of performance and speed. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示Firefox在性能和速度方面也很有竞争力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Taiwan-based Foxconn, formally known as Hon Hai Precision Industry, did not provide an estimate on the quarterly revenue drop, but said the first three months will be compared to a high base in the same period last year, when its factories in mainland China resumed normal operations after disruptive pandemic controls were relaxed by the government, - 总部位于台湾的富士康，正式名称为鸿海精密工业，并未提供季度收入下降的估计，但表示前三个月将与去年同期的较高基数进行比较，当时其在中国大陆的工厂在政府放松了中断的疫情管制后恢复了正常运营，<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Foxconn did not provide an estimate on the quarterly revenue drop，表示富士康未提供对季度收入下降的估计。其中主语是Foxconn，谓语是did not provide，宾语是an estimate on the quarterly revenue drop，修饰语是formally known as Hon Hai Precision Industry。but said the first three months will be compared to a high base in the same period last year, when its factories in mainland China resumed normal operations after disruptive pandemic controls were relaxed by the government是一个并列复句，其中第一个分句是said the first three months will be compared to a high base in the same period last year，表示前三个月将与去年同期的较高基数进行比较，谓语是will be compared，主语是the first three months；第二个分句是its factories in mainland China resumed normal operations after disruptive pandemic controls were relaxed by the government，表示其在中国大陆的工厂在政府放松了中断的疫情管制后恢复了正常运营，谓语是resumed，主语是its factories in mainland China。这个句子的意思是说，总部位于台湾的富士康，正式名称为鸿海精密工业，并未提供季度收入下降的估计，但表示前三个月将与去年同期的较高基数进行比较，当时其在中国大陆的工厂在政府放松了中断的疫情管制后恢复了正常运营。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Foxconn did not provide an estimate of the quarterly drop, but said the year’s first three months represent an off-peak season for the industry</li>
<li>The world’s largest electronics contract manufacturer reported total 2023 revenue was down 7 per cent year on year to US$198.9 billion</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/e222829d-56dc-48eb-b8cb-9a2ea658a625_cee121ea.jpg" /><figcaption>Foxconn Technology Group’s dim first-quarter outlook reflects concerns raised by investors of major client Apple about sluggish iPhone sales. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foxconn?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Foxconn Technology Group</a>, the world’s biggest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> assembler, expects revenue to decline in the first quarter of 2024 amid weak global consumer electronics demand, extending a decrease in sales in the past three months.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>-based Foxconn, formally known as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hon-hai-precision-industry?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Hon Hai Precision Industry</a>, did not provide an estimate on the quarterly revenue drop, but said the first three months will be compared to a high base in the same period last year, when its factories in mainland China resumed normal operations after disruptive pandemic controls were relaxed by the government, according to the company’s statement on Friday.</p><p>The world’s largest electronics contract manufacturer also indicated that the year’s first quarter is typically an off-peak season for the industry.</p><p>Revenue for the company’s December quarter fell 5.4 per cent year on year to NT$1.85 trillion (US$60 billion), but was up by 20 per cent from the previous quarter. Total 2023 revenue was US$198.9 billion, down 7 per cent from 2022.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen" class="image-inline caption" height="1243" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/09a87505-ea2a-40a2-91f3-d3980a90b343_8f795096.jpg" title="People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen" width="2000" /><figcaption>People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen</figcaption></figure></div><p>Foxconn on Friday blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, even though the company went through a bumpy period a year ago when its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3225783/worlds-largest-iphone-factory-zhengzhou-ramps-hiring-foxconn-chairman-reassures-china-supply-chain" target="_self" title="">biggest iPhone plant in Zhengzhou</a>, capital of central Henan province, was rocked by an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3197909/coronavirus-iphone-factory-exodus-shows-how-chinas-covid-narrative-still-strikes-fear-public?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">exodus of tens of thousands of employees</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3200747/violence-erupts-foxconn-zhengzhou-plant-workers-protest-over-benefits-and-covid-19-controls-worlds?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">violent workers’ protests</a> amid a Covid-19 outbreak that began in late October.</p><p>The company’s dim first-quarter outlook reflects concerns raised by investors of major client Apple about sluggish iPhone sales, which prompted the US tech giant to be <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">hit by two ratings downgrades</a> this week.</p><p>“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">said in a client note</a>, which pointed to weakness in China and subdued demand in developed markets.</p><p>Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247501/apples-reign-worlds-most-valuable-stock-market-value-jeopardy-bumpy-2024-start" title="">Apple’s lofty status as world’s most valuable stock at risk from bumpy 2024 start</a></h3><p>Apple, which has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022, has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.</p><p>The company’s iPhones also face intense competition on the mainland against a resurgent <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, which is seeing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" target="_self" title="">strong demand for its new 5G handsets</a> in the world’s largest smartphone market.</p><p>While Apple <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" target="_self" title="">continues to lead the global premium smartphone market</a>, where handsets are priced from US$600, Huawei has gained ground in this segment on the back of its new Mate 60 series.</p><p>Foxconn is also <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234562/foxconn-offers-higher-hourly-rates-workers-shenzhen-its-huawei-production-unit-its-iphone-operation" target="_self" title="">offering higher rates for workers that make Huawei’s handsets</a> in southern tech hub <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shenzhen" target="_self" title="">Shenzhen</a> than those that make iPhones, according to a South China Morning Post report last September.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions" title="">Foxconn ramps up investment in giant Apple plant in India</a></h3><p>Still, Foxconn has stepped up efforts to diversify its manufacturing supply chain for Apple and other clients amid the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246222/chinas-middle-class-does-not-dare-spend-until-post-covid-economy-shows-clear-signs-recovery" target="_self" title="">weak post-pandemic economic recovery</a> in mainland China and rising geopolitical tensions between Beijing and Washington.</p><p>Foxconn won approval to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions" target="_self" title="">invest at least US$1 billion more in a plant</a> it is building in India that will make Apple products, on top of the US$1.6 billion it earlier pledged, according to a report by Bloomberg last month.</p><p>On the mainland, Foxconn continues to invest in central Henan province, where it employs 200,000 workers in the firm’s Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p><p>The Taiwanese firm, which was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239113/china-says-investigation-apple-supplier-foxconns-operations-mainland-normal-law-enforcement" target="_self" title="">put under investigation in October by mainland regulators</a>, this year plans to start building new factories for smartphones and other electronics products in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of 520 major construction projects for 2024 released this week by the province’s Development and Reform Commission.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s reign as world’s most valuable stock by market value in jeopardy from bumpy 2024 start</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247501/apples-reign-worlds-most-valuable-stock-market-value-jeopardy-bumpy-2024-start</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  苹果公司股价周五下跌0.4%，此前有报道称美国司法部已接近对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。据彭博社汇编的数据，这家科技巨头今年迄今市值已蒸发约1770亿美元。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple股价受反垄断诉讼消息影响下跌，市场地位面临挑战。</li>    <li>Theme: 苹果公司股价下跌，原因是美国司法部可能提起反垄断诉讼，公司面临来自不同方面的压力，其在科技界的地位也受到挑战。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 作者认为反垄断诉讼可能对苹果公司造成负面影响，投资者正在抛售苹果股票，转向表现更佳的科技公司。</li>    <li>Main information: 苹果公司股价连续五日下跌，反垄断诉讼将使公司面临更多问题，包括iPhone销量放缓和Apple Watch专利问题，分析师认为此举可能攻击苹果公司紧密集成其设备和服务的商业模式。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果公司股价周五下跌了0.4%，此前有报道称美国司法部接近对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。根据彭博社汇编的数据，这家科技巨头今年的市值已经蒸发了约1770亿美元。  <ul>    <li>摘要：反垄断诉讼消息导致苹果股价下跌，公司面临市场地位挑战。</li>    <li>主题：苹果股价下跌的原因是美国司法部可能提起反垄断诉讼，公司受到来自各方面的压力，科技界的地位也受到挑战。</li>    <li>观点：作者认为反垄断诉讼对苹果公司可能会产生负面影响，投资者正在抛售苹果股票，转向表现更佳的科技公司。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果股价连续五日下跌，分析师认为反垄断诉讼将使苹果公司面临更多问题，包括iPhone销量放缓和Apple Watch专利问题。他们认为此举可能攻击苹果公司紧密集成其设备和服务的商业模式。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>erase (v.) - /ɪˈreɪs/ 抹去，擦除。    <p>原文例句：The tech giant has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，由e-（出）和rase（抹除）组成，意为“抹去，擦除”。在这个例句中，它描述了苹果公司今年迄今为止市值已蒸发约1770亿美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>notch (v.) - /nɒtʃ/ 刻痕，缺口。    <p>原文例句：The decline notched the fifth consecutive negative day for Apple, its longest losing streak since October. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle English，指“在某物上留下缺口或刻痕”。在这个例句中，它描述了苹果股价连续五日下跌，使其录得自10月以来最长的连续下跌纪录。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>close to - 接近，靠近。    <P>原文例句：The US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由close（关闭，接近）和to（到，向）构成的，表示“接近，靠近”。在这个例句中，它表示美国司法部接近对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The decline notched the fifth consecutive negative day for Apple, its longest losing streak since October.- 这一下跌记录了苹果连续第五个负面交易日，是自 10 月以来最长的亏损连败。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是The decline，谓语是notched，宾语是the fifth consecutive negative day for Apple。its longest losing streak since October是一个形容词性从句，修饰The decline，表示苹果自 10 月以来最长的亏损连败。这个句子的意思是说，这次下跌记录了苹果连续第五个负面交易日，也是自 10 月以来最长的亏损连败。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 过去发生的动作或状态在另一个过去动作或状态发生之前已经完成。    <p>原文例句：That has shrunk its lead over fellow technology juggernaut Microsoft Corp – whose shares have seen a less pronounced decline to begin the year – to less than US$100 billion. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种表示过去动作或状态在另一个过去动作或状态发生之前已经完成的时态，结构是：had + been + 过去分词。在这个例句中，it作为主语，had和been都是助动词，shrunk是过去分词，has seen是现在完成时的形式。这个句子的意思是说，这一事件使其领先地位低于竞争对手科技巨头微软公司，后者今年初的股价跌幅较小，目前两者之间的差距不足1000亿美元。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人对客观事实的假设或愿望。    <p>原文例句：“Everybody’s selling their winners and buying losers,” said Brian Mulberry, client portfolio manager at Zacks Investment Management. “There’s a big rebalance going on.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示说话人对客观事实的假设或愿望。结构是：助动词（would、should、could等）+ 主语 + 动词。在这个例句中，助动词是would，主语是everybody，动词是selling和buying。这个句子的意思是说，布莱恩·穆尔贝里说，“每个人都在抛售赢家，购买输家，”“正在进行一场大规模的再平衡。”</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Shares of Apple fell 0.4 per cent on Friday after a report that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company</li>
<li>The tech giant has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/0bab1060-0f68-4b59-b625-ee8f62b7b778_cec54c59.jpg" /><figcaption>People walk past an Apple Store in the Glendale Galleria shopping mall in California on December 26, 2023. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> just had its worst start to the year by one measure, as investors react to mounting pressures on the company, putting its long-standing status as the world’s most valuable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/stocks" target="_self" title="">stock</a> by market value in jeopardy.</p><p>Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.</p><p>The decline notched the fifth consecutive negative day for Apple, its longest losing streak since October.</p><p>The potential antitrust case against Apple “would add to the plethora of problems it faces, from slowing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> sales to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246452/apple-resumes-sale-watches-after-appeals-court-lifts-us-ban" target="_self" title="">Apple Watch patent issues</a>”, Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Anurag Rana wrote in a note. “The suit could attack Apple’s business model of tightly integrating its devices and services.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/bdba7b4d-2eef-4fae-a196-1d3cd943fe89_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Cupertino, California-based company has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022, but has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.</p><p>While the stock has suffered bigger percentage declines in the first week of January, the losses are the biggest market value destruction at the start of any year on record.</p><p>The downturn began earlier in the week after the technology giant was hit by two <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" target="_self" title="">ratings downgrades</a>, with analysts flagging a weak macro environment in China pressuring demand for iPhones.</p><p>That has shrunk its lead over fellow technology juggernaut <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft Corp</a> – whose shares have seen a less pronounced decline to begin the year – to less than US$100 billion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247211/apple-leads-us383-billion-tech-rout-reversal-groups-2023-rally" title="">Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</a></h3><p>“Investors realise how rare it is to have two people go negative,” said Gene Munster, managing partner of Deepwater Asset Management. “I’ve been covering this company for a long time and I’ve never seen two downgrades before an earnings report.”</p><p>Apple is also likely under pressure as investors rotate their portfolios at the start of the year.</p><p>“Everybody’s selling their winners and buying losers,” said Brian Mulberry, client portfolio manager at Zacks Investment Management. “There’s a big rebalance going on.”</p><p>The losses have pushed Apple’s market value down to about US$2.8 trillion, nearing Microsoft’s US$2.7 trillion. Shares of Microsoft fell less than 0.1 per cent Friday to close at about US$368.</p><p>The Windows software maker has benefited from the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> trade that has mesmerised Wall Street over the past year. The company is <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content" target="_self" title="">OpenAI</a>’s largest shareholder and has invested about US$13 billion into the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> parent.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech trade group representing TikTok, Snapchat and Meta sues Ohio over state’s new law limiting children’s use of social media apps</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247497/tech-trade-group-representing-tiktok-snapchat-and-meta-sues-ohio-over-states-new-law-limiting</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In Ohio, a new state law requires children under 16 to obtain parental consent before signing up for social media and video gaming apps. The NetChoice trade group, representing tech giants like TikTok and Facebook, has filed a lawsuit challenging the law, arguing that it violates freedom of speech and is overly broad and vague. The law was intended to protect children's mental health and shield them from addictive social media platforms.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Ohio's law mandates parental consent for children's social media use, sparking a legal challenge over free speech concerns.</li>    <li>Theme: The conflict between protecting children's well-being and preserving free speech in the digital age.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The NetChoice trade group's perspective on the law's constitutionality and its potential impact on families and tech companies.</li>    <li>Main information: Details of the law, including the age restriction, parental consent requirement, and privacy guidelines for social media companies. Mention of similar lawsuits won by the trade group in other states.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  俄亥俄州一项新的州法律要求 16 岁以下的儿童在注册社交媒体和视频游戏应用程序之前获得父母的同意。代表 TikTok 和 Facebook 等科技巨头的 NetChoice 贸易集团对这项法律提出质疑，认为它侵犯了言论自由，过于广泛且模糊。该法律旨在保护儿童的心理健康，并保护他们免受会上瘾的社交媒体平台的侵害。  <ul>    <li>摘要：俄亥俄州法律要求儿童使用社交媒体必须征得父母同意，引发了对言论自由问题的法律质疑。</li>    <li>主题：在数字时代保护儿童福祉与维护言论自由之间的冲突。</li>    <li>观点：NetChoice 贸易集团对该法律的合宪性及其对家庭和科技公司潜在影响的看法。</li>    <li>主要信息：该法律的详细信息，包括年龄限制、父母同意要求以及社交媒体公司的隐私准则。还提到了该贸易集团在其他州赢得的类似诉讼。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>pending (adj.) - /ˈpendɪŋ/ 等待中的，悬而未决的。    <p>原文例句：A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由pend（挂起）构成的，表示“尚未解决的，等待决定的”。在这个例句中，它指的是俄亥俄州的一项正在等待中的法律，该法律要求儿童在使用社交媒体应用程序之前获得父母的同意。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>vague (adj.) - /veɪg/ 模糊的，含糊的。    <p>原文例句：The litigation argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps – unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由vagus（流浪的）构成的，表示“不确定的，不明确的”。在这个例句中，它指的是俄亥俄州的一项法律，该法律被认为过于宽泛和模糊，因为它缺乏明确的标准来确定哪些内容是适当的，哪些是不适当的。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unconstitutionally impedes - 违反宪法地阻碍。    <P>原文例句：The litigation argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps – unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由unconstitutionally（违宪地）和impede（阻碍）构成的，表示“违反宪法地阻碍”。在这个例句中，它指的是俄亥俄州的一项法律，该法律被认为违反宪法地阻碍了言论自由。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The NetChoice trade group filed its lawsuit against Republican Attorney General Dave Yost in US District Court for the Southern district of Ohio. - NetChoice 贸易集团在美国俄亥俄州南区地方法院对共和党总检察长戴夫·约斯特提起诉讼。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是The NetChoice trade group，谓语是filed its lawsuit，宾语是against Republican Attorney General Dave Yost in US District Court for the Southern district of Ohio。NetChoice trade group是一个专有名词，表示NetChoice贸易集团。filed its lawsuit是一个过去分词短语作谓语，表示NetChoice贸易集团提起了诉讼。against Republican Attorney General Dave Yost in US District Court for the Southern district of Ohio是一个介词短语作状语，表示NetChoice贸易集团在美国俄亥俄州南区地方法院对共和党总检察长戴夫·约斯特提起诉讼。这个句子的意思是说，NetChoice贸易集团在美国俄亥俄州南区地方法院对共和党总检察长戴夫·约斯特提起诉讼。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>一般过去时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这种时态用于描述过去发生的动作或状态，其结构为：主语 + 过去式动词。在这个例句中，过去式动词是been making，表示过去一直持续的动作，而过去式动词made则表示过去发生的单一动作。这个句子的意思是说，该公司已经在印度生产iPhone和其他产品很多年了，其中包括最新的iPhone 15。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The law forms part of a state budget bill that Ohio Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July and is set to take effect on January 15</li>
<li>The NetChoice trade group argues that Ohio’s law unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/0827334f-9aca-4109-b4e2-813fa20ac5b8_06ce695b.jpg" /><figcaption>Ohio’s new law requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps. Photo: TNS</figcaption></figure><p>A trade group representing major tech companies including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/snapchat" target="_self" title="">Snapchat</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/facebook" target="_self" title="">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/instagram" target="_self" title="">Instagram</a> operator <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226704/meta-takes-aim-twitter-launch-rival-app-threads" target="_self" title="">Meta Platforms</a> sued Ohio on Friday over the state’s pending law that requires children to get parental consent to use <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">apps</a>.</p><p>The law was part of an US$86.1 billion state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July. It is set to take effect on January 15.</p><p>The administration pushed the measure as a way to protect children’s mental health, with Republican Lieutenant Governor Jon Husted saying at the time that social media was “intentionally addictive” and harmful to kids.</p><p>The NetChoice trade group filed its lawsuit against Republican Attorney General Dave Yost in US District Court for the Southern district of Ohio. It seeks to block the law from taking effect.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP" class="image-inline caption" height="1410" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/8d380f8f-5e87-4f75-add2-ca49bea0915b_3ad8b242.jpg" title="A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP" width="2000" /><figcaption>A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The litigation argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> apps – unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p><p>The law also requires social media companies to provide parents with their privacy guidelines, so that families can know what content will be censored or moderated on their child’s profile.</p><p>“We at NetChoice believe families equipped with educational resources are capable of determining the best approach to online services and privacy protections for themselves,” Chris Marchese, director of the organisation’s litigation centre, said in a statement.</p><p>“With NetChoice v Yost, we will fight to ensure all Ohioans can embrace digital tools without their privacy, security and rights being thwarted.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247089/montana-appealing-ruling-blocked-state-barring-tiktok-use" title="">Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok use</a></h3><p>The group has won lawsuits against similar restrictions in California and Arkansas.</p><p>Husted, who leads Ohio’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> initiatives and championed the law, called Friday’s lawsuit “cowardly but not unexpected”.</p><p>“In filing this lawsuit, these companies are determined to go around parents to expose children to harmful content and addict them to their platforms,” Husted said in a statement.</p><p>He also alleged the tech companies know their algorithms are harming children “with catastrophic health and mental health outcomes”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China needs ‘groundbreaking’ policy changes to embrace disruptive technologies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247450/china-needs-groundbreaking-policy-changes-embrace-disruptive-technologies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>China needs to make significant changes to its industrial policymaking to prepare for the disruptive impact of emerging technologies like artificial intelligence and quantum computing.</li>    <li>The nation's economic success in the past resulted from careful industrial policies and imported technologies but this approach may hinder progress in the future.</li>    <li>China needs to shift from selective industrial policies to functional policies that support innovation and entrepreneurship and invest more in basic research.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国需要对产业政策进行重大调整，以应对人工智能、量子计算等颠覆性技术的冲击。</li>    <li>过去中国的经济成功源于谨慎的产业政策和引进技术，但这种做法可能会阻碍未来的进步。</li>    <li>中国需要从选择性产业政策转向支持创新和创业的功能性政策，并加大对基础研究的投入。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>functional (adj.) - /ˈfʌŋkʃənəl/ 实用性，功能性    <p>原文例句：Huang said in the report published by the English-language Asian Review of Political Economy in October 2022 that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由function（功能）和-al（形容词后缀）构成，表示“功能性的，实用的”。在这个例句中，它指的是选择性产业政策制度，即过去导致中国经济成功的政策制度，可能在未来导致失败并成为陷阱。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>diversified (adj.) - /daɪˈvɜːrsɪfaɪd/ 多元化的，多样化的    <p>原文例句：“Only by promoting innovation and entrepreneurship, relaxing market access, improving the business environment, and allowing as many as SMEs as possible to grow rapidly can these SMEs play an important role in economic development driven by innovation,” he said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由diversify（使多样化）和-ed（过去分词后缀）构成，表示“多样化的，多元化的”。在这个例句中，它指的是中小企业（SMEs），即只有通过促进创新和创业，放宽市场准入，改善营商环境，让尽可能多的中小企业快速发展，这些中小企业才能在创新驱动的经济发展中发挥重要作用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>prejudge (v.) - /priːˈdʒʌdʒ/ 预先判断，预先估量    <p>原文例句：In 2016 when mapping out a national scientific and technology plan, Beijing vowed to improve tracking revolutionary industrial development to be capable of prejudging “the turning point” of possible replacements for traditional industries.</p><p>例句讲解：这个单词由pre-（先于，之前）和judge（判断）构成，表示“预先判断，预先估量”。在这个例句中，它指的是北京在制定国家科技计划时，承诺改进对革命性产业发展的跟踪，以便能够预先判断传统产业可能被取代的“拐点”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>industrial policy - 产业政策    <p>原文例句：China should make ‘groundbreaking changes’ to its industrial policymaking amid its push to become a global technological and economic leader, analysts said</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由industrial（产业的）和policy（政策）构成，表示“产业政策”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国应该对其产业政策进行“突破性改变”，以实现成为全球技术和经济领导者的目标。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>economic development - 经济发展    <p>原文例句：“Only by promoting innovation and entrepreneurship, relaxing market access, improving the business environment, and allowing as many as SMEs as possible to grow rapidly can these SMEs play an important role in economic development driven by innovation,” he said.</p> <p>例句讲解：这个词组由economic（经济的）和development（发展）构成，表示“经济发展”。在这个例句中，它指的是只有通过促进创新和创业，放宽市场准入，改善营商环境，让尽可能多的中小企业快速发展，这些中小企业才能在创新驱动的经济发展中发挥重要作用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huang said in the report published by the English-language Asian Review of Political Economy in October 2022 that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”. - 黄在2022年10月刊登在英文《亚洲政治经济评论》上的一篇报告中表示，过去导致中国经济成功的选择性产业政策制度，“甚至可能导致失败并成为未来的陷阱”。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huang said that the selective industrial policy regime may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future，其中主语是Huang，谓语是said，宾语是that the selective industrial policy regime may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future。Huang in the report published by the English-language Asian Review of Political Economy in October 2022是一个介词短语作状语，表示黄在2022年10月刊登在英文《亚洲政治经济评论》上的一篇报告中。这个句子的意思是说，黄在2022年10月刊登在英文《亚洲政治经济评论》上的一篇报告中表示，过去导致中国经济成功的选择性产业政策制度，“甚至可能导致失败并成为未来的陷阱”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词作定语 - 分词可以用来修饰名词或代词，起到定语的作用。    <p>原文例句：Huang Shaoqing, a professor of economics at the Antai College of Economics and Management at Shanghai Jiao Tong University, said in a report.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个分词作定语的例子，其中分词是a professor of economics at the Antai College of Economics and Management at Shanghai Jiao Tong University，修饰的名词是Huang Shaoqing。这个分词表示Huang Shaoqing是上海交通大学安泰经济与管理学院的经济学教授。这个句子的意思是说，上海交通大学安泰经济与管理学院经济学教授黄少卿在一份报告中表示。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 倒装句是指句子中某个成分的位置与正常语序不同。    <p>原文例句：In 2016 when mapping out a national scientific and technology plan, Beijing vowed to improve tracking revolutionary industrial development to be capable of prejudging “the turning point” of possible replacements for traditional industries.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，其中当in 2016 when mapping out a national scientific and technology plan作状语时，主谓语序发生倒装，正常语序应该是Beijing vowed to improve tracking revolutionary industrial development in 2016 when mapping out a national scientific and technology plan。这个句子的意思是说，北京在2016年制定国家科技计划时，承诺改进对革命性产业发展的跟踪，以便能够预先判断传统产业可能被取代的“拐点”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Disruptive technologies, including artificial intelligence and quantum computing, will significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate</li>
<li>China should make ‘groundbreaking changes’ to its industrial policymaking amid its push to become a global technological and economic leader, analysts said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/df3b6f4b-498c-4140-80f2-8b42e0ebe9ed_9f02ea50.jpg" /><figcaption>China’s HL-2M reactor in Sichuan could provide a long-term solution to the world’s energy needs by generating power without producing nuclear waste. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China needs to adjust its industrial policymaking to brace for possible revolutionary changes to its economy by disruptive technologies, analysts said.</p><p>From artificial intelligence (AI) to quantum computing, and from room-temperature superconductivity to controllable nuclear fusion, disruptive technologies are set to significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate.</p><p>China’s economic miracle over the past four decades has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs.</p><p>This model has been adopted by other economies in East Asia during their development in the second half of 20th century.</p><blockquote>How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgentHuang Shaoqing</blockquote><p>“As frontier technologies, no one knows what technology truly has promising prospects, which could ultimately be screened out by the market through competition,” Huang Shaoqing, a professor of economics at the Antai College of Economics and Management at Shanghai Jiao Tong University, said in a report.</p><p>“Therefore, in the early development stage of disruptive technologies, economies of scale are not important and even dangerous.”</p><p>Huang said in the report published by the English-language Asian Review of Political Economy in October 2022 that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”.</p><p>“How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgent,” he wrote in the report, which had earlier been published in Mandarin by the Journal of Comparative Studies in February 2022.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>The urgency has become more prominent for Beijing, which views innovation and technological advancement as key to countering the heightened containment efforts by the United States, and also crucial for its ambition to become an economic and tech superpower by the middle of the century.</p><p>Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, said China needs to plan areas where matured technologies can be applied, including sectors influenced by US export bans, and that involve more markets.</p><p>“China needs to make groundbreaking changes to its industrial policymaking, otherwise, it will never be a global technological and economic leader,” Peng said.</p><p>“Decision makers need to listen more to private companies, give them enough funding for industrial research, and place them at the front role of disruptive industrial exploration.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies" title="">‘More, better’: premier urges China to focus on application of core technologies</a></h3><p>But as it is impossible to determine in advance which technology would prevail, a country can gain an advantage only if it develops enough small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) to offer sufficient diversified technological routes, Huang added.</p><p>“Only by promoting innovation and entrepreneurship, relaxing market access, improving the business environment, and allowing as many as SMEs as possible to grow rapidly can these SMEs play an important role in economic development driven by innovation,” he said.</p><p>In 2016 when mapping out a national scientific and technology plan, Beijing vowed to improve tracking revolutionary industrial development to be capable of prejudging “the turning point” of possible replacements for traditional industries.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>At the time it added that it would make a timely plan for research into disruptive technologies, such as AI, quantum information, genome editing, unmanned driving, hydrogen power and nanotechnology.</p><p>Li Yangwei, a technical consultant in the computing sector in Shenzhen, said disruptive technologies may lead to bigger tech and economic gaps among regions within China, but when there are more participants, the cost of any potential failures can be lowered.</p><p>He also said small market players can offer advice to the central government about industrial policies, but amid hefty external pressure and geopolitical complications, Beijing may still allocate resources to big companies or state-owned enterprises.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3243101/chinas-ai-aspirations-will-fuel-economy-drive-investment-trillions-dollars-mckinsey" title="">China’s AI gains will fuel economy as windfall swells into trillions: McKinsey</a></h3><p>“It also requires technocrats to be socially, economically and politically insightful, as well as having strong communication skills and being given central decision-making power,” Li said.</p><p>China’s basic research accounted for more than 6 per cent of its total research and development (R&amp;D) expenditure in the last four years, lower than the 16 to 18 per cent in the US and 22 per cent in France over the last 10 years.</p><p>Basic research from enterprises only accounted for 0.78 per cent of China’s overall R&amp;D expenditure, behind over 6 per cent in developed countries, according to a report in February by the Science and Technology Daily, a newspaper backed by the Ministry of Science and Technology.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s ‘king of software’, Wang Wenjing, steps down as president of enterprise management systems firm Yonyou amid mounting losses</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247446/chinas-king-software-wang-wenjing-steps-down-president-enterprise-management-systems-firm-yonyou</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Yonyou Network Technology founder Wang Wenjing has stepped down as president of the company due to sluggish sales and increasing losses.</li>    <li>Wang remains the company's chairman and chief executive, with a focus on corporate strategy and product development.</li>    <li>Veteran Yonyou executive Chen Qiangbin takes over as president, responsible for operations and management.</li>    <li>The change aims to improve performance after two years of stagnant revenue growth and widening losses.</li>    <li>Yonyou's shift from selling software licenses to collecting service fees via a software-as-a-service model has resulted in cloud-based services accounting for 70% of the company's revenue.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>用友网络科技创始人王文京因业绩疲软、亏损扩大辞去公司总裁职务。</li>    <li>王文京仍担任公司董事长兼首席执行官，负责企业战略和产品开发。</li>    <li>用友老将陈强斌接任总裁，负责运营和管理。</li>    <li>此项变动旨在改善公司在过去两年营收停滞和亏损扩大的局面。</li>    <li>用友从销售软件许可证转向通过软件即服务模式收取服务费，导致公司70%的收入来自云服务。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sluggish (adj.) - /ˈslʌɡɪʃ/ 缓慢的，迟缓的。    <p>原文例句：Wang Wenjing stepped down as president of the company due to sluggish sales and increasing losses.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由slug（鼻涕虫）和-ish（类似的）构成，意为“像鼻涕虫一样慢，缓慢的”。在这个例句中，它描述了用友网络科技的销售业绩疲软，增长缓慢。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>widening (adj.) - /ˈwaɪdənɪŋ/ 扩大的，增长的。    <p>原文例句：Wang saw its losses widen 91 per cent year on year to 1 billion yuan.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由wide（宽的）和-en（变成）构成，意为“变宽，扩大，增加”。在这个例句中，它描述了用友网络科技的亏损从去年同期增长了91%，扩大到了10亿元人民币。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>software-as-a-service (SaaS) - 软件即服务。    <p>原文例句：Yonyou's shift from selling software licenses to collecting service fees via a software-as-a-service model has resulted in cloud-based services accounting for 70% of the company's revenue.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指一种软件许可和交付模式，用户通过互联网按需获取软件，并根据使用情况付费。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The change aims to improve performance after two years of stagnant revenue growth and widening losses. - 此项变动旨在改善公司在过去两年营收停滞和亏损扩大的局面。    <p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是The change aims to improve performance，其中主语是The change，谓语是aims to improve performance，宾语是performance。after two years of stagnant revenue growth and widening losses是一个介词短语作时间状语，表示在过去两年营收停滞和亏损扩大的情况下。这个句子的意思是说，此项变动旨在改善公司在过去两年营收停滞和亏损扩大的局面。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示用友网络科技从过去许多年来一直是大陆最大的企业管理软件提供商。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>过去式 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Wang, who was 24 when he founded Yonyou after leaving a job in government, initially provided accounting software to businesses and quickly became a dominant player in that market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去式是一种时态，结构是：动词的过去式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去发生。在这个例句中，它表示王文京在24岁时辞去政府工作创办用友之后，最初为企业提供会计软件，并迅速成为该市场的主导者。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Tech billionaire Wang, 60, will remain in his roles as Yonyou chairman and chief executive, overseeing corporate strategy and product development</li>
<li>The senior management shuffle at Yonyou reflects the firm’s effort to turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/6c7f31d3-f7f3-4577-a795-008077b768f9_4bcd59c9.jpg" /><figcaption>Yonyou Network Technology founder Wang Wenjing retains his roles as chairman and chief executive at the Beijing-based enterprise management systems company. Photo: Weibo</figcaption></figure><p>Tech billionaire <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/347601/ufsoft-creates-fast-fortune-and-billion-dollar-goal" target="_self" title="">Wang Wenjing</a>, who was once known as China’s “king of software”, has stepped down as president of enterprise management systems provider Yonyou Network Technology, as the company he founded in 1988 continues to struggle with sluggish sales and mounting losses amid the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3241783/chinas-2023-gdp-forecasts-twisted-and-turned-prognosticators-puzzled-over-countrys-future" target="_self" title="">weak post-pandemic economic recovery</a>.</p><p>Wang had tendered his resignation with immediate effect, according to Yonyou’s filing with the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai-stock-index" target="_self" title="">Shanghai Stock Exchange</a> on Wednesday. “The company’s board expresses its sincere gratitude to Wang for his contribution,” the Beijing-based firm said.</p><p>The 60-year-old Wang – with a net worth of US$3.1 billion as of January 5, according to Forbes – will remain in his roles as Yonyou chairman and chief executive, overseeing corporate strategy and product development, according to a separate statement released by the firm.</p><p>Veteran Yonyou executive Chen Qiangbin, 48, takes over as company president, with a focus on operations and management, according to the company. After joining Yonyou in 2000, Chen was involved in software development, sales and then served as general manager at the firm’s branch offices in Beijing, northern Hebei province and southwestern Sichuan province.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/9f56e087-6a3a-4e69-b9a6-4ca4b123727b_b201e52d.jpg" title="Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Yonyou, ranked by research firm Gartner as one of the world’s top 10 enterprise resource planning (ERP) software providers, saw its shares close down 2.48 per cent to 16.49 yuan (US$2.32) on Friday.</p><p>ERP refers to software designed to automate business processes, as well as provide insights and internal controls, often in real time. It manages operations including accounting and finance, procurement, supply chain, manufacturing, human resources and collaboration.</p><p>In recent years, Yonyou changed its focus from selling licences of its ERP and other enterprise management software to collecting service fees by providing these systems via a software-as-a-service model called Yonyou BIP. By 2022, cloud-based services accounted for nearly 70 per cent of the firm’s revenue.</p><p>Still, the senior management shuffle at Yonyou reflects the company’s effort to try and turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth and widening losses, as fresh opportunities beckon from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" target="_self" title="">Beijing’s digitalisation drive</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" title="">China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms</a></h3><p>Yonyou initiated one of its largest organisational changes last year, when it set up 23 industry client and solution business units to cover a range of industries including manufacturing, consumer products, energy, logistics and the public sector. The move was expected to make its operations more focused on vertical industries, instead of regional markets.</p><p>Even as China’s weak macroeconomic environment has driven a round of poor earnings from cybersecurity and finance software stocks, Yonyou’s third-quarter results last year – with “positive revenue growth across all segments” – “indicate that ERP demand has been resilient”, according to a November research note by Jefferies.</p><p>While it reported 2 per cent revenue growth in the first three quarters of last year, Yonyou saw its losses widen 91 per cent year on year to 1 billion yuan.</p><p>Wang, who was 24 when he founded Yonyou <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/242891/software-rewards-u-turn-decision" target="_self" title="">after leaving a job in government</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/496999/software-firm-hopes-name-will-score-goal" target="_self" title="">initially provided accounting software</a> to businesses and quickly became a dominant player in that market. When Yonyou – first known as Ufsoft and then Ufida – expanded into ERP and other enterprise management systems, it surpassed the performance of major foreign ERP players like Oracle and SAP in the Chinese market.</p><p>Yonyou currently has more than 230 branch offices worldwide – including in the mainland, Hong Kong, Macau, Australia, New Zealand and a number of countries in Southeast Asia.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>McDonald’s China and Cainiao partner on RFID chips to improve supply chain efficiencies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247447/mcdonalds-china-and-cainiao-partner-rfid-chips-improve-supply-chain-efficiencies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>McDonald's China partners with Cainiao, Alibaba's logistics arm, to implement RFID technology and boost supply chain efficiency.</li>    <li>RFID technology reduces stocktaking time from 1 hour to 15 minutes and improves inventory data accuracy by 30%.</li>    <li>McDonald's and Cainiao also plan to explore digitisation and automation technologies in the supply chain.</li>    <li>Cainiao, preparing for an IPO in Hong Kong, aims to raise at least US$1 billion.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>麦当劳中国与阿里巴巴集团控股的物流业务菜鸟合作，使用射频识别（RFID）芯片和其他技术来提高供应链效率。</li>    <li>RFID技术将餐厅每日的盘点时间从1小时减少到15分钟，同时将库存数据的准确性提高了30%。</li>    <li>麦当劳和菜鸟还计划探索供应链中的数字化和自动化技术。</li>    <li>菜鸟正准备在香港进行首次公开募股（IPO），目标是筹集至少10亿美元。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>implement (v.) - /ˈɪmplɪˌment/ 实施，执行。    <p>原文例句：McDonald’s China unit has partnered with Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics business, to improve supply chain efficiency using radio frequency identification (RFID) chips and other technologies.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由in-（投入）和plementum（填充物）组成，意为“填充物，工具”。在这个例句中，它指的是实施或执行某种措施或计划。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>accuracy (n.) - /ˈækjʊrəsi/ 准确性。    <p>原文例句：A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes while improving the accuracy of inventory data by 30 per cent. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由ad-（向……）和curare（照料，注意）组成，意为“照料，注意”。在这个例句中，它指的是准确性或正确性。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>on a daily basis - 每天，每日。    <P>原文例句：Established in 2013, Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s huge e-commerce empire, handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由on（在……上），a（一个）和daily（每天的）构成的，表示“每天，每日”。在这个例句中，它表示菜鸟每天处理超过400万件跨境包裹。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong. - 麦当劳中国与菜鸟的协议是在该公司准备在香港进行首次公开募股之际达成。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The deal comes，其中主语是The deal，谓语是comes。as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong是一个时间状语从句，表示麦当劳中国与菜鸟的协议是在物流公司准备在香港进行首次公开募股之际达成。这个句子的意思是说，麦当劳中国与菜鸟的协议是在该公司准备在香港进行首次公开募股之际达成。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 表示伴随情况或原因。    <p>原文例句：Cainiao moved into the RFID field with the launch of its own tags in 2021, which it said could achieve 99.9 per cent recognition accuracy.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句式，表示伴随情况或原因。结构是：主句 + 现在分词短语。其中主句是Cainiao moved into the RFID field，现在分词短语是with the launch of its own tags in 2021，表示伴随情况或原因，即菜鸟在2021年推出自己的标签时进入RFID领域。这个句子的意思是说，菜鸟在2021年推出自己的标签时进入RFID领域，并表示这些标签可以实现99.9%的识别准确度。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>连接词when引导的定语从句 - 表示时间。    <p>原文例句：A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句式，表示时间。结构是：先行词 + when + 主句。其中先行词是A trial project of the RFID technology，连接词when引导定语从句，主句是the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants，表示时间，即试行射频识别技术，可以将餐厅每天的盘点时间从一个小时减少到15分钟。这个句子的意思是说，试行射频识别技术，可以将餐厅每天的盘点时间从一个小时减少到15分钟。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants</li>
<li>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/d5e1a0a3-a5e3-492f-b311-a67d3c5f12ec_d1186b0d.jpg" /><figcaption>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong. Photo: Reuters </figcaption></figure><p>McDonald’s China unit has partnered with Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics business, to improve supply chain efficiency using radio frequency identification (RFID) chips and other technologies.</p><p>Under a deal signed on Thursday, McDonald’s China will deploy Cainiao’s RFID technology in its supply chain with built-in tags on food packages, allowing the company to track products from factories to restaurants, according to a statement by the Hangzhou-based logistics firm.</p><p>A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants while improving the accuracy of inventory data by 30 per cent, according to the statement.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240676/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-will-enhance-its-overseas-presence-proposed-buyout-local-rival-best" title="">Alibaba logistics spin-off Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout</a></h3><p>RFID is a third-generation identification technology, after bar codes and QR codes, and has been widely adopted in supply chain tracking. With a built-in microchip, data is transmitted through radio frequency signals.</p><p>Apart from deploying RFID technology to improve efficiency in inventory and logistics, McDonald’s and Cainiao will also explore digitisation and automation technologies in the supply chain, Cainiao said.</p><p>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3235860/alibabas-cainiao-files-us1-billion-ipo-helping-hong-kong-land-worlds-second-biggest-listing-2023" target="_self" title="">an initial public offering (IPO) in Hong Kong</a> after submitting its A1 filing to the city’s stock exchange last September.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month. The listing is part of a group-wide restructuring of Alibaba as the e-commerce titan seeks to free up decision- making amid increased competition across its businesses. Alibaba also owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Established in 2013, Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s huge e-commerce empire, handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023. Alibaba announced it would spin Cainiao off in the restructuring announced in March.</p><p>Cainiao moved into the RFID field with the launch of its own tags in 2021, which it said could achieve 99.9 per cent recognition accuracy. The company announced in April last year that it had produced and sold over 100 million RFID tags in just two years.</p><p>McDonald’s China has a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year. It has also been stepping up efforts to digitise its operations in the country, which is the fast-food giant’s second-largest market globally.</p><p>Last month, McDonald’s China said it would work with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> to build a native app based on the next iteration of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3136017/will-huaweis-harmony-operating-system-end-global-duopoly-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS</a>, the Chinese telecommunications equipment and smartphone giant’s self-developed mobile platform.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China unveils 3-year ‘data action plan’ as Beijing seeks to boost growth through tech</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247423/china-unveils-3-year-data-action-plan-beijing-seeks-boost-growth-through-tech</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China has a new 3-year plan to boost its economy using data.</li>    <li>The plan includes building 300 new "representative" application scenarios for data by 2026.</li>    <li>The data industry is expected to grow 20% annually.</li>    <li>The plan aims to improve data quality, circulation, and applications.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国制定了一项新的 3 年计划，旨在利用数据来提振经济。</li>    <li>该计划包括在 2026 年之前为数据构建 300 个新的“具有代表性”的应用场景。</li>    <li>数据产业预计每年增长 20%。</li>    <li>该计划旨在提高数据质量、流通和应用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unleash (v.) - 释放，解开。    <p>原文例句：The goal was to unleash economic value while ensuring security and privacy.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语单词“onleasan”，意思是“释放”。在这个例句中，它表示释放经济价值，同时确保安全和隐私。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>mechanism (n.) - 机制，手段。    <p>原文例句：The digital economy still faces challenges including low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped applications potential.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古希腊单词“μηχανή”，意思是“机器，装置”。在这个例句中，它表示流通机制，即数据流通的手段和方式。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>artificial intelligence (AI) - 人工智能。    <p>原文例句：The agency’s plan involves mobilising data resources to support development of China’s own artificial intelligence (AI) large language models.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由artificial（人工）和intelligence（智能）构成的，表示人或机器展示出来的智能，具有人类智能的机器或计算机系统。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China aims to build more than 300 “representative” application scenarios by 2026, grow its data industry by 20 per cent every year, and multiply data trading volume.<p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，由三个分句组成，主语都是China，谓语分别是aims to build、grow和multiply。这三个分句之间用逗号分隔，表示并列关系。这个句子的意思是，中国计划到 2026 年构建 300 多个“具有代表性”的应用场景，每年使数据产业增长 20%，并扩大数据交易量。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：The NDA was announced in March last year as Beijing ramped up efforts in managing the country’s growing pool of data that is fragmented across different sectors and industries.</p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句型是指在句中对某个成分进行强调的句子结构。强调句型的基本结构是：It is/was + 被强调成分 + that/who + 其他部分。在这个例句中，被强调成分是The NDA，It is/was + 被强调成分 + that/who + 其他部分的结构是：It was the NDA that was announced in March last year。这个句子的意思是，国家数据局于去年三月宣布成立，当时北京正在加大力度管理分散在不同行业和领域的国家不断增长的数据池。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达假设、愿望、建议、请求等。    <p>原文例句：The agency’s plan involves mobilising data resources to support development of China’s own artificial intelligence (AI) large language models - the technology used to train AI applications like ChatGPT.</p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是指在句子中使用虚拟语气动词形式来表达假设、愿望、建议、请求等。虚拟语气动词形式有过去式和过去完成式两种。在这个例句中，虚拟语气动词形式是used，表示“用于”。这个句子的意思是，该机构的计划包括动员数据资源来支持开发中国自己的人工智能（AI）大型语言模型——该技术用于训练像 ChatGPT 这样的 AI 应用程序。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China aims to build more than 300 ‘representative’ application scenarios by 2026, and grow its data industry by 20 per cent every year</li>
<li>The digital economy still faces challenges including low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped applications potential</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/7195ef42-b909-415f-a96d-069d4c81cfa9_a08669f1.jpg" /><figcaption>A visitor shakes hands with a humanoid robot during the China International Digital Economy Expo 2023 in Hebei Province. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China’s newly established data administration, an agency created by Beijing to make data an effective production factor, has unveiled a three-year action plan to use the country’s massive troves of information to boost its economy.</p><p>According to the plan published by the National Data Administration (NDA) on Thursday, China aims to build more than 300 “representative” application scenarios by 2026, grow its data industry by 20 per cent every year, and multiply data trading volume.</p><p>The initiative is aimed at “cultivating” a new driving force for China’s economic development, leveraging the country’s advantages including a sizeable market, and abundant data resources and use cases, the NDA said.</p><p>The agency’s plan involves mobilising data resources to support development of China’s own artificial intelligence (AI) large language models - the technology used to train AI applications like ChatGPT. It will also increase efforts to have research institutions and leading enterprises build industry databases to create high quality datasets for training AI models.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" title="">China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms</a></h3><p>The blueprint comes at a time when China’s digital economy, having developed rapidly in recent years, still faces challenges including the low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped potential for applications, it said.</p><p>The NDA was announced in March last year as Beijing ramped up efforts in managing the country’s growing pool of data that is fragmented across different sectors and industries. The goal was to unleash economic value while ensuring security and privacy.</p><p>While the country’s internet watchdog, the Cyberspace Administration of China, has put in place laws and regulations governing data security, Beijing did not have a government body overseeing development policies for data until the establishment of the NDA.</p><p>The new administration, which officially began operations in October, is tasked with “coordinating and promoting the construction of data infrastructure, coordinating the integration, sharing, development and utilisation of data resources” across China’s economy and society, it said in March 2023.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246289/china-turns-spotlight-digital-economy-quest-common-prosperity-under-president-xi-jinping" title="">China’s focuses on digital economy to drive ‘common prosperity’ under Xi</a></h3><p>The agency, established under China’s top economic planner, the National Development and Reform Commission, is headed by information technology (IT) veteran Liu Liehong, former chairman of state-owned telecommunications network operator China Unicom.</p><p>The three-year plan will “guide and encourage” different types of private capital to invest in the data industry, and support data brokers in raising capital by going public.</p><p>The NDA also singled out 12 industries that should make better use of data, including manufacturing, agriculture, commerce, transport, finance and IT.</p><p>China’s new data strategies come as it seeks to catch up with the US in the development of AI, despite facing a host of challenges including restricted access to advanced chips.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong-listed Chinese miner CMOC takes Glencore’s cobalt crown as output jumps 170% in 2023</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247376/hong-kong-listed-chinese-miner-cmoc-takes-glencores-cobalt-crown-output-jumps-170-2023</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  CMOC Group, a Hong Kong-listed mining company, saw a substantial increase in its cobalt output last year, becoming the world's largest producer of the metal used in electric vehicle batteries. The company's Kisanfu mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo contributed significantly to this growth, helping to drive down cobalt prices. The global EV market is expected to continue expanding, with China being the largest market for both EVs and EV batteries.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: CMOC Group becomes the world's top cobalt producer, boosting output by 170% and exceeding its guidance.</li>    <li>Theme: Surging cobalt production from CMOC's Kisanfu mine leads to a market surplus and price slump.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The increasing demand for cobalt in electric vehicle batteries amidst the global EV boom.</li>    <li>Main information: CMOC's cobalt output, Kisanfu mine's contribution, impact on cobalt prices, and the growing EV market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  CMOC集团是一家在香港上市的矿业公司，去年其钴产量大幅增长，一跃成为全球最大的电动汽车电池用钴生产商。该公司位于刚果民主共和国的Kisanfu矿山对这一增长做出了重大贡献，帮助压低了钴的价格。预计全球电动汽车市场将继续扩大，中国将成为电动汽车和电动汽车电池的最大市场。  <ul>    <li>摘要：CMOC集团成为全球最大的钴生产商，产量增长170%，超过预期目标。</li>    <li>主题：CMOC的Kisanfu矿山钴产量激增，导致市场供应过剩，价格暴跌。</li>    <li>观点：全球电动汽车热潮下，对电动汽车电池中钴的需求不断增长。</li>    <li>主要信息：CMOC的钴产量、Kisanfu矿山的贡献、对钴价的影响以及不断增长的电动汽车市场。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>exceed (v.) - /ɪkˈsiːd/ 超过，超越。    <p>原文例句：CMOC’s copper output also jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes, establishing it as one of the world’s top producers at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由ex-（超过）和cedere（离开，让路）组成，意为“超过，超越”。在这个例句中，它表示CMOC的铜产量也增长了51%，达到419,539吨，使其成为世界顶级铜生产商之一，而此时许多矿业公司都在努力提高产量。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>slump (n.) - /slʌmp/ 突然下降，大幅下跌。    <p>原文例句：Soaring output at the US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle English，表示“突然下降，大幅下跌”。在这个例句中，它表示价格的大幅下跌，即Kisanfu矿山产量激增导致去年钴价格大幅下跌。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>be on par with - 与……齐平，与……相当。    <p>原文例句：Seoul-based consultancy SNE Research said in a report last February that electric cars with a driving range of more than 300 kilometres were sold at about US$30,000, on par with prices of petrol-powered vehicles.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由be（是，成为），on（在……上）和par（平等，齐平）组成的，表示“与……齐平，与……相当”。在这个例句中，它表示价格相当，即SNE Research在一份报告中表示，续航里程超过300公里的电动汽车售价约为30,000美元，与汽油动力汽车的价格相当。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Glencore is set to announce its full production results next month. - 嘉能可将于下个月公布其完整的生产业绩。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Glencore，谓语是is set to announce，宾语是its full production results。next month是一个时间状语，表示下个月。这个句子的意思是说，嘉能可将于下个月公布其完整的生产业绩。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去进行时 - 表示过去某个时间段内正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Global consultancy AlixPartners forecast in a research report in July that electric vehicles (EVs) would account for 34 per cent of global sales by 2028 and make up 61 per cent of sales in 2035, compared to 14 per cent in 2022.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，表示过去某个时间段内正在进行的动作或状态。结构是：was/were + 现在分词。其中was/were要根据主语的时态和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。在这个例句中，it表示全球咨询公司AlixPartners在7月的一份研究报告中预测，到2028年，电动汽车（EV）将占全球销量的34%，到2035年将占销量的61%，而2022年仅为14%。这个句子的意思是说，全球咨询公司AlixPartners在7月的一份研究报告中预测，到2028年，电动汽车（EV）将占全球销量的34%，到2035年将占销量的61%，而2022年仅为14%。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The company’s output of the key metal in EV batteries exceeded its own guidance by more than 20 per cent</li>
<li>Soaring output at CMOC’s US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/978ac785-70c2-47f2-8569-299b57f5feb3_f7bc69b7.jpg" /><figcaption>Excavators and drillers work in an open pit at Tenke Fungurume, a copper and cobalt mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>China’s CMOC Group boosted its cobalt output by more than 170 per cent last year, with surging production at a new mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo helping the company leapfrog Glencore as the world’s top producer of the key battery metal.</p><p>Hong Kong-listed CMOC produced 55,526 tonnes of cobalt in 2023, it said in a filing on Thursday. In October, Glencore forecast output of as much as 42,000 tonnes. While investors and traders had been expecting a large increase at CMOC’s massive Kisanfu mine – which came online in the second quarter – the full-year result exceeded the company’s own production guidance by more than 20 per cent.</p><p>Soaring output at the US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year, alongside rising production in Indonesia and a rebound in exports from CMOC’s other operation in Congo, Tenke-Fungurume. The market was already in one of its biggest ever surpluses as 2023 began, and the additional output helped drive a 30 per cent slump in prices over the year.</p><p>The mismatch between supply and demand became so acute that by midyear Glencore had started to stockpile surplus at its operations in Congo in a bid to bring the market back into balance. Glencore is set to announce its full production results next month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/bc0491e6-2aee-4541-8141-aa5c1fb6228a_1126e908.jpg" title="An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>CMOC’s copper output also jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes, establishing it as one of the world’s top producers at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output.</p><p>Cobalt is a material used in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3234469/global-ev-transition-accelerates-falling-battery-costs-hasten-purchase-price-parity-further-blow" target="_self" title="">NCM (lithium, nickel, cobalt and manganese) batteries</a> powering electric cars, which offer vehicles a longer driving range than nickel-based LFP (lithium, iron and phosphate) counterparts.</p><p>Global consultancy AlixPartners forecast in a research report in July that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicles (EVs)</a> would account for 34 per cent of global sales by 2028 and make up 61 per cent of sales in 2035, compared to 14 per cent in 2022.</p><p>In China, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243806/li-auto-xpeng-pace-chinese-ev-makers-race-towards-2023-sales-record-amid-all-time-high-monthly" target="_self" title="">EV penetration rate</a> exceeded 40 per cent in 2023 amid motorists’ rising penchant for environmentally friendly cars featuring autonomous driving technology and digital cockpits.</p><p>Mainland China is now the world’s largest automotive and EV market, with sales of battery-powered cars accounting for about 60 per cent of the global total.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246699/chinese-battery-maker-gotion-starts-making-energy-storage-packs-fremont-plant-kicking-made-america" title="">Chinese EV battery maker Gotion starts making energy storage packs in US</a></h3><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3237220/chinese-ev-makers-course-smashing-85-million-2023-sales-target-mainland-industry-players-and" target="_self" title="">Electric vehicle (EV) sales on the mainland</a>, however, are seen growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from the projected 30 per cent increase in 2023.</p><p>Seoul-based consultancy SNE Research said in a report last February that electric cars with a driving range of more than 300 kilometres were sold at about US$30,000, on par with prices of petrol-powered vehicles, which helped EVs gain popularity around the globe.</p><p><em>Additional reporting by</em> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/author/daniel-ren" target="_self" title=""><em>Daniel Ren</em></a></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Qualcomm unveils chip for mixed reality to compete with Apple’s Vision Pro</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247367/qualcomm-unveils-chip-mixed-reality-compete-apples-vision-pro</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  芯片设计公司Qualcomm发布了骁龙XR2+芯片，主要用于虚拟现实和混合现实头戴设备。这款芯片能够运行12个或更多高清摄像头，将被三星电子和谷歌用于正在开发的产品。Qualcomm是移动电话处理器领域最大的制造商，其芯片一直是许多其他公司吸引消费者进入虚拟现实和混合现实设备市场的核心。这些设备将信息投射到用户对物理世界的视野中，能够缓解外科手术患者的恐惧。XR2+芯片将提供4K分辨率的图像，并能够处理更多摄像头，有助于深度感知和眼部追踪。Qualcomm正在与包括谷歌和三星在内的多家合作伙伴合作，预计将在下周的CES展上发布相关产品。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Qualcomm发布骁龙XR2+芯片，用于虚拟现实和混合现实设备。</li>    <li>Theme: 虚拟现实和混合现实设备市场发展现状及Qualcomm的新芯片技术。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 虚拟现实和混合现实设备的市场前景广阔，Qualcomm的新芯片技术将推动该领域的进一步发展。</li>    <li>Main information: XR2+芯片的功能和优势；Qualcomm与谷歌、三星等合作伙伴的合作；新芯片将用于的产品和上市时间。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  芯片设计公司高通发布了骁龙 XR2+ 芯片，该芯片专为虚拟现实和混合现实头戴设备而设计。这款芯片能够运行 12 个或更多的高清摄像头，将被三星电子和谷歌用于正在开发的产品。高通是移动电话处理器领域最大的制造商，其芯片一直是许多其他公司吸引消费者进入虚拟现实和混合现实设备市场的核心。这些设备将信息投射到用户对物理世界的视野中，能够缓解外科手术患者的恐惧。XR2+ 芯片将提供 4K 分辨率的图像，并能够处理更多摄像头，有助于深度感知和眼部追踪。高通正在与包括谷歌和三星在内的多家合作伙伴合作，预计将在下周的 CES 展上发布相关产品。  <ul>    <li>摘要：高通发布骁龙 XR2+ 芯片，用于虚拟现实和混合现实设备。</li>    <li>主题：虚拟现实和混合现实设备市场发展现状及高通的新芯片技术。</li>    <li>观点：虚拟现实和混合现实设备的市场前景广阔，高通的新芯片技术将推动该领域的进一步发展。</li>    <li>主要信息：XR2+ 芯片的功能和优势；高通与谷歌、三星等合作伙伴的合作；新芯片将用于的产品和上市时间。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>resolve (v.) - /rɪˈzɒlv/ 解决，解决。    <p>原文例句：The company is now working with Panasonic to resolve the problems.</p>    <p>例句讲解：resolve由re-（再）和solve（溶解，解决）构成，表示“重新解决，解决”。例句中，company与resolve之间是逻辑上的动宾关系，可知resolve意为“解决”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fabricate (v.) - /ˈfæbrɪkeɪt/ 制造，编造。    <p>原文例句：The company fabricates the chips at its own factories.</p>    <p>例句讲解：fabricate由fa（做）和-bricate（做）构成，表示“做，制造”。例句中，company与fabricates之间是逻辑上的主谓关系，可知fabricates意为“制造”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>virtual reality (VR) - 虚拟现实。    <P>原文例句：Virtual reality headsets can be used for gaming, education, and training.</P>    <p>例句讲解：virtual reality由virtual（虚拟的）和reality（现实）构成，表示“虚拟现实”。例句中，virtual reality与headsets之间是逻辑上的定语关系，可知virtual reality意为“虚拟现实”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The chip design firm said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung and Google. - 芯片设计公司表示，这款能够运行 12 个或更多高清摄像头的全新组件将由三星和谷歌使用。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The chip design firm said，其中主语是The chip design firm，谓语是said，宾语是the new component...will be used by Samsung and Google。which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras是一个定语从句，修饰先行词the new component，表示这款新组件能够运行 12 个或更多高清摄像头。will be used by Samsung and Google是一个被动语态，其中主语是the new component，谓语是被动语态形式will be used，宾语是Samsung and Google。这个句子的意思是说，芯片设计公司表示，这款能够运行 12 个或更多高清摄像头的全新组件将由三星和谷歌使用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用来表示假设、猜测或愿望。    <p>原文例句：If XR2+ headsets were widely available, they could have a significant impact on the market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气的条件句，结构是：If + 过去式，would/could/should/might + 动词原形。其中If引导条件状语从句，would/could/should/might是情态动词，表示说话人的主观意愿或猜测。在这个例句中，If XR2+ headsets were widely available是一个条件状语从句，表示如果XR2+头戴设备被广泛使用。could have a significant impact on the market是一个虚拟语气的结果状语从句，表示虚拟的情况下可能产生的结果，即XR2+头戴设备可能对市场产生重大影响。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors, announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态的句子，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has是助动词，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip是一个现在完成时态的句子，表示高通公司从过去的某个时间开始一直持续到现在一直是移动电话处理器最大的制造商，并宣布了骁龙XR2+芯片。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The chip design firm said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung and Google</li>
<li>Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off</li>
</ul><p>Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors, announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro.</p><p>The San Diego, California-based chip design firm said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung Electronics and Alphabet’s Google on products under development.</p><p>The market for devices that project information onto the user’s view of the physical world was fired up last year by Apple’s announcement that it would sell a mixed-reality headset. Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off.</p><p>Augmented reality imposes graphics and written content on top of a person’s view of the world. Virtual reality places a consumer in a closed digital world. Apple’s coming Vision Pro and Meta Platforms' most-recent Quest 3 headset mix the technologies. Previous versions of Qualcomm’s XR chip have been featured in devices from Microsoft and Meta.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3240824/can-virtual-reality-ease-surgery-fears-patients-hong-kong-study-may-have-answer" title="">Virtual reality could be key to easing fears in surgical patients: study</a></h3><p>Headsets with the XR2+ will use processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors to project 4K-resolution images on each lens, according to Qualcomm’s Said Bakadir, a senior director of product management.</p><p>That improvement in quality will ease eye fatigue from reading text, reduce the potential for motion sickness and let device makers implement new features, he said. The chip’s ability to handle more cameras will aid in-depth perception and the eye tracking required to orient the user in the real world and recognise items.</p><p>“A lot of people want more juice to do more things,” Bakadir said. “People want to push the platform even higher.”</p><p>Qualcomm is working with a number of partners in addition to Google and Samsung, and announcements from customers may come as soon as next week’s CES show with products available as early as this year, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
