<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong-listed Chinese miner CMOC takes Glencore’s cobalt crown as output jumps 170% in 2023</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247376/hong-kong-listed-chinese-miner-cmoc-takes-glencores-cobalt-crown-output-jumps-170-2023</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>CMOC Group, a Chinese mining company, produced 55,526 tonnes of cobalt in 2023, surpassing Glencore as the world's top producer of the metal.</li>    <li>The increased output from CMOC's Kisanfu mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo was a major factor in the 30% decline in cobalt prices last year.</li>    <li>China's demand for EVs drove the surge in cobalt production, with over 60% of global sales coming from the country in 2023.</li>    <li>Cobalt is a key material in lithium-ion batteries, which are used in electric vehicles and offer longer driving ranges than other battery technologies.</li>    <li>Despite the increase in cobalt production, electric vehicle sales in China are expected to grow at a slower pace in 2024, from 30% to 20% year-over-year.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国矿业公司CMOC集团在2023年生产了55,526吨钴，使其超越嘉能可在全球钴产量中排名第一。</li>    <li>CMOC在刚果民主共和国的Kisanfu矿山的产量增加是去年钴价下跌30％的主要因素。</li>    <li>中国对电动汽车的需求推动了钴产量的激增，2023年中国占全球销量的60％以上。</li>    <li>钴是锂离子电池中的关键材料，后者用于电动汽车并提供比其他电池技术更长的续航里程。</li>    <li>尽管钴产量增加，但预计2024年中国电动汽车的销量将以较慢的速度增长，从2023年的30%增长到2024年的20%。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Excavators (n.) - /ˈɛks.kə.veɪ.tər/ 挖掘机, 铲土机.    <p>原文例句：Excavators and drillers work in an open pit at Tenke Fungurume, a copper and cobalt mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语Excavate，意思是“挖出”。在这个例句中，它指的是在刚果民主共和国的Tenke Fungurume铜钴矿的一个露天矿坑中工作的挖掘机和钻机。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>forecast (v.) - /fɔːrˈkæst/ 预测，预报。    <p>原文例句：In October, Glencore forecast output of as much as 42,000 tonnes. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由fore（前面）和cast（投掷）组成，意思是“投掷到前面，预报”。在这个例句中，它指的是嘉能可在十月份预测的产量可能达到42000吨。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>surplus (n.) - /ˈsɜːr.pləs/ 过剩，盈余。    <p>原文例句：The market was already in one of its biggest ever surpluses as 2023 began, and the additional output helped drive a 30 per cent slump in prices over the year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语surplus，意思是“过多的，剩余的”。在这个例句中，它指的是在2023年开始时，市场已经处于有史以来最大的盈余之一，而额外的产量导致价格在今年下降了30％。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>by midyear - 到年中。    <P>原文例句：By midyear Glencore had started to stockpile surplus at its operations in Congo in a bid to bring the market back into balance. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由by（在……之前），midyear（年中）构成，表示“到年中”。在这个例句中，它表示嘉能可在年中开始在其刚果的运营中储存盈余，以使市场恢复平衡。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in addition - 此外，另外。    <P>原文例句：Soaring output at the US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year, alongside rising production in Indonesia and a rebound in exports from CMOC’s other operation in Congo, Tenke-Fungurume. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……中），addition（添加，增加）构成，表示“在……中添加，此外”。在这个例句中，它表示美国18亿美元的Kisanfu矿山的产量激增，导致去年钴价大幅下跌，此外还有印度尼西亚的产量增加和CMOC在刚果的另一家运营商Tenke-Fungurume的出口反弹，这两个因素也造成了钴价下跌。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Cobalt is a material used in NCM (lithium, nickel, cobalt and manganese) batteries powering electric cars, which offer vehicles a longer driving range than nickel-based LFP (lithium, iron and phosphate) counterparts.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，由主句Cobalt is a material used in NCM batteries和两个定语从句that power electric cars和which offer vehicles a longer driving range than nickel-based LFP counterparts组成。主句中的谓语是is，主语是Cobalt，宾语是a material used in NCM batteries。定了语从句that power electric cars是对Cobalt is a material used in NCM batteries的补充说明，说明钴是用于电动汽车的NCM电池的材料。定语从句which offer vehicles a longer driving range than nickel-based LFP counterparts是对Cobalt is a material used in NCM batteries的进一步补充说明，说明钴是用于电动汽车的NCM电池的材料，并且这种电池可以使汽车具有比基于镍的LFP电池更长的续航里程。这个句子的意思是说，钴是用于NCM（锂、镍、钴和锰）电池的材料，这种电池为电动汽车提供动力，并且比基于镍的LFP（锂、铁和磷酸盐）电池能使汽车具有更长的续航里程。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>since从句 - 表示从过去某个时间一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：CMOC’s copper output also jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes, establishing it as one of the world’s top producers at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个since从句，表示从过去某个时间一直持续到现在的动作或状态。结构是：since + 时间点/时间段 + 主语 + 谓语。其中since表示“从……以来”，时间点/时间段表示从句开始的时间，主语是动作或状态的执行者，谓语是动作或状态的描述。在这个例句中，since表示从过去某个时间以来，时间点/时间段没有给出，主语是CMOC’s copper output，谓语是jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes。这个句子的意思是说，CMOC的铜产量也增长了51%，达到419,539吨，使其成为世界上最大的铜生产商之一，而这段时间里许多矿工都在努力提高产量。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>定语从句 - 表示对某个先行词进行修饰或说明。    <p>原文例句：Electric vehicles (EVs) would account for 34 per cent of global sales by 2028 and make up 61 per cent of sales in 2035, compared to 14 per cent in 2022. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个定语从句，对先行词Electric vehicles (EVs)进行修饰或说明。结构是：[先行词] + 关系代词 + 主语 + 谓语。其中关系代词是指代先行词的词，主语是动作或状态的执行者，谓语是动作或状态的描述。在这个例句中，先行词是Electric vehicles (EVs)，关系代词是would，主语是account for 34 per cent of global sales by 2028，谓语是make up   <ul><li>The company’s output of the key metal in EV batteries exceeded its own guidance by more than 20 per cent</li>
<li>Soaring output at CMOC’s US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/978ac785-70c2-47f2-8569-299b57f5feb3_f7bc69b7.jpg" /><figcaption>Excavators and drillers work in an open pit at Tenke Fungurume, a copper and cobalt mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>China’s CMOC Group boosted its cobalt output by more than 170 per cent last year, with surging production at a new mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo helping the company leapfrog Glencore as the world’s top producer of the key battery metal.</p><p>Hong Kong-listed CMOC produced 55,526 tonnes of cobalt in 2023, it said in a filing on Thursday. In October, Glencore forecast output of as much as 42,000 tonnes. While investors and traders had been expecting a large increase at CMOC’s massive Kisanfu mine – which came online in the second quarter – the full-year result exceeded the company’s own production guidance by more than 20 per cent.</p><p>Soaring output at the US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year, alongside rising production in Indonesia and a rebound in exports from CMOC’s other operation in Congo, Tenke-Fungurume. The market was already in one of its biggest ever surpluses as 2023 began, and the additional output helped drive a 30 per cent slump in prices over the year.</p><p>The mismatch between supply and demand became so acute that by midyear Glencore had started to stockpile surplus at its operations in Congo in a bid to bring the market back into balance. Glencore is set to announce its full production results next month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/bc0491e6-2aee-4541-8141-aa5c1fb6228a_1126e908.jpg" title="An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>CMOC’s copper output also jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes, establishing it as one of the world’s top producers at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output.</p><p>Cobalt is a material used in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3234469/global-ev-transition-accelerates-falling-battery-costs-hasten-purchase-price-parity-further-blow" target="_self" title="">NCM (lithium, nickel, cobalt and manganese) batteries</a> powering electric cars, which offer vehicles a longer driving range than nickel-based LFP (lithium, iron and phosphate) counterparts.</p><p>Global consultancy AlixPartners forecast in a research report in July that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicles (EVs)</a> would account for 34 per cent of global sales by 2028 and make up 61 per cent of sales in 2035, compared to 14 per cent in 2022.</p><p>In China, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243806/li-auto-xpeng-pace-chinese-ev-makers-race-towards-2023-sales-record-amid-all-time-high-monthly" target="_self" title="">EV penetration rate</a> exceeded 40 per cent in 2023 amid motorists’ rising penchant for environmentally friendly cars featuring autonomous driving technology and digital cockpits.</p><p>Mainland China is now the world’s largest automotive and EV market, with sales of battery-powered cars accounting for about 60 per cent of the global total.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246699/chinese-battery-maker-gotion-starts-making-energy-storage-packs-fremont-plant-kicking-made-america" title="">Chinese EV battery maker Gotion starts making energy storage packs in US</a></h3><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3237220/chinese-ev-makers-course-smashing-85-million-2023-sales-target-mainland-industry-players-and" target="_self" title="">Electric vehicle (EV) sales on the mainland</a>, however, are seen growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from the projected 30 per cent increase in 2023.</p><p>Seoul-based consultancy SNE Research said in a report last February that electric cars with a driving range of more than 300 kilometres were sold at about US$30,000, on par with prices of petrol-powered vehicles, which helped EVs gain popularity around the globe.</p><p><em>Additional reporting by</em> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/author/daniel-ren" target="_self" title=""><em>Daniel Ren</em></a></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Qualcomm unveils chip for mixed reality to compete with Apple’s Vision Pro</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247367/qualcomm-unveils-chip-mixed-reality-compete-apples-vision-pro</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Qualcomm has introduced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip, designed for virtual and mixed reality headsets. It can power 12 or more high-definition cameras and will be used by Samsung and Google. XR chip has been a vital component in several companies' attempts to attract consumers to the market, which has yet to gain traction. Augmented reality and virtual reality differ in their presentation techniques. Apple and Meta headsets integrate both technologies. Qualcomm's XR chip has been utilized in Microsoft and Meta devices.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Qualcomm unveils the Snapdragon XR2+ chip for virtual and mixed reality headsets, targeting advanced visual experiences.</li>    <li>Theme: The evolution of XR technology and the competitive landscape in the virtual and mixed reality market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Qualcomm's contribution to the development and advancement of XR technology.</li>    <li>Main information: Features and capabilities of the Snapdragon XR2+ chip; adoption by Samsung and Google; potential applications in virtual and mixed reality headsets; industry competition and challenges.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  高通公司最新推出骁龙XR2+芯片，专用于虚拟现实和混合现实头显。该芯片可驱动12个或更多高清摄像头，并将被三星和谷歌在研产品采用。XR芯片一直是多家公司吸引消费者购买该品类的核心组成部分，但该市场尚未起飞。增强现实和虚拟现实两种技术在呈现方式上有所不同。苹果和Meta头显均结合了这两种技术。高通的XR芯片已被微软和Meta设备采用。  <ul>    <li>摘要：高通推出骁龙XR2+芯片，用于虚拟现实和混合现实头显，带来更出色的视觉体验。</li>    <li>主题：XR技术的演进以及虚拟现实和混合现实市场的竞争格局。</li>    <li>观点：高通在XR技术发展和进步中的贡献。</li>    <li>主要信息：骁龙XR2+芯片的特点和功能；三星和谷歌的采用；虚拟现实和混合现实头显中的潜在应用；行业竞争和挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Immerse (v.) - /ɪˈmɜːrs/ 沉浸，专心于。    <p>原文例句：Staff at the Hong Kong Science Museum immerse themselves in a virtual reality experience, November 9. 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由in（进入）和mergere（使沉没）组成，意为“使沉没，使沉浸”。在这个例句中，它描述了香港科技馆的工作人员沉浸在虚拟现实体验中。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Perception (n.) - /pəˈsɛpʃən/ 知觉，感知。    <p>原文例句：The chip’s ability to handle more cameras will aid in-depth perception and the eye tracking required to orient the user in the real world and recognise items.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由per（通过）和capere（取）组成，意为“通过某种方式获取，感知”。在这个例句中，它描述了芯片处理更多摄像头的能力将有助于深度感知和眼动追踪，以便在现实世界中定位用户并识别物品。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take off - 开始，获得进展。    <P>原文例句：The market for devices that project information onto the user’s view of the physical world was fired up last year by Apple’s announcement that it would sell a mixed-reality headset. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由take（拿，取）和off（离开）组成，表示“开始，起飞，获得进展”。在这个例句中，它表示去年苹果公司宣布将出售混合现实头盔后，投射信息到用户视野中的设备市场开始启动。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors, announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro. - 高通作为最大的手机处理器制造商，宣布推出骁龙XR2+芯片，该芯片专为虚拟现实和混合现实头显设计，将与苹果即将推出的Vision Pro展开竞争。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Qualcomm announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip，其中主语是Qualcomm，谓语是announced，宾语是the Snapdragon XR2+ chip。designed for virtual and mixed reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰chip，表示该芯片专为虚拟现实和混合现实头显设计，将与苹果即将推出的Vision Pro展开竞争。这个句子的意思是说，高通作为最大的手机处理器制造商，宣布推出骁龙XR2+芯片，该芯片专为虚拟现实和混合现实头显设计，将与苹果即将推出的Vision Pro展开竞争。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列连词 - 用于连接两个或两个以上词语、短语或句子，表示并列关系。    <p>原文例句：That improvement in quality will ease eye fatigue from reading text, reduce the potential for motion sickness and let device makers implement new features. </p>    <p>语法讲解：并列连词是连接词的一种，用于连接两个或两个以上词语、短语或句子，表示并列关系。常见的并列连词有and、but、or、so、yet等。在这个例句中，并列连词and被用来连接三个分句，表示这三个分句并列关系。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表示说话者对某件事的假设、愿望、请求或建议。    <p>原文例句：Qualcomm is working with a number of partners in addition to Google and Samsung, and announcements from customers may come as soon as next week’s CES show with products available as early as this year, he said.</p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是英语中一种特殊的语气，用于表示说话者对某件事的假设、愿望、请求或建议。虚拟语气的标志是使用would、should、could、might、may等情态动词或be动词的过去式。在这个例句中，虚拟语气被用来表示高通公司与谷歌和三星以外にも许多合作伙伴合作，并且客户的公告可能最早在下周的CES展会上发布，产品最早可能在今年推出。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The chip maker said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung and Google</li>
<li>Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/236c15ea-71fb-4df9-9833-fe66286fc8bd_a46da414.jpg" /><figcaption>Staff at the Hong Kong Science Museum immerse themselves in a virtual reality experience, November 9. 2023. Photo: May Tse</figcaption></figure><p>Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors, announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro.</p><p>The San Diego-based chip maker said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung Electronics and Alphabet’s Google on products under development.</p><p>The market for devices that project information onto the user’s view of the physical world was fired up last year by Apple’s announcement that it would sell a mixed-reality headset. Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3240824/can-virtual-reality-ease-surgery-fears-patients-hong-kong-study-may-have-answer" title="">Virtual reality could be key to easing fears in surgical patients: study</a></h3><p>Augmented reality imposes graphics and written content on top of a person’s view of the world. Virtual reality places a consumer in a closed digital world. Apple’s coming Vision Pro and Meta Platform’s most-recent Quest 3 headset mix the technologies. Previous versions Qualcomm’s XR chip have featured in devices from Microsoft and Meta.</p><p>Headsets with the XR2+ will use processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors to project 4K-resolution images on each lens, according to Qualcomm’s Said Bakadir, a senior director of product management.</p><p>That improvement in quality will ease eye fatigue from reading text, reduce the potential for motion sickness and let device makers implement new features, he said. The chip’s ability to handle more cameras will aid in-depth perception and the eye tracking required to orient the user in the real world and recognise items.</p><p>“A lot of people want more juice to do more things,” Bakadir said. “People want to push the platform even higher.”</p><p>Qualcomm is working with a number of partners in addition to Google and Samsung, and announcements from customers may come as soon as next week’s CES show with products available as early as this year, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>OpenAI in talks with dozens of publishers to license content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  OpenAI and news publisher Politico's parent company Axel Springer recently signed a multi-year licensing agreement worth tens of millions of dollars. OpenAI is actively negotiating licensing deals with numerous publishers to obtain content for training its artificial intelligence (AI) models. This is crucial as OpenAI strives to balance the need for updated, accurate data with concerns about data sourcing in its model-building process. However, The New York Times filed a lawsuit against OpenAI and Microsoft for using its articles without permission. This lawsuit poses significant challenges to OpenAI, including potential financial implications and the need to modify its training data, affecting its deal-making efforts with the media industry.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: OpenAI's licensing deal with Politico and its ongoing negotiations with publishers for training AI models.</li>    <li>Theme: The importance of licensing agreements for OpenAI's AI training and the legal challenges posed by The New York Times' lawsuit.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Balancing the need for updated data for AI training with concerns about data sourcing; the potential impact of the lawsuit on OpenAI's business and deal-making.</li>    <li>Main information: OpenAI's licensing deal with Axel Springer; negotiations with various publishers; The New York Times' lawsuit and its implications for OpenAI's training data and financial stability.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  OpenAI最近与Politico的母公司Axel Springer签署了一份多年的授权协议，价值数千万美元。OpenAI正在积极与众多出版商谈判授权协议，以获得内容来训练其人工智能（AI）模型。这至关重要，因为OpenAI在努力平衡模型构建过程对更新、准确数据的需求与有关数据来源的担忧。然而，《纽约时报》因未经允许使用其文章而对OpenAI和微软提起诉讼。此案给OpenAI带来了重大挑战，包括潜在的财务影响和修改其训练数据的需要，影响了其与媒体行业的交易。  <ul>    <li>摘要：OpenAI与Politico的授权协议以及与出版商正在进行的谈判，以训练AI模型。</li>    <li>主题：授权协议对OpenAI的AI训练的重要性，以及《纽约时报》的诉讼所带来的法律挑战。</li>    <li>观点：平衡AI训练对更新数据的需求与对数据来源的担忧；诉讼对OpenAI业务和交易的潜在影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：OpenAI与Axel Springer的授权协议；与多家出版商的谈判；《纽约时报》的诉讼及其对OpenAI的训练数据和财务稳定性的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>strive (v.) - /straɪv/ 努力以达到某一目的。    <p>原文例句:“Here, the content is used for training a model. It’s not used to reproduce the content. It’s not used to replace the content.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：“在这里，内容用于训练模型。它不做重复内容之用，它不做替代内容之用。”这个例句中的“strive”作谓语动词，意思是努力以达到某一目的，在这个例子中，OpenAI正在努力使他们的AI模型更加准确和智能。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>implication (n.) - /ɪmplɪˈkeɪʃ(ə)n/ 含义，暗示。    <p>原文例句：“The current situation is vastly different than the situations that the publishers faced in the past with search engines and social media,” Rubin said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Rubin说：“目前的情况与过去出版商在搜索引擎和社交媒体中面临的情况非常不同。”这个例句中的“implication”作宾语，意思是含义，暗示，这个例子中的“implication”指的是OpenAI和出版商之间的情况与搜索引擎和社交媒体之间的情况的区别。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>artificial intelligence (AI) - 人工智能。    <p>原文例句：“The Times, however, disagrees with OpenAI’s stance, arguing that ChatGPT is flat out copying its journalists’ work without paying for it.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：“然而，《纽约时报》不同意OpenAI的立场，认为ChatGPT完全是在不支付费用的情况下复制其记者的作品。”这个例句中的“artificial intelligence (AI)”作主语，意思是人工智能，这个例子中的“artificial intelligence (AI)”指的是OpenAI开发的语言模型ChatGPT。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>balance the need for ... with ... - 平衡对……的需要和……之间。    <p>原文例句：“OpenAI said it is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles, a broader effort than was previously known as the start-up looks for content to train its artificial intelligence models.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：“OpenAI表示，它正在与数十家出版商谈判授权协议，这是一个比以前已知范围更广泛的努力，这家初创公司正在寻找内容来训练其人工智能模型。”这个例句中的“balance the need for ... with ...”作状语，意思是平衡对……的需要和……之间，在这个例子中，“balance the need for ... with ...”指的是OpenAI在寻找内容来训练人工智能模型时，需要平衡对最新、准确数据的需求和对数据来源的担忧之间。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>OpenAI is in the middle of many negotiations and discussions with many publishers. - OpenAI正在与许多出版商进行许多谈判和讨论。    <p>句子分析：这个句子是一个主动语态的一般现在时句，主语是OpenAI，谓语是is in the middle of many negotiations and discussions with many publishers，作宾语的是many negotiations and discussions with many publishers。这个句子的意思是OpenAI正在与许多出版商进行许多谈判和讨论。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：“The suit poses an existential challenge to OpenAI’s business.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是The suit，谓语是poses，宾语是an existential challenge to OpenAI’s business。这个句子的意思是这场诉讼对OpenAI的业务构成了一个存在的挑战。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>非谓语动词 - 不能单独作谓语，只能作定语、状语或表语。    <p>原文例句：“It’s not used to reproduce the content. It’s not used to replace the content.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，to reproduce the content和to replace the content都是非谓语动词，它们分别作定语和状语。to reproduce the content作定语，修饰content，意思是复制内容；to replace the content作状语，修饰not used，意思是取代内容。这个句子的意思是它不用于复制内容，它不用于取代内容。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars</li>
<li>One of the companies it had been in talks with, The New York Times, sued OpenAI and Microsoft for using articles without permission</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/cbdcaa18-c730-440d-8607-38a29cbf4417_8608f55a.jpg" /><figcaption>The Open AI logo on a smartphone in a photo arranged on December 29, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>OpenAI said it is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles, a broader effort than was previously known as the start-up looks for content to train its artificial intelligence models.</p><p>“We are in the middle of many negotiations and discussions with many publishers. They are active. They are very positive. They’re progressing well,” Tom Rubin, OpenAI’s chief of intellectual property and content, told Bloomberg News. “You’ve seen deals announced, and there will be more in the future.”</p><p>OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars, a person familiar with the matter previously told Bloomberg. In July, OpenAI announced an agreement with the Associated Press for an undisclosed amount. These deals are key to OpenAI’s future as it is balancing the need for updated, accurate data to build its models with growing scrutiny about where that data is sourced from.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246524/chinese-ai-champion-sensetime-introduces-go-playing-robot-japan-south-korea" title="">Chinese AI champion SenseTime introduces Go playing robot to Japan, South Korea</a></h3><p>But last week, one of the companies it had been in talks with, The New York Times Co, sued OpenAI and Microsoft for using the publication’s articles without permission.</p><p>The suit poses an existential challenge to OpenAI’s business. If the Times wins the case, OpenAI may not only owe billions of dollars, but could also be forced to destroy any of its training data that includes work from the Times, a costly and complicated task. More immediately, however, the lawsuit complicates OpenAI’s deal-making efforts with the media industry.</p><p>“The current situation is vastly different than the situations that the publishers faced in the past with search engines and social media,” Rubin said. “Here, the content is used for training a model. It’s not used to reproduce the content. It’s not used to replace the content.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246667/chinas-cloud-market-growth-plateaus-despite-big-ai-push" title="">China’s cloud market growth plateaus despite big AI push</a></h3><p>The Times, however, disagrees with OpenAI’s stance, arguing that ChatGPT is flat out copying its journalists’ work without paying for it. In its lawsuit, the publisher showed examples in which ChatGPT spit out entire paragraphs of nearly verbatim text from The New York Times (although some have pointed out that in certain examples, it was specifically prompting ChatGPT to reproduce Times content). The publisher argues that is proof OpenAI used New York Times data.</p><p>“If Microsoft and OpenAI want to use our work for commercial purposes, the law requires that they first obtain our permission,” The New York Times said in a statement. “They have not done so.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong-based AI-driven company sells potential breast cancer drug in deal whose value could exceed US$500 million</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247263/hong-kong-based-ai-driven-company-sells-potential-breast-cancer-drug-deal-whose-value-could-exceed</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Insilico Medicine, an AI-driven drug discovery company based in Hong Kong, has entered into a deal with Menarini Group, an Italy-based pharmaceutical company, to develop and commercialize a novel AI-powered small molecule inhibitor for hormone-sensitive cancers, including breast cancer.</li>    <li> The agreement grants Stemline Therapeutics, a subsidiary of Menarini, the exclusive global rights to develop and market the drug, with a total potential value exceeding US$500 million.</li>    <li> This collaboration highlights the growing role of AI technology in revolutionizing drug discovery, offering greater efficiency, accuracy, and cost-saving benefits.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Insilico Medicine，一家位于香港的人工智能药物研发公司，与意大利制药公司 Menarini Group 达成协议，共同开发和商业化一种新型的人工智能驱动的治疗激素敏感性癌症（包括乳腺癌）的药物。</li>    <li>根据协议，Menarini 的子公司 Stemline Therapeutics 将获得该药物的全球独家开发和销售权，总潜在价值超过 5 亿美元。</li>    <li>此次合作突显了人工智能技术在药物发现领域日益重要的作用，可带来更高的效率、准确性和成本效益。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>hormone-sensitive cancer (n.) - 激素敏感性癌症。    <p>原文例句：Breast cancer, a hormone-sensitive cancer, is the most common cancer worldwide, and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the WHO.</p>    <p>例句讲解：激素敏感性癌症是指受激素水平影响而生长的癌症。乳腺癌是全球最常见的癌症之一，也是女性癌症死亡的主要原因。</p></li>    <li>AI-driven (adj.) - 人工智能驱动的。    <p>原文例句：Insilico Medicine, a Hong Kong-based AI-driven drug discovery company...</p>    <p>例句讲解：人工智能驱动的指的是利用人工智能技术来推进药物发现。Insilico Medicine 是一家位于香港的人工智能药物研发公司，致力于利用人工智能技术来加速新药的开发。</p></li>    <li>small molecule inhibitor (n.) - 小分子抑制剂。    <p>原文例句：The exclusive licensing agreement grants Stemline the global rights to develop and commercialize a novel small molecule KAT6A inhibitor...</p>    <p>例句讲解：小分子抑制剂是指能够与特定的蛋白质分子结合并阻止其功能的小分子化合物。 KAT6A 抑制剂是一种新型的小分子抑制剂，有望用于治疗激素敏感性癌症。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>compound annual growth rate (CAGR) - 复合年增长率。    <p>原文例句：The AI-driven drug discovery market is projected to grow at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 23.72 per cent from 2023 to 2030...</p>    <p>例句讲解：复合年增长率是衡量投资在一定时期内平均每年增长的百分比。 AI 驱动的药物发现市场预计从 2023 年到 2030 年的复合年增长率为 23.72%。</p></li>    <li>clinical trial (n.) - 临床试验。    <p>原文例句：In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence.</p>    <p>例句讲解：临床试验是用于评估药物或治疗方法对人体的安全性和有效性的研究。 Insilico Medicine 计划在香港进行首次公开募股 (IPO)，以资助其通过人工智能发现和设计的药物的临床试验。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Insilico, founded by Zhavoronkov in 2014, has a pipeline that consists of 31 programmes for 29 drug targets in cancer, fibrosis, immunity, central nervous system and ageing-related diseases.    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是 Insilico，谓语是 has，宾语是 a pipeline。介词短语 by Zhavoronkov in 2014 表示时间，介词短语 for 29 drug targets 表示目的。从句 consists of 31 programmes 表示 Insilico 的工作重点。</p></li>    <li>Under the exclusive licensing agreement, Insilico has granted Stemline the global rights to develop and commercialize a novel small molecule KAT6A inhibitor as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers and other oncology indications.    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是 Insilico has granted Stemline the global rights，从句是 Under the exclusive licensing agreement 和 as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers and other oncology indications。介词短语 Under the exclusive licensing agreement 表示条件，从句 as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers and other oncology indications 表示目的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时由 have/has + 过去分词构成。在这个例句中，revealed 是过去分词，表示这个动作发生在过去，但其结果或影响一直持续到现在的。这个句子告诉我们，该公司在去年 6 月公布了一项在香港进行首次公开募股 (IPO) 的计划，以资助其通过人工智能发现和设计的药物的临床试验。</p></li>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：The agreement comes at a time when cutting-edge technology is playing a greater role in drug discovery.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态由 be + 过去分词构成。在这个例句中，is playing 是被动语态，表示动作“playing”是由句子中的宾语“technology”承受的。这个句子告诉我们，在当今时代，前沿技术在药物发现中发挥着越来越重要的作用。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Insilico grants Italy’s Menarini Group, the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule inhibitor, as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers</li>
<li>Breast cancer, a hormone-sensitive cancer, is the most common cancer worldwide, and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the WHO</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/0aa273cd-964f-49d2-be3b-69223d5b9a88_d8bebbd1.jpg" /><figcaption>null</figcaption></figure><p>Insilico Medicine, a Hong Kong-based AI-driven drug discovery company that intends to list in Hong Kong after it unveiled an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3225736/hong-kong-based-biotech-insilico-medicine-shifts-ipo-plan-city-new-york" target="_self" title="">initial public offering plan</a> (IPO) last year, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group in a deal that could reach a value of over US$500 million.</p><p>Stemline Therapeutics, a wholly owned unit of Menarini, will make a US$12 million upfront payment to Insilico under the agreement, which will be followed by sales royalties worth up to “double digits”. The combined value of the deal includes all development, regulatory, and commercial milestones.</p><p>The agreement comes at a time when cutting-edge technology is playing a greater role in drug discovery. AI has emerged as a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery by enhancing efficiency and accuracy while reducing the time-consuming aspects of research and development, experts say.</p><p>The AI-driven drug discovery market is projected to grow at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 23.72 per cent from 2023 to 2030, reaching an estimated value of US$7.1 billion by 2030, according to US-based Vantage Market Research.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/8d6c5116-f305-4968-8ef3-f757c1373823_34f54c2a.jpg" title="An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The technology expedites the process of identifying potential drugs, according to Insilico’s founder and co-CEO, Dr Alex Zhavoronkov.</p><p>Under the exclusive licensing agreement, Insilico has granted Stemline the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule KAT6A inhibitor as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers and other oncology indications.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3199001/sanofi-signs-research-tie-hong-kongs-insilico-medicine-accelerate-ai-powered-drug-discovery" title="">Sanofi signs with Hong Kong biotech firm Insilico to spur AI drug discovery</a></h3><p>Breast cancer is the most common cancer worldwide and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the World Health Organization.</p><p>The global breast cancer market is projected to hit around US$73.68 billion by 2032 with a registered CAGR of 9.9 per cent, according to Precedence Research.</p><p>“The partnership at the early stage preclinical trial is truly optimal when the partner is very committed,” said Zhavoronkov.</p><p>Menarini, an international pharmaceutical and diagnostics company with a turnover of more than US$4.4 billion and operations in 140 countries, sees the collaboration with Insilico as an opportunity to explore new treatment approaches and potentially unlock transformative cancer therapies, according to CEO Elcin Barker Ergun.</p><p>Insilico, founded by Zhavoronkov in 2014, has a pipeline that consists of 31 programmes for 29 drug targets in cancer, fibrosis, immunity, central nervous system and ageing-related diseases.</p><p>In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence.</p><p>Zhavoronkov declined to reveal a timeline for its IPO but said market sentiment was a concern.</p><p>Insilico has a presence in the markets of the US, Greater China, Canada and the Middle East. It launched the Generative AI and Quantum Computing Research and Development Center in Abu Dhabi in February 2023.</p><p>To date, the company has raised more than US$400 million via private markets. In 2022, it secured series D financing of US$95 million from investors such as Prosperity7, a growth venture fund of Saudi Arabia’s Aramco, and others including B Capital Group, Warburg Pincus, and Hong Kong-based Qiming Ventures.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese EV maker Hozon predicts fivefold jump in overseas sales as growth slows in hyper-competitive domestic market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247305/chinese-ev-maker-hozon-predicts-fivefold-jump-overseas-sales-growth-slows-hyper-competitive-domestic</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  The Shanghai-based maker of Neta branded cars aims to deliver 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets in 2024, mainly in Southeast Asia, accounting for one-third of Hozon's total deliveries. The company's first overseas assembly plant in Thailand started operation two months ahead of schedule, with an annual capacity of 20,000 units. The second assembly facility will be operational by the second quarter. Hozon expects to sell 1 million EVs in 2026, including 400,000 outside mainland China, and plans to build plants in the Middle East, Africa, and South America.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese EV start-up Hozon New Energy Automobile targets significant overseas sales growth in 2024.</li>    <li>Theme: Hozon's global expansion strategy to counter slowing domestic growth and fierce competition in the Chinese EV market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Hozon's confidence in the global appeal of Chinese-made electric cars and its goal of designing and manufacturing EVs for a global audience.</li>    <li>Main information: Hozon's sales target of 100,000 units in overseas markets in 2024; the operation of assembly plants in Thailand and Indonesia; plans to build plants in the Middle East, Africa, and South America; Hozon's aim to sell 1 million EVs in 2026, including 400,000 outside mainland China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  上海总部，生产 Neta 牌汽车的车企希望在今年向 60 个海外市场销售 10万辆汽车，重点放在东南亚市场。公司在泰国的第一家海外工厂于 11 月份开始组装汽车，比预期提前了两个月。2022 年 8 月 24 日，表演者在泰国曼谷的发布仪式上展示了 Hozon NETA V。照片：EPA-EFE中国的电动汽车 (EV) 初创公司 Hozon New Energy Automobile 预计，随着中国汽车制造商对国际销售的信心增强，以便应对国内增长放缓，其在 2024 年的海外销量将增长五倍。据副总裁周江透露，这家总部位于上海、生产 Neta 牌汽车的制造商计划今年在海外市场（主要在东南亚）交付 10 万辆汽车，因为他们已在泰国和印度尼西亚开设了组装厂。他说，到那时，海外销售额将占 Hozon 在 2024 年总交付量的三分之一，预计将达到 30 万辆。“总体而言，中国制造的电动汽车受到世界各地客户的欢迎，”他在周四的媒体简报中说。“此外，我们相信公司的全球视野，即设计和制造面向所有人的电动汽车。”Hozon New Energy Automobile 电动汽车等待从上海运往海外。照片：微博 11 月底时，Hozon（也被称为 Neta Auto）在其第一家泰国海外工厂开始组装汽车，比计划提前了大约两个月。这座工厂的年生产能力为 2 万辆，生产右舵版本的 Neta 汽车。周表示，Hozon 在中国境外的第二家组装厂将在第二季度投入运营。“由于国内市场增长放缓，那些品牌和汽车能够吸引外国买家的中国电动汽车制造商将在未来几年内加大海外扩张力度，”上海咨询公司 Suolei 的高级经理埃里克·汉 (Eric Han) 说。“事实上，他们在家乡的市场上凭借价格竞争，在其他市场享有较高的利润率。”卖空者以比亚迪为目标，全球顶级电动汽车制造商，随着竞争的加剧“哪吒”是 Neta 的名称之一，它在中国神话中是一位保护神。该品牌属于中国经济型电动汽车，目标客户是中低收入人群，他们更喜欢电池驱动的汽车，而不是耗油的内燃机汽车。根据惠誉评级公司在 11 月发布的一份报告，2024 年中国大陆的电动汽车销量预计将同比增长 20%，低于 2023 年预计的 30% 增幅。随着电动汽车市场挤满了 200 家企业，新一轮降价已开始生效，比亚迪（全球最大的制造商）和理想汽车等顶尖企业提供折扣以吸引买家。中国电动汽车：蔚来和小鹏推出目标富裕买家的 MPV 车型Hozon 在 2023 年向国内外客户交付了总计 127,496 辆汽车，较上年同期下降 16%。该公司在 8 月宣布已通过交叉融资交易筹集 70 亿元人民币（9.86 亿美元），但未披露投资者的姓名。交叉融资通常会给创业企业更多的时间和资金来发展业务，以便首次公开募股 (IPO)。投资者通常会以折扣价完成交叉融资交易，同时在预期 IPO 中站稳脚跟。中国比亚迪超越特斯拉，成为纯电动汽车的最大制造商根据电动汽车公司投资者之一奇虎 360 技术公司的年度报告，Hozon 在 2022 年报告净亏损 69 亿元人民币，比上一年 29 亿元人民币的亏损增加了 138%。周表示，该公司在 2026 年的目标是销售 100 万辆电动汽车，其中包括 40 万辆在海外销售。他还表示，该公司计划在中东、非洲和南美洲等市场建设工厂。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国电动汽车初创公司 Hozon New Energy Automobile 计划在 2024 年大幅提高海外销量。</li>    <li>主题：Hozon 的全球扩张战略，以应对国内增长放缓和中国电动汽车市场激烈的竞争。</li>    <li>观点：Hozon 对中国制造的电动汽车的全球吸引力的信心，以及其为全球受众设计和制造电动汽车的目标。</li>    <li>主要信息：Hozon 在 2024 年海外市场的销售目标为 10 万辆；泰国和印度尼西亚组装厂的运营；计划在中东、非洲和南美洲建设工厂；Hozon 计划在 2026 年销售 100 万辆电动汽车，其中包括 40 万辆在海外销售。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>drive (v.) - /draɪv/ 驾驶，驱动。    <p>原文例句：The plant, with an annual capacity of 20,000 units, produces right-hand-drive versions of Neta vehicles.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语drīfan，表示“使移动，驱使，驾驶”。在这个例句中，它指的是Neta汽车的右舵版本，即方向盘在汽车的右侧。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>supplier (n.) - /səˈplaɪ.ər/ 供应商，提供者。    <p>原文例句：Meanwhile, in the first three months of the year, Toyota maintained its position as the top supplier of passenger cars in the country, selling 11,388 units, a 2.8 per cent increase year on year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语supleier，意为“提供，供给”。在这个例句中，它指的是 passenger cars 的供应商，即汽车的提供者。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：However, this did not prevent China from becoming the top importer in terms of the number of vehicles purchased.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示在购买的汽车数量方面，中国成为最大的进口国。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>drive (v.) - /draɪv/ 驾驶，驱动。    <p>原文例句：The plant, with an annual capacity of 20,000 units, produces right-hand-drive versions of Neta vehicles.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语drīfan，表示“使移动，驱使，驾驶”。在这个例句中，它指的是Neta汽车的右舵版本，即方向盘在汽车的右侧。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>supplier (n.) - /səˈplaɪ.ər/ 供应商，提供者。    <p>原文例句：Meanwhile, in the first three months of the year, Toyota maintained its position as the top supplier of passenger cars in the country, selling 11,388 units  <ul><li>The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars aims to deliver 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia</li>
<li>Company started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand in November, about two months ahead of schedule</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/2f9a94ae-4006-4789-9e96-32506d8ef0a5_7020747c.jpg" /><figcaption>Performers present a Hozon NETA V during a launch ceremony in Bangkok, Thailand, on August 24, 2022. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> start-up Hozon New Energy Automobile expects its sales outside mainland China to jump five-fold in 2024 as the country’s increasingly confident carmakers look to international sales to counter slowing growth at home.</p><p>The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars, aims to deliver a total 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia, as it starts operations of assembly plants in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243541/chinese-ev-maker-hozon-kicks-operations-its-first-overseas-factory-thailand-it-steps-push-southeast" target="_self" title="">Thailand</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3230821/hozon-steps-plans-develop-right-hand-drive-neta-electric-cars-indonesia-it-pushes-ahead-its-hong" target="_self" title="">Indonesia</a>, according to vice-president Zhou Jiang.</p><p>At that level, overseas sales would account for a third of Hozon’s total deliveries in 2024, which are likely to hit 300,000 units, he said.</p><p>“Overall, Chinese-made electric cars are well received by customers around the world,” he said in a media briefing on Thursday. “Moreover, we are confident of our company’s global perspective with the goal of designing and manufacturing EVs for all the people.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo" class="image-inline caption" height="1328" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/338ee101-bc2d-48a2-8f3d-5ae81ace116c_515c76ff.jpg" title="Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo" width="2000" /><figcaption>Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo</figcaption></figure></div><p>At the end of November, Hozon, also known as Neta Auto, started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand, about two months ahead of schedule. The plant, with an annual capacity of 20,000 units, produces right-hand-drive versions of Neta vehicles.</p><p>Hozon’s second assembly facility outside China will be operational by the second quarter, Zhou said.</p><p>“Owing to a slowing domestic market, Chinese EV makers whose brands and vehicles can attract foreign buyers will step up their overseas expansion in the coming years,” said Eric Han, a ­senior ­manager at Suolei, an advisory firm in Shanghai. “Indeed, they enjoy a higher profit margin in other markets because of price competition at home.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247229/short-sellers-target-byd-worlds-top-ev-maker-rivalry-intensifies" title="">Short sellers target BYD, world’s top EV maker, as rivalry intensifies</a></h3><p>Neta is a variation of the name Nezha, a protection deity in Chinese mythology. The brand falls into the category of budget EVs in China, aimed at middle- and low-income drivers who prefer battery-powered vehicles to cars powered by petrol-guzzling internal combustion engines.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246896/chinese-ev-makers-face-day-reckoning-2024-competition-and-price-war-force-out-underperformers" target="_self" title="">EV sales in mainland China</a> are seen growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from the projected 30 per cent increase in 2023.</p><p>With the EV market crowded with 200 players, a new round of price cuts is in effect, with top players like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest maker</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3229066/xpeng-gets-volkswagens-us700-million-investment-jointly-develop-evs-worlds-largest-vehicle-market" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> offering discounts to lure buyers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/markets/article/3247151/china-evs-xpeng-and-li-auto-roll-out-x9-and-mega-mpvs-aimed-rich-buyers-bid-dominate-segment" title="">China EVs: Xpeng and Li Auto roll out minivan models with focus on rich buyers</a></h3><p>Hozon delivered a total of 127,496 vehicles to domestic and overseas customers in 2023, down 16 per cent year on year.</p><p>In August, the company announced it had <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3232811/chinese-ev-start-hozon-raises-us960-million-pre-ipo-financing-looks-expand-footprint-home-and-abroad" target="_self" title="">raised 7 billion yuan (US$986 million)</a> in a crossover financing deal, without disclosing the names of the investors.</p><p>Crossover financing typically gives a start-up more time and capital to develop its business before an initial public offering (IPO). Investors normally close cross-financing deals at a discounted price while gaining a foothold in the prospective IPO.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>Hozon reported a net loss of 6.9 billion yuan in 2022, 138 per cent wider than a 2.9 billion yuan loss in the previous year, according to the annual report of 360 Security Technology, one of the EV company’s investors.</p><p>Zhou said the carmaker targets total sales of 1 million EVs in 2026, including 400,000 outside mainland China. It also plans to build plants in markets like the Middle East, Africa and South America, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China is on track to be world AI leader by 2030, with Hong Kong’s help</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3247052/china-track-be-world-ai-leader-2030-hong-kongs-help</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>在中国，人工智能（AI）市场、企业和技术都在强劲增长，监管环境日益成熟。香港可以通过提供人工智能人才和资金来为这一发展做出贡献。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China is a key player in the global race for AI breakthroughs, and its AI industry is growing rapidly.</li>    <li>Theme: China has set its sights on becoming a world leader in AI by 2030, and it has been making significant progress in this area.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Hong Kong can play a role in China's AI development by providing talent and funding.</li>    <li>Main information: The rapid growth of China's AI market; the country's large number of AI enterprises and research papers; the supportive policies and infrastructure for AI development; the potential role of Hong Kong in providing talent and funding.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>在中国，人工智能（AI）市场、企业和技术都在强劲增长，监管环境日益成熟。香港可以通过提供人工智能人才和资金来为这一发展做出贡献。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国是全球人工智能突破竞赛中的主要参与者，其人工智能产业正在快速发展。</li>    <li>主题：中国已将目标锁定在2030年成为世界人工智能创新中心，并且在这一领域取得了重大进展。</li>    <li>观点：香港可以通过提供人才和资金在中国的AI发展中发挥作用。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国AI市场的快速增长；该国大量的人工智能企业和研究论文；支持人工智能发展的政策和基础设施；香港在提供人才和资金方面的潜在作用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>capacity (n.) - (尤指机器的)容量，能力。    <p>原文例句：One reason is that AI is a foundational technology with the capacity to increase productivity, boost competitiveness and help solve social challenges.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由capere（接受，采取）和-ity（状态或质量）组成，表示“能力，容纳或接受的能力，量”。在这个例句中，它指的是人工智能作为一项基础技术，有能力提高生产力，增强竞争力，并帮助解决社会挑战。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>contribute (v.) - (为某事)做出贡献，提供（钱或帮助）。    <p>原文例句：Hong Kong can contribute by providing AI talent and funding.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由con-（在一起）和tribuere（给予或分配）组成，表示“做出贡献，给予或提供”。在这个例句中，它指的是香港可以通过提供人工智能人才和资金来做出贡献。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>achieve dominance - 获得支配地位，取得优势。    <P>原文例句：Why are nations racing to achieve AI dominance? </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由achieve（达到，实现）和dominance（优势，统治地位）构成的，表示“获得支配地位，取得优势”。在这个例句中，它表示各国竞相争夺人工智能的优势地位。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Meanwhile, Hong Kong has a key role to play in China’s AI development. - 与此同时，香港在中国的人工智能发展中发挥着关键作用。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Hong Kong，谓语是has a key role to play，宾语是in China’s AI development。key role to play是一个固定短语，表示“关键作用”。China’s AI development是一个名词短语，表示“中国的人工智能发展”。这个句子的意思是说，香港在中国的人工智能发展中发挥着关键作用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词作主语 - 分词可以作为主语，表示执行动作或处于某种状态的人或物。    <p>原文例句：According to the State Council’s 2017 guidelines, AI should be used to promote China’s technology, economy and social welfare, maintain national security and contribute to the world.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，promote China’s technology, economy and social welfare、maintain national security和contribute to the world都是分词短语作主语。这三个分词短语分别表示“促进中国科技、经济和社会福利”、“维护国家安全”和“为世界做出贡献”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 所谓倒装句，就是故意把主语和谓语的位置倒过来的一种句子。    <p>原文例句：According to the 2023 AI Index Report by the Stanford Institute for Human-Centred Artificial Intelligence, global investment in AI has significantly increased over the last decade.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，谓语global investment in AI has significantly increased被放在了主语According to the 2023 AI Index Report by the Stanford Institute for Human-Centred Artificial Intelligence之前。这种情况就是所谓的倒装句语序，即把谓语和主语的位置颠倒过来，目的是为了强调句子的某个成分，比如时间、地点、方式等。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China’s AI market, firms and tech are growing strongly, while the regulatory climate is maturing. Hong Kong can contribute by providing AI talent and funding</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/ccb3683c-5993-48ba-ab9c-122ea06719a8_5241b49e.jpg" /><figcaption>A woman stands in front of a poster during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai on July 6 last year. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>If we are in the midst of a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3236727/expect-chinas-regulators-help-ai-firms-race-against-us-european-peers" target="_self" title="">global race</a> for artificial intelligence (AI) breakthroughs, China is definitely a key player. While 2023 has been a year of AI hype – especially for generative AI, amid the popularity of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> – the industry has been of interest to most countries for years and will only become more important.</p><p>According to the 2023 AI Index Report by the Stanford Institute for Human-Centred Artificial Intelligence, global investment in AI has significantly increased over the last decade. By 2022, private investment in AI had grown to 18 times greater than in 2013.</p><p>Back in 2017, China made AI a national priority, stating its ambition to become “the world’s premier artificial intelligence innovation centre” by 2030.</p><p>According to the State Council’s 2017 guidelines, AI should be used to promote China’s technology, economy and social welfare, maintain national security and contribute to the world. The guidelines also said: “AI should be applied in the public service and social management to build a safer, more comfortable and convenient society.”</p><p>Why are nations racing to achieve AI dominance? One reason is that AI is a foundational technology with the capacity to increase productivity, boost competitiveness and help solve social challenges.</p><p>So what does the AI industry in China look like? According to a recent Nikkei study, “China is the undisputed champion in artificial intelligence research papers … far surpassing the US in both quantity and quality”.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>China’s AI market is projected to reach US$38.89 billion this year, and will grow by a compound annual rate of 18 per cent to reach US$104.7 billion by 2030. This is less than the US market, the world’s largest at a projected US$106.5 billion this year.</p><p>In addition, China has more than 4,300 AI enterprises and at least 238 <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241659/chinese-tech-companies-frenzy-over-ai-large-language-models-huge-waste-resources-baidu-ceo-says" target="_self" title="">large language models</a> (LLMs) – deep-learning AI algorithms based on very large data sets – with tech giants such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3239981/baidu-launches-paid-version-ernie-bot-chinese-firms-rush-make-money-their-generative-ai-chatbots" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3244693/alibaba-research-unit-unveils-llm-tailored-southeast-asia-e-commerce-giant-pushes-ai-fast-growth" target="_self" title="">Alibaba</a> (owner of the South China Morning Post) <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239432/tencent-using-hunyuan-ai-model-180-services-amid-competition-local-rivals-baidu-and-alibaba" target="_self" title="">Tencent</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238698/alibaba-tencent-and-other-major-chinese-backers-invest-us342-million-start-zhipu-ai-tech-sector-sees" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239031/iflytek-says-its-large-language-model-outperforms-chatgpt-chinese-ai-firm-vows-counter-us-chip-curbs" target="_self" title="">iFlyTek</a> all venturing into the field.</p><p>It is fair to say China can indeed become a world leader in AI by 2030. This is especially given its number of AI companies, number of people working in them, advanced AI infrastructure and supportive policies.</p><p>Furthermore, China has 975 million smartphone users, by far the highest in any country, meaning it generates a vast amount of digital information – and data plays a paramount role in developing AI.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>From a regulatory perspective, China has taken a further step towards digitalisation and innovation. At the third Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation, President Xi Jinping proposed the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238360/belt-and-road-forum-china-launches-ai-framework-urging-equal-rights-and-opportunities-all-nations" target="_self" title="">Global AI Governance Initiative</a> for countries participating in the Belt and Road Initiative.</p><p>The initiative calls for a “people-centred” approach to AI (i.e., developing AI for the good of humanity and its progress), more inclusiveness and fairness in AI development so countries can benefit regardless of their political or economic situation, testing and assessment systems based on AI risk levels, and regulation reform to protect privacy and data security.</p><p>Even though Global AI Governance Initiative is not the first multilateral forum on AI, it is undoubtedly one of the bigger ones, with potential implications for the AI regulatory scene across the globe.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3216079/how-hong-kong-can-play-role-preventing-ai-armageddon" title="">How Hong Kong can play a role in preventing AI Armageddon</a></h3><p>Meanwhile, Hong Kong has a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226804/hong-kongs-financial-secretary-tells-waic-city-has-key-role-play-chinas-ai-development" target="_self" title="">key role</a> to play in China’s AI development. Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po has said the city can contribute by providing talent and funding.</p><p>At the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai in July, Chan <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226804/hong-kongs-financial-secretary-tells-waic-city-has-key-role-play-chinas-ai-development" target="_self" title="">said</a> Hong Kong had advantages when it came to attracting talent in the current geopolitical landscape: “Our universities have brought together scientific researchers from the mainland and around the world, and the Hong Kong government has given a lot of policy and financial support in the past few years.”</p><p>Moreover, Chan added, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3241373/guangdong-authorities-unveil-new-data-transfer-guidelines-amid-push-build-greater-bay-area-ai-hub" target="_self" title="">Greater Bay Area</a> has formed “the whole industrial chain of AI from research to market application”.</p><p>To sum up, China will probably become the global AI leader and Hong Kong has a role to play in this. China’s AI industry is powerful and will keep on growing. While it is still too early to say if the Global AI Governance Initiative will be a success, it is relevant that China starts leveraging the Belt and Road Initiative.</p><p><strong>Dr Oriol Caudevilla is an honorary fellow at the Asian Institute of International Financial Law at the University of Hong Kong and a board director at the Global Impact FinTech Forum. The views do not necessarily reflect those of any of the organisations the author collaborates with</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba reduces stake in GoGoX amid Hong Kong logistics services firm’s mounting losses, as it faces cutthroat competition on the mainland</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247308/alibaba-reduces-stake-gogox-amid-hong-kong-logistics-services-firms-mounting-losses-it-faces</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba has further reduced its stake in logistics service provider GoGoX Holdings due to cutthroat competition and regulatory pressure in the mainland's intracity delivery courier market.</li>    <li>Alibaba's stake in GoGoX has decreased to 8.89% from 12.23% in mid-2023.</li>    <li>GoGoX has faced losses since 2018 owing to fierce competition and its international expansion.</li>    <li>GoGoX saw its market value shrink by more than 90% since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022.</li>    <li>GoGoX is expected to remain in the red this year, but it narrowed its losses in the first half of 2023.</li>    <li>Alibaba's partial divestment in GoGoX comes amid preparations for the IPO of its logistics arm Cainiao Smart Logistics Network.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>阿里巴巴进一步减持物流服务提供商GoGoX控股的股份，原因是面临国内货运市场激烈的竞争和监管压力。</li>    <li>阿里巴巴所持有的GoGoX的股份从2023年中期的12.23%下降至8.89%。</li>    <li>自2018年以来，由于激烈的竞争和国际扩张，GoGoX一直陷入亏损。</li>    <li>自2022年6月在港交所首次亮相以来，GoGoX的市值已缩水超过90%。</li>    <li>预计GoGoX今年仍将亏损，但2023年上半年亏损有所收窄。</li>    <li>阿里巴巴在GoGoX的阶段性减持，是为了筹备物流臂菜鸟网络的首次公开募股（IPO）。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>cutthroat (adj.) - /ˈkʌtˌθrəʊt/ 非常激烈的，残酷的。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba Group Holding has further reduced its stake in Hong Kong-listed logistics service provider GoGoX Holdings, which is facing cutthroat competition and regulatory pressure in the mainland’s intracity delivery courier market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词由cut（切，割）和throat（喉咙）组成，表示“割断喉咙”，引申为“非常激烈的，残酷的”。在这个例句中，它指的是物流服务提供商GoGoX Holdings在大陆城市内部送货快递市场中面临非常激烈的竞争和监管压力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>intracity (adj.) - /ˈɪntrəˌsɪti/ 城市内部的。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba Group Holding has further reduced its stake in Hong Kong-listed logistics service provider GoGoX Holdings, which is facing cutthroat competition and regulatory pressure in the mainland’s intracity delivery courier market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词由intra（ внутри）和city（城市）组成，表示“在城市内部”。在这个例句中，它指的是物流服务提供商GoGoX Holdings在大陆城市内部送货快递市场中面临非常激烈的竞争和监管压力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>courier (n.) - /ˈkʌrɪər/ 快递员，信使。    <p>原文例句：GoGoX is competing in a crowded on-demand cargo delivery services market on the mainland, where its hometown rival Lalatech Holdings operates Huolala.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于古法语的correor（信使），表示“快递员，信使”。在这个例句中，它指的是物流服务提供商GoGoX在大陆城市内部送货快递市场中面临非常激烈的竞争，其家乡的竞争对手Lalatech Holdings经营着Huolala。    </p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>narrow down (v.) - /næroʊ ˈdaʊn/ 缩小，限制。    <p>原文例句：The company narrowed its losses to 642.9 million yuan (US$90.37 million) in the first half of 2023, from 1.05 billion yuan in the same period in 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由narrow（狭窄）和down（向下）组成，表示“变窄，变小”。在这个例句中，它指的是该公司2023年上半年的亏损从2022年同期的10.5亿人民币收窄至6.429亿人民币。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>similar to - 类似于，相似于。    <p>原文例句：“This is still a market with huge demand and many opportunities even with the price wars, similar to those in the bike-sharing and ride-hailing sectors,” Zhang said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由similar（相似的）和to（到）组成，表示“与……相似，与……类似”。在这个例句中，它指的是即使存在价格战，这个市场仍然有巨大的需求和许多机会，类似于共享单车和叫车服务行业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba logistics spin-off Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout - 阿里巴巴物流子公司菜鸟收购百世以提升海外地位。    <p>句子分析：这是一个名词性复合句，主句是Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout，其中主语是Cainiao，谓语是to boost海外地位，宾语是Best buyout。Alibaba logistics spin-off是一个名词性短语，作主语Cainiao的定语，表示阿里巴巴的物流子公司菜鸟。with Best buyout是一个介词短语，作状语，表示通过收购百世来提升海外地位。这个句子的意思是说，阿里巴巴的物流子公司菜鸟收购百世以提升海外地位。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>非谓语动词作主语 - 可以用在句子中作主语。    <p>原文例句：Following those moves, the biggest shareholder of GoGoX remains billionaire Yao Jinbo – the founder, chairman and chief executive of mainland Chinese online classifieds giant 58.com – with a 38.69 per cent share.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，Following those moves是一个非谓语动词短语，作主语，表示在那些举动之后。remains billionaire Yao Jinbo是谓语，其中remains是谓语动词，billionaire Yao Jinbo是主语。这个句子的意思是说，在那些举动之后，GoGoX的最大股东仍然是亿万富翁姚劲波——大陆在线分类广告巨头58.com的创始人、董事长兼首席执行官——持有38.69%的股份。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>倒装 - 把句子中通常在后面的成分提前到前面。    <p>原文例句：Still, GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，Still, GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018是一个倒装句，把通常在后面的成分Still提前到了前面。owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion是一个介词短语，作状语，表示由于大陆激烈的竞争和持续的国际扩张。这个句子的意思是说，自2018年以来，GoGoX一直亏损，原因是大陆激烈的竞争和持续的国际扩张。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Alibaba has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, leaving it with an 8.89 per cent equity holding as of December</li>
<li>GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/2c781207-f507-4907-bf84-a2425ae1e9fa_2a843a15.jpg" /><figcaption>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022. Image: GoGoX</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> has further reduced its stake in Hong Kong-listed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/transport-and-logistics" target="_self" title="">logistics</a> service provider <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/gogovan" target="_self" title="">GoGoX Holdings</a>, which is facing cutthroat competition and regulatory pressure in the mainland’s intracity delivery courier market.</p><p>Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, slashing its equity holding to 8.89 per cent as of late December from 12.23 per cent in mid-2023, according to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong-stock-market" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong stock exchange</a> records.</p><p>Following those moves, the biggest shareholder of GoGoX remains billionaire Yao Jinbo – the founder, chairman and chief executive of mainland Chinese online classifieds giant 58.com – with a 38.69 per cent share. GoGoX co-founder Chen Xiaohua, with a 5.95 per cent stake, retains his position as the company’s third-biggest shareholder.</p><p>Founded as GoGoVan in Hong Kong in 2013, GoGoX <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/china-tech/article/2108658/gogovan-become-hong-kongs-first-us1-billion-start-after-merger-58" target="_self" title="">became the city’s first unicorn in 2017</a> after its merger with short-distance freight service platform operator 58 Suyun. Still, GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/ab59b907-e9a0-49bd-b7d8-bd576851c04c_8a6158cb.jpg" title="GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX" width="2000" /><figcaption>GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX</figcaption></figure></div><p>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3182875/gogox-shares-rise-hkex-trading-debut-listing-hong-kongs" target="_self" title="">its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022</a>. Its share price closed up 6.8 per cent to HK$0.63 on Thursday.</p><p>The company – which expects to remain in the red this year, according to its 2022 prospectus – narrowed its losses to 642.9 million yuan (US$90.37 million) in the first half of 2023, from 1.05 billion yuan in the same period in 2022.</p><p>GoGoX also went through a major management reshuffle in December, as founder Chen resigned from his chairman role. The company tapped Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, another co-founder and the co-chief executive of GoGoX, as its new chairman.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hangzhou" target="_self" title="">Hangzhou</a>-based Alibaba’s partial divestment initiative at GoGoX comes amid its preparations for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3235860/alibabas-cainiao-files-us1-billion-ipo-helping-hong-kong-land-worlds-second-biggest-listing-2023" target="_self" title="">initial public offering (IPO) of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network</a>, which submitted its A1 filing to the Hong Kong stock exchange last September.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee" class="image-inline caption" height="1298" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/daae0416-e269-4485-a0b4-cb91724c76ec_051879a6.jpg" title="Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee" width="2000" /><figcaption>Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee</figcaption></figure></div><p>Alibaba is trying to stop the bleeding with its stake cut, as its initial goal with the GoGoX investment was to gain financial returns through the listing and create synergy with its own services, according to Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangdong-based consultancy iiMedia.</p><p>“This is still a market with huge demand and many opportunities even with the price wars, similar to those in the bike-sharing and ride-hailing sectors,” Zhang said. “So the bigger problem is more likely to lie within the operation of GoGoX, which will need revolutionary measures to reverse its losses.”</p><p>At present, GoGoX is competing in a crowded on-demand cargo delivery services market on the mainland, where its hometown rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246071/chinese-tech-ipos-watch-2024-global-fast-fashion-online-retailer-shein-leads-pack" target="_self" title="">Lalatech Holdings</a> operates Huolala. Competition has become more intense in recent years after traditional logistics firms and ride-hailing companies also set up similar app-based courier delivery operations.</p><p>Chinese ride-hailing giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/didi-chuxing" target="_self" title="">Didi Chuxing</a>, for example, started its own intracity freight service in 2020 and launched its autonomous trucking business Kargobot in April last year. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3137463/full-truck-chinas-uber-trucks-raise-us157-billion-us" target="_self" title="">Full Truck Alliance</a>, known as China’s “Uber for trucks” and focused on long-haul logistics services, in April launched its Sheng Sheng brand dedicated to same-city delivery.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240676/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-will-enhance-its-overseas-presence-proposed-buyout-local-rival-best" title="">Alibaba logistics spin-off Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout</a></h3><p>Huolala currently leads the mainland’s intracity courier delivery services market with a 61 per cent share, according to Frost &amp; Sullivan data cited in the prospectus of Lalatech, which is eyeing a Hong Kong IPO.</p><p>Similar to on-demand services like ride hailing, the early stage of competition in intracity freight services has relied heavily on subsidies for users.</p><p>That “cash-burning” business model, however, has faced increased scrutiny from regulators, who recently summoned Lalatech for talks regarding drivers’ rights and unfair price cuts.</p><p>GoGoX and other courier delivery services providers have also received “reminders” from regulators about their operations in the past year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Amid US tech war, Premier Li Qiang urges China to focus on application of core technologies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  李强总理本周对中部湖北省进行了为期两天的访问，期间走访了高校和制造企业，包括半导体、激光和化工企业。他呼吁在中美科技战的大背景下，加强产学研合作。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 李总理考察湖北省期间强调加强产学研合作，推进科技自立，加快经济复苏，提振市场信心。</li>    <li>Theme: 中美科技战背景下，加强产学研合作，推动科技自立，助推经济复苏和市场信心。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 产学研合作是科技创新的关键，需通过精准施策，优化政策，促进科技成果转化为市场产出。</li>    <li>Main information: 李总理视察高校和企业，敦促加强产学研合作，以新兴技术驱动生产力，加快经济复苏；湖北省作为长江经济带的核心区域，需要加强产学研合作，推动科研成果转化；中美科技战背景下，中国不断寻求突破关键技术制约，实现科技自立；李总理还视察了水利项目和化工企业，倡导发展循环经济，实现绿色发展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Premier Li Qiang visited universities as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers during a two-day visit to the central Hubei province this week. He called for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive, urging for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States. Li stressed the need to accelerate the development of productivity driven by emerging technologies and kick-start a robust economic performance for the year. He emphasized the importance of enhancing collaboration between academia and business through precise and supportive measures to facilitate the transformation of scientific research into market production.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Li's visit focused on promoting technological self-reliance, collaboration between academia and industry, and stimulating economic growth amid the ongoing US-China tech war.</li>    <li>Theme: China's efforts to enhance its technological capabilities, bridge the gap between research and market applications, and bolster economic recovery.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Li emphasized the significance of collaboration, innovation, and market-oriented research to address the challenges posed by the tech war and achieve sustainable economic growth.</li>    <li>Main information: Li's tour included visits to universities, tech companies, and industrial sites, highlighting the need for improved cooperation between academia and industry, stronger investment in emerging technologies, and the promotion of green development and circular economy practices.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>collaboration (n.) - /kəˌlæbəˈreɪʃən/ 协作，合作。    <p>原文例句：Premier Li Qiang called for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由co-（共同）和labor（工作）构成的，表示“共同工作，合作”。在这个例句中，它指的是李总理呼吁在中美科技战的背景下加强产学研合作。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>semiconductor (n.) - /ˌsemɪkənˈdʌktər/ 半导体。    <p>原文例句：Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central Hubei province this week. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由semi-（半）和conductor（导体）构成的，表示“半导体”。在这个例句中，它指的是李总理在湖北省考察了半导体制造企业。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>amid the ongoing tech war - 在正在进行的技术战中。    <P>原文例句：Premier Li Qiang called for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由amid（在……中）和the ongoing tech war（正在进行的技术战）构成的，表示“在正在进行的技术战中”。在这个例句中，它表示李总理在中美科技战的背景下呼吁加强产学研合作。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>more and better - 更多、更好的。    <P>原文例句：Premier Li Qiang pushed for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由more（更多）和better（更好）构成的，表示“更多、更好的”。在这个例句中，它表示李总理在推动中国科技自立的过程中，强调要加强核心技术的市场应用，做到“更多、更好”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>He called for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States. - 他呼吁在中美科技战的背景下加强产学研合作。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是He，谓语是called，宾语是for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States。这个句子表示李总理呼吁在中美科技战的背景下加强产学研合作。这个句子的结构是比较简单的，但是其中的几个单词和短语都比较重要。例如，collaboration（合作）是一个比较重要的单词，它表示“共同工作，合作”；academia（学术界）是一个比较重要的短语，它表示“高校和科研机构”；business（企业）是一个比较重要的单词，它表示“企业和公司”；amid（在……中）是一个比较重要的介词，它表示“在……中”；the ongoing tech war（正在进行的技术战）是一个比较重要的短语，它表示“中美科技战”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 表示强调句子的某个成分，强调的成分要放在句首，主语和助动词之间。    <p>原文例句：We must expedite the development of productivity driven by emerging technology, and kick-start a robust economic start of the year. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句型的句子，强调的成分是We，它放在了句首，主语是we，助动词是must，谓语是expedite the development of productivity driven by emerging technology, and kick-start a robust economic start of the year。这个句子的意思是，我们必须加快新兴技术驱动的生产力发展，并启动一个强劲的经济开局。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>倒装句型 - 表示强调特殊情况，将谓语动词提前到主语之前。    <p>原文例句：Given the escalating containment efforts by the United States, Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句型的句子，将谓语动词is continually seeking提前到了主语Beijing之前。这个句子的意思是，鉴于美国不断升级的围堵措施，北京一直在寻求用自主技术解决关键环节的问题。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central province of Hubei this week</li>
<li>He called for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/3a8be64d-f864-409e-859c-0eef4d4f4ae3_9e966ee7.jpg" /><figcaption>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central Hubei province this week.</figcaption></figure><p>Premier Li Qiang pushed for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive during a two-day tour of Hubei province this week, with the world’s second-largest economy in urgent need of stabilisation to quell investor concerns and lift market confidence.</p><p>“We must expedite the development of productivity driven by emerging technology, and kick-start a robust economic start of the year,” he said in a statement following the tour of the central province on Tuesday and Wednesday, according to the official Xinhua News Agency.</p><p>Hubei is a key part of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3237870/xi-jinping-tells-chinas-biggest-economic-zone-balance-growth-and-security-and-no-more-mega-projects" target="_self" title="">Yangtze River Economic Belt,</a> which is one of President Xi Jinping’s key regional development strategies. It includes 11 provinces and municipalities, and accounts for over 40 per cent of China’s population and economic size.</p><p>“We need to improve collaboration between academia and business, by introducing more precise and supportive measures, thus fluidly turning scientific research into market production,” the premier said after visiting HGLaser Engineering and semiconductor manufacturer Yangtze Memory Technologies Corporation (YMTC) in the provincial capital of Wuhan.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245242/amid-us-tech-war-china-stuck-middle-technology-trap-it-time-open-its-doors-wider" title="">Time to open its doors wider, or will China fall into a middle-technology trap?</a></h3><p>Given the escalating <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245242/amid-us-tech-war-china-stuck-middle-technology-trap-it-time-open-its-doors-wider" target="_self" title="">containment efforts by the United States,</a> Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology.</p><p>Development was also mentioned as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3244856/chinas-development-biggest-political-priority-key-econ-meeting-leaders-vow-counter-risks-lift" target="_self" title="">China’s biggest priority</a> for 2024 at the tone-setting central economic work conference in mid-December.</p><p>HGLaser introduced China’s first fully domestically produced chip-cutting machine in July, according to the WeChat account of Donghu New Technology Development Zone in Wuhan.</p><p>But unlike China’s leading memory chip maker, YMTC, HGLaser has not been sanctioned by the US. YMTC was added to the US trade blacklist <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3203494/us-adds-36-chinese-companies-export-blacklist-including-countrys-top-flash-memory-chip-maker?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">in December 2022.</a></p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>During his two-day tour, Li also inspected Wuhan University’s laboratory on high-resolution Earth observation and the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3241788/chinas-gps-beidou-navigation-system-recognised-global-standard-commercial-aviation-important" target="_self" title="">BeiDou navigation system.</a></p><p>The home-grown BeiDou system, which is China’s equivalent to the US’ Global Positioning System (GPS), can be applied to agriculture, forestry and meteorology.</p><p>China, though, has long suffered from loose cooperation between academia, including universities and research institutes, and enterprises focused on market applications.</p><p>The cooperation issues include poor communication and insufficient resource sharing, which creates obstacles affecting the transformation of inventions in China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3241788/chinas-gps-beidou-navigation-system-recognised-global-standard-commercial-aviation-important" title="">‘Important milestone’: China’s GPS-like BeiDou navigation system hits new height</a></h3><p>As of the end of 2022, only 3.9 per cent of inventions at Chinese universities were industrialised, according to the latest data available by the China National Intellectual Property Administration, compared to around 50 per cent in the US.</p><p>Li also visited water conservancy projects and a chemical company focusing on green development in Yichang, as well as a battery industrial estate set up by Guangdong Brunp Recycling Technology, a subsidiary under China’s leading lithium battery maker, Contemporary Amperex Technology (CATL).</p><p>CATL is a supplier to several carmakers, including Tesla, BMW and Volkswagen.</p><p>The premier also encouraged companies to promote China’s sustainability by focusing on the circular economy to drive companies up the value chain.</p><p>The circular economy model seeks to minimise wasting resources and environmental impact by extending the life cycle of products.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>PDD halts development of local services offering to avoid head-on competition with Meituan and Ele.me, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247286/pdd-halts-development-local-services-offering-avoid-head-competition-meituan-and-eleme-report-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  The Chinese e-commerce giant PDD has halted the development of its local life services offering due to intense competition in the market. With an estimated worth of 35 trillion yuan by 2025, the sector has attracted major players such as Meituan, Alibaba Group Holding, and ByteDance, leading PDD to refrain from direct confrontation.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: PDD's retreat from local life services due to market competition.</li>    <li>Theme: The intensifying rivalry among Chinese Big Tech firms in the local services market leads PDD to change strategy.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The challenges faced by PDD in establishing a foothold in the local services market and the dynamic landscape of the industry.</li>    <li>Main information: PDD's initial plans for local services; the company's strengths and weaknesses in the market; the dominance of Meituan and other competitors; PDD's continued expansion overseas.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国电商巨头拼多多因市场竞争激烈，已停止发展本地生活服务业务。该领域预计到2025年价值将达到35万亿元人民币，吸引了美团、阿里巴巴集团控股、字节跳动等巨头，导致拼多多选择避免正面交锋。  <ul>    <li>摘要：拼多多因市场竞争退出本地生活服务领域。</li>    <li>主题：中国互联网巨头在本地生活服务领域的竞争加剧，导致拼多多改变了战略。</li>    <li>观点：拼多多在本地生活服务领域站稳脚跟所面临的挑战，以及行业格局的动态变化。</li>    <li>主要信息：拼多多对本地生活的最初计划；公司在该领域的优势和劣势；美团等竞争对手的优势；拼多多继续在海外扩张。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rivalry (n.) - /ˈraɪv(ə)lri/ 竞争，敌对。    <p>原文例句：Chinese Big Tech firms have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Rivalry可以追溯到中世纪的rival，意思为竞争对手，敌对者。rivalry这个单词主要指“竞争，敌对”。在这个例句中，它的意思是中国科技巨头在预计2025年价值35万亿元人民币的地方服务市场上展开了激烈的竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>dominance (n.) - /ˈdɒmɪnəns/ 统治，支配。    <p>原文例句：Meituan, which merged with restaurant review site Dianping and bike-sharing start-up Mobike, currently leads the sector with a range of food delivery, taxi-ride and hotel reservation services.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Dominance源于拉丁语dominari，意为统治，奴役。Dominance主要指“统治，支配”。在这个例句中，它的意思是美团通过与餐厅点评网站大众点评和共享单车创业公司摩拜单车的合并，目前在提供食品配送、出租车出行和酒店预订服务等一系列服务方面处于领先地位。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>head-to-head rivalry - 正面较量，面对面的竞争。    <p>原文例句：PDD Holdings has halted work on its local life services offering, avoiding head-to-head rivalry with Meituan, Alibaba Group Holding and ByteDance.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Head-to-head rivalry是一个形容词短语，Head-to-head表示“面对面的，正面相对的”，rivalry表示“竞争，敌对”。Head-to-head rivalry这个词组主要指“正面较量，面对面的竞争”。在这个例句中，它的意思是拼多多暂停了本地生活服务业务，避免与美团、阿里巴巴集团控股和字节跳动正面交锋。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>PDD had “completely halted [development of] the local services business”, according to Chinese media outlet LatePost. - 根据中国媒体《晚点Post》，拼多多已“完全停止了本地生活服务业务的开发”。<p>句子分析：这是一个陈述句，主语是PDD，谓语是had halted，宾语是development of the local services business。completely是一个副词，修饰halted，表示完全地。according to Chinese media outlet LatePost是一个介词短语，表示根据中国媒体《晚点Post》的报道。这个句子的意思是说，根据中国媒体《晚点Post》的报道，拼多多已经完全停止了本地生活服务业务的开发。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：PDD had leveraged Duoduo Maicai’s business development team of around 3,000 people to sign up bricks-and-mortar outlets, such as restaurants and tourist attractions, the report said.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + been + 过去分词。其中had是have的过去式，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示拼多多利用多多买菜的约3000人的业务发展团队签约了实体店，例如餐馆和旅游景点，这一动作或状态发生在报道撰写之前。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>PDD had planned to launch local services offering in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, report says</li>
<li>Chinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in local services market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/416b82eb-4e16-46af-8cd9-c30d0a415c2f_5ba32be4.jpg" /><figcaption>Chinese Big Tech firms have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025. Photo: AFP </figcaption></figure><p>E-commerce giant PDD Holdings has halted work on its local life services offering, avoiding head-to-head rivalry with Meituan, Alibaba Group Holding and ByteDance, whose Douyin short video app has also dipped a toe into the sector.</p><p>PDD has “completely halted [development of] the local services business”, according to Chinese media outlet LatePost. PDD did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p>PDD, whose market cap overtook Alibaba in November after the firm beat revenue estimates, had planned to launch the service – which facilitates in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets – in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, LatePost reported. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>PDD had leveraged Duoduo Maicai’s business development team of around 3,000 people to sign up bricks-and-mortar outlets, such as restaurants and tourist attractions, the report said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244976/amazon-doubles-down-china-e-commerce-strategy-rivals-shein-temu-gain-traction" title="">Amazon doubles down on China e-commerce strategy as Shein, Temu gain traction</a></h3><p>However, PDD’s management has not been completely satisfied with the performance of Duoduo Maicai, which was established in 2020 in the midst of the Covid-19 pandemic. It enables residents in a community to purchase groceries and other daily essentials in bulk, bringing prices down.</p><p>Although the unit has become an industry leader, it is not profitable due to low gross margins, according to the LatePost report, which cited a PDD executive. Duoduo Maicai is nevertheless expected to remain operational despite the halting of local life services, according to Chinese news portal Sina.</p><p>Chinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan (US$4.9 trillion) by 2025, according to estimates by market intelligence firm iResearch.</p><p>Meituan, which merged with restaurant review site Dianping and bike-sharing start-up Mobike, currently leads the sector with a range of food delivery, taxi-ride and hotel reservation services.</p><p>Alibaba has been seeking to catch up with the merger of its Koubei restaurant rating service and navigation app Amap. Alibaba’s local services segment also runs food delivery unit <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3048045/chinas-eleme-deliver-food-100-restaurants-frontline-medical-staff?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Ele.me</a>, grocery delivery service Taoxianda, and online travel platform Fliggy.</p><p>ByteDance’s Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has leveraged its more than 600 million daily active users to make <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3207434/bytedance-primes-short-video-app-douyin-challenge-meituan-demand-local-services-amid-chinas-push?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">aggressive moves in segments of on-demand e-commerce</a>. The company set up a centre dedicated to developing local services in 2020.</p><p>Abandoning the local services market comes as PDD continues to expand aggressively overseas with its Temu app, now available in the United States, Japan and several other markets. The budget shopping platform helped drive an almost doubling of PDD’s third-quarter revenue to 68.8 billion yuan.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Microsoft to show off Copilot AI key for Windows keyboards at CES, in first change to layout since 1994</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247280/microsoft-show-copilot-ai-key-windows-keyboards-ces-first-change-layout-1994</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Microsoft is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to allow users to access its AI assistant.</li>    <li>The Copilot key will be located to the right of the space bar, making it easily accessible for users.</li>    <li>The new key is a testament to Microsoft's commitment to artificial intelligence and its integration into Windows.</li>    <li>Microsoft envisions 2024 as "the year of the AI PC," with a focus on incorporating AI technology into various products.</li>    <li>The company has been retooling its products around AI tech, including Windows, Office, Bing search, and customer and finance products.</li>    <li>Microsoft's partnership with OpenAI and investment in its GPT-4 technology play a significant role in its AI endeavors.</li>    <li>Despite the introduction of AI features, Microsoft's push into AI services has yet to boost sales, suggesting a need for further enhancements.</li>    <li>Microsoft's efforts to integrate AI into hardware and silicon may lead to pressure on consumers to upgrade as the technology evolves.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>微软将在 Windows 键盘上添加一个 Copilot 键，允许用户立即调出其人工智能助手。</li>    <li>Copilot 键将位于空格键的右侧，方便用户轻松访问。</li>    <li>这个新按键证明了微软对人工智能的承诺，以及将其集成到 Windows 中的决心。</li>    <li>微软设想 2024 年是“AI PC 之年”，重点将人工智能技术融入各种产品中。</li>    <li>该公司一直在围绕人工智能技术对其产品进行改造，包括 Windows、Office、Bing 搜索以及客户和金融产品。</li>    <li>微软与 OpenAI 的合作以及对其实 GPT-4 技术的投资在其人工智能努力中发挥着重要作用。</li>    <li>尽管引入了人工智能功能，但微软进军人工智能服务领域并未提振销量，这表明需要进一步改进。</li>    <li>微软努力将人工智能集成到硬件和硅中可能会给消费者带来升级压力，因为该技术不断发展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Copilot (n.) - 副驾驶员，辅助飞行员。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft is adding a button to the Windows keyboard to activate its AI Copilot service. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Copilot 在这里指的是微软的人工智能助手，它可以帮助用户完成各种任务，比如创建图像、撰写电子邮件和总结文本。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>retool (v.) - 改造，更新。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Retool 在这里指的是微软对旗下产品的改造，使其能够更好地利用人工智能技术来生成新的内容。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>seamless (adj.) - 无缝的，流畅的。    <p>原文例句：“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Seamlessly 在这里指的是人工智能技术将与 Windows 系统、硅芯片和硬件无缝集成，从而为用户提供流畅、自然的使用体验。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>the year of the AI PC - AI PC 之年。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft sees 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“The year of the AI PC”指的是微软将 2024 年视为“AI PC 之年”，这表明微软将重点关注将人工智能技术融入个人电脑。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>weave into - 融入，编织到。    <p>原文例句：“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“Weave into”在这里指的是人工智能技术将与 Windows 系统、硅芯片和硬件无缝集成，就像编织在一起一样。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Microsoft’s Copilot key will be available this month on new Windows 11 computers. - 微软的 Copilot 键将于本月在新的 Windows 11 电脑上提供。</li>    <p>句子解析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是 Microsoft’s Copilot key，谓语是 will be available，宾语是 new Windows 11 computers。句子说明了微软的 Copilot 键将于本月在新的 Windows 11 电脑上提供。</p>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Microsoft sees 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’ and has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content. - 微软将 2024 年视为“AI PC 之年”，过去一年一直在围绕能够生成新内容的人工智能技术改造其最受欢迎的产品。</li>    <p>句子解析：这是一个复合句，由两个简单句组成。第一个简单句的主语是 Microsoft，谓语是 sees，宾语是 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’。第二个简单句的主语是 Microsoft，谓语是 has spent，宾语是 the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content。句子说明了微软将 2024 年视为“AI PC 之年”，过去一年一直在围绕能够生成新内容的人工智能技术改造其最受欢迎的产品。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 (Present Perfect Tense) - 表示从过去开始到现在已经完成或持续到现在的动作或状态。</li>    <p>原文例句：Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content. - 微软过去一年一直在围绕能够生成新内容的人工智能技术改造其最受欢迎的产品。</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，has spent 是现在完成时的形式，表示微软从过去开始到现在已经持续了一年的改造行动。这也是一个简单的句子，主语是 Microsoft，谓语是 has spent，宾语是 the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content。句子说明了微软过去一年一直在围绕能够生成新内容的人工智能技术改造其最受欢迎的产品。</p>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 (Passive Voice) - 表示动作或状态由句子的主语承受。</li>    <p>原文例句：The Redmond, Washington-based company sees 2024 as “the year of the AI PC”, according to Mehdi. - 总部位  <ul><li>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Start key</li>
<li>The tech giant sees 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’ and has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/e31b152f-c194-4f64-8148-b14c9b1dd6e5_1adc5e70.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft said it is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to allow users to immediately call up its artificial intelligence assistant. Photo: YouTube / Windows</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft</a> is adding a button to the Windows keyboard to activate its AI Copilot service, with the first devices to sport the new key available this month.</p><p>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Windows/Start key in 1994, underscoring the company’s commitment to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a>. Microsoft’s hardware partners will show off Windows 11 computers with the Copilot button over the coming days at the CES technology conference and, over time, it will become a required feature.</p><p>The short cut will help users create images, write emails and summarise text with the help of AI.</p><p>“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234530/microsoft-sees-booming-enterprise-ai-demand-hong-kong-amid-us-china-tech-war-threatens-cloud" title="">Microsoft touts booming enterprise AI demand in Hong Kong amid cloud push</a></h3><p>The Redmond, Washington-based company sees 2024 as “the year of the AI PC”, according to Mehdi, mirroring the budding trend among smartphone makers to tout their latest models as “AI phones”. Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves, but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets. That list now includes Windows, Office, Bing search, security software and customer and finance products. The work heavily leverages the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">GPT-4 technology</a> from OpenAI, in which Microsoft has invested US$13 billion.</p><p>For device makers, Microsoft’s push into AI services has not yet translated into a boost for sales, as the novel Copilot features are being rolled out to new and existing devices alike. Mehdi’s promise of weaving AI into hardware and silicon may signal more pressure on consumers to upgrade as Microsoft evolves and improves its AI proposition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese search engine giant Baidu to donate quantum computing facility to state-backed lab in similar move to Alibaba</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247255/chinese-search-engine-giant-baidu-donate-quantum-computing-facility-state-backed-lab-similar-move</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese tech giants Baidu and Alibaba are donating their quantum computing research facilities to research institutions, a move that reflects the intense competition in the country's artificial intelligence (AI) race. Baidu is donating its facility to the Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences (BAQIS), while Alibaba donated its lab to Zhejiang University last year. Both companies aim to contribute to the advancement of quantum computing and foster collaboration in the field.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese tech giants contribute quantum computing research facilities to research institutions.</li>    <li>Theme: Baidu and Alibaba's donations signal the intensifying competition in China's AI race.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Quantum computing's potential to revolutionize various industries and the strategic importance of fostering research in this field.</li>    <li>Main information: Baidu's donation of its quantum computing facility to BAQIS; Alibaba's previous donation of its quantum lab to Zhejiang University; the significance of quantum computing in solving complex problems beyond the capabilities of traditional computers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国科技巨头百度和阿里巴巴正在将其量子计算研究设施捐赠给科研机构，此举反映了该国人工智能（AI）领域日益激烈的竞争。百度将自己的设施捐赠给北京量子信息科学研究院（BAQIS），而阿里巴巴去年将其实验室捐赠给了浙江大学。两家公司均旨在为量子计算的发展做出贡献，并促进该领域的合作。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国科技巨头为科研机构贡献量子计算研究设施。</li>    <li>主题：百度和阿里巴巴的捐赠标志着中国人工智能领域竞争的加剧。</li>    <li>观点：量子计算的潜力能够彻底改变各个行业，以及在该领域促进研究的重要战略意义。</li>    <li>主要信息：百度将量子计算设施捐赠给BAQIS；阿里巴巴之前将量子实验室捐赠给浙江大学；量子计算在解决传统计算机无法解决的复杂问题中的重要性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>quantum computing (n.) - 量子计算    <p>原文例句：Although quantum computers are not designed to replace traditional computers, they are able to solve very complex statistical problems via simultaneous multiple calculations, making them much faster. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个术语是指一种利用量子力学原理来进行计算的计算方式，这种计算方式具有比传统计算机更快的速度和更强的计算能力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>intellectual property (n.) - 知识产权    <p>原文例句：In March last year, Baidu and BAQIS jointly launched the country’s first quantum computing intellectual property (IP) alliance, with the goal of facilitating easier IP cross-licensing and innovation in the industry. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指由法律所保护的对象，如版权、商标、专利等，通常涉及创造性的作品、技术创新或商业信息等领域。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 关于，就……而言。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组通常用来说明或强调某件事的具体情况或方面。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Baidu said on Thursday it would donate its Baidu Institute for Quantum Computing and associated experiment apparatus to BAQIS, a government-backed laboratory. - 百度周四宣布将把百度量子计算研究所和相关的实验仪器捐赠给政府支持的实验室BAQIS。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Baidu said it would donate its Baidu Institute for Quantum Computing and associated experiment apparatus to BAQIS，其中主语是Baidu，谓语是said，宾语是it would donate its Baidu Institute for Quantum Computing and associated experiment apparatus to BAQIS。on Thursday是一个时间状语，表示周四。a government-backed laboratory是一个定语从句，修饰BAQIS，表示BAQIS是一个政府支持的实验室。这个句子的意思是说，百度周四宣布将把百度量子计算研究所和相关的实验仪器捐赠给政府支持的实验室BAQIS。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Chinese scientists use quantum computing to simulate black hole. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示中国科学家已经使用了量子计算来模拟黑洞。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物引起的或造成的。    <p>原文例句：New US investment curbs to have limited impact on China’s targeted tech sectors.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语态，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。被动语态表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物引起的或造成的，强调动作或状态的接受者。在这个例句中，它表示新的美国投资限制对中国的目标科技行业的影响有限。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Last March, Baidu and BAQIS jointly launched the country’s first quantum computing intellectual property alliance, with the goal of facilitating easier IP cross-licensing</li>
<li>In 2023, Alibaba’s in-house research institution Damo Academy announced it was donating its own quantum lab to Zhejiang University</li>
</ul><p>Chinese search engine giant Baidu is donating its quantum computing research facility to the Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences (BAQIS), in a move similar to one made last year by e-commerce giant Alibaba Group Holding, as both firms lock horns in the country’s artificial intelligence (AI) race.</p><p>Baidu said on Thursday it would donate its Baidu Institute for Quantum Computing and associated experiment apparatus to BAQIS, a government-backed laboratory. The two parties are currently discussing details of the donation, according to a company statement.</p><p>Beijing-based Baidu, which was an early Chinese investor in AI applications including autonomous driving, established its quantum computing facility in early 2018.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3230671/tech-war-new-us-investment-curbs-have-limited-impact-chinas-targeted-semiconductors-quantum" title="">New US investment curbs to have limited impact on China’s targeted tech sectors</a></h3><p>It was launched with a mission to “become a top-tier global quantum computing research institution in five years”, with a focus on several areas including quantum AI, quantum algorithms and quantum architecture, according to local media the Paper.</p><p>In March last year, Baidu and BAQIS jointly launched the country’s first quantum computing intellectual property (IP) alliance, with the goal of facilitating easier IP cross-licensing and innovation in the industry.</p><p>Quantum computing is an emerging field of science that harnesses the principles of fundamental physics to solve problems too complex for traditional computers.</p><p>While quantum computers are not designed to replace traditional computers, they are able to solve very complex statistical problems via simultaneous multiple calculations, making them much faster.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3224737/chinese-scientists-use-quantum-computing-simulate-black-hole" title="">Chinese scientists use quantum computing to simulate black hole</a></h3><p>China and the US have been competing for supremacy in this field in recent years, although the technology is still in its early stage of development. Beijing did not define the area as a national priority until late 2020.</p><p>Last November, Alibaba’s in-house research institution Damo Academy announced it was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242956/alibaba-donates-its-quantum-lab-local-university-shifts-focus-ai-agriculture-healthcare" target="_self" title="">donating its own quantum lab to Zhejiang University.</a> Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Damo Academy said at the time that it would become more focused on fundamental research in AI and its application in areas such as agriculture and healthcare.</p><p>While quantum computing is still a long way from achieving large-scale commercialisation, the new trend of generative AI has been spreading rapidly around the world.</p><p>OpenAI, which unleashed a new era of AI with its conversational bot ChatGPT, was reported to be generating annual revenues of US$1.6 billion, according to US digital media outlet The Information. The San-Francisco-based start-up’s rival Anthropic was forecast to rake in over US$850 billion in annualised revenue by the end of 2024.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TikTok eyes US$17.5 billion shopping business on Amazon’s turf</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247219/tiktok-eyes-us175-billion-shopping-business-amazons-turf</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  TikTok, aiming to increase its US e-commerce business tenfold to US$17.5 billion this year, poses a significant threat to Amazon. TikTok Shop, combining online entertainment and impulse buying, intends to capitalize on its social media reach and viral videos to attract buyers. The company seeks to expand sales across the US and Latin America. TikTok Shop has been successful in snatching a portion of Chinese consumer spending from Alibaba and JD.com due to its user-friendly interface, free shipping, and subsidies for influencers. TikTok is increasing fees imposed on merchants to generate revenue from its e-commerce platform. TikTok's growth in the US e-commerce market will lead to competition with fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: TikTok's ambitious e-commerce goals and strategies in the US market.</li>    <li>Theme: TikTok's aggressive expansion in the US e-commerce market, leveraging its social media reach and viral video appeal to capture a significant market share.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The potential impact of TikTok Shop on the US e-commerce landscape and its competition with established players like Amazon.</li>    <li>Main information: TikTok Shop's tenfold growth target in the US, its unique features combining entertainment and shopping, expansion plans in Latin America, Indonesia, and leveraging TikTok's user base, free shipping and influencer promotions, increasing fees for merchants, and competition with other Chinese e-commerce platforms in the US market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  TikTok 计划将其美国电子商务业务的规模扩大十倍，达到 175 亿美元，这对亚马逊构成了更大的威胁。TikTok Shop 结合了在线娱乐和冲动购物，旨在利用其社交媒体影响力和病毒式视频来吸引买家。该公司寻求在美国和拉丁美洲扩张销售，计划在未来几个月在这些地区推出电子商务业务，两位知情人士透露。TikTok 在一份声明中表示：“彭博社报道的美国商品销售数字推测不准确。”字节跳动由张一鸣和梁汝波于十多年前创立，由于短视频平台 TikTok 及其中国兄弟应用抖音的病毒式传播，公司发展成为一家估值超过 2000 亿美元的互联网巨头。TikTok Shop 是这家总部位于北京的非上市公司的增长最快的功能之一，它正在寻求社交媒体广告之外的新增长动力。字节跳动 2023 年的收入激增约 30%，超过 1100 亿美元，领先于增长速度远更慢的老牌社交媒体竞争对手 Meta Platforms 和腾讯控股。TikTok Shop 允许用户在滚动浏览其主要社交媒体应用程序内的短视频和直播的永久供稿时购买商品，希望消费者将其用作亚马逊或 Sea 的 Shopee 的替代品。这种形式——努力将亚马逊购物的便利性与 Meta 的 Instagram 等应用程序提供的产品发现相结合——已经帮助抖音从阿里巴巴集团控股和京东手中抢夺了很大一部分中国消费支出，特别是在疫情期间的封锁规定驱使人们在网上花费更多时间之后。阿里巴巴拥有南华早报。TikTok Shop 允许用户在滚动浏览短视频和直播的永久供稿时购买商品。图片来源：Shutterstock Images 字节跳动有意将其电子商务模式出口到全球。在美国，TikTok 为在视频和直播中兜售小工具、服装和化妆品的网红提供免费送货和补贴。该公司表示，在 11 月黑色星期五和网络星期一促销活动的推动下，超过 500 万新美国客户在 TikTok 上购买了商品。该公司在美国拥有约 1.5 亿用户。TikTok 于周三宣布，将从 4 月开始对商家收取每次销售 6% 的费用，并在 7 月开始对大多数产品类别的销售收取 8% 的费用，这标志着用于吸引卖家的促销活动即将结束。这些佣金仍然远低于亚马逊卖家费用，后者的费用通常约为 15%，但这表明 TikTok 正迅速从中获得收入。美国人越来越习惯在中国的电子商务应用程序上购物，其中包括颇受欢迎的时尚网站 Shein 和 PDD Holdings 的 Temu，自 2 月份在超级碗播放广告以来，Temu 的人气激增。尚不清楚 TikTok Shop 为全球或其他市场设定的销售目标。在印度尼西亚，TikTok 已通过一笔 15 亿美元的交易控制了 GoTo 集团的电子商务部门 Tokopedia，这使该公司在经过几个月当地政府的审查后重新启动其在线零售服务。  <ul>    <li>摘要：TikTok 在美国电子商务市场中的雄心勃勃的目标和战略。</li>    <li>主题：TikTok 在美国电子商务市场激进扩张，利用其社交媒体影响力和病毒式视频吸引力来占领大量市场份额。</li>    <li>观点：TikTok Shop 对美国电子商务格局的潜在影响，以及它与亚马逊等成熟参与者的竞争。</li>    <li>主要信息：TikTok Shop 在美国十倍增长的目标、其结合娱乐和购物的独特功能、在拉丁美洲、印度尼西亚的扩张计划、利用 TikTok 的用户基础、免费送货和网红推广、提高商家费用，以及在与美国市场上其他中国电子商务平台的竞争。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>crucial (adj.) - /ˈkruːʃəl/ 决定性的，关键的。    <p>原文例句：TikTok is aiming to grow the size of its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, posing a bigger threat to Amazon.com.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“crucial”意为“决定性的，关键的”，强调事物的至关重要性。在此句中，“crucial”被用来形容TikTok对亚马逊构成的威胁，凸显了TikTok在美国电子商务市场的发展潜力和竞争态势。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>e-commerce (n.) - /ˌiːˈkɑːmərs/ 电子商务。    <p>原文例句：TikTok is aiming to grow the size of its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, posing a bigger threat to Amazon.com.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“e-commerce”意为“电子商务”，指利用互联网进行商品或服务的交易。在此句中，“e-commerce”指TikTok在美国的电子商务业务，凸显了TikTok在该领域的布局和发展目标。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the US - 在美国。    <P>原文例句：TikTok is aiming to grow the size of its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, posing a bigger threat to Amazon.com.</P>    <p>例句讲解：“in the US”意为“在美国”，指地点或范围。在此句中，“in the US”限定了TikTok电子商务业务的开展区域，突出了其在美国市场的拓展目标。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein, which have been making big strides among younger American shoppers. - TikTok 的雄心勃勃的目标不仅给亚马逊带来了冲突，也给同为中国所有、在年轻美国购物者中取得了重大进展的 Temu 和 Shein 带来了冲突。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash，其中主语是TikTok’s ambitious target，谓语是sets up a clash，宾语是not just with Amazon but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein，其中not just with Amazon but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein是一个并列结构，其中not just with Amazon是一个否定结构，表示“不仅……”，而also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein是一个肯定结构，表示“也……”。which have been making big strides among younger American shoppers是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰先行词Temu and Shein，表示Temu 和 Shein 在年轻美国购物者中取得了重大进展。这个句子的意思是说，TikTok 的雄心勃勃的目标不仅给亚马逊带来了冲突，也给同为中国所有、在年轻美国购物者中取得了重大进展的 Temu 和 Shein 带来了冲突。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由分词和其修饰语构成的短语，在句中作状语或定语。    <p>原文例句：TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams.</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams是由分  <ul><li>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon, but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein</li>
<li>TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales</li>
</ul><p>TikTok, the global hit short-video platform owned by ByteDance, aims to grow the size of its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, according to people familiar with the matter, posing a bigger threat to Amazon.com.</p><p>The 2024 merchandise volume goal for the US version of TikTok Shop – which melds online entertainment with impulse buying – was discussed in internal meetings in recent weeks and may still change depending on how the business goes, said the people, who asked not to be named discussing private information.</p><p>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon but also fellow Chinese-owned budget retail outfits Temu and Shein, which have been making big strides among younger American shoppers.</p><p>Unlike its two rival discounters, TikTok is counting on its social media reach and the appeal of viral videos to hook buyers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales through its platform, Bloomberg News reported. The company is now seeking to expand sales across the US and Latin America, where it is planning to launch the e-commerce operation in coming months, two people familiar with the matter said.</p><p>“The speculated US merchandise sales figures represented by Bloomberg are inaccurate,” TikTok said in a statement.</p><p>ByteDance, founded more than a decade ago by Zhang Yiming and Liang Rubo, grew into an internet leader worth more than US$200 billion thanks to the virality of short-video platforms TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin. TikTok Shop is one of the fastest-growing features for the Beijing-based, closely held company, which is seeking a new growth driver beyond social-media advertising. ByteDance’s revenue surged roughly 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing the projected growth of far more established social media rivals Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings.</p><p>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams within its main social media app, hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee. That format – an effort to combine the ease of shopping on Amazon with the product discovery afforded by apps like Meta’s Instagram – has already helped Douyin snatch a significant portion of Chinese consumer spending from Alibaba Group Holding and JD.com, particularly after lockdown rules during the pandemic drove people to spend more time online. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/80b40a96-5660-44d3-a756-f6c48d3cb312_1126e908.jpg" title="TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>ByteDance is intent on exporting its e-commerce model globally. In the US, TikTok is offering free shipping and subsidies to influencers who peddle gadgets, clothes and make-up in videos and live streams. In November, boosted by Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals, more than 5 million new US customers bought something on TikTok, the company said. It has roughly 150 million users in the country.</p><p>TikTok on Wednesday announced it will increase fees imposed on merchants to 6 per cent of each sale beginning in April and to 8 per cent in July in most product categories, marking an end to promotions used to entice sellers. Those commissions are still significantly lower than Amazon seller fees, which are typically about 15 per cent, but the boost signals TikTok is quickly moving to generate revenue from its e-commerce platform.</p><p>Americans are increasingly comfortable shopping on Chinese e-commerce apps, including the popular fashion site Shein and PDD Holdings' Temu, which has exploded in popularity since airing a Super Bowl ad in February.</p><p>It is unclear what sales targets TikTok Shop has set globally or for other markets. In Indonesia, TikTok has taken control of GoTo Group’s e-commerce unit Tokopedia in a US$1.5 billion deal, which allowed the company to restart its online retail service after months of scrutiny by the local government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247211/apple-leads-us383-billion-tech-rout-reversal-groups-2023-rally</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>After a strong performance in 2023, the so-called "Magnificent Seven" tech stocks (Apple, Amazon, Alphabet, Microsoft, Meta Platforms, Tesla, and Nvidia) have faced a downturn in the last four trading days, leading to a decline in the Bloomberg Magnificent 7 Price Return Index.</li>    <li>Investors' concerns over the sustainability of the 2023 rally and the Federal Reserve's ability to achieve a soft landing for the economy have contributed to the decline.</li>    <li>Specific stock pressure has been observed, with Apple facing downgrades due to concerns about iPhone demand and Tesla losing its top position in electric vehicle sales to BYD.</li>    <li>Despite the downturn, some tech stocks still have room to grow, as they remain below their all-time highs.</li>    <li>However, continued delivery of solid and profitable technology is crucial for these companies to maintain investor confidence.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>在2023年强劲表现之后，所谓的“ великолепная семёрка”科技股（苹果、亚马逊、Alphabet、微软、Meta Platforms、特斯拉和英伟达）在过去四个交易日遭遇下跌，导致彭博 великолепная семёрка价格回报指数下跌。</li>    <li>投资者对2023年反弹的可持续性以及美联储实现经济软着陆能力的担忧导致下滑。</li>    <li> наблюдается особое давление на акции, причем Apple 面临降级，原因是人们担心 iPhone 需求，而特斯拉在电动汽车销量方面输给了比亚迪，失去了榜首位置。</li>    <li>尽管出现下滑，一些科技股仍有增长空间，因为它们仍低于历史高点。</li>    <li>然而，持续提供扎实且盈利的技术对于这些公司维持投资者信心至关重要。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>surge (v.) - 急剧上升，激增。    <p>原文例句：The Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“surge”的意思是“急剧上升”，通常用来描述快速增长的数量或价格。在这个例句中，“The Magnificent Seven surged” означает “ великолепная семёрка” 激增，指的是这七只科技股在去年出现了大幅上涨。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>recoup (v.) - 弥补，恢复。    <p>原文例句：Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“recoup”的意思是“弥补，恢复”，通常用来描述弥补损失或恢复失去的东西。在这个例句中，“Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier” означает , 2023 年的大部分收益弥补了前一年的损失，指的是2023年这些科技股的涨幅抵消了前一年的跌幅。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>短语：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stick power - 持续力，持久力。    <p>原文例句：It is a signal that investor doubts over the sticking power of the 2023 rally were well-placed.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“stick power”的意思是“持续力，持久力”，通常用来描述事物持续存在或发挥作用的能力。在这个例句中，“It is a signal that investor doubts over the sticking power of the 2023 rally were well-placed” означает является сигналом того, что сомнения инвесторов в устойчивости ралли 2023 года были обоснованными，指的是投资者对2023年反弹的可持续性的担忧是正确的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD.- 尽管特斯拉表示第四季度交付的电动汽车数量超过分析师预期，但该公司在电动汽车销量方面输给了中国的比亚迪，失去了榜首位置。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Tesla lost its place，其中主语是Tesla，谓语是lost，宾语是its place。Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected是一个让步状语从句，表示尽管特斯拉表示第四季度交付的电动汽车数量超过分析师预期。as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD是一个结果状语从句，表示特斯拉在电动汽车销量方面输给了中国的比亚迪，失去了榜首位置。这个句子的意思是说，尽管特斯拉表示第四季度交付的电动汽车数量超过分析师预期，但该公司在电动汽车销量方面输给了中国的比亚迪，失去了榜首位置。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式 - 表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has shed 8.8 per cent in the last four days, its longest streak of losses in more than four weeks.</p>    <p>语法讲解：动词不定式是由“to”加动词原形构成的，表示动作或状态。在这个例句中，“to lose”表示“亏损”，是动词不定式。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示两个事物或情况之间的比较。    <p>原文例句：Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是由形容词或副词的原级加上“er”或“more”构成的，表示两个事物或情况之间的比较。在这个例句中，“more”表示“更多”，是比较级。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023</li>
<li>Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD</li>
</ul><p>The largest technology stocks that lifted the broader market last year are having a less-rosy start to 2024.</p><p>The so-called Magnificent Seven, which includes Apple, Amazon.com, Alphabet, Microsoft, Meta Platforms, Tesla and Nvidia, slipped for the last four trading days, the longest losing streak in a month, according to the Bloomberg Magnificent 7 Price Return Index.</p><p>Shares of Apple, down 4.6 per cent in the time period, lead the slump that has erased US$383 billion in market value. The Nasdaq 100 Index has also fallen in the last four trading days.</p><p>“We don’t know if last year’s rally has fully ended, but it is completely normal to expect markets will pull back after a rally like we saw,” said Steve Sosnick, chief strategist at Interactive Brokers Group. “Without the year-end factors that turbocharged the rally, I think we’re seeing the party winding down.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" title="">Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets</a></h3><p>It is a signal that investor doubts over the sticking power of the 2023 rally were well-placed.</p><p>Though the Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023 as investors mulled the Federal Reserve’s ability to execute a soft landing for the US economy, which would likely mean fewer interest rate cuts than expected.</p><p>“You’re not going to get high-single-digit or double-digit earnings growth if we get something worse than a soft landing,” Sosnick said. “But we’re not going to get six cuts with a soft landing.”</p><p>A few members of the group have also seen specific stock pressure early this year. Apple shares have been weighed down after gaining a new bear; Barclays analysts early this week downgraded shares of the tech giant to underweight, saying they expect soft demand for iPhones going forward.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" title="">Apple hits 7-week low after Barclays downgrade on demand concerns</a></h3><p>Tesla has shed 8.8 per cent in the last four days, its longest streak of losses in more than four weeks. Though Tesla reported on Tuesday that it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as the top seller of electric cars to China’s BYD.</p><p>To be sure, it is likely too early to say the tech-focused rally is over. Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier, and some of the group – Amazon, Alphabet, Meta and Tesla – are still below their all-time highs, signalling they could have room to run.</p><p>But, the largest tech names also have their work cut out for them in 2024. The companies need to continue to deliver not only solid technology, but profitable technology going forward, according to Sosnick.</p><p>“In December everyone bought the sizzle,” he said. “Now we have to see if the steak is any good.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>New refund policies from Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com spark fears of customer abuse among merchants</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247168/new-refund-policies-alibabas-taobao-and-jdcom-spark-fears-customer-abuse-among-merchants</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  中国电子商务巨头阿里巴巴集团的淘宝和京东推出了新的退款政策，允许消费者在保留不满意商品的情况下获得退款。这一政策引发了部分商家的担忧，他们认为消费者可能会滥用该政策，损害他们的利益。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: E-commerce platforms in China introduce new refund policies, sparking concerns over potential misuse.</li>    <li>Theme: The controversy surrounding the implementation of "refund only" policies in China's e-commerce market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Merchants' fears of consumer abuse and the impact on their businesses; Alibaba's prioritization of consumer rights; industry experts' opinions on the effectiveness of the policy.</li>    <li>Main information: The new "refund only" policies adopted by Taobao and JD.com; potential consequences for merchants selling high-quality products; merchant backlash on social media platforms; Taobao's offer of an appeal option for merchants; Pinduoduo's implementation of the policy and its success; opinions of a Beijing software developer and an industry analyst.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国电商巨头阿里巴巴集团旗下的淘宝和京东推出了新的退款政策，允许消费者在保留不满意商品的情况下获得退款。这一政策引起了部分商家的担忧，认为消费者可能会滥用该政策，损害他们的利益。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国电商平台推出新的退款政策，引发潜在滥用担忧。</li>    <li>主题：中国电商市场中“仅退款”政策实施引发的争议。</li>    <li>观点：商家对消费者滥用政策的担忧及其对业务的影响；阿里巴巴优先考虑消费者权益；行业专家对政策有效性的看法。</li>    <li>主要信息：淘宝和京东采用的新“仅退款”政策；对销售高质量产品的商家的潜在影响；商家在社交媒体平台上的反弹；淘宝为商家提供申诉选项；拼多多实施该政策及其成功；北京软件开发人员和行业分析师的观点。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>audit (n.) - /ˈɔːdɪt/ 审计，审查。    <p>原文例句：Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice was initially launched in 2021 and is seen as a key factor behind the Shanghai-based budget-shopping platform’s rise to prominence. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于法语auditer（审计），表示“对财务记录或账目进行审查或审计”。在这个例句中，它指的是拼多多最初于2021年推出的“退款但保留商品”的做法，这被认为是这家上海预算购物平台崛起背后的关键因素。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>extensive (adj.) - /ɪkˈstɛnsɪv/ 广泛的，大量的。    <p>原文例句：Meanwhile, some merchants took to social media platforms such as Douyin and Weibo to express anger at the potential for policy abuse.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语extendere（延伸），表示“ گسترده، شامل ”.在这个例句中，它描述了部分商家在抖音和微博等社交媒体平台上表达对潜在政策滥用的愤怒，这些平台是商家和消费者互动的重要渠道。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>robust consumer protection - 强有力的消费者保护。    <P>原文例句：Tang Guangyao, a 38-year-old Beijing software developer, said he has shifted from other e-commerce platforms to Pinduoduo as a primary shopping channel owing to its robust consumer protection, even though it focuses on budget prices. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由robust（强有力的）和consumer protection（消费者保护）组成，表示“有效和全面的消费者保护措施”。在这个例句中，它描述了拼多多强有力的消费者保护措施，即使它专注于预算价格，这也吸引了38岁的北京软件开发人员唐光耀将拼多多作为其主要的购物平台。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>This [new refund policy] isn’t very practical for platforms such as Taobao, Tmall and JD.com,” said Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangzhou-based iiMedia, pointing out that Pinduoduo’s focus on rock-bottom prices means that the costs of the scheme are more bearable than for merchants on rival sites. - 张毅是广州iiMedia的创始人兼首席分析师，他说：“对于淘宝、天猫和京东等平台来说，这项[新的退款政策]不太实用。”他指出，拼多多专注于最低价格，这意味着该计划的成本对竞争对手网站上的商家来说更容易承受。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是This new refund policy isn’t very practical，其中主语是This new refund policy，谓语是isn’t very practical。for platforms such as Taobao, Tmall and JD.com是一个介词短语作定语，修饰This new refund policy，表示这项新的退款政策对于淘宝、天猫和京东等平台来说不太实用。pointing out that Pinduoduo’s focus on rock-bottom prices means that the costs of the scheme are more bearable than for merchants on rival sites是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰said，表示张毅说这句话的原因或根据，即拼多多专注于最低价格，这意味着该计划的成本对竞争对手网站上的商家来说更容易承受。这个句子的意思是说，对于淘宝、天猫和京东等平台来说，这项新的退款政策不太实用，因为拼多多专注于最低价格，这意味着该计划的成本对竞争对手网站上的商家来说更容易承受。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>条件句 - 表示某一事件或情况发生时所产生的结果或后果。    <p>原文例句：By following this [Pinduoduo] refund policy … [rival platforms] will give their merchants a dilemma,” he added. - 他补充说：“通过遵循此 [拼多多] 退款政策……[竞争对手平台] 将让他们的商家陷入困境”。</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个条件句，类型是第二类条件句，表示不太可能或假设的情况以及由此产生的结果。结构是：If + 过去时，should/could/might/would + 动词原形。在这个例句中，条件句是If [rival platforms] follow this [Pinduoduo] refund policy，表示如果竞争对手平台遵循此拼多多退款政策，结果是[rival platforms] will give their merchants a dilemma，表示竞争对手平台将让他们的商家陷入困境。这个句子的意思是说，如果竞争对手平台遵循此拼多多退款政策，他们将让他们的商家陷入困境。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Taobao and JD.com have introduced policies that allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it</li>
<li>Some merchants have raised concerns that consumers may look to exploit the terms of these ‘refund only’ policies, hitting their operations</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/85b29bec-f2e3-42ad-ba41-d20ec559a707_664d3160.jpg" /><figcaption>Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse under new refund policies. Photo: SCMP</figcaption></figure><p>New “refund only” policies introduced by Chinese e-commerce players including Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao and JD.com have sparked concern among some sellers about potential abuse of the terms, according to merchants and analysts.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com in late December introduced new policies that – in certain circumstances – allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it. This may occur when a consumer complains about the poor quality of a product, or about an inaccurate and misleading description on the platform. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Alibaba, whose company mission is “to make it easy to do business anywhere”, had a long internal debate over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo, which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it.</p><p>Even though some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse, Alibaba came down on the side of consumer rights in such a situation as merchants are ultimately dependent on buyer confidence, according to a person briefed on the discussions who asked not to be identified.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>However, since the policy went into effect last week there has been an increased number of claims under the “refund but keep the purchase” policy, according to one merchant who runs apparel shops on both Taobao and JD.com, adding that some consumers were looking to exploit the situation.</p><p>The 33-year-old online shop owner, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of retribution from the platforms, said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products, because they will bear higher costs in the event of more claims.</p><p>“This refund terms only works for merchants who sell dirt-cheap goods,” she said, adding that the policy clearly favoured consumers.</p><p>Meanwhile, some merchants took to social media platforms such as Douyin and Weibo to express anger at the potential for policy abuse.</p><p>One user with the handle “PengqiangweiVerna” posted on Weibo that the practice will “foster a group of online freeloaders”. Another Douyin user called “Xinzhouxiaohuolang” posted a dozen videos denouncing such refund requests.</p><p>Both Taobao and JD.com have said that any decisions on refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments.</p><p>A person familiar with the situation at Taobao, who asked not to be identified as they are not authorised to talk to the media, said that the platform has offered merchants an appeal option if they think they have been wronged.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Wednesday.</p><p>Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice was initially launched in 2021 and is seen as a key factor behind the Shanghai-based budget-shopping platform’s rise to prominence.</p><p>Tang Guangyao, a 38-year-old Beijing software developer, said he has shifted from other e-commerce platforms to Pinduoduo as a primary shopping channel owing to its robust consumer protection, even though it focuses on budget prices.</p><p>But some analysts say simply following Pinduoduo’s lead may not work for rival platforms.</p><p>“This [new refund policy] isn’t very practical for platforms such as Taobao, Tmall and JD.com,” said Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangzhou-based iiMedia, pointing out that Pinduoduo’s focus on rock-bottom prices means that the costs of the scheme are more bearable than for merchants on rival sites.</p><p>“By following this [Pinduoduo] refund policy … [rival platforms] will give their merchants a dilemma,” he added.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
