<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Samsung set for smallest profit drop in 6 quarters on chip rebound</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247610/samsung-set-smallest-profit-drop-6-quarters-chip-rebound</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary:</h2>  Samsung Electronics, the world's largest maker of memory chips, smartphones and televisions, is projected to experience a 14% decline in profit during the fourth quarter. Nevertheless, the company's chip division is anticipated to minimize its quarterly loss to approximately 1.2 trillion won. Samsung's overall performance is expected to improve compared to the previous six quarters.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung Electronics' projected profit decline in the fourth quarter and its efforts to reduce chip division losses.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's financial performance and the impact of chip division losses on its overall profitability.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Analysts' estimates of Samsung's quarterly profit and the implications for its market position.</li>    <li>Main information: Expected profit decline, chip division loss reduction, and potential recovery in semiconductor prices.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  三星电子作为全球最大的内存芯片、智能手机和电视制造商，预计将在第四季度出现14%的利润下滑。尽管如此，该公司的芯片部门有望将季度亏损减少至约1.2万亿韩元。与前六个季度相比，三星的整体业绩有望改善。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星电子预计第四季度利润下降，以及其为减少芯片部门亏损所做的努力。</li>    <li>主题：三星的财务业绩及其芯片部门亏损对其整体获利能力的影响。</li>    <li>观点：分析师对三星季度利润的估计及其对市场地位的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：预期的利润下降、芯片部门亏损减少以及半导体价格的潜在复苏。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rebound (v.) - /rɪˈbaʊnd/ 反弹    <p>原文例句：Analysts said its Dynamic Random Access Memory (DRAM) chips business returned to a profit.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词指的是反弹，复苏，重新恢复。在这个句子中，它指的是三星的动态随机存取存储器（DRAM）芯片业务恢复盈利。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>surge (n.) - /sɜːrdʒ/ 猛增，激增    <p>原文例句：Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词指突然的增加，猛增。在这个句子中，它指的是三星 Galaxy Z Fold 5智能手机在首尔三星商店中的突然增加。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>according to - 根据，依据    <p>原文例句：Samsung’s chip division likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由according to（根据，依据）和average（平均）构成的，表示“根据，依据”。在这个句子中，它表示三星的芯片部门根据八次预测的平均值，将季度亏损减少至约1.2万亿韩元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>A Samsung Electronics Store at dusk in Seoul, South Korea, on January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg - 三星电子商店在2024年1月7日韩国首尔的黄昏中的照片。照片：彭博社<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是A Samsung Electronics Store at dusk in Seoul, South Korea, on January 7, 2024，其中主语是A Samsung Electronics Store，谓语是was，宾语是Photo: Bloomberg。这个句子的意思是说，这个句子是一个关于三星电子商店在2024年1月7日韩国首尔的黄昏时分的照片。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 用来比较两个对象或事物的程度。    <p>原文例句：Operating profit likely fell to 3.7 trillion won (US$2.82 billion) in the October-December quarter, according to the average of an LSEG SmartEstimate from 30 analysts, weighted toward those who are more consistently accurate.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个比较级，表示“更……”，它是由more（更）和consistent（一致）构成的。在这个句子中，它表示那些更有可能准确的分析师的LSEG SmartEstimate的平均值，认为运营利润可能会在10月至12月季度下降到3.7万亿韩元（28.2亿美元）。这个句子的意思是说，根据30位分析师的LSEG SmartEstimate的平均值，运营利润可能会在10月至12月季度下降到3.7万亿韩元（28.2亿美元），其中权重倾向于那些更有可能准确的分析师。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The world’s biggest maker of memory chips, smartphones and televisions is expected to show a 14 per cent fall in fourth-quarter profit</li>
<li>Samsung’s chip division likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/027a90ed-e4d7-47fd-bac1-0e9d97718aa7_4040710f.jpg" /><figcaption>A Samsung Electronics  Store at dusk in Seoul, South Korea, on January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters, analysts estimate, as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean company’s mainstay chip division.</p><p>The world’s biggest maker of memory chips, smartphones and televisions is expected to show a 14 per cent fall in fourth-quarter profit when it announces preliminary earnings on Tuesday.</p><p>Operating profit likely fell to 3.7 trillion won (US$2.82 billion) in the October-December quarter, according to the average of an LSEG SmartEstimate from 30 analysts, weighted toward those who are more consistently accurate.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/article/3245933/us-gather-chips-supply-chain-intelligence-boost-national-security" title="">US to gather chip supply chain intelligence to boost national security</a></h3><p>That would compare with an operating profit of 4.31 trillion won in the December quarter of the previous year. Samsung last reported a year-on-year quarterly profit increase for the second quarter of 2022.</p><p>A solid set of results would justify Samsung’s sharp stock market run-up in the fourth quarter, which has made it Asia’s second-most valuable listed company after Taiwanese rival TSMC, with a market capitalisation of about US$390 billion.</p><p>Samsung’s chip division – traditionally its biggest earner – likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts. Analysts said its Dynamic Random Access Memory (DRAM) chips business returned to a profit.</p><p>Samsung had reported chip division losses of 4.36 trillion won and 3.75 trillion won in the second and third quarters, respectively, as a chip glut from slow demand for gadgets driven by inflation pressures on consumers caused the worst industry downturn in decades.</p><p>However, prices of DRAM chips – used in tech devices – and NAND flash chips – used to store data – rebounded in the December quarter, including for older chips, in a sign of an industry-wide recovery expected this year.</p><p>Mobile DRAM chip prices rose an estimated 18 to 23 per cent during the fourth quarter, while mobile NAND flash chip prices rose 10 to 15 per cent, according to data provider TrendForce.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/8f2d3cfa-7d39-4dd6-b8f2-d7fda417159f_34f54c2a.jpg" title="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>While Samsung has repeatedly cut production since the first half of 2023 to cope with the downturn, analysts and sources said Samsung took in more supply of silicon wafers, the building blocks for semiconductors, in the fourth quarter, signalling it is gearing up to increase DRAM chip production.</p><p>Samsung was also more aggressive in selling memory chips than competitors such as SK Hynix in the fourth quarter in a bid to lower inventory, analysts said.</p><p>Rival Micron Technology forecast a quarterly revenue above market estimates last month, in a sign of a recovery in the memory chip market in 2024.</p><p>Samsung’s mobile business likely saw an operating profit of around 2.5 trillion won, according to an average of forecasts from eight analysts, as shipments of its two flagship foldable models were estimated to have fallen about 1 million units each versus the third quarter.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Podcasts gain popularity in China as one in five internet users tuned in last year, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247572/podcasts-gain-popularity-china-one-five-internet-users-tuned-last-year-says-report</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Podcasts have gained popularity in China, with over 220 million internet users listening to podcasts on the Ximalaya platform in 2023. The audience for podcasts skews towards young professionals in higher-tier cities. Consumers are also more inclined to pay for quality podcast content, with over 22,000 podcast hosts earning a combined 70 million yuan on Ximalaya last year.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Rising popularity of podcasts in China; preferences and monetization.</li>    <li>Theme: The increasing popularity of podcasts in China, particularly among young professionals, and the monetization opportunities it presents for podcast hosts.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The role of Ximalaya in promoting podcast adoption; the impact of censorship on podcast content preferences.</li>    <li>Main information: Statistics on podcast listeners and podcast hosts' earnings; popular podcast genres; the use of artificial intelligence tools in podcast creation; and the impact of online censorship on podcast content.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  播客在中国获得了欢迎，2023年有超过2.2亿互联网用户在喜马拉雅平台上收听播客。播客听众主要集中于高线城市的年轻专业人士。消费者也越来越倾向于为优质播客内容买单，去年超过22000位播客主创在喜马拉雅共计获得7000万元的收入。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国播客流行趋势的兴起；播客听众的喜好和播客创作者的变现机会。</li>    <li>主题：播客在中国的日益普及，尤其是其在年轻专业人士群体中的流行，以及播客创作者的变现机会。</li>    <li>观点：喜马拉雅在促进播客普及方面的作用；网络审查制度对播客内容偏好的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：播客听众的统计数据和播客主持人的收入数据；流行的播客类型；人工智能工具在播客创作中的应用以及网络审查制度对播客内容的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>niche (n.) - /niːʃ/ 特定人群，小众市场。    <p>原文例句：The niche sector gained popularity in 2023. - 这个曾经的小众行业在2023年获得了欢迎</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源于法语，本身意为“壁龛，小空间”，引申为“特定人群，小众市场”。在这个例句中，它指的是播客行业，指播客这个曾经的小众行业在2023年获得了欢迎。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>tier-one (adj.) - 一线，一线城市。    <p>原文例句：Those from tier-one and tier-two cities accounted for more than 65 per cent of the total audience. - 一线和二线城市的听众占总听众的65%以上。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由tier（层）和one（一）组成的，意为“一线，一线城市”。在这个例句中，它指的是一线城市和二线城市，指一线和二线城市的听众占总听众的65%以上。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>monetization (n.) - /ˌmʌnɪtaɪˈzeɪʃən/ 货币化，变现。    <p>原文例句：Providing an additional monetization channel for the industry. - 为行业提供额外的变现渠道。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于monetize（货币化），意为“货币化，变现”。在这个例句中，它指的是播客行业中变现的渠道，指为播客行业提供额外的变现渠道。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tune into - 收听，收看。    <p>原文例句：More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts on Ximalaya’s platform last year. - 去年，全国11亿多网民中有2.2亿收听喜马拉雅平台上的播客。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由tune（调音）和into（进入）组成的，意为“收听，收看”。在这个例句中，它指的是收听播客，指去年，全国11亿多网民中有2.2亿收听喜马拉雅平台上的播客。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>skew towards - 倾向于，偏向于。    <p>原文例句：The audience for its podcasts skewed towards young Chinese professionals working in the country’s higher-tier cities. - 该平台播客的听众主要集中于高线城市的年轻专业人士。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由skew（倾斜）和towards（向……）组成的，意为“倾向于，偏向于”。在这个例句中，它指的是播客听众的分布，指该平台播客的听众主要集中于高线城市的年轻专业人士。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Consumers in China are also increasingly more inclined to pay for quality podcast content, with more than half signing up for premium content. - 中国消费者也越来越倾向于为优质播客内容付费，超过一半的人注册了付费内容。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个较长的复合句，主句是Consumers are also increasingly more inclined to pay for quality podcast content，其中主语是Consumers，谓语是are inclined to pay，宾语是for quality podcast content。with more than half signing up for premium content是一个介词短语作原因状语，表示原因，即超过一半的人注册了付费内容。这个句子的意思是说，中国消费者也越来越倾向于为优质播客内容付费，超过一半的人注册了付费内容。</p>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence (AI), which increases efficiency and helps with content creation, thanks to a suite of AI-powered audio tools Ximalaya launched last year. - 中国播客行业也赶上了生成型人工智能(AI)的浪潮，这提高了效率并帮助内容创作，这要归功于喜马拉雅去年推出一套人工智能驱动的音频工具。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个较长的复合句，主句是The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence，其中主语是The podcast industry in China，谓语是is riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence。which increases efficiency and helps with content creation是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰波浪，表示人工智能提高了效率并帮助内容创作。thanks to a suite of AI-powered audio tools Ximalaya launched last year是一个介词短语作原因状语，表示原因，即由于喜马拉雅去年推出一套人工智能驱动的音频工具。这个句子的意思是说，中国播客行业也赶上了生成型人工智能(AI)的浪潮，这提高了效率并帮助内容创作，这要归功于喜马拉雅去年推出一套人工智能驱动的音频工具。</p>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Still, Chinese podcasts are flourishing despite the country’s online content crackdown. - 尽管中国对网络内容进行了打击，但中国播客仍在蓬勃发展。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Chinese podcasts are flourishing，其中主语是Chinese podcasts，谓语是are flourishing。despite the country’s online content crackdown是一个介词短语作让步状语，表示让步，即尽管中国对网络内容进行了打击。这个句子的意思是说，尽管中国对网络内容进行了打击，但中国播客仍在蓬勃发展。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The audience for its podcasts skewed towards young Chinese professionals working in the country’s higher-tier cities. - 该平台播客的听众主要集中于高线城市的年轻专业人士。</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示播客听众一直集中于高线城市的年轻专业人士，强调这种状态的持续性。</p></li>  </ul> <ul>      <ul><li>More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts on Ximalaya’s platform last year, across 31 genres</li>
<li>Young professionals helped Chinese podcasts attract ads from global brands such as drinks giant Coca-Cola and luxury carmaker Cadillac</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/07/969c6d9b-b3d1-45c5-a751-cfa7be075015_87249c56.jpg" /><figcaption>Podcast hosts earned a combined total of 70 million yuan on Ximalaya last year. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure><p>One in five internet users in China listened to a podcast last year, as the once niche sector gained popularity in 2023, according to recently published research.</p><p>More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts hosted by Ximalaya last year, across 31 genres of programmes, according to research published on Friday by the Chinese podcast service provider.</p><p>The audience for its podcasts skewed towards young Chinese professionals working in the country’s higher-tier cities, Ximalaya’s research showed.</p><p>The user group aged between 24 and 40 years represented more than 60 per cent of podcast listeners in China, while those from tier-one and tier-two cities accounted for more than 65 per cent of the total audience.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after" title="">China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech must end, party paper says</a></h3><p>Consumers in China are also increasingly more inclined to pay for quality podcast content, with more than half signing up for premium content. More than 22,000 podcast hosts earned a combined total of 70 million yuan (US$9.8 million) on Ximalaya last year, the company revealed in its research.</p><p>Young professionals also helped Chinese podcasts attract ads from global brands, from food and beverage giant Coca-Cola to luxury US carmaker Cadillac, providing an additional monetisation channel for the industry, according to a separate report by market consultancy iResearch.</p><p>Chinese users primarily tuned into podcasts during their daily commutes, with health and lifestyle, Chinese history, global politics, frontier technology, business and entertainment, as well as fantasy and thriller stories among the most popular genres on the Ximalaya platform.</p><p>Chinese podcast preferences were partially the result of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3244838/chinas-online-censors-target-short-videos-artificial-intelligence-and-pessimism-latest-crackdown" target="_self" title="">the country’s strict censorship of online content.</a> General news and politics, two of the most popular genres among podcast listeners in Western countries, were missing from the list in China, according to Ethan Cramer-Flood, a researcher at market consultancy Insider Intelligence.</p><p>“In the West, maybe news and politics rank relatively highly, whereas in China it’s just nowhere to be found because the censorship regime is so strict there,” Flood said in an online discussion last November. “So it’s [topics] like lifestyle, fashion, pet care … sports [that] are all at the top of the list because [they are] nothing remotely controversial.”</p><p>Still, Chinese podcasts are flourishing despite the country’s online content crackdown. In 2023, Ximalaya’s platform hosted 5.2 million more podcast episodes than the year before.</p><p>The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence (AI), which increases efficiency and helps with content creation, thanks to a suite of AI-powered audio tools Ximalaya launched last year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese EV maker Geely introduces first pure electric Galaxy model, to woo mainstream buyers from BYD, foreign brands</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247567/chinese-ev-maker-geely-introduces-first-pure-electric-galaxy-model-woo-mainstream-buyers-byd-foreign</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Geely Automobile Group has introduced the Galaxy E8, a pure electric sedan, to compete with BYD's top-selling models. The E8 offers comparable or superior features at a lower price and targets budget-conscious mainland motorists. Geely plans to introduce seven models under the Galaxy brand by 2025 and differentiates it from its Zeekr brand, which targets affluent buyers.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Geely launches the Galaxy E8 sedan to challenge BYD's dominance in the electric vehicle market.</li>    <li>Theme: Geely's entry into the affordable electric sedan segment with the Galaxy E8.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The intensifying competition in China's electric vehicle market and Geely's strategy to differentiate its brands based on target consumers.</li>    <li>Main information: Introduction of the Galaxy E8, its features, pricing, planned production, and Geely's partnership with Nio to promote battery swapping technology.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  吉利汽车集团推出纯电动轿车银河E8，与比亚迪的热销车型展开竞争。E8在以较低价格提供同等或更好的配置，目标是预算敏感的内地车主。吉利计划到2025年推出七款银河品牌车型，并将其与定位高端买家的极氪品牌区别开来。  <ul>    <li>摘要：吉利推出银河E8轿车，挑战比亚迪在电动汽车市场的主导地位。</li>    <li>主题：吉利推出经济型纯电动轿车银河E8，进入纯电动轿车细分市场。</li>    <li>观点：中国电动汽车市场的竞争日益激烈，吉利根据目标消费群体对其品牌进行差异化的策略。</li>    <li>主要信息：银河E8的推出、其特点、价格、计划产量以及吉利与蔚来合作推广电池更换技术的计划。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>affordable (adj.) - /əˈfɔːdəbl/ 可负担的，买得起的。    <p>原文例句：Geely plans to offer seven models under the affordable Galaxy brand by 2025, while its Zeekr brand targets more affluent buyers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“affordable”的意思是“可负担得起的”，形容词，指价格合理、大众能够承受的。在这个例句中，它指的是吉利计划在2025年推出七款价格亲民的银河品牌车型。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>blockbuster (n.) - /ˈblɒkbʌstə/ 卖座影片，热门作品。    <p>原文例句：“In terms of safety, design, performance and intelligence, E8 proves to be superior to all blockbuster models,” he said during a media briefing after a launch ceremony on Friday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“blockbuster”的意思是“热门影片”，复数形式“blockbusters”在这里代指“热销车型”。在这个例句中，它指的是吉利汽车集团首席执行官甘家悦在发布会后的媒体简报中表示，银河E8在安全、设计、性能和智能方面都优于所有热销车型。</p></li>    </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：“In terms of safety, design, performance and intelligence, E8 proves to be superior to all blockbuster models,” he said during a media briefing after a launch ceremony on Friday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“in terms of”的意思是“就……而言”，是一个介词短语，表示从某个角度或方面来看。在这个例句中，它指的是吉利汽车集团首席执行官甘家悦在发布会后的媒体简报中表示，银河E8在安全、设计、性能和智能方面都优于所有热销车型。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Geely plans to offer seven models under the affordable Galaxy brand by 2025, while its Zeekr brand targets more affluent buyers. - 吉利计划到2025年推出七款银河品牌车型，而其极氪品牌定位高端买家。<p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，由两个分句组成，用“while”连接。第一个分句是“Geely plans to offer seven models under the affordable Galaxy brand by 2025”。主语是“Geely”，谓语是“plans to offer”，宾语是“seven models”。“under the affordable Galaxy brand”是介词短语，作状语，表示吉利计划在银河品牌下提供七款车型。“by 2025”是时间状语，表示吉利计划在2025年之前推出七款车型。第二个分句是“its Zeekr brand targets more affluent buyers”。主语是“its Zeekr brand”，谓语是“targets”，宾语是“more affluent buyers”。这个句子的意思是说，吉利计划到2025年推出七款银河品牌车型，而其极氪品牌定位高端买家。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级和最高级 - 形容词和副词的比较级和最高级形式。    <p>原文例句：“In terms of safety, design, performance and intelligence, E8 proves to be superior to all blockbuster models,” he said during a media briefing after a launch ceremony on Friday.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级和最高级是形容词和副词用来比较两个或多个事物或情况的语法形式。比较级表示两个事物或情况中较好或较差的一方，最高级表示多个事物或情况中最优或最差的一方。在这个例句中，甘家悦表示银河E8在安全、设计、性能和智能方面都优于所有热销车型，使用了“superior”这个比较级的形容词。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Galaxy E8 sells for almost about US$25,000, nearly US$5,000 less than BYD’s Han model</li>
<li>Geely plans to offer seven models under the affordable Galaxy brand by 2025, while its Zeekr brand targets more affluent buyers</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/07/fe08d875-eae8-4f43-a06b-0f78505b4ace_faa77576.jpg" /><figcaption>Geely Automobile Group’s Galaxy E8 sells for 175,800 yuan (US$24,752). Photo: Geely</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/geely" target="_self" title="">Geely Automobile Group</a>, one of China’s largest private carmakers, has launched a pure electric sedan under its mass-market brand Galaxy to take on BYD’s bestselling models amid intensified competition.</p><p>The basic edition of the E8, with a driving range of 550 kilometres, sells for 175,800 yuan (US$24,752), 34,000 yuan lower than the Han <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> built by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a>, which has a range of 506km.</p><p>Hangzhou-based Geely will begin delivering the Class B sedan in February, hoping to target budget-sensitive mainland motorists, according to the company’s CEO Gan Jiayue.</p><p>“In terms of safety, design, performance and intelligence, E8 proves to be superior to all blockbuster models,” he said during a media briefing after a launch ceremony on Friday. “We expect it to be an ideal model to replace both existing petrol and electric cars.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The E8 features a 45-inch screen supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology. Photo: Geely" class="image-inline caption" height="1275" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/07/d39c782a-7ceb-4ed9-8296-284ba2472139_c5eb9682.jpg" title="The E8 features a 45-inch screen supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology. Photo: Geely" width="2000" /><figcaption>The E8 features a 45-inch screen supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology. Photo: Geely</figcaption></figure></div><p>Geely lowered the price of the model by 12,200 yuan from its 188,000 yuan pricing on December 16 when presales started.</p><p>Based on the company’s Sustainable Experience Architecture (SEA), the E8 is also its first full-electric car, following two plug-in hybrid vehicles – the L7 sport-utility vehicle and the L6 sedan – launched in 2023.</p><p>The company plans to manufacture and sell a total of seven models under the Galaxy brand by 2025. The cars will be more affordable for mainland consumers than the company’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3239497/search-engine-baidu-and-carmaker-geelys-venture-starts-delivery-self-driving-ev-compete-teslas-model" target="_self" title="">Zeekr-branded EVs</a>, which compete against premium models built by companies like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a>, Gan said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247229/short-sellers-target-byd-worlds-top-ev-maker-rivalry-intensifies" title="">Short sellers target BYD, world’s top EV maker, as rivalry intensifies</a></h3><p>Its parent, Zhejiang Geely Holding Group, also owns marquees including Volvo, Lotus and Lynk. Geely Holding has a nearly 6 per cent share of mainland China’s EV market.</p><p>The E8 uses a Qualcomm Snapdragon 8295 chip to support its intelligent features such as voice-activated controls. A 45-inch screen, the biggest in a Chinese-made smart vehicle, is supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology.</p><p>At present, the Class B sedan category in China is dominated by petrol-powered models from foreign carmakers such as Volkswagen and Toyota.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>BYD, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest EV maker</a>, backed by Warren Buffett’s Berkshire Hathaway, delivered a total of 228,383 <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3217091/china-ev-war-how-byd-grew-elon-musks-ridicule-berkshire-hathaways-ridiculous-us98-billion-success-12" target="_self" title="">Han sedans</a> to Chinese customers in 2023, up 59 per cent on year.</p><p>Sales of battery-powered vehicles in mainland China are seen as growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from a 37 per cent rise last year, according to the China Passenger Car Association.</p><p>China is the world’s largest automotive and EV market, with sales of electric cars accounting for about 60 per cent of the global total. But only a few makers, including BYD and Li Auto, are profitable.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>A new round of price cuts is in effect, with top players like BYD and Xpeng offering discounts to lure buyers.</p><p>In November, Geely’s parent company formed a partnership with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246154/chinas-nio-unveils-et9-executive-sedan-its-most-expensive-ev-yet-flexes-tech-muscle-luxury-sector" target="_self" title="">Shanghai-based Nio</a>, a premium EV maker, to promote battery swapping technology as the two companies try to overcome the problem of inadequate charging infrastructure.</p><p>Battery-swapping technology allows owners of electric cars to quickly exchange a spent battery pack for a fully charged one.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei teardown shows 5-nm laptop chip made in Taiwan, not China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247568/huawei-teardown-shows-5-nm-laptop-chip-made-taiwan-not-china</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The newly released Huawei Technologies' laptop, the Qingyun L540, is powered by a 5-nm chip from Taiwan's TSMC, dispelling speculations of a major breakthrough by China's SMIC.</li>    <li>Huawei's previous 7-nm processor in the Mate 60 Pro smartphone, made by SMIC, sparked a debate about the effectiveness of US sanctions.</li>    <li>Huawei's 2023 sales saw 9% growth due to the Mate 60 Pro's revival, boosting the company's revenue to over $100 billion.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>华为技术公司最新发布的笔记本电脑青云L540搭载了台积电2020年生产的5纳米芯片，打破了中国中芯国际可能实现重大技术突破的传言。</li>    <li>华为此前在Mate 60 Pro智能手机中使用中芯国际生产的7纳米处理器，引发了对美国制裁有效性的争论。</li>    <li>2023年，华为的销售额增长了9%，这得益于Mate 60 Pro的复苏，使公司的收入超过1000亿美元。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>counter (v.) - /ˈkaʊntər/ 反对，抵消。    <p>原文例句：That counters speculation that Huawei’s mainland Chinese chipmaking partner, Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC), may have achieved a major leap in fabrication technique.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词在句中作动词，表示“反对，抵消”。Huawei的内地中国芯片制造合作伙伴中芯国际可能在制造工艺技术上取得重大飞跃的猜测，被这个消息抵消了。</p></li>    <li>speculation (n.) - /ˌspekjʊˈleɪʃən/ 推测，猜测。    <p>原文例句：That counters speculation that Huawei’s mainland Chinese chipmaking partner, Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC), may have achieved a major leap in fabrication technique.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词在句中作名词，表示“推测，猜测”。Huawei的内地中国芯片制造合作伙伴中芯国际可能在制造工艺技术上取得重大飞跃的推测，被这个消息抵消了。</p></li>    <li>achieve (v.) - /əˈtʃiːv/ 实现，达到。    <p>原文例句：Industry experts had previously speculated that SMIC achieved that milestone by developing workarounds to US sanctions, which would have marked a second technological triumph for the Chinese national champion in the span of months.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词在句中作动词，表示“实现，达到”。行业专家此前曾猜测中芯国际通过解决美国制裁的问题来实现这一里程碑，这将成为中国民族冠军在几个月内取得的第二次技术胜利。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take orders from - 接受……的订单。    <p>原文例句：It was only in 2020 that TSMC stopped taking orders from Huawei to comply with elevated US trade restrictions.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组在句中作动词短语，表示“接受……的订单”。台积电在2020年才停止接受华为的订单，以遵守美国提高的贸易限制。</p></li>    <li>be on the list - 在……名单上。    <p>原文例句：While Huawei has been on Washington’s Entity List since 2019, it was only in 2020 that TSMC stopped taking orders from Huawei to comply with elevated US trade restrictions.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组在句中作谓语，表示“在……名单上”。自2019年以来，华为一直被列入华盛顿的实体名单，但直到2020年台积电才停止接受华为的订单，以遵守美国提高的贸易限制。</p></li>    <li>stockpile (v.) - /ˈstɑːkpʌɪl/ 储存，堆积。    <p>原文例句：Huawei has since sunk billions into chip research and stockpiling in past years, while also building a domestic network of suppliers and manufacturing partners, in some cases with government backing.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词在句中作动词，表示“储存，堆积”。近年来，华为已投入数十亿美元进行芯片研究和囤积，同时还建立了一个由供应商和制造合作伙伴组成的国内网络，在某些情况下得到了政府的支持。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei caused a stir in the US and China last August when it released a smartphone with a 7-nm processor made by Shanghai-based SMIC. - 去年8月，华为发布了一款采用上海中芯国际制造的7纳米处理器的智能手机，在美国和中国引起了轰动。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huawei caused a stir in the US and China，其中主语是Huawei，谓语是caused a stir，宾语是in the US and China。last August when it released a smartphone with a 7-nm processor made by Shanghai-based SMIC是一个时间状语从句，表示华为发布智能手机的时间和原因。这个句子的意思是说，去年8月，华为发布了一款采用上海中芯国际制造的7纳米处理器的智能手机，在美国和中国引起了轰动。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Huawei has since sunk billions into chip research and stockpiling in past years.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这句话使用了现在完成时，表示华为从过去的几年开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。现在完成时由have/has + been + 过去分词构成。在这个例句中，have been used表示“一直持续到现在的动作或状态”，chip research and stockpiling表示“芯片研究和囤积”。这个句子的意思是说，华为从过去的几年开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态是芯片研究和囤积。</p></li>    <li>过去进行时 - 表示过去某个时间正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：While Huawei has been on Washington’s Entity List since 2019, it was only in 2020 that TSMC stopped taking orders from Huawei to comply with elevated US trade restrictions.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这句话使用了过去进行时，表示过去某个时间正在进行的动作或状态。过去进行时由was/were + 动词的-ing形式构成。在这个例句中，was on表示“正在进行的动作或状态”，Entity List表示“实体名单”。这句话的意思是说，华为从2019年开始一直被列入华盛顿的实体名单，直到2020年台积电才停止接受华为的订单，以遵守美国提高的贸易限制。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Qingyun L540 notebook contains a 5-nm chip made by TSMC in 2020, around the time US sanctions cut off Huawei’s access to the chip maker</li>
<li>Huawei caused a stir in the US and China last August when it released a smartphone with a 7-nm processor made by Shanghai-based SMIC</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/07/c9380a71-e793-48d8-862d-3a8e754b72f5_e6e9a731.jpg" /><figcaption>A Chinese flag flutters near a Huawei store in Shanghai,  September 8, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies’ newest laptop runs on a chip made by Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), a teardown of the device showed, quashing talk of another Chinese technological breakthrough.</p><p>The Qingyun L540 notebook contains a 5-nanometre chip made by the Taiwanese company in 2020, around the time US sanctions cut off Huawei’s access to the chip maker, research firm TechInsights found after dismantling the device for Bloomberg News. That counters speculation that Huawei’s mainland Chinese chipmaking partner, Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC), may have achieved a major leap in fabrication technique.</p><p>Huawei caused a stir in the US and China last August when it released a smartphone with a 7-nm processor made by Shanghai-based SMIC. A teardown by the Canada-based research outfit for Bloomberg News showed the Mate 60 Pro’s chip was only a few years behind the cutting edge, a feat that US trade curbs were meant to prevent. That revelation spurred celebration across the Chinese tech scene, and a debate in the US about the effectiveness of sanctions.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" title="">Huawei sees 9 per cent sales growth in 2023, boosted by Mate 60 Pro 5G comeback</a></h3><p>In the latest teardown, TechInsights discovered a Kirin 9006C processor fabricated via TSMC’s 5-nm method, which was assembled and packaged around the third quarter of 2020. Industry experts had previously speculated that SMIC achieved that milestone by developing workarounds to US sanctions, which would have marked a second technological triumph for the Chinese national champion in the span of months.</p><p>Representatives for Huawei and TSMC did not provide comment when reached by Bloomberg News.</p><p>The advances encapsulated in the Mate 60 smartphone in 2023 cemented Huawei’s role as the standard-bearer for Chinese efforts to wean itself off Western technologies and create domestic alternatives. Chinese consumers snapped up the smartphone in the final quarter, helping the company regain the symbolically important US$100 billion revenue threshold – eroding Apple’s iPhone dominance along the way.</p><p>A foray into 5-nm territory would have represented a big leap for the Shenzhen conglomerate, bringing it closer to the most-advanced processes currently in use, mostly centred around 3-nm nodes. Before TSMC cut off ties with Huawei, it was supplying chips as advanced as 5-nm to the Chinese firm.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246414/huawei-and-xiaomi-launch-new-ev-models-china-reigniting-worries-about-price-wars-worlds-largest-ev" title="">New EVs from Huawei, Xiaomi could renew price wars in China’s car market</a></h3><p>It is unclear how Huawei managed to procure a three-year-old processor, though the Chinese company has been stockpiling vital semiconductors since the US began cutting off its access to components and gear globally. While Huawei has been on Washington’s Entity List since 2019, it was only in 2020 that TSMC stopped taking orders from Huawei to comply with elevated US trade restrictions.</p><p>Huawei has since sunk billions into chip research and stockpiling in past years, while also building a domestic network of suppliers and manufacturing partners, in some cases with government backing.</p><p>The L540 is the latest in a line of laptops that Huawei began selling around 2016, when the then-networking leader developed ambitions to get into mobile and computing devices and round out its offerings.</p><p>Its emergence coincides with a growing call from Beijing to replace foreign technology in sensitive environments, from mandates to stop using iPhones in the workplace to replacing Dell and HP computers.</p><p>Some online retailers touted that the new laptop was designed specifically to comply with recent, stringent requirements in China on data security across sensitive government organs. Huawei’s official site highlights the device’s security features, but did not go into that detail.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
