<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: Hong Kong start-ups attract interest from Microsoft, Best Buy amid overseas push</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248382/ces-2024-hong-kong-start-ups-attract-interest-microsoft-best-buy-amid-overseas-push</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  • Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella visited the booth of a Hong Kong start-up called AI Guided at CES 2024, exhibiting a belt with haptic feedback to aid the visually impaired.  • 40 companies showed interest in exhibiting at the Eureka Park start-up area in CES this year, with 20 Hong Kong-based companies presenting their innovative products.  • Best Buy expressed interest in the furniture with embedded speakers created by Invisible & Innovation Technology, aiming for disruptive design and sustainability.  • Beverage maker XOXO Beverages showcased their cocktail-making machines at CES with plans for expansion beyond Hong Kong.  • Two participating companies specializing in micro-LED displays are Sitan Semiconductor International and Raysolve Technology, gaining attention from major brands.  • CES provided an opportunity for start-ups to seek partnerships, attract investments, and expand their business beyond their home market.  • AI Guided hopes for potential investment from Microsoft due to the company's support for accessibility technology.  • Hong Kong aims to establish itself as a tech hub, aiming to attract start-ups and create a vibrant tech ecosystem.</div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  • 微软首席执行官萨提亚·纳德拉在2024年国际消费类电子产品展览会（CES）期间参观了香港初创企业AI Guided的展位，该公司展示了一款通过触觉反馈帮助视障人士识别的腰带。  • 今年共有40家公司表示有兴趣在CES尤里卡公园初创企业展区参展，其中20家来自香港，展示了他们具有创新意义的产品。  • 百思买对Invisible & Innovation Technology研发的嵌入了扬声器的家具表现出兴趣，该公司旨在实现颠覆性设计和可持续性。  • 饮料制造商XOXO Beverages在CES上展示了他们的鸡尾酒制作机，并计划将其推广到香港以外的地区。  • 参与展出的两家专门从事微型LED显示屏的公司是Sitan Semiconductor International和Raysolve Technology，他们吸引了主要品牌的目光。  • CES为初创企业提供了寻求合作关系、吸引投资和开拓本国市场以外业务的机会。  • AI Guided希望获得微软的潜在投资，因为微软支持无障碍技术。  • 香港的目标是将自己打造成为一个科技中心，旨在吸引初创企业并创造一个充满活力的科技生态系统。</div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Eureka (n.) - /jʊˈriːkə/ 尤里卡。    <p>原文例句：Even leading up to the show, Hong Kong Science and Technology Park (HKSTP) said 40 companies applied to exhibit in the Eureka Park start-up area, a marked improvement over previous years, according to H L Yiu, corporate development officer for HKSTP, which runs the pavilion. </p>    <p>例句讲解：尤里卡是希腊语中的欢呼声，表示成功或发现。在这个例句中，它指的是香港科技园展馆内的Eureka Park初创企业展区，这是一个专门展示初创企业创新产品的区域。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>spur (v.) - /spɜːr/ 推动，刺激。    <p>原文例句：The city aims to be carbon neutral by 2050. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语，表示“刺激，激励，推动，促使”。在这个例句中，它表示这座城市的目的是在2050年实现碳中和，即温室气体排放量为零。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：We had to make some selection of companies that have more of a mature level of readiness in terms of being ready to sell,” Yiu said in an interview. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示我们不得不选择一些在销售方面已经相当成熟的公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Realme unveils 12 Pro series smartphone in parallel event to CES - Realme在与CES同期举行的活动中发布12 Pro系列智能手机。<p>句子分析：这是一个主动语态的陈述句，主语是Realme，谓语是unveils，宾语是12 Pro series smartphone。in parallel event to CES是一个介词短语，作时间状语，表示在与CES同期举行的活动中。这个句子的意思是说，Realme在与CES同期举行的活动中发布了12 Pro系列智能手机。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella stopped by the booth of a start-up at the Hong Kong pavilion that makes an AI-powered belt to guide blind people</li>
<li>Other start-ups say they have received interest at the show from retailers and other potential partners as Hong Kong firms look overseas</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/c4aa2f7b-bda4-4f1d-8d18-95ebfe7901e8_6e29421c.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella meets with Steve Kong, co-founder and chief technology officer of AI Guided, at CES to learn more about the Hong Kong start-up’s belt for guiding the blind. Photo: Handout </figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft">Microsoft</a> and Best Buy expressed interest in Hong Kong <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups">start-ups</a> at CES 2024, after the city’s pavilion at the world’s largest consumer electronics show saw the most interest there in years.</p><p>Last Tuesday, the first day of the trade show in Las Vegas, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella swung by the Tech Hong Kong pavilion to chat with AI Guided, a company that makes a belt with haptic feedback for obstacle detection, helping to guide the blind.</p><p>“Microsoft really supports accessibility technology,” said Steve Kong, co-founder and chief technology officer of AI Guided. “The dream of our company is that in three to five years … visually impaired people can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world.”</p><p>AI Guided is one of 20 Hong Kong-based companies exhibiting with the city’s start-up pavilion this year, a big improvement over the eight that exhibited last year because of the last-minute lifting of Covid-19 restrictions.</p><p>Even leading up to the show, Hong Kong Science and Technology Park (HKSTP) said 40 companies applied to exhibit in the Eureka Park start-up area, a marked improvement over previous years, according to H L Yiu, corporate development officer for HKSTP, which runs the pavilion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248116/ces-2024-china-smartphone-brand-realme-unveils-new-handset-sidelines-trade-show-its-biggest-rivals" title="">Realme unveils 12 Pro series smartphone in parallel event to CES</a></h3><p>“We had to make some selection of companies that have more of a mature level of readiness in terms of being ready to sell,” Yiu said in an interview. “We really mean to help them get new business.”</p><p>With limited space, HKSTP focused on picking companies that were closer to having products ready to go, or even already in the market, with the goal of picking up business deals at CES.</p><p>For some, that could pan out in a big way.</p><p>Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology, aka Invisible Tech, which builds speakers into furniture, said it has received interest from Best Buy. A representative from the largest electronics retail chain in the US told Invisible Tech that it had not seen other products like its cabinet with an embedded speaker in the base, according to the start-up’s co-founder Patrick Lee.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1507" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/8c535fe2-a0b7-472a-a511-c0de39fad1c7_cffec5fe.jpg" title="Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Best Buy always wants to source something new,” said Lee. “Furniture is a very traditional thing that [has not had] much disruptive design or link with technology.”</p><p>Invisible Tech also uses recycled materials in some parts of its products. Henry Cheung, the company’s other co-founder, said the company wants to “help Hong Kong fulfil its carbon neutral mission”. The city aims to be carbon neutral by 2050.</p><p>The Hong Kong pavilion at this year’s CES, which concluded on Friday, featured a variety of start-ups that make products ranging from the quirky to the practical.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" title="">Chinese EV maker shows off flying car but admits urban use is far off</a></h3><p>XOXO Beverages already has its cocktail-making machine in about 10 bars and restaurants in Hong Kong, but it has not expanded to home use yet. Co-founder Peter Yau said CES was the best show the company has been to.</p><p>“People from all around the world come by and are very interested in the product,” Yau said. “[We got] a lot of contacts, and we’re looking to see what we can do after [the show] with those guys.”</p><p>Two of the participating companies, Sitan Semiconductor International and Raysolve Technology, make micro-LED displays, something that has become more important amid rising interest in augmented reality glasses.</p><p>Sitan was started at the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, and the company said its tech has already found its way into products from big brands like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tcl" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tcl">TCL</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo">Oppo</a> and Meizu – although not all of these products have been released.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1613" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/2b040077-b3ac-4878-bb0e-daa1b2414354_75a0b9ef.jpg" title="XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>For most of the start-ups, though, CES was about getting leads and looking for ways to expand beyond their home market. Getting the attention of a tech giant like Microsoft is one way to achieve that.</p><p>Asked about the prospects of Microsoft investing, AI Guided’s Kong said, “I hope so … I will still have another discussion with them, so we’ll see.”</p><p>This kind of attention also may help the Hong Kong government justify its efforts to turn the city into a tech hub, which has had mixed results in a city better known as a regional financial hub.</p><p>“From a tech area standpoint, I think the opportunity to come to Hong Kong is surging,” said HKSTP’s Yiu. “The number of start-ups that we nurture every year is an increasing trend.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Elon Musk’s Tesla loses US$94 billion in market valuation as winter sets in for global electric vehicle market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248400/elon-musks-tesla-loses-us94-billion-market-valuation-winter-sets-global-electric-vehicle-market</link>
<description><![CDATA[  <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Tesla's stock price has dropped significantly in the first two weeks of 2024 due to negative news, such as price cuts, rising labor costs, and slowing demand for electric vehicles. The company's market capitalization has decreased by over US$94 billion. This is the worst start to a year for Tesla since it went public in 2010. The company's gross margin has also been declining due to price cuts, and Tesla is facing competition from other car manufacturers.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tesla's stock price plummets due to a series of negative news, signaling the company's worst start to a year since its public debut.</li>    <li>Theme: Tesla's challenges in maintaining its growth and dominance in the electric vehicle market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Experts' concerns about Tesla's overvaluation and the need for more tangible progress in autonomous driving technology.</li>    <li>Main information: Price cuts, rising labor costs, slowing demand, declining gross margin, competition from BYD, and Musk's wealth decline.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  特斯拉在今年的前两周内损失惨重，原因是一系列负面新闻，包括再次降价其中国制造的汽车。这家美国汽车制造商自去年年初以来一直在大幅降价其汽车，以提振需求。特斯拉首席执行官埃隆·马斯克（Elon Musk）2022年3月22日在德国柏林-勃兰登堡工厂开业时赞扬了新电动汽车的推出。照片：美联社特斯拉在2023年表现出色，其股价在12个月内上涨了一倍多。但2024年却以不同的基调开局，埃隆·马斯克的电动汽车（EV）制造商遭遇了有史以来最糟糕的年初开局。这家公司在今年短短两周内，市值损失就超过940亿美元。原因不难理解，这家总部位于德克萨斯州奥斯汀的电动汽车制造商一直受到一系列负面消息的打击：汽车租赁巨头赫兹全球控股公司（Hertz Global Holdings）对电动汽车的态度转变、再次降价其在中国制造的汽车，以及劳动力成本上升的迹象。所有这一切都发生在电动汽车需求增长放缓的情况下，尤其是在美国。“投资者对特斯拉的主要担忧是增长停滞，”考恩分析师杰弗里·奥斯本在接受采访时说。中国的降价只会加剧这些担忧，因为它开始看起来像“电动汽车行业的恶性竞争，因为该市场的竞争非常激烈”。2024年1月6日，一名特斯拉车主在北京的公司一个充电站给他的车充电。照片：彭博社自2010年上市以来，特斯拉的市值在年初遭受的打击是该公司同期内遭遇的最大损失。按百分比计算，特斯拉自1月年初以来的12%跌幅是自2016年以来最严重的，当时该股在该年的前九个交易日里下跌了14%。更糟糕的是，这家电动汽车制造商的近期好转几率似乎不大。特斯拉自2023年初以来一直在大幅降价其汽车，以提振需求。但结果是其曾经丰厚的利润率稳步下降。特斯拉第三季度的汽车毛利率（扣除监管积分）从一年前的27.9%下降至16.3%。而且，随着特斯拉美国工厂的生产工人获得加薪，压力只增不减。“电动汽车正在经历周期性低迷，但竞争态势加剧了周期性压力，”斯皮尔投资公司首席投资官伊万娜·德莱夫斯卡在接受采访时说。“降价和利润暴跌都是这些不利的竞争态势的产物。”特斯拉在中国降价以保持对高端电动汽车市场的控制权。此外，特斯拉还不得不将原本运往柏林工厂的汽车改道，原因是西方国家在红海的军事行动和安全问题，并根据一位知情人士透露，公司将从1月29日至2月11日暂停其位于德国首都附近工厂的大部分生产。特斯拉在10月的第三季度财报中首次警告电动汽车需求放缓。几乎就在之后，全球各地的汽车制造商和供应商纷纷以自己的悲观预测表示附和。许多汽车制造商收回了其扩张计划。然后，本月早些时候，特斯拉公布了其第四季度的交付数据。虽然这些数据好于分析师的预期，但该公司在全球电动汽车销量上落后于中国的比亚迪汽车。结果，特斯拉的投资者们被粗暴地唤醒。去年，该公司的股票是标普500指数中表现第八好的股票。今年到目前为止，它是表现第八差的股票。2024年1月12日，勃兰登堡，格吕内海德：特斯拉柏林-勃兰登堡超级工厂。由于红海的安全问题，特斯拉已基本暂停其位于德国的柏林-勃兰登堡超级工厂的生产。照片：德新社自然而然，马斯克个人遭受了很大打击。彭博亿万富翁指数显示，这位全球首富去年积累的财富比地球上其他任何人都多，而今年到目前为止，他的净资产已缩水230亿美元。马斯克去年重新登上彭博财富指数榜首，超过路易威登酩轩轩尼诗集团创始人兼首席执行官伯纳德·阿诺特，但现在亚马逊创始人兼执行董事长杰夫·贝索斯正在迅速逼近，截至周五收盘，贝索斯的净资产为1790亿美元，而马斯克为2060亿美元。马斯克的净资产大部分来自他持有的特斯拉13%股份和约3.04亿份可行权股票。彭博财富指数显示，他还拥有太空探索技术公司约42%的股份，该公司估值约为530亿美元。即便如此，特斯拉仍然是全球从汽油动力汽车向纯电动汽车过渡的关键参与者。原因在于：该公司远远领先于其潜在竞争对手。中国的比亚迪可能在销量上超过了特斯拉，但其收入和利润仍然落后。而且比亚迪不在美国销售汽车，而特斯拉仍然是美国市场的领导者。中国的比亚迪超越特斯拉成为最大的纯电动汽车制造商。在很多方面，特斯拉最大的问题可能还是其过去的成功以及它所激发的希望。随着投资者涌入该股票，特斯拉的市值暴涨，使其成为全球任何其他汽车公司的市值都难以企及。然而，随着股价被定价为完美无缺的，这也使它们对任何负面新闻的反应非常敏感。这就是为什么许多特斯拉支持者认为，它不应该与普通汽车公司相提并论。对他们来说，该公司最终的真正价值在于未来，并且希望开发出第一款真正的自动驾驶汽车。唯一的问题是，特斯拉已经为此承诺了很多年，而且大多数专家表示，这项技术还需要很多年，甚至几十年的时间才能实现。“特斯拉尚未兑现其自动驾驶和人工智能承诺，而这些承诺已经包含在估值中，”斯皮尔的德莱夫斯卡说。“仅仅成为另一家汽车制造商是不足以支撑7500亿美元的估值的。”###</div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>barrage (n.) - /ˈbærɪdʒ / 挡路之物，倾盆大雨，猛烈炮火。    <p>原文例句：The company has lost more than US$94 billion in market valuation in just the first two weeks of this year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French的barrer（阻止，挡住），意思是“挡路之物，障碍物，屏障”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉在今年前两周遭受的一系列负面消息，这些消息对特斯拉的市值产生了很大的负面影响。</p></li>    <li>exacerbate (v.) - /ɪgˈzæsərbət/ 加剧，使恶化。    <p>原文例句：“We are going through a cyclical downturn for EVs, but competitive dynamics are exacerbating the cyclical pressures,” Ivana Delevska, chief investment officer at Spear Invest, said in an interview. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由ex-（从……出来）和acerbate（使尖锐）组成的，意思是“加剧，使恶化”。在这个例句中，它指的是竞争态势加剧了电动汽车的周期性压力。</p></li>    </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>priced for perfection - 被定价为完美无缺的。    <P>原文例句：With the shares priced for perfection, that also made them highly vulnerable to big reactions to any negative news. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由priced（定价）和for perfection（为完美）构成的，意思是“被定价为完美无瑕的”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉的股票被定价为完美无缺的，这使得它们对任何负面消息的反应都很敏感。</p></li  <ul><li>Tesla’s losses in the first two weeks of this year have come from a barrage of negative news, including another price cut for its made-in-China cars</li>
<li>The US carmaker has been cutting prices on its vehicles aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/83cb01fa-622e-4130-b271-fd9276597c55_850fb60a.jpg" /><figcaption>Tesla chief executive Elon Musk applauds the roll-out of new electric vehicles at the opening of the firm’s Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant  in Germany on March 22, 2022. Photo:  AP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> had a blockbuster 2023, as its shares more than doubled in 12 months. But 2024 is starting on a different note, with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/elon-musk" target="_self" title="">Elon Musk</a>’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle</a> (EV) maker off to its worst start to any year – ever.</p><p>The company has lost more than US$94 billion in market valuation in just the first two weeks of this year. It is not hard to figure out why, as the Austin, Texas-based EV maker has been pounded by a barrage of negative news: an about-face on EVs from the car rental giant Hertz Global Holdings, yet another price cut for its cars <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-manufacturing" target="_self" title="">made in China</a>, and signs of rising labour costs.</p><p>All of this comes in the face of slowing growth in demand for EVs, especially in the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>.</p><p>“Investors’ main concern on Tesla is stagnating growth,” Cowen analyst Jeffrey Osborne said in an interview. The price cuts in China only fan those concerns, because it is starting to look like “a race to the bottom for the EV industry given intense competition in that market”.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/b52c250b-b6c8-47e5-91ec-7f2278c772c1_a66cec46.jpg" title="A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The hit to Tesla’s market capitalisation to start the year is the biggest the company has seen over a similar period since it went public in 2010. In percentage terms, Tesla’s 12 per cent drop since the start of January is the worst since 2016, when the stock fell 14 per cent over the first nine trading days of the year.</p><p>To make matters worse, the odds of an imminent turnaround for the EV maker do not look good.</p><p>Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early 2023 in an effort to boost demand. But the result has been a steady erosion of its once-hefty profit margin. Tesla’s automotive gross margin ex-regulatory credits for the third quarter fell to 16.3 per cent from 27.9 per cent a year ago. And the pressure is only mounting, now that production workers at Tesla’s US plants are getting pay rises.</p><p>“We are going through a cyclical downturn for EVs, but competitive dynamics are exacerbating the cyclical pressures,” Ivana Delevska, chief investment officer at Spear Invest, said in an interview. “Price cuts and plummeting margins are all a function of these unfavourable competitive dynamics.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing" title="">Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</a></h3><p>Adding to the woes, Tesla has had to divert shipments destined for its Berlin plant after Western military actions and security concerns in the Red Sea, and is suspending most production at its plant near the German capital from January 29 to February 11, according to a person familiar with the matter.</p><p>Tesla first warned about the deceleration in EV demand during its October third-quarter earnings report. Almost immediately after, carmakers and suppliers across the globe chimed in with their own downbeat forecasts. Many carmakers dialled back their plans for expansion.</p><p>Then, earlier this month, Tesla reported its fourth-quarter delivery numbers. While they were better than what analysts expected, they put the company behind China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD Co</a> in global electric-car sales.</p><p>The result has been a rude awakening for Tesla investors. Last year, the stock was the eighth best performer in the S&amp;P 500. So far this year, it is the eighth worst.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="12 January 2024, Brandenburg, Gruenheide: The Tesla Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant. Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa" class="image-inline caption" height="1201" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/47b22035-65d8-46f4-a5cf-8ceaf3d20b48_c243b8f2.jpg" title="12 January 2024, Brandenburg, Gruenheide: The Tesla Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant. Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa" width="2000" /><figcaption>12 January 2024, Brandenburg, Gruenheide: The Tesla Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant. Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Naturally, Musk is taking a big hit personally. The world’s richest person, who gained more wealth last year than anyone else on the planet, has seen his net worth shrink by US$23 billion so far this year, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index.</p><p>Musk regained the top spot on Bloomberg’s wealth index last year, overtaking LVMH Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton founder and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226276/lvmh-boss-bernard-arnaults-visit-highlights-growing-importance-huge-mainland-chinese-market-luxury" target="_self" title="">Bernard Arnault</a>, but now <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon.com</a> founder and executive chairman <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jeff-bezos" target="_self" title="">Jeff Bezos</a> is rapidly closing in, with US$179 billion to Musk’s US$206 billion as of Friday’s close.</p><p>The bulk of Musk’s net worth comes from his 13 per cent stake in Tesla and about 304 million exercisable stock options. He also owns about 42 per cent of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/spacex" target="_self" title="">Space Exploration Technologies</a>, which is valued at about US$53 billion, according to Bloomberg’s wealth index.</p><p>With all that being said, Tesla remains a key player in the global transition from petrol-powered vehicles to largely electric ones. The reason: the company is so far ahead of its potential rivals. China’s BYD may have surpassed Tesla in the number of units sold, but it still lags in revenue and profits. And BYD does not sell cars in the US, where Tesla remains the market leader.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>In many ways, Tesla’s biggest problem may be its past success and the hope it generated. As investors piled into the stock, Tesla’s market capitalisation ballooned, making it way larger than any other car company in the world. However, with the shares priced for perfection, that also made them highly vulnerable to big reactions to any negative news.</p><p>That is why so many Tesla proponents argue that it should not be compared to regular car companies. To them, the ultimate true value of the company rests in the future and it is hope to develop the first truly <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/self-driving-cars-autonomous-vehicles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">self-driving vehicles</a>. The only problem is Tesla has been promising this for years, and most experts say the technology is still years, maybe even decades, away.</p><p>“Tesla has not been able to deliver on fully autonomous driving and AI promises, which are already embedded in the valuation,” Spear’s Delevska said. “Being simply another automotive manufacturer is not going to cut it for a US$750 billion valuation.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese etching tools giant AMEC sees 2023 sales rise more than 30% on strong demand from mainland semiconductor fabs</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248391/chinese-etching-tools-giant-amec-sees-2023-sales-rise-more-30-strong-demand-mainland-semiconductor</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>China's Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment (AMEC) expects revenue to reach US$879 million in 2023, up 32.1% due to strong domestic orders.</li>    <li>The company's core etching tools, including CCP and ICP, are expected to contribute 75% of total revenue.</li>    <li>AMEC's market share for CCP equipment in China is expected to reach 60%, up from 24% in October 2022.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国先进微电子设备公司（AMEC）预计 2023 年营收将达到 8.79 亿美元，比上年增长 32.1%，这得益于强劲的国内订单。</li>    <li>该公司预计，其核心蚀刻设备，包括 CCP 和 ICP，将贡献其总收入的 75%。</li>    <li>AMEC 在中国 CCP 设备市场的份额预计将达到 60%，高于 2022 年 10 月的 24%。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - 收入。    <p>Example sentence: In 2023, AMEC's revenue is expected to reach US$879 million.</p>    </li>    <li>core (adj.) - 核心。    <p>Example sentence: AMEC expects its core etching tools to account for 75% of its total revenue.</p>    </li>    <li>semiconductor (n.) - 半导体。    <p>Example sentence: AMEC's equipment is used by semiconductor foundries to manufacture chips.</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>fabrication plant - 制造厂。    <p>Example sentence: AMEC's equipment is used in semiconductor fabrication plants.</p>    </li>    <li>net profit - 净利润。    <p>Example sentence: AMEC's net profit last year is projected to be from 1.7 billion yuan to 1.85 billion yuan.</p>    </li>    <li>replace foreign-produced components - 替换外国生产的组件。    <p>Example sentence: AMEC plans to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts.</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>AMEC expects sales of its core etching tools, including so-called capacitively coupled plasma (CCP) and inductive coupled plasma (ICP), to account for 75 per cent of the firm’s total revenue last year, which would be up nearly 50 per cent to 4.7 billion yuan.<p>Sentence analysis: This sentence is complex and contains several clauses. The main clause is "AMEC expects sales of its core etching tools... to account for 75 per cent of the firm’s total revenue last year". The phrase "including so-called capacitively coupled plasma (CCP) and inductive coupled plasma (ICP)" is a non-restrictive appositive that provides more information about the core etching tools. The phrase "which would be up nearly 50 per cent to 4.7 billion yuan" is a relative clause that modifies the noun phrase "total revenue".</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Use of "up" to indicate an increase:    <p>Example sentence: AMEC's revenue is expected to be up 32.1% in 2023.</p>    </li>    <li>Use of "replace" to indicate substitution:    <p>Example sentence: AMEC plans to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts.</p>    </li>    <li>Use of "percent" to indicate a percentage:    <p>Example sentence: AMEC's revenue is expected to reach US$879 million, up 32.1% year-on-year.</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Shanghai-based AMEC expects its 2023 revenue to reach US$879 million, up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic orders</li>
<li>The company said sales of its core etching tools will account for 75 per cent of its total revenue last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/977166e1-00b7-4d05-941a-ada3e90b90d0_07dcf1ac.jpg" /><figcaption>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment workers at the company’s main production site in Shanghai. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese etching tools giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3232334/tech-war-china-chip-tool-firm-amecs-profit-boosted-strong-local-demand-it-reshuffles-tech-board-wake" target="_self" title="">Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment</a> (AMEC) expects revenue last year to grow more than 30 per cent from 2022, as core <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> breakthroughs enabled the firm to deploy more chip-making gear to domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> fabrication plants.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a>-based AMEC said in a regulatory filing on Sunday that its 2023 revenue is expected to reach 6.26 billion yuan (US$879 million), up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic demand. The company said it recorded 8.36 billion yuan worth of new orders, a 32.3 per cent year-on-year increase.</p><p>Net profit last year is projected to be from 1.7 billion yuan to 1.85 billion yuan, representing year-on-year growth of between 45 per cent and 58 per cent.</p><p>AMEC’s positive earnings guidance reflects its successful strategy to expand sales on the mainland, months after founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230803/us-wants-chinas-chip-industry-5-generations-behind-cutting-edge-head-equipment-maker-amec-says-wuxi" target="_self" title="">Gerald Yin Zhiyao</a> said the firm had devised a detailed road map to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy" target="_self" title="">tightened US semiconductor sanctions</a>.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/8dc83513-a48d-478e-9d86-f625246bf8fe_ada0205e.jpg" title="Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Yin had said 80 per cent of US-restricted components that AMEC used would be replaced with domestic parts by the end of last year. He expected the company to achieve a 100-per cent replacement rate in 2024.</p><p>AMEC shares in Shanghai closed down 2.07 per cent to 134.66 yuan last Friday.</p><p>With state-backed efforts to localise great swathes of China’s semiconductor supply chain, mainland semiconductor foundries have accelerated adoption of locally made equipment since October 2022, when Washington <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3195461/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-self-sufficiency-drive-under-siege-new" target="_self" title="">first tightened export controls</a> to cut off the country’s access to advanced chip-making gear from the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">US</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netherlands" target="_self" title="">the Netherlands</a>.</p><p>AMEC expects sales of its core etching tools, including so-called capacitively coupled plasma (CCP) and inductive coupled plasma (ICP), to account for 75 per cent of the firm’s total revenue last year, which would be up nearly 50 per cent to 4.7 billion yuan.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1414" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/646d3f0c-dcc0-4e3c-87fa-0e91b99b21a2_bfef4330.jpg" title="Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>AMEC said that its CCP and ICP equipment saw increased adoption by domestic foundry clients on the strength of the firm’s breakthroughs in core technologies last year.</p><p>Etching tools are some of the most important processing equipment used by semiconductor foundries. It is an area where China has strong players such as AMEC and state-backed Naura Technology Group.</p><p>AMEC’s domestic CCP equipment market share is projected to hit 60 per cent in the near future, up from 24 per cent in October 2022. The firm’s share in ICP gear sales on the mainland is predicted to reach 75 per cent from almost zero, according to company chief executive Yin, after once-dominant US chip equipment maker Lam Research saw its mainland sales drop sharply.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China price wars help spark US$157 billion rout in mainland consumer stocks, as firms including Alibaba, Yum China and BYD drag the market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248377/china-price-wars-help-spark-us157-billion-rout-mainland-consumer-stocks-firms-including-alibaba-yum</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Consumer stocks in China have underperformed the MSCI China Index since late September 2023 due to weak consumer demand and a lack of positive drivers.</li>    <li>Companies in various sectors are engaging in promotional activities to attract customers amid economic uncertainty and a property market slump.</li>    <li>Consumer prices have been falling for three consecutive months, raising concerns about corporate earnings and share prices.</li>    <li>The weak demand is resulting in a deflationary environment, particularly affecting businesses that cannot maintain higher volumes with lower prices.</li>    <li>The EV industry has been severely impacted by intense competition, with Chinese manufacturers following Tesla's lead in cutting prices to boost sales.</li>    <li>Internet giants like Alibaba and JD.com have also faced challenges due to fierce market competition and price wars.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>自2023年9月末以来，中国消费类股票指数表现不佳，主要原因是消费需求疲软和缺乏积极驱动因素。</li>    <li>各个行业的公司都在开展促销活动，以吸引客户，因为经济不确定性和房地产市场低迷。</li>    <li>消费价格连续三个月下降，引发了对公司盈利和股价的担忧。</li>    <li>需求疲软导致通货紧缩环境，这尤其影响了无法以较低价格维持较高销售量的企业。</li>    <li>电动汽车行业受到激烈竞争的严重影响，中国制造商效仿特斯拉降价以提振销量。</li>    <li>由于激烈的市场竞争和价格战，阿里巴巴和京东等互联网巨头也面临挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>tepid (adj.) - /ˈtɛpɪd/ 不冷不热的，微温的。    <p>原文例句：From electric vehicles (EVs) to fast food, companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由tepe（温暖）构成，表示“不冷不热的，微温的”。在这个例句中，它描述了消费者对工作前景的担忧和房地产市场的持续低迷导致的财富缩减，使他们对消费持谨慎态度。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>deflationary (adj.) - /dɪˈfleɪʃ(ə)n(ə)ri/ 通货紧缩的。    <p>原文例句：The bigger picture is that the weak demand is leading to a deflationary environment, which particularly bodes ill for businesses that cannot achieve higher volumes with lower prices.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由deflate（紧缩）和-ion（状态）构成，表示“通货紧缩的”。在这个例句中，它描述了需求疲软导致的价格下降，对那些无法以较低价格维持较高销售量的企业来说尤其不利。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>wage a battle - 展开激烈的竞争。    <p>原文例句：From electric vehicles (EVs) to fast food, companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由wage（进行，从事）和battle（战斗，争斗）构成，表示“展开激烈的竞争”。在这个例句中，它描述了各个行业的企业为了吸引客户而展开的促销竞争。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Consumer prices fell for a third-straight month in December, the longest streak since 2009, deepening concerns about companies’ profits and share prices.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Consumer prices fell for a third-straight month in December，其中主语是Consumer prices，谓语是fell，宾语是for a third-straight month in December。第一个分句longest streak since 2009是一个非限定性定语从句，修饰Consumer prices，表示这是自2009年以来最长的连续下降月数。第二个分句deepening concerns about companies’ profits and share prices是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示价格下降加剧了人们对公司利润和股价的担忧。这个句子的意思是说，12月份，消费者价格连续第三个月下降，这是自2009年以来最长的连续下降月数，加剧了人们对公司利润和股价的担忧。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>因果倒装句型 - 将原因从句置于结果从句之前，以强调原因。    <p>原文例句：That’s all symbolic of a very weak consumption environment that includes lack of consumer confidence and weak income growth.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个因果倒装句，结果从句是That’s all symbolic of a very weak consumption environment，原因从句是that includes lack of consumer confidence and weak income growth。因果倒装句型常用于强调原因，表示如果没有原因，就不会有结果。在这个例句中，它强调了消费者信心缺乏和收入增长疲弱是造成消费环境非常疲弱的原因。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023</li>
<li>The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include Alibaba, Yum China Holdings and BYD, which have all been offering big discounts</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/b3e8597a-be7a-4197-85aa-c1a7be1f6626_e063aefc.jpg" /><figcaption>People fly dragon-shaped kites on the Bund in front of buildings in Pudong’s Lujiazui Financial District in Shanghai on January 9, 2024. China’s stock market suffers from a lack of positive drivers ahead of the Lunar New Year. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>The seemingly relentless decline in prices of Chinese goods amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247712/chinas-retail-sales-weaken-year-falling-home-prices-jobs-outlook-feed-consumer-insecurity-ubs" target="_self" title="">tepid consumer demand</a> is denting expectations that corporate earnings can revive the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-stock-market" target="_self" title="">flagging stock market</a>.</p><p>From <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicles</a> (EVs) to fast food, companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3244649/china-inflation-4-takeaways-novembers-data-deflationary-pressure-heightened" target="_self" title="">Consumer prices</a> fell for a third-straight month in December, the longest streak since 2009, deepening concerns about companies’ profits and share prices.</p><p>“That’s all symbolic of a very weak consumption environment that includes lack of consumer confidence and weak income growth,” said Ng Xin-yao, an investment director for Asian equities at abrdn. “We are cautious on fourth-quarter earnings across most sectors, and would assume that continues in the first quarter unless the government starts doing something massive to support the economy.”</p><p>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/msci" target="_self" title="">MSCI China Index</a> since the end of September, after the real estate measure. The aggregate market value of companies included in the two consumer indexes has fallen by about US$157 billion since.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/c17c04b3-1a34-4b5f-9767-75f9273ed6e5_8a6158cb.jpg" title="Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include e-commerce giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, restaurant operator <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3209531/kfc-pizza-hut-operator-yum-china-open-1300-stores-worst-over-posts-earnings-decline-2022" target="_self" title="">Yum China Holdings</a> and EV maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD Co</a> – which have all been offering big discounts. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>The world’s second-largest stock market has started 2024 on a dismal note, with the MSCI China gauge already down more than 4 per cent so far this year. It capped a third straight annual decline in 2023.</p><p>“The bigger picture is that the weak demand is leading to a deflationary environment, which particularly bodes ill for businesses that cannot achieve higher volumes with lower prices,” said Daisy Li, a fund manager at EFG Asset Management HK.</p><p>The EV industry has been among the worst hit by intense competition as growth slows, with Chinese makers following the lead of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> in lowering prices to boost sales. BYD and local peers including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a> have shed billions of dollars in market value in the past few months.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing" title="">Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</a></h3><p>“Retail prices are falling fast,” Morgan Stanley analysts wrote in their 2024 outlook report for the Chinese EV sector. “While local brands, in general, have fared better than luxury and foreign brands in terms of widening discounts, we expect discounts to further widen into the first quarter this year on the back of seasonality effects.”</p><p>Even China’s vaunted <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants have been impacted, with Alibaba and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> seeing their stock prices tumble, as they wage a fierce battle for market share. The price war has made US-listed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247286/pdd-halts-development-local-services-offering-avoid-head-competition-meituan-and-eleme-report-says" target="_self" title="">PDD Holdings</a>, operator of discount sites <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="">Pinduoduo</a> on the mainland and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>, one of the rare bright spots in China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> industry.</p><p>Many economy and market observers are hoping for interest-rate cuts and government spending to help prevent the nation from entering a deflationary spiral.</p><p>Fund managers have said the next catalyst they are watching is pricing and sales data around the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/lunar-new-year" target="_self" title="">Lunar New Year</a> in February, which will offer more clues on consumer confidence.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>The next few weeks may also be key for policy action, given Chinese leaders will soon gear up for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/national-peoples-congress" target="_self" title="">National People’s Congress</a>. That annual legislative session, held in March, is where the government is expected to announce its official growth target for 2024.</p><p>A Morgan Stanley survey conducted late last month suggests seasonally better consumer sentiment ahead of the holidays. However, “sustainability is in doubt amid slowing economic recovery”, analysts including Lillian Lou wrote in a note.</p><p>Salary cuts and job losses have remained among the top concerns of households, they wrote, adding that the number of consumers anticipating the economy to worsen ticked up by two percentage points from November to 13 per cent.</p><p>In all, there is little hope for a quick fix. Citigroup expects consensus estimates to fall for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-ning-company-ltd" target="_self" title="">Li Ning</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3217413/anta-sports-seeks-us15-billion-equity-placement-market-discount-triggering-stocks-worst-sell-six" target="_self" title="">Anta Sports Products</a> around the upcoming results season, hurt by foreign competition and pushes into lower-tier cities with cheaper products.</p><p>Fast-food companies are still locked in a protracted fight for customers, with some offering full meals for around US$3. It is difficult to make money at such low prices.</p><p>“We expect industry margins to erode until the irrational price war ends,” Kevin Yin, an analyst at JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co., wrote in a note, while cutting estimates for Yum China. “No player is immune” to the headwinds created by the nation’s slowing demand growth, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Stanford students win hearts in China with US$32,000 household robot that can cook shrimp and wash pans</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248330/stanford-students-win-hearts-china-us32000-household-robot-can-cook-shrimp-and-wash-pans</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  American researchers developed Mobile Aloha, a versatile two-handed robot capable of diverse tasks like cooking, rinsing, and wiping, thanks to advanced AI algorithms and human demonstration data training.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Mobile Aloha robot excels in household tasks, impressing Chinese netizens.</li>    <li>Theme: Unveiling the capabilities of the Mobile Aloha robot through its impressive performance in various household tasks.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Recognizing the potential of dual-armed robots in aiding human tasks and addressing labor shortage issues.</li>    <li>Main Information: Mobile Aloha's features include remote control, autonomous imitation learning, and successful task completion with an 80% success rate.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  美国研究人员开发出名为 Mobile Aloha 的多功能双臂机器人，它能够完成烹饪、冲洗、擦拭等多种任务，这要归功于先进的人工智能算法和人类演示数据训练。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Mobile Aloha 机器人在家务任务中表现出色，让中国网友印象深刻。</li>    <li>主题：通过 Mobile Aloha 机器人在各种家务任务中的出色表现，揭示其能力。</li>    <li>观点：认识到双臂机器人辅助人类任务和解决劳动力短缺问题的潜力。</li>    <li>主要信息：Mobile Aloha 的功能包括远程控制，自主模仿学习，以及以 80% 的成功率成功完成任务。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>combination (n.) - /ˌkɑːmbɪˈneɪʃən/ 联合，合并，组合。    <p>原文例句：At the moment, Mobile Aloha is still in its early stages, but it shows promise as a potential solution to the combination of a labor shortage and an aging global population.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由combine（联合，合并）和-tion（后缀，表示状态或结果）构成，表示“联合，合并，组合”。在这个例句中，它指的是劳动力短缺和全球人口老龄化相结合的问题。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>autonomous (adj.) - /ɔːˈtɒnəməs/ 自主的，独立的。    <p>原文例句：Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由auto（自我）和nomos（法律）构成，表示“自主的，独立的”。在这个例句中，它指的是Mobile Aloha机器人可以自主地工作。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>demonstration (n.) - /ˌdemənˈstreɪʃən/ 示范，演示，论证。    <p>原文例句：After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由demonstrate（示范，演示）和-tion（后缀，表示状态或结果）构成，表示“示范，演示，论证”。在这个例句中，它指的是人类对机器人进行的50次示范。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>remote control - 遥控，遥控器。    <p>原文例句：Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由remote（遥远的）和control（控制）构成，表示“遥控，遥控器”。在这个例句中，它指的是Mobile Aloha机器人可以通过人类用户进行远程控制。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>imitation learning - 模仿学习。    <p>原文例句：Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由imitation（模仿）和learning（学习）构成，表示“模仿学习”。在这个例句中，它指的是Mobile Aloha机器人可以通过模仿人类的动作进行学习。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>labor shortage - 劳动力短缺。    <p>原文例句：At the moment, Mobile Aloha is still in its early stages, but it shows promise as a potential solution to the combination of a labor shortage and an aging global population. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由labor（劳力）和shortage（短缺）构成，表示“劳动力短缺”。在这个例句中，它指的是全球范围内劳动力短缺的问题。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent. - 经过50次人类示范并通过数据集进行联合训练后，机器能够烹饪虾、冲洗平底锅、端起酒杯并擦拭下面溢出的液体——成功率至少达到80%。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath，其中主语是The machine，谓语是is able to，宾语是cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath。After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示在经过50次人类示范并通过数据集进行联合训练之后，with a success rate of at least 80 per cent是一个介词短语作状语，表示成功率至少达到80%。这个句子的意思是说，经过50次人类示范并通过数据集进行联合训练后，机器能够烹饪虾、冲洗平底锅、端起酒杯并擦拭下面溢出的液体，成功率至少达到80%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词结构 - 由分词构成的结构，在句中作不同成分。    <p>原文例句：After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent. </p>    <p>语法讲解：分词结构是指由分词构成的结构，在句中可以作不同成分。在原文例句中，After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets是一个分词结构，在句中作状语。这个分词结构由两个过去分词短语组成，分别是After going through 50 human demonstrations和being co-trained on data sets。这两个分词短语分别修饰主句中的谓语动词is able to，表示在经过50次人类示范和通过数据集联合训练之后。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>强调句 - 对句子的某一部分进行强调的句子结构。    <p>原文例句：It is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent. </p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句是对句子的某一部分进行强调的句子结构。在原文例句中，It is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent是一个强调句。这个强调句强调了机器能够烹饪虾、冲洗平底锅、端起酒杯并擦拭下面溢出的液体，成功率至少达到80%。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Mobile Aloha, a two-handed system, can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning</li>
<li>It is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, the inventors say</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/a5391667-ecfe-41e0-ba55-d4bcc8573340_5eb9826c.jpg" /><figcaption>Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning. Photo: Screenshot</figcaption></figure><p>A US$32,000 robot developed by a team at Stanford University has caught the attention of Chinese online users, after a video showing the two-handed robot cooking a three-course meal went viral.</p><p>Mobile Aloha, built by two computer-science PhD candidates from China, is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p><p>After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, according to the project’s website.</p><p>It took three months to develop the robot, according to Zipeng Fu, who co-leads the project with Tony Zhao, advised by Stanford assistant professor Chelsea Finn. Fu and Zhao are also student researchers at Google DeepMind, an artificial intelligence (AI) research laboratory.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Fu said they had to tackle both hardware and software challenges. To save cost, they assembled the machine on their own. The goal was to make a robot that could “complete complex home or office tasks that were not shown to be possible previously”.</p><p>The robot can walk at 1.42 metres per second, roughly equivalent to human speed, reach as high as 2 metres and extend one metre beyond its base, the team said.</p><p>When it comes to the software, the duo took a “data-driven AI approach using human demonstration data to teach the robot” instead of the traditional way of “tons of programming and manual tuning” that is not scalable, Fu said.</p><p>The robot cost US$32,000 to build, including on-board power and computing. Fu said he and Zhao, who have open-sourced the whole system, “don’t have any business plan at the moment”.</p><p>As the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ageing-society" target="_self" title="">global population gets older</a>, domestic robots are expected to play a critical role in the smart home ecosystem. The market is estimated to grow at an annual rate of nearly 20 per cent from US$8.6 billion this year to US$22.5 billion by 2029, according to market research firm Mordor Intelligence.</p><p>Global tech giants have been betting big on the sector. In 2021, American online retailer Amazon.com unveiled Astro, a nearly US$1,000 household robot designed for home monitoring. Japanese electronics giant Sony launched the latest generation of its Aibo robot dog in 2018, priced at around US$2,900.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s Big Tech firms from Tencent to Alibaba cut external investments further in 2023 amid troubled economy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248311/chinas-big-tech-firms-tencent-alibaba-cut-external-investments-further-2023-amid-troubled-economy</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  The total investment deals made by Chinese internet giants Alibaba, Tencent, and Baidu plunged by nearly 40% in 2023, data from ITJuzi shows. The largest reduction in investments was seen by Tencent, which participated in only 39 deals, a decline from 95 in 2022 and 299 in 2021. Web search and AI firm Baidu participated in 24 deals, down from 52 in 2021, while e-commerce giant Alibaba took part in 39 deals, a fall from 91 in 2021. Despite the overall slowdown in investments, Xiaomi emerged as the top investor among its peers with 82 deals made in 2023.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese internet giants reduce external investments in 2023, led by Tencent.</li>    <li>Theme: Impact of economic slowdown, regulatory headwinds, and geopolitical tensions on investment strategies of internet giants.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Necessity for Chinese internet giants to adapt to changing market conditions and regulatory landscape.</li>    <li>Main information: Total investment deals by Alibaba, Tencent, and Baidu decreased by nearly 40% in 2023; Tencent faced the largest reduction; Xiaomi emerged as the top investor by number of investments.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  IT桔子数据显示，去年阿里巴巴、腾讯、百度三家互联网巨头的投资总额下降了近40%。腾讯作为中国互联网行业的投资大户，投资数量却大幅下滑，去年仅投资了39家，而2022年和2021年分别投资了95家和299家。网络搜索和人工智能公司百度去年投资了24家企业，而2021年为52家。电子商务巨头阿里巴巴投资了39家企业，而2021年为91家。尽管整体投资额下降，但小米却以82笔投资成为业内投资最活跃的公司。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国互联网巨头2023年削减外部投资，腾讯领跌。</li>    <li>主题：经济放缓、监管趋严和地缘政治紧张局势对互联网巨头投资策略的影响。</li>    <li>观点：中国互联网巨头需要适应不断变化的市场状况和监管环境。</li>    <li>主要信息：阿里巴巴、腾讯、百度三家互联网巨头在2023年的投资总额下降了近40%；腾讯的投资数量下降幅度最大；小米成为投资数量最多的互联网公司。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>slash (v.) - /slæʃ/ 削减，裁减。    <p>原文例句：China’s internet giants from Alibaba Group Holding to Tencent Holdings slashed external investments last year amid an economic slowdown, regulatory headwinds and geopolitical tensions. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古诺斯语的“slasa”，意思是“击打”，它表示“用锋利的工具快速而用力地切割”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国各大互联网公司在经济放缓、监管趋严以及地缘政治紧张的情况下大幅削减外部投资。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>participation (n.) - /pɑːrtɪsɪˈpeɪʃən/ 参与，参加。    <p>原文例句：Web search and artificial intelligence (AI) firm Baidu participated in 24 investment deals last year, down from 52 in 2021.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语的“participatio”，意为“共享，参与”。它表示“参与某项活动或事件”。在这个例句中，它指的是网络搜索和人工智能公司百度去年参与的投资交易数量从2021年的52笔减少到24笔。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take part in - 参与，参加。    <P>原文例句：E-commerce giant Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, took part in 39 deals, a fall from 91 in 2021, according to ITJuzi. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组的意思是“参与，参加”。在这个例句中，它指的是阿里巴巴集团参与的投资交易数量从2021年的91笔减少到39笔。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Tencent headquarters in Shenzhen. Photo: AFP - 腾讯位于深圳的总部。照片：法新社<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是The Tencent headquarters，谓语是in Shenzhen，宾语是Photo。Photo: AFP是一个介词短语，作状语，表示照片的来源。这个句子的意思是说，腾讯总部位于深圳，照片来自法新社。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>介词短语 - 用来修饰名词或代词，表示该名词或代词与其他词语之间的关系。    <p>原文例句：Tencent’s investments last year were mainly related to corporate services, healthcare and video games.</p>    <p>语法讲解：介词短语是一个由介词和名词或代词组成的短语，用来修饰名词或代词，表示该名词或代词与其他词语之间的关系。在这个例句中，介词短语related to corporate services, healthcare and video games修饰名词investments，表示腾讯去年的投资主要与企业服务、医疗保健和电子游戏相关。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由分词和修饰语组成的短语，可以作定语或状语。    <p>原文例句：Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters - 百度位于北京的总部。照片：路透社。</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语是一个由分词和修饰语组成的短语，可以作定语或状语。在这个例句中，分词短语located in Beijing修饰名词headquarters，起定语作用，表示百度总部位于北京；分词短语Photo: Reuters修饰整个句子，起状语作用，表示照片的来源是路透社。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Total investment deals made by Alibaba, Tencent and Baidu plunged by nearly 40 per cent last year, data from ITJuzi shows</li>
<li>Smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor among its peers by number of investments, with 82 deals made in 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/44791123-3b25-419d-83ab-8b90abaff588_62f5b773.jpg" /><figcaption>The Tencent headquarters in Shenzhen. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>China’s internet giants from Alibaba Group Holding to Tencent Holdings slashed external investments last year amid an economic slowdown, regulatory headwinds and geopolitical tensions, according to data compiled by a Chinese consultancy.</p><p>Total investment deals made by Alibaba, Tencent and Baidu plunged by nearly 40 per cent to 102 in 2023, with Tencent – known for its expansive holdings in China’s internet sector – seeing the largest reduction in deals, data from ITJuzi showed.</p><p>The social media and video gaming titan struck 39 investment contracts with 37 companies last year, a sharp decline from the 95 and 299 deals it made in 2022 and 2021, respectively.</p><p>Web search and artificial intelligence (AI) firm Baidu participated in 24 investment deals last year, down from 52 in 2021. E-commerce giant Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, took part in 39 deals, a fall from 91 in 2021, according to ITJuzi.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/7597aa81-09a5-4a11-9eec-a437d76b7f0a_d667e456.jpg" title="The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure></div><p>2021 was a watershed year for Chinese internet firms, as Beijing kicked off a campaign to rein in the “disorderly expansion of capital”. Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding.</p><p>Tencent’s investments last year were mainly related to corporate services, healthcare and video games. Advanced manufacturing firms were Alibaba’s top picks, with eight related deals being struck by the Hangzhou-based company and its affiliates during the year.</p><p>Alibaba, which is grappling with anaemic consumer spending at home, made four investment deals in the e-commerce sector, three of them outside China.</p><p>AI was another investment favourite among Chinese tech giants last year, as they raced to build and promote their local rivals to OpenAI’s ChatGPT.</p><p>Tencent and Alibaba each backed seven and four AI start-ups developing large language models (LLMs), the technology which underpins chatbots like ChatGPT, which can understand complex questions and give humanlike responses.</p><p>Last year, Alibaba’s in-house research facility Damo Academy also launched a research laboratory to recruit more than a hundred postdoctoral candidates to work on cutting-edge areas, including AI and semiconductors.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1325" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/5991da2b-d385-4951-b2a1-8a232f9ce1c4_bc1c8442.jpg" title="Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Other major Chinese tech companies made even fewer investments.</p><p>TikTok owner ByteDance struck five external investment deals last year, while online shopping platform operator JD.com made just two.</p><p>ByteDance’s largest deal in 2023 was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244634/tiktok-restarts-e-commerce-indonesia-us15-billion-investment-goto-gojek-tokopedia-unit" target="_self" title="">a US$1.5 billion investment into Indonesia’s biggest e-commerce firm Tokopedia</a>, which allows the Beijing-based company to restart its local online shopping business after Indonesian regulators banned TikTok Shop.</p><p>Meanwhile, Chinese smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor by number of investments, with 82 deals made during the year.</p><p>The company, also based in Beijing, in December launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246558/xiaomi-unveils-its-first-ev-su7-setting-its-sights-tesla-highly-competitive-china-market" target="_self" title="">its first electric vehicle, the SU7</a>, designed to compete against the likes of Tesla and Porsche in China’s hotly contested car market.</p><p>In that same month, Xiaomi invested in three start-ups in the vehicle and transport industry, according to ITJuzi.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong needs to speed up approval of spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds after US launch, industry insiders say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248282/hong-kong-needs-speed-approval-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-after-us-launch-industry</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Hong Kong is trailing behind the United States in authorizing spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs), despite regulators indicating readiness for such a move in December. Industry experts emphasize the urgency of approving crypto ETFs to enhance Hong Kong's competitiveness in the global digital asset market.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Hong Kong's efforts to become a virtual-asset hub are impeded by the lack of spot crypto ETFs, which are gaining traction in the U.S. </li>    <li>Theme: Hong Kong's delayed authorization of spot cryptocurrency ETFs compared to the U.S. market, highlighting the need for regulatory agility in the digital asset industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of spot crypto ETFs in providing accessible and legitimate investment opportunities; the potential impact on Hong Kong's position as a financial center.</li>    <li>Main information: U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission's recent approval of spot Bitcoin ETFs; investor interest in these products; Hong Kong's plans to allow spot virtual asset ETFs; Mainland China's ban on cryptocurrencies and its stance on Web3.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  香港在授权现货加密货币ETF方面落后于美国，尽管监管机构在去年12月表示该市已准备好这样做。业内人士敦促当地监管机构加强批准，以增强该市在全球加密货币市场中的竞争力。据中欧基金管理公司数量投资主管王毅表示，香港证券及期货事务监察委员会（SFC）去年12月表示准备授权散户使用现货虚拟资产ETF，但此类产品的实际推出已经落后于美国，中欧基金管理公司目前运营着两只加密货币期货ETF。根据路透社援引LSEG数据的一篇报道，美国上市的现货比特币ETF在周四的交易额为46亿美元，原因是投资者涌入美国证券交易委员会周三批准的具有里程碑意义的产品。在获得美国证券交易委员会的标志性批准后，包括贝莱德的iShares Bitcoin Trust、灰度比特币信托和ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF在内的11只现货比特币ETF于周四开始交易，预计这将有助于将加密货币行业与更受监管的传统金融世界联系起来。2024年1月11日，随着比特币现货交易所交易基金开始交易，贝莱德代表与嘉宾在纽约纳斯达克市场敲响开盘钟。图源：彭博社美国现货比特币ETF的成功推出预计将有助于促使香港监管机构批准类似的加密货币基金在该市运营。现货加密货币ETF使投资者能够接触虚拟资产，而无需直接购买任何加密货币代币。以太坊扩容初创企业Taiko的研究员RJ Ke表示，这些基金“赋予加密货币行业更多的合法性，也为与主流金融展开更多合作的机会打开了大门”。“香港可能会在未来几个月加快比特币ETF的申请。”据中国媒体财新周三采访加密货币交易应用运营商HashKey Group的首席运营官翁利文称，约有10家基金管理公司正准备在香港推出现货虚拟资产支持的ETF。翁表示，多达八家公司处于推出“高级阶段”。美国监管机构SEC授权现货比特币ETF在加密货币领域取得突破在获得美国现货加密货币ETF的批准后，比特币上涨约3.4%，至47,500美元。这几乎是该加密货币在2022年11月创下的水平的三倍，当时加密货币交易所FTX申请破产，导致比特币价格跌至17,000美元以下。数字资产托管解决方案提供商Cobo联合创始人兼首席执行官茅世兴（也称“Discus Fish”）表示，香港需要尽快推出现货虚拟资产ETF，“以确保该市在全球加密货币市场保持竞争力，并巩固其作为全球金融中心的地位”。茅表示，美国的批准可能会影响其他司法管辖区，原因是“SEC是世界上最有影响力和最具声誉的金融监管机构之一”，他还补充说，该机构的举措“通常为其他国家和地区的金融监管机构提供了重要的参考”。“然而，每个国家和地区都有其独立的立场和监管目标，”他说。香港将推动散户进入现货加密货币交易所交易基金的准入资格VDX数字资产平台的首席运营官唐纳德·戴伊赞同Cobo掌门人的看法，他表示SEC的决定将使其同行“认真考虑类似的ETF是否可行且可取”。戴指出，SFC在12月发表的关于准备授权此类基金的声明已经“原则上为发行人在香港推出现货加密货币ETF打开了一条道路”。据市场分析公司CoinGecko称，除了美国，现在全球有9个市场允许现货加密货币ETF运营。其他市场包括加拿大、德国、瑞士以及开曼群岛（位于加勒比海）和法国西北海岸附近的泽西等避税天堂。然而，中国大陆不太可能效仿。去年12月，中国工业和信息化部表示，将起草一份符合国家需要的Web3发展计划。但该公告并未提到加密货币，尽管北京继续支持香港成为主要虚拟资产中心的雄心。北京将在严格禁止加密货币的情况下起草国家Web3发展计划中国政府于2013年禁止银行处理比特币，并于2017年迫使加密货币交易所迁至海外。2021年，该国监管机构重申了国家禁止所有金融机构参与加密货币相关活动的禁令。中国国家媒体最近强调了现货加密货币ETF所涉及的风险。据人民日报下属的国际金融报援引上海交通大学助理教授李楠的话报道，美国批准现货比特币ETF“将使加密货币市场更加疯狂，为洗钱等非法交易提供了温床”。###</div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>legitimate (adj.) - /lɪˈdʒɪtɪmət/ 合法，正当的。    <p>原文例句：These funds “give the crypto industry more legitimacy and also opens up more collaboration opportunities with mainstream finance”, said RJ Ke, a researcher with ethereum scaling start-up Taiko. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由legis（法律）和timus（合适的）组成，表示“正当的，合法的”。在这个例句中，它指的是现货加密货币ETF可以为加密货币行业带来更多的合法性。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>ambitious (adj.) - /æmˈbɪʃəs/ 雄心勃勃的，有野心的。    <p>原文例句：Hong Kong should soon follow the United States’ lead in authorising spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs), bolstering the city’s ambition to become a major virtual-asset hub in Asia, according to industry insiders. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由ambire（追求）和-osus（丰富的）组成，表示“雄心勃勃的”。在这个例句中，它指的是香港雄心勃勃地成为亚洲主要的虚拟资产中心。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>exchange-traded fund (ETF) - 交易所交易基金。    <P>原文例句：Hong Kong should soon follow the United States’ lead in authorising spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs), bolstering the city’s ambition to become a major virtual-asset hub in Asia, according to industry insiders. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由exchange（交换），traded（交易），fund（基金）组成，表示“交易所交易基金”。在这个例句中，它指的是香港应该尽快效仿美国，授权现货加密货币交易所交易基金。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>virtual asset - 虚拟资产。    <P>原文例句：Spot cryptocurrency ETFs enable investors to gain exposure to virtual assets without directly buying any crypto tokens.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由virtual（虚拟的）和asset（资产）组成的，表示“虚拟资产”。在这个例句中，它指的是现货加密货币交易所交易基金使投资者能够接触虚拟资产，而无需直接购买任何加密货币代币。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“These funds ‘give the crypto industry more legitimacy and also opens up more collaboration opportunities with mainstream finance’, said RJ Ke, a researcher with ethereum scaling start-up Taiko.” - “这些基金‘赋予加密货币行业更多的合法性，也为与主流金融展开更多合作的机会打开了大门’，”以太坊扩容初创企业Taiko的研究员RJ Ke表示。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是These funds ‘give the crypto industry more legitimacy’，其中主语是These funds，谓语是give，宾语是the crypto industry more legitimacy。also opens up more collaboration opportunities with mainstream finance是一个并列分句，  <ul><li>Hong Kong has fallen behind the US in authorising spot cryptocurrency ETFs, even though regulators in December said the city was prepared to do so</li>
<li>Industry insiders urge local regulators to step up approvals to strengthen the city’s competitiveness in the global cryptocurrency market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/3b2dd50a-a4ac-4010-9e13-b8b9d2dcf87f_4276bf76.jpg" /><figcaption>The successful launch of spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds in the US is expected to help move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong</a> should soon follow the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>’ lead in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">authorising spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a> (ETFs), bolstering the city’s ambition to become a major <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3197838/hong-kong-unveils-policies-develop-virtual-assets-industry-challenging-singapore-hub-status" target="_self" title="">virtual-asset hub in Asia</a>, according to industry insiders.</p><p>While the city’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/sfc" target="_self" title="">Securities and Futures Commission</a> (SFC) in December said it was prepared to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" target="_self" title="">authorise retail access to spot virtual asset ETFs</a>, the actual launch of such products has already fallen behind the US, according to Wang Yi, the head of quantitative investment at CSOP Asset Management, which currently runs two <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/digital-currencies" target="_self" title="">cryptocurrency</a> futures ETFs.</p><p>US-listed spot <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bitcoin" target="_self" title="">bitcoin</a> ETFs saw US$4.6 billion worth of shares trade hands on Thursday, according to a Reuters report that cited LSEG data, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248152/us-bitcoin-etfs-trades-soar-us46-billion-first-day-after-landmark-sec-approval" target="_self" title="">investors jumped into the landmark products</a> approved by the US securities regulator on Wednesday.</p><p>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust, Grayscale Bitcoin Trust and ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF, among others – began trading on Thursday, following the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">US Securities and Exchange Commission’s landmark approval</a> that is expected to help bring the cryptocurrency industry closer to the more regulated world of traditional finance.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/9cebdb57-e859-4c52-8114-95780d50fca8_a66cec46.jpg" title="Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The successful US launch of spot bitcoin ETFs is expected to help move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city.</p><p>Spot cryptocurrency ETFs enable investors to gain exposure to virtual assets without directly buying any crypto tokens.</p><p>These funds “give the crypto industry more legitimacy and also opens up more collaboration opportunities with mainstream finance”, said RJ Ke, a researcher with ethereum scaling start-up Taiko. “Hong Kong is likely to accelerate bitcoin ETF applications in the coming months.”</p><p>Around 10 fund management firms are preparing to launch spot virtual asset-backed ETFs in Hong Kong, according to Chinese media Caixin’s interview on Wednesday of Livio Weng, chief operating officer at <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239953/hong-kongs-hashkey-launches-first-crypto-trading-app-retail-investors-gives-away-new-token" target="_self" title="">crypto trading app operator HashKey Group</a>. Weng said that up to eight companies were at an “advanced stage” to launch.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" title="">US regulator SEC authorises spot bitcoin ETFs in cryptocurrency breakthrough</a></h3><p>Bitcoin jumped about 3.4 per cent to US$47,500, following the spot crypto ETF approvals in the US. That was nearly three times the level that the original cryptocurrency reached in November 2022, when <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3199385/crypto-exchange-giant-ftx-collapses-files-bankruptcy-protection-global-digital-currency-market-posts" target="_self" title="">failed crypto exchange FTX filed for bankruptcy</a> to send bitcoin’s price below US$17,000.</p><p>Hong Kong needs to launch spot virtual asset ETFs as soon as possible to “ensure that the city remains competitive in the global cryptocurrency market and strengthen its position as a global financial centre”, said Mao Shixing, also known as “Discus Fish”, who is the co-founder and chief executive of digital asset custody solutions provider Cobo.</p><p>Mao said the US approvals could impact other jurisdictions because “the SEC is one of the most influential and reputable financial regulators in the world”, adding that the agency’s initiatives “often serve as important references for financial regulators in other countries and regions”.</p><p>“However, each country and region has its own independent stance and regulatory objectives,” he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" title="">Hong Kong to push retail access to spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a></h3><p>Echoing the Cobo head’s view, Donald Day, chief operating officer at digital asset platform VDX, said the SEC’s decision would make its peers “seriously consider whether similar ETFs would be permissible and desirable”.</p><p>Day pointed out that the SFC’s statement in December about being prepared to authorise such funds has “in principle opened a pathway for issuers to launch spot crypto ETFs in Hong Kong”.</p><p>With the US, there are now nine markets around the world that have allowed the operation of spot crypto ETFs. The other markets include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/canada?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Canada</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/germany?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Germany</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/switzerland?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Switzerland</a>, and tax havens such as the Cayman Islands in the Caribbean and Jersey near the coast of northwestern France, according to market analytics firm CoinGecko.</p><p>Mainland China, however, is unlikely to follow suit.</p><p>In December, China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology said it will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" target="_self" title="">draft a national Web3 development plan</a> to suit the country’s needs. But the announcement did not mention cryptocurrencies even though Beijing maintains its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3216894/chinese-officials-pledge-support-hong-kongs-tech-web3-ambitions-digital-economy-summit?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">support for Hong Kong’s ambition to become a major virtual-asset hub</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" title="">Beijing to draft national Web3 development plan amid strict cryptocurrency ban</a></h3><p>The Chinese government banned banks from handling bitcoin in 2013 and forced cryptocurrency exchanges to move offshore in 2017. In 2021, the country’s regulators reiterated the state’s prohibition on all financial institutions from engaging in crypto-related activities.</p><p>China’s state media recently emphasised the risks involved in spot cryptocurrency ETFs.</p><p>The US approval of spot bitcoin ETFs “would make the cryptocurrency market even more frantic, providing fertile ground for illegal transactions such as money laundering”, according to a report by the International Financial News, a newspaper under the People’s Daily, which cited Shanghai Jiao Tong University assistant professor Li Nan.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
