<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China convenes Huawei, Tencent, Baidu to draft metaverse standards in bid to become global technology leader</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3249180/china-convenes-huawei-tencent-baidu-draft-metaverse-standards-bid-become-global-technology-leader</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  China has formed a working group of 60 experts to establish standards for the metaverse industry. The group includes representatives from technology firms, government officials, and academic researchers. They will focus on building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards, promoting the standards, and training talent. The working group will also encourage local companies and institutions to participate in international standard-setting activities.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China establishes a working group to develop metaverse industry standards.</li>    <li>Theme: The Chinese government's efforts to regulate and promote the development of the metaverse industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of establishing standards for the metaverse industry to ensure its healthy and orderly development.</li>    <li>Main information: Composition of the working group; responsibilities of the working group; emphasis on both domestic and international standard-setting.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国成立了由60名专家组成的元宇宙行业标准工作组。该工作组包括来自科技企业、政府官员和学术研究机构的代表。他们将重点建设和维护元宇宙行业标准体系、推广标准和培养人才。工作组还将鼓励国内企业和机构积极参与国际标准制定工作。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国成立元宇宙行业标准工作组。</li>    <li>主题：中国政府为规范和推动元宇宙行业发展的努力。</li>    <li>观点：建立元宇宙行业标准以确保其健康有序发展的重要意义。</li>    <li>主要信息：工作组组成；工作组职责；强调国内与国际标准制定并行。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>metaverse (n.) - /ˌmetəˈvɜːrs/ 元宇宙。    <p>原文例句：China has formed a working group to establish metaverse standards. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由meta（超越，更高层次）和verse（世界）构成的，是一个复合词，表示“超越现实世界的虚拟世界”。在这个例句中，它指的是元宇宙，即一种基于虚拟现实和增强现实技术的虚拟世界。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>titans (n.) - /ˈtaɪtn̩z/ 巨头。    <p>原文例句：Representatives from telecoms equipment giant Huawei Technologies, video gaming titans Tencent Holdings and NetEase, web search and artificial intelligence champion Baidu, financial technology firm Ant Group and computer maker Lenovo Group are among those on the list published by the MIIT on Friday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由Greek titān（巨人，泰坦神）构成的，表示“巨人，伟人，巨头”。在这个例句中，它指的是科技巨头，即在某个领域中具有统治地位的大型企业。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>set up - 建立，设立。    <P>原文例句：Shanghai has planned to set up both government-backed and private funds dedicated to metaverse development. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由set（设置，放置）和up（向上，向上移动）构成的，表示“建立，设立”。在这个例句中，它指的是上海计划建立专门用于元宇宙开发的政府支持基金和私人基金。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In 2022, Meta, Microsoft and others founded the Metaverse Standards Forum, which also comprises Huawei, Tencent and some other Chinese tech giants. - 在2022年，Meta、微软等公司建立了元宇宙标准论坛，其中也包含华为、腾讯等中国科技巨头。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是Meta, Microsoft and others founded the Metaverse Standards Forum，其中主语是Meta, Microsoft and others，谓语是founded，宾语是the Metaverse Standards Forum。which also comprises Huawei, Tencent and some other Chinese tech giants是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰the Metaverse Standards Forum，表示元宇宙标准论坛还包括华为、腾讯等中国科技巨头。这个句子的意思是说，在2022年，Meta、微软等公司建立了元宇宙标准论坛，其中也包含华为、腾讯等中国科技巨头。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作定语 - 修饰先行词，使之特指。    <p>原文例句：The group is tasked with building, maintaining and promoting metaverse industry standards, China’s technology regulator says. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的语法结构，结构是：现在分词 + 名词或代词。其中现在分词是由动词的现在分词形式构成的，名词或代词是现在分词短语所修饰的先行词。这个语法结构表示现在分词所表示的动作或状态对先行词的限制或补充说明，使先行词特指。在这个例句中，现在分词短语building, maintaining and promoting metaverse industry standards是对先行词the group的限制或补充说明，表示该工作组的任务是建立、维护和推广元宇宙行业标准。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>动名词作主语 - 名词性短语作主语。    <p>原文例句：Beijing is hoping to become a leader in the emerging field. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的语法结构，结构是：动名词 + to be + 其他。其中动名词是由动词的现在分词形式构成的，to be是系动词，其他是动名词短语作主语的补语部分。这个语法结构表示动名词短语所表示的动作或状态是句子陈述的主体。在这个例句中，动名词短语become a leader in the emerging field是对句子陈述的主体，表示北京希望成为新兴领域的领导者。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The working group consists of 60 experts, including those from the private sector as well as government officials and academic researchers</li>
<li>The group is tasked with building, maintaining and promoting metaverse industry standards, China’s technology regulator says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/56f4a36f-d5d5-434d-8326-ac2adaa5400e_7b70980f.jpg" /><figcaption>China has formed a working group to establish metaverse standards. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) has assembled 60 experts, including some from the country’s largest technology firms, to form a new working group to establish standards for the metaverse sector.</p><p>Representatives from telecoms equipment giant Huawei Technologies, video gaming titans Tencent Holdings and NetEase, web search and artificial intelligence champion Baidu, financial technology firm Ant Group and computer maker Lenovo Group are among those on the list published by the MIIT on Friday.</p><p>Ant is an affiliate of Alibaba Group Holding, owner of the Post.</p><p>Other members include MIIT officials and researchers from Peking University, Fudan University and other renowned institutions in the country.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>The MIIT in September proposed to form a working group to “guide the healthy and orderly development of the metaverse industry through standard regulation”, cautioning that the sector was facing ethical and security challenges.</p><p>The group would be tasked with “building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards”, “promoting the standards” and “training talent”, the regulator said in its proposal.</p><p>Besides focusing on domestic standards, the group would also “encourage local companies and institutions to deeply engage in international standard-setting activities”.</p><p>The metaverse, a loosely-defined term that refers to a virtual three-dimensional world, has become a trending topic in the past few years.</p><p>US social media giant Facebook changed its name to Meta Platforms in 2021. CEO and founder Mark Zuckerberg explained during the rebranding announcement that he sought to embrace “the next chapter for the internet”.</p><p>In 2022, Meta, Microsoft and others founded the Metaverse Standards Forum, which also comprises Huawei, Tencent and some other Chinese tech giants.</p><p>Beijing is hoping to become a leader in the emerging field. Five authorities, including the MIIT, released a joint plan last year to nurture at least <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3233933/china-wants-metaverse-firms-global-influence-and-plans-five-industrial-clusters-2025" target="_self" title="">three metaverse companies “with global influence”</a> by 2025.</p><p>Several local governments have made it a priority to develop the metaverse sector.</p><p>Beijing’s eastern Tongzhou district, considered a “sub-centre” of the capital city, has vowed to incorporate more than 100 metaverse-related firms by the end of the year.</p><p>Shanghai has planned to set up both government-backed and private funds dedicated to metaverse development. The first one, established in late 2022, raised an initial sum of 1 billion yuan (US$140 million).</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TuSimple will continue its drive to Asia-Pacific in wake of autonomous truck firm’s decision to delist from Nasdaq</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3249140/tusimple-will-continue-its-drive-asia-pacific-wake-autonomous-truck-firms-decision-delist-nasdaq</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  图森未来将业务重心转向亚太地区，包括中国、日本和澳大利亚，这里的监管支持和强劲的供应链将有助于实现其商业目标。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 图森未来退市纳斯达克，转向亚太地区寻求更好的商业机会。</li>    <li>Theme: 图森未来将重心转向亚太地区，以实现其商业目标和退出纳斯达克交易所的计划。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 亚太地区的成熟硬件供应链有助于图森未来的商业目标；自动驾驶业界为实现盈利持续努力；图森未来高管认为他们最需要解决的挑战是从演示和试点走向实际提供有利可图的商业服务。</li>    <li>Main information: 图森未来在日本开展了 4 级自动驾驶卡车的测试运行；图森未来在纳斯达克宣布自愿退市，最后交易日预计在 2 月 7 日左右；图森未来去年 10 月裁员 75%，在美结束运营；图森未来领导人在亚太地区探索另一个 IPO 的可能性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  图森未来宣布退出美国，重点转向亚洲，将业务重心转移到亚太地区，包括中国、日本和澳大利亚等地，希望借此获取监管支持和强劲的供应链，帮助其实现商业目标。  <ul>    <li>摘要：图森未来退市纳斯达克，转向亚太地区寻求更好的商业机会。</li>    <li>主题：图森未来将重心转向亚太地区，以实现其商业目标和退出纳斯达克交易所的计划。</li>    <li>观点：亚太地区的成熟硬件供应链有助于图森未来的商业目标；自动驾驶业界为实现盈利持续努力；图森未来高管认为他们最需要解决的挑战是从演示和试点走向实际提供有利可图的商业服务。</li>    <li>主要信息：图森未来在日本开展了 4 级自动驾驶卡车的测试运行；图森未来在纳斯达克宣布自愿退市，最后交易日预计在 2 月 7 日左右；图森未来去年 10 月裁员 75%，在美结束运营；图森未来领导人在亚太地区探索另一个 IPO 的可能性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>autonomous (adj.) - /ˌɔːtˈɒnəməs/ 自主的，独立的。    <p>原文例句：Last July, Alphabet unit Waymo announced that it would slow down work in the self-driving truck field under its Via subsidiary. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Greek，由auto-（自己）和nomos（法律）构成的，表示“自治的，独立的，有自己法律的”。在这个例句中，它被用来形容Waymo的子公司Via在自动驾驶卡车领域的工作。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>pilot (n.) - /ˈpaɪlət/ 飞行员，驾驶员，引导者。    <p>原文例句：TuSimple was also the first company to deploy autonomous trucks on pilot tests between the cities of Tucson and Phoenix in Arizona and Las Vegas, Nevada in 2018. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，表示“掌舵手，领航员，飞行员”。在这个例句中，它被用来形容图森未来在2018年首次在图森、凤凰城和拉斯维加斯之间部署自动驾驶卡车进行试点测试。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>primary market - 股票、债券等首次发行时进行交易的市场，也称发行市场，类似于我国的证券交易所。    <P>原文例句：TuSimple, once considered a star in the global autonomous driving sector and a leader in US self-driving truck development, has focused on Level 4 autonomy. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组指首次发行股票或债券的市场，也称为发行市场或初级市场。在这个例句中，它被用来描述图森未来作为全球自动驾驶领域的明星企业和美国自动驾驶卡车开发的领导者，一直专注于4级自动驾驶技术。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC, including China, Japan and Australia, where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help the firm’s commercial goals, Lu said in a Friday interview, as the self-driving industry continues to push for profitability. - 卢在星期五的一次采访中表示，图森未来正在将重点转移到包括中国、日本和澳大利亚在内的亚太地区，那里的监管支持和强大的供应链能够帮助公司实现其商业目标，因为自动驾驶行业仍在继续推动盈利。<p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾句子，主语是TuSimple，谓语是is shifting its focus to APAC，宾语是China, Japan and Australia。as the self-driving industry continues to push for profitability是一个时间状语从句，表示当自动驾驶行业继续推动盈利时。这个句子的意思是说，图森未来正在将重点转移到包括中国、日本和澳大利亚在内的亚太地区，那里的监管支持和强大的供应链能够帮助公司实现其商业目标。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>复数动词 - 一般由动词词干和-s/-es/-ies组成，用于表示主语为复数或不可数名词。    <p>原文例句：TuSimple reported a US$248.6 million loss from operations in the first nine months of 2023, narrowing from a US$341.7 million loss in the same period in the previous year. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，动词report和narrow分别用作过去式和现在分词，并且都使用了复数形式，表示TuSimple在2023年前九个月的运营亏损为2.486亿美元，比前一年的同期亏损3.417亿美元有所减少。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>条件从句 -  是指以连词if, when, unless, as, as soon as等为首的复合句中含有的分句，可归纳为以下三个类型：（1）if为主语从句（表假设）（2）if为主语从句（表的条件）（3）if为时间状语从句    <p>原文例句：Lu said the company could explore another IPO down the road “when the company makes more progress and the market conditions make sense”, but it has no timeline or location in mind at the present time. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这段话是对担任首席执行官的Lu的引述。when the company makes more progress and the market conditions make sense是一个条件状语从句，表示当公司取得更大进展，市场状况合理时。在这个句子中，条件从句修饰了谓语could explore another IPO，表示该公司到时候可能会考虑进行另一次IPO。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC, including China, Japan and Australia, where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help</li>
<li>TuSimple this week announced a plan to voluntarily delist from Nasdaq, with its last trading day expected to be around February 7</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/9379da4f-2af9-460b-b031-733718defcaa_f6769707.jpg" /><figcaption>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC. Photo: Handout </figcaption></figure><p>Autonomous truck company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217769/tusimple-working-resolving-us-issues-after-management-turmoil-and-pushing-ahead-autonomous-driving?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">TuSimple Holdings</a> will continue to pivot to the Asia-Pacific (APAC) region for better commercial opportunities and in line with its plan to delist from the Nasdaq exchange, said chief executive officer Lu Cheng.</p><p>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC, including China, Japan and Australia, where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help the firm’s commercial goals, Lu said in a Friday interview, as the self-driving industry continues to push for profitability.</p><p>“For autonomous trucks, we have to integrate the advanced software capabilities – the virtual driver – with reliable and scalable hardware that includes the truck itself, Tier-1 components coupled with the right use case,” Lu said. “That’s one of the benefits of focusing our business more on APAC because of the maturity of the hardware supply chain.”</p><p>The company started test runs of Level 4 autonomous trucks in Japan last year, and conducted full autonomous runs – without a human in the truck – on public roads in Shanghai. Level 4 is considered to be fully autonomous driving, although a human driver can still request control, and the car still has a cockpit.</p><p>San Diego, California-based TuSimple, which carried out an initial public offering (IPO) in 2021, announced its plan to voluntarily delist from Nasdaq on Wednesday, with its last trading day on the exchange expected to be around February 7.</p><p>The company cited changes in the capital markets for “pre-commercialised companies” and significantly increased stock price volatility as part of its rationale for delisting. It also said being a private firm would help the company better navigate its transformation.</p><p>The company’s shares closed at US$0.49 on Thursday, trading around 98 per cent lower than its debut price of US$40.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244089/autonomous-trucking-company-tusimple-cease-us-operations-amid-new-round-lay-offs-focus-asia-pacific" title="">Autonomous trucking firm TuSimple to exit US amid new lay-offs, focus on Asia</a></h3><p>Lu said the company could explore another IPO down the road “when the company makes more progress and the market conditions make sense”, but it has no timeline or location in mind at the present time.</p><p>TuSimple said last month that it was cutting 75 per cent of its workforce and winding down its operations in the US. The retreat comes amid further consolidation in the autonomous driving industry, with several leading players announcing lay-offs and downsizing in the past year.</p><p>Last July, Alphabet unit Waymo announced that it would slow down work in the self-driving truck field under its Via subsidiary. Last May, Embark Technology – an early proponent of self-driving truck software development in the US – delisted from the Nasdaq and went private via a merger, after running out of capital to pursue commercial production.</p><p>The lack of a clear path to profitability and real commercialisation is a challenge for the industry, which includes technology, hardware supply chain, and regulatory issues, Lu said. “Being able to move from demos and pilots to actually providing a real service that is profitable is the biggest challenge,” he added.</p><p>TuSimple reported a US$248.6 million loss from operations in the first nine months of 2023, narrowing from a US$341.7 million loss in the same period in the previous year.</p><p>TuSimple, once considered a star in the global autonomous driving sector and a leader in US self-driving truck development, has focused on Level 4 autonomy. It was also the first company to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/2169885/driverless-tech-start-aims-replace-15-million-truckers-us-china?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">deploy autonomous trucks on pilot tests</a> between the cities of Tucson and Phoenix in Arizona and Las Vegas, Nevada in 2018.</p><p>The company has been grappling with a US government investigation, corporate disputes and lay-offs since 2022.</p><p>The US Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS), an inter-agency panel that reviews the national security implications of foreign investments in the US, kicked off an investigation of TuSimple with the FBI and the Securities and Exchange Commission in 2022.</p><p>The inquiry revolves around whether TuSimple co-founder and then-chief executive Hou Xiaodi <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217769/tusimple-working-resolving-us-issues-after-management-turmoil-and-pushing-ahead-autonomous-driving?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">made illegal funding or technology transfers to Hydron</a>, a Chinese autonomous truck start-up established by another TuSimple co-founder Chen Mo in 2021.</p><p>How was fired by the company’s board in October 2022 after an internal investigation, with it citing a “loss in trust and confidence” in connection with the alleged sharing of confidential information with Hydron.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong eyes ‘more flexible’ path in regulating spot cryptocurrency ETFs as US races ahead with approvals</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249086/hong-kong-eyes-more-flexible-path-regulating-spot-crypto-etfs-us-races-ahead-approvals</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  The Hong Kong government plans to develop a more lenient regulatory framework for spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs) compared to the United States. While the US has a head start in terms of approval speed and market size, Hong Kong aims to differentiate itself by allowing both cash and in-kind subscriptions for its spot cryptocurrency ETFs. This approach reflects a different regulatory landscape, as the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) has reservations about allowing direct involvement with bitcoin in ETF transactions due to the unregulated nature of spot bitcoin trading in the US. However, Hong Kong's regulated virtual asset trading platforms provide a more favorable environment for virtual asset ETFs. Industry experts are optimistic about Hong Kong's potential to become a cryptocurrency hub, citing its adaptable regulatory environment and clear vision for regulating virtual assets. However, the city faces strong competition from major jurisdictions like the US, which has a larger market and established financial giants offering spot cryptocurrency ETFs.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Hong Kong's proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions, setting it apart from the US approach.</li>    <li>Theme: Hong Kong aims to develop a more flexible framework for spot cryptocurrency ETFs to attract industry and establish itself as a cryptocurrency hub.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The difference in regulatory approaches between Hong Kong and the US reflects the ongoing evolution of virtual asset regulation worldwide.</li>    <li>Main information: Hong Kong's proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs; comparison with the US approach; industry optimism about Hong Kong's prospects.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  目前，香港政府计划针对现货加密货币交易所交易基金（ETF）制定一套较为宽松的监管框架，有别于美国的监管方式。尽管美国在审批速度和市场规模上都处于领先地位，但香港旨在允许其现货加密货币 ETF 进行现金和实物认购，以实现差异化。这种做法反映了不同的监管格局，因为美国证券交易委员会 (SEC) 对在 ETF 交易中直接涉及比特币持保留态度，原因是现货比特币交易在美国不受监管。然而，香港受监管的虚拟资产交易平台为虚拟资产 ETF 提供了一个更有利的环境。业内专家对香港有望成为加密货币中心感到乐观，他们认为香港拥有适应性强的监管环境和清晰的虚拟资产监管愿景。然而，该市面临着来自美国等主要司法管辖区的激烈竞争，美国拥有更大的市场和提供现货加密货币 ETF 的成熟金融巨头。  <ul>    <li>摘要：香港针对现货加密货币 ETF 提出的规则允许进行现金和实物认购，使其有别于美国的方式。</li>    <li>主题：香港旨在为现货加密货币 ETF 制定更灵活的框架，以吸引业界人士并确立其作为加密货币中心的声誉。</li>    <li>观点：香港和美国在监管方式上的差异反映了全球虚拟资产监管的不断演变。</li>    <li>主要信息：香港针对现货加密货币 ETF 提出的规则；与美国方式的比较；业界人士对香港前景的乐观情绪。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>diversify (v.) - /dɪˈvɜːsɪfaɪ/ 使多元化，使多样化。    <p>原文例句：Foxconn and other Taiwanese electronics manufacturers diversify their businesses outside China as tensions rise between Washington and Beijing.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由 di-（分开）和 versus（转向）组成，意为“使变化，使多样化”。在这个例句中，它描述了鸿海和其他台湾电子制造商在华盛顿和北京之间的紧张关系升级时，努力使他们的业务多样化。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>spectator (n.) - /ˈspɛkteɪtər/ 观众，旁观者。    <p>原文例句：Spectators of the tournament were treated to a rare view of the Northern Lights.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语 spectator，意为“观看者”。在这个例句中，它指的是观看比赛的观众或旁观者。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Firefox is also very competitive in terms of performance and speed.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由 in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和 of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示 Firefox 在性能和速度方面也很有竞争力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>keep pace with - 跟上，保持同步。    <P>原文例句：To keep pace with the rapidly changing demands of the market, companies need to innovate constantly.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由 keep（保持）和 pace（速度，节奏）组成，表示“保持速度或节奏”。在这个例句中，它表示为了满足市场快速变化的需求，公司需要不断创新。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong’s proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs and the products approved in the US is that Hong Kong will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions. - 香港针对现货加密货币 ETF 提出的规则与其在美国获得批准的产品之间的主要区别在于香港允许进行现金和实物认购。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是 Hong Kong will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions，其中主语是 Hong Kong，谓语是 will allow，宾语是 both cash and in-kind subscriptions。The proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs and the products approved in the US 是一个并列短语作主语，修饰 will allow，表示香港针对现货加密货币 ETF 提出的规则和在美国获得批准的产品。is that 是一个连接词，将两个句子连接起来，表示香港针对现货加密货币 ETF 提出的规则与在美国获得批准的产品之间的主要区别在于香港允许进行现金和实物认购。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示与事实相反或不确定的事情。    <p>原文例句：If I were you, I would take a different approach.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气例句，表示说话人假设的情况与事实相反。结构是：if + 过去式，would + 动词原形。在这个例句中，it 表示说话人假设的情况与事实相反，would take 表示说话人将采取的行动。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：I have been working on this project for several weeks.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时例句，表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。在这个例句中，have been working 表示动作从过去的某个时间开始一直持续到现在，即我已经在这个项目上工作了好几个星期。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>A key difference between Hong Kong’s proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs and the US is that the city will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions</li>
<li>The SFC and Hong Kong Monetary Authority’s plan to authorise spot cryptocurrency ETFs has given the industry optimism about the city’s prospects of becoming a cryptocurrency hub</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/cfc5c501-3421-4cf4-a330-cfc6070fee33_e8f94cca.jpg" /><figcaption>Stacks of cryptocurrency coin representations are set against the backdrop of the Hong Kong flag. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure><p>Hong Kong is set to develop a more flexible regime for cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs), even though the US leads in both approval speed and market size, experts said.</p><p>A key difference between Hong Kong’s proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs and products approved in the US is that Hong Kong will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions. Under such rules, participating dealers can directly use bitcoin to subscribe to or redeem the ETF’s shares, whereas in the US, such subscriptions and redemptions are only allowed with cash.</p><p>The different approach reflects a divergence of virtual asset regulatory frameworks, where the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) “appears reluctant to allow licensed dealers to touch bitcoin” when subscribing for and redeeming ETF shares because spot bitcoin trades are unregulated in the US, according to Andrew Fei, a partner at King &amp; Wood Mallesons in Hong Kong.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3248972/hong-kong-securities-watchdog-puts-virtual-asset-trading-platforms-aramex-and-difx-alert-list" title="">Hong Kong securities watchdog puts virtual asset trading platforms on fraud alert</a></h3><p>Regulators in Hong Kong last month said that they will allow retail access to spot virtual asset ETFs, and are willing to accept applications from funds hoping to offer such products to the public.</p><p>After nine spot bitcoin ETFs in the US, offered by fund giants including BlackRock and Fidelity, attracted nearly US$2 billion in their first three days of trading, virtual asset industry participants in Hong Kong have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248282/hong-kong-needs-speed-approval-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-after-us-launch-industry" target="_self" title="">urged the Hong Kong government to speed up</a> the approval of the city’s own offerings.</p><p>“I hope that Hong Kong, amid the rapid development and intense competition in the virtual asset sector, can seize a spot globally as quickly as possible,” Legislative Council member Johnny Ng Kit-chong wrote in a post on X, formerly Twitter, last week. “[Hong Kong should] strive to be the first to implement relevant policies and products particularly in Asia.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246415/hong-kong-regulators-propose-tougher-rules-sale-stablecoins-retail-investors" title="">Hong Kong regulators propose licensing for sale of stablecoins to public</a></h3><p>In a statement last week, SEC chair Gary Gensler said that despite its approval of spot bitcoin ETFs, the regulator “did not approve or endorse bitcoin”, which is “primarily a speculative, volatile asset that’s also used for illicit activity including ransomware, money laundering, sanction evasion, and terrorist financing”.</p><p>“In the US, the spot bitcoin market is largely unregulated and the SEC remains somewhat sceptical about spot bitcoin transactions,” Fei said.</p><p>However, because spot virtual asset transactions on licensed virtual asset trading platforms are regulated in Hong Kong, the city’s Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) “appears to be more comfortable with virtual asset ETFs”, he added.</p><p>The SFC and the Hong Kong Monetary Authority’s joint plan to authorise spot cryptocurrency ETFs has given the industry <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual?module=hard_link&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">optimism</a> about the city’s prospects of becoming a cryptocurrency hub.</p><p>“Hong Kong’s regulatory environment, known for adaptability, positions it well in navigating the evolving world of digital assets,” said Dmitry Lapidus, senior liquid analyst at US venture capital firm CoinFund.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Nasdaq board in Times Square, New York, shows video of the opening bell as Bitcoin Spot ETF’s are launched on the Nasdaq Exchange on January 11. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1335" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/a280c4ae-0893-40b7-9b49-19d29cae20e5_a57dc0a9.jpg" title="The Nasdaq board in Times Square, New York, shows video of the opening bell as Bitcoin Spot ETF’s are launched on the Nasdaq Exchange on January 11. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Nasdaq board in Times Square, New York, shows video of the opening bell as Bitcoin Spot ETF’s are launched on the Nasdaq Exchange on January 11. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Hong Kong is one of the few major jurisdictions in the world that has a clear vision on regulating virtual assets now, and I truly believe this move will continue to serve Hong Kong as a global financial hub in the coming days,” said Kennix Chan, executive director at Victory Securities Company Limited.</p><p>But the city will face strong competition from jurisdictions like the US, experts noted.</p><p>The American cryptocurrency market is poised to be much larger for US and world investors, especially when the ones offering the spot cryptocurrency ETFs are finance heavyweights such as Blackrock, Fidelity, Franklin, and Invesco, said Jack Poon, professor of practice for fintech and entrepreneurship at the Hong Kong Polytechnic University.</p><p>“They have a huge existing customer base and a brand that retail investors feel comfortable with,” Poon said, adding that they are also offering low fees that issuers in Hong Kong may not be able to absorb in the long term.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba co-founder Jack Ma praises rural teachers for their educational passion and ‘belief in the future’ in annual address</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249115/alibaba-co-founder-jack-ma-praises-rural-teachers-their-educational-passion-and-belief-future-annual</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In a video message, Jack Ma, co-founder of Alibaba, expressed his admiration for rural teachers in China, praising their dedication and belief in the future. Ma, a former teacher himself, emphasized the importance of empowering students in the countryside, fostering creativity, curiosity, and confidence. Despite challenging conditions, these teachers are committed to bringing quality education to their students.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Jack Ma's appreciation for rural teachers' efforts to nurture creativity and confidence in students.</li>    <li>Theme: The significant role of rural teachers in shaping the future of students in rural areas.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Ma's perspective on the transformative power of education and the impact of rural teachers in overcoming challenges.</li>    <li>Main information: Ma's interactions with rural teachers, his praise for their passion and belief in the future, and his ongoing support for educational initiatives.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在一段视频讲话中，阿里巴巴联合创始人马云表达了对中国乡村教师的钦佩，赞扬了他们的奉献精神和对未来的信念。马云曾是教师，他强调了赋能乡村地区学生、培养创造力、好奇心和自信心的重要性。尽管条件艰苦，这些教师致力于为学生带来优质的教育。  <ul>    <li>摘要：马云赞赏乡村教师在培养学生创造力和自信心方面的努力。</li>    <li>主题：乡村教师在塑造乡村地区学生未来方面发挥的重要作用。</li>    <li>观点：马云对教育变革力量和乡村教师在克服挑战中发挥的作用的看法。</li>    <li>主要信息：马云与乡村教师的互动，他对他们热情和信念的赞扬，以及他持续支持教育事业的举措。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>foster (v.) - /ˈfɑːstə/ 培养，促进。    <p>原文例句：The projects have fostered 120 rural principals, enlisted 800 pre-service teachers, and revamped 63 boarding schools in rural areas. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语，意思是“养育，培育”。在这个例句中，it指的是这些项目培养了120名乡村校长，招募了800名在职前教师，并改造了63所农村寄宿学校。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the run up to - 在……之前，在……的准备阶段。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba co-founder Ma has met with rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），the（冠词），run（奔跑），up（向上）和to（向……）构成的，表示“在……之前，在……的准备阶段”。在这个例句中，it指的是阿里巴巴的联合创始人马云在过去的九年里，一直在中国农历新年前夕与乡村教师见面。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Jack Ma, co-founder of Alibaba Group Holding, has praised the mentality of rural teachers in China and their “belief in the future”.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是Jack Ma, co-founder of Alibaba Group Holding，谓语是has praised，宾语是the mentality of rural teachers in China and their “belief in the future”。has praised是一个现在完成时态的动词，表示马云已经赞扬了中国乡村教师的心态和他们的“对未来的信念”。the mentality of rural teachers in China and their “belief in the future”是一个由两个名词短语组成的复合宾语，表示马云赞扬了中国乡村教师的心态和他们的“对未来的信念”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子的某个部分。    <p>原文例句：Every year, 100 outstanding rural teachers are shortlisted and granted 100,000 yuan (US$14,260) each to support rural education.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句型，结构是：It is/was + 被强调的部分 + that/who + 其他。在这个例句中，被强调的部分是100 outstanding rural teachers，that引导了一个限制性定语从句，修饰100 outstanding rural teachers，表示每年有100名优秀的乡村教师入围并获得100,000元（14,260美元）的资助，以支持乡村教育。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Ma expressses his admiration for their efforts to bring out the creativity, curiosity and confidence of students in the countryside</li>
<li>Alibaba co-founder Ma has met with rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/c86b1bc7-27d2-4497-8b44-73ac9588866e_487c5401.jpg" /><figcaption>Alibaba founder Jack Ma praises rural teachers for their ‘belief in the future’. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Jack Ma, co-founder of Alibaba Group Holding, has praised the mentality of rural teachers in China and their “belief in the future”, in a message of public support from the increasingly reclusive Chinese billionaire.</p><p>In a videotaped speech issued by the Jack Ma Foundation on Thursday, Ma – a former teacher himself – is seen speaking to a group of rural Chinese teachers, expressing his admiration for their efforts to bring out the creativity, curiosity and confidence of students amid challenging conditions in the countryside.</p><p>Ma, 59, praises their “sincere passion for education” and their “belief in the future”, according to excerpts of his comments issued by the Foundation.</p><p>Ma, who has maintained a low profile since stepping down as chairman of e-commerce giant Alibaba in 2019, has met with Chinese rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245634/jack-ma-backed-fishery-and-agriculture-company-18-meters-starts-sale-seafood-products-alibabas" title="">Jack Ma-backed firm 1.8 Meters starts online sales via Alibaba’s Freshippo and Tmall</a></h3><p>The Jack Ma Rural Teachers Initiative and Jack Ma Rural Teachers Award were officially launched on September 16, 2015. Every year, 100 outstanding rural teachers are shortlisted and granted 100,000 yuan (US$14,260) each to support rural education, according to the Foundation’s website. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>In recent years Ma has advocated for agricultural and educational development, as well as environmental protection. Ma, who signed off with a guitar and a rock star wig at a farewell event for thousands of employees in 2019, has pursued several educational causes, including the Rural Principal Initiative, launched in 2016, and the Pre-Service Teachers and Rural School Initiative, both launched in 2017.</p><p>The projects have fostered 120 rural principals, enlisted 800 pre-service teachers, and revamped 63 boarding schools in rural areas.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
