<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Nokia set to exit telecommunications joint venture with Huawei amid US-China tensions</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249181/nokia-set-exit-telecommunications-joint-venture-huawei-amid-us-china-tensions</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  芬兰公司诺基亚已找到买家，将其在大唐电信科技的多数股权出售给一个包括国有实体在内的集团，但须等待政府的最终批准。华为一直被视为大唐电信科技的实际控制者，该公司自2021年以来一直销售中国巨头的重新贴牌手机。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Finnish company Nokia has found new buyers for its majority stake in TD Tech, but awaits government approval.</li>    <li>Theme: The sale of Nokia's majority stake in TD Tech, a joint venture with Huawei, and the involvement of government entities in the deal.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Huawei's role as the de facto controller of TD Tech and its efforts to circumvent US sanctions.</li>    <li>Main information: The new buyers include state-owned entities and venture capital firms; TD Tech has presence in over 100 countries; Huawei's opposition to Nokia's previous sale attempt.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  芬兰公司诺基亚已找到买家，将其在大唐电信科技的多数股权出售给一个包括国有实体在内的集团，但须等待政府的最终批准。华为一直被视为大唐电信科技的实际控制者，该公司自2021年以来一直销售中国巨头的重新贴牌手机。  <ul>    <li>摘要：芬兰公司诺基亚已找到买家，将其在大唐电信科技的多数股权出售给一个包括国有实体在内的集团，但须等待政府的最终批准。</li>    <li>主题：诺基亚出售其在大唐电信科技的多数股权，以及国有实体参与该交易。</li>    <li>观点：华为作为大唐电信科技的实际控制者的角色，以及其规避美国制裁的努力。</li>    <li>主要信息：新买家包括国有实体和风投公司；大唐电信科技在100多个国家开展业务；华为反对诺基亚先前的出售尝试。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stake (n.) - 股份，利益。    <p>原文例句：The Finnish company will sell its majority stake in TD Tech to a group that includes state-owned entities. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语staca，表示“柱子，桩子”。stake可以指股票或债券，还可以指利害关系。在这个例句中，它指的是诺基亚将其在大唐电信科技的多数股权出售给一个包括国有实体在内的集团。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>joint venture (n.) - 合资企业。    <p>原文例句：Under the latest agreement, wireless technology firm TD Tech will be jointly controlled by Huawei and a group of entities that include the government-owned Chengdu High-Tech Investment Group and Chengdu Gaoxin Jicui Technology Co. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于joint（共同的）和venture（冒险），表示“合资企业，共同冒险”。在这个例句中，它指的是诺基亚和华为的技术合资企业TD Tech，该企业将由华为和包括成都高新技术投资集团和成都高新技术集团在内的实体共同控制。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>de facto (adv.) - 事实上的，实际上。    <p>原文例句：Huawei has long been considered the de facto controller of TD Tech. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语de facto，表示“事实上，实际上”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为一直被视为大唐电信科技的实际控制者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fall through - 失败，落空。    <P>原文例句：A proposed deal fell through last year following strong protest by the Chinese partner. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由fall（倒下，失败）和through（穿过，落空）组成，表示“失败，落空”。在这个例句中，它指的是诺基亚去年试图将其多数股权出售给上海上市的油墨制造商东方新材料，但由于中国合作伙伴的强烈抗议，最终失败，未能成功达成交易。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>antitrust concerns - 反垄断问题。    <P>原文例句：Regulators said they had no antitrust concerns on the deal. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由antitrust（反垄断）和concerns（担忧，问题）组成，表示“反垄断问题”。在这个例句中，监管机构表示他们对这笔交易没有反垄断问题，认为这不会对竞争产生不利影响。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The document did not reveal how much equity each of the new participants will hold. - 该文件没有披露每个新参与者将持有多少股份。<p>句子分析：这是一个否定句，主语是The document，谓语是不及物动词did not reveal，宾语是how much equity each of the new participants will hold。how much equity each of the new participants will hold是一个疑问词引导的从句，作宾语。在这个例句中，The document是主语，did not reveal是谓语，how much equity each of the new participants will hold是宾语。这个句子的意思是，该文件没有披露每个新参与者将持有多少股份。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由主语承受或接受的。    <p>原文例句：TD Tech, founded in 2005, had been a joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens until 2007. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是TD Tech，谓语是被动语态的动词had been，宾语是joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens。had been是一个过去完成时的被动语态动词，表示TD Tech在2007年之前一直是华为和德国科技巨头西门子的合资企业。在这个例句中，TD Tech是主语，had been是谓语，joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens是宾语。这个句子的意思是，TD Tech在2007年之前一直是华为和德国科技巨头西门子的合资企业。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Finnish company will sell its majority stake in TD Tech to a group that includes state-owned entities, pending final government approval</li>
<li>Huawei has long been considered the de facto controller of TD Tech, which has been selling rebranded phones from the Chinese giant since 2021</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/96782c3a-8a2e-4d29-8e59-79d66ccfe5a6_def6fa44.jpg" /><figcaption>The Nokia headquarters in Espoo, Finland. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Finnish telecoms equipment giant Nokia has found new buyers for its majority stake in a Beijing-based joint venture with Huawei Technologies, after a proposed deal fell through last year following strong protest by the Chinese partner.</p><p>Under the latest agreement, wireless technology firm TD Tech will be jointly controlled by Huawei and a group of entities that include the government-owned Chengdu High-Tech Investment Group and Chengdu Gaoxin Jicui Technology Co, as well as venture capital firm Huagai, according to a disclosure published on Friday by the State Administration for Market Regulation (SAMR).</p><p>The document did not reveal how much equity each of the new participants will hold. Before the sale, Nokia owned 51 per cent of TD Tech, while Huawei held 49 per cent.</p><p>Regulators said they had no antitrust concerns on the deal and would solicit public feedback until January 28. Huawei and TD Tech together control no more than 10 per cent of China’s smartphone market, according to the SAMR, which did not specify the time frame for that data.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/36a09b3c-7803-48e6-a443-6a2cec7d849d_34f54c2a.jpg" title="An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Huawei had a 14 per cent share in the Chinese smartphone market in the third quarter last year, putting it in fifth place behind its spin-off Honor and rivals Oppo, Vivo and Apple, data from market intelligence firm Counterpoint Research showed.</p><p>TD Tech, founded in 2005, had been a joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens until 2007, when Siemens sold half of its stake to Nokia. In 2013, Siemens divested all its shares, making Nokia the major shareholder.</p><p>Known for its wireless communications equipment, including 4G and 5G networking gear, TD Tech has a presence in more than 100 countries serving 8 million industry customers, according to its website.</p><p>While Nokia had been the majority owner of the joint venture, Huawei has been the de facto controller, according to industry observers.</p><p>“The management are former Huawei employees, with product solutions based on Huawei products but fine-tuned for the industry market,” Yang Guang, an analyst covering the telecoms sector at research firm Omdia, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3216677/huawei-opposition-nokia-sale-joint-venture-threatens-finnish-firms-exit-us-china-tensions-weigh-deal" target="_self" title="">said last year</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3216677/huawei-opposition-nokia-sale-joint-venture-threatens-finnish-firms-exit-us-china-tensions-weigh-deal" title="">Huawei opposition to Nokia sale of joint venture threatens Finnish firm’s exit</a></h3><p>When Nokia last year tried to sell its majority stake to Shanghai-listed ink maker New East New Materials, Huawei threatened to stop licensing technology to TD Tech. That deal ultimately collapsed.</p><p>Huawei likely did not want to lose control of TD Tech, which could help the Chinese tech giant circumvent some US sanctions and help it address certain market segments more efficiently, Yang said at the time.</p><p>TD Tech in 2021 started selling what amounted to rebranded Huawei phones under its own brand. They included the M40 5G, which used a 7-nanometre chip from Taiwan-based MediaTek instead of Huawei’s own Kirin processors.</p><p>Sanctions imposed by Washington currently bar companies from selling to Huawei advanced chips made with US-origin technology, which includes MediaTek processors made by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a>, the world’s largest contract chip maker.</p><p>Despite the US restrictions, Huawei last year launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233636/huaweis-mate-60-pro-will-help-it-take-lost-ground-china-can-it-help-smartphone-giant-regain-global" target="_self" title="">its Mate 60 Pro</a>, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G processor.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
