<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Samsung to kick off year of AI phones with new launch this month</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247104/samsung-kick-year-ai-phones-new-launch-month</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In recent years, Samsung and other mobile phone manufacturers have relied on the development of camera technology and flexible display screens to enhance the performance of their products. In 2024, Samsung will focus on developing artificial intelligence to increase sales in the smartphone market, planning to launch new flagship products with built-in AI technology. Counterpoint Research predicts that more than one billion smartphones with built-in generative AI will be shipped by the end of 2027. Huawei has released a new Nova series of smartphones but has not yet announced details about the chips used. Companies such as OpenAI and Nvidia are at the forefront of generative AI development, which involves responding to user requests with text or images. Integrating AI into devices is the next step in the development of this technology, and Samsung and Qualcomm are at the forefront of this innovation, looking to capture a significant share of the smartphone market.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung emphasizes AI technology to enhance smartphone performance and sales.</li>    <li>Theme: The role of artificial intelligence in enhancing smartphone features.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Samsung's leadership in AI integration and the potential growth of the generative AI market.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's upcoming product launch, Counterpoint Research's predictions for AI-powered smartphones, Huawei's new Nova series, and the role of companies like OpenAI and Nvidia in AI development.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  近年来，三星等手机厂商已依靠相机技术和柔性显示屏的发展来提升产品的性能。2024年，三星将着重发展人工智能来增加手机市场的销售额，计划推出搭载内置人工智能技术的全新旗舰产品。Counterpoint Research预测，到2027年底，全球出货的具有内置生成型人工智能的智能手机将超过10亿部。华为推出了新的Nova系列智能手机，但并未公布芯片方面的细节。OpenAI和英伟达等公司处于生成型人工智能发展的最前沿，该技术涉及用文本或图像回应用户请求。将人工智能集成到设备中是该技术发展的下一步，而三星和高通则走在这一创新的最前沿，希望占据智能手机市场的很大份额。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星强调人工智能技术，以提高智能手机性能和销量。</li>    <li>主题：人工智能在增强智能手机功能中的作用。</li>    <li>观点：三星在人工智能集成方面的领先地位和生成型人工智能市场潜在增长。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星即将推出的产品、Counterpoint Research对人工智能智能手机的预测、华为新的Nova系列以及OpenAI和英伟达等公司在人工智能发展中的作用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>generative AI (n.) - 生成型人工智能。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“generative AI”是“generative”和“AI”的组合，“generative”意为“生成性的，创造性的”，“AI”意为“人工智能”。“generative AI”是指能够从现有数据或知识中创建新数据的AI。在这个例句中，“generative AI”是指能够生成文本、图像或代码等新数据的AI。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>promising (adj.) - 有希望的，有前途的。    <p>原文例句：The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：“promising”源自拉丁语“promissus”，意为“许诺的，承诺的”。“promising”表示“有希望的，有前途的”，通常用来形容某人或某物具有实现预期的潜力。在这个例句中，“promising”用来形容即将发布的Galaxy AI具有实现预期的潜力。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>capture (v.) market share - 占据市场份额。    <p>原文例句：“Similar to what it did with foldables, Samsung is likely to capture almost 50 per cent share for the next two years, followed by key Chinese OEMs like Xiaomi, Vivo, Honor and Oppo.”    <p>例句讲解：动词“capture”有“捕捉，夺取，占据”等含义，在商业语境中，“capture market share”表示“占据市场份额”。在这个例句中，“capture market share”是指三星通过推出具有AI功能的智能手机，预计将在未来两年占据近50%的市场份额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device on January 17 in San Jose, California – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – with a livestreamed event. - 三星电子宣布计划于1月17日在加利福尼亚州圣何塞发布其下一款旗舰设备——可能被称为Galaxy S24——并举行一场直播发布会。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch，其中主语是Samsung Electronics，谓语是announced，宾语是it plans to launch。其后有两个分句作状语，第一个分句是its next flagship device on January 17 in San Jose, California，其中主语是its next flagship device，谓语是to launch，宾语是on January 17 in San Jose, California。第二个分句是likely to be known as the Galaxy S24，其中主语是it，谓语是to be known as，宾语是the Galaxy S24。这个句子的意思是说，三星电子宣布计划于1月17日在加利福尼亚州圣何塞发布其下一款旗舰设备——可能被称为Galaxy S24——并举行一场直播发布会。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句 - 用于强调句子中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句是指在句子中使用“only”或“not only…but also”等词语来强调某个成分。在强调句中，被强调的成分通常位于句首或句尾。在这个例句中，强调句是“only that ‘Galaxy AI is coming.’”，其中“only”强调了“Galaxy AI is coming”这一成分。这个句子的意思是说，发布会的预告片只承诺“Galaxy AI即将到来”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去的某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去完成时是指在过去的某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。其结构是：had + 过去分词。在这个例句中，过去完成时是“are expected to be shipped”，其中“had”省略，过去分词是“shipped”。这个句子的意思是说，根据Counterpoint Research的估计，到2027年底，全球出货的具有内置生成型人工智能的智能手机将超过10亿部。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In past years, Samsung and fellow mobile makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out</li>
<li>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/7ec45056-5dac-41c9-9c8d-90ebe51417b8_a1a0985b.jpg" /><figcaption>Samsung employees show models of the Galaxy S23 Fan Edition during its rollout in Seoul, South Korea, December 8, 2023. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>The world’s most prolific smartphone maker is leaning into artificial intelligence as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.</p><p>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device on January 17 in San Jose, California – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – with a livestreamed event. The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming.” In past years, Samsung and fellow mobile makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out, but 2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246310/huawei-launches-new-nova-smartphones-without-giving-details-chip-attention-remains-fixed-its" title="">Huawei launches new Nova smartphones without giving details on chip</a></h3><p>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates. OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Dall-E tools, which generate text or visual responses to users’ queries, are at the forefront of a generative-AI wave that is swept across the tech industry – and helped make Nvidia a trillion-dollar company by providing the key AI-training accelerators. The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices, as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year.</p><p>“Samsung and Qualcomm are immediate leaders as current product offerings and capabilities position them as first movers,” the Counterpoint researchers wrote in December. “Similar to what it did with foldables, Samsung is likely to capture almost 50 per cent share for the next two years, followed by key Chinese OEMs like Xiaomi, Vivo, Honor and Oppo.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok use</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247089/montana-appealing-ruling-blocked-state-barring-tiktok-use</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Montana's Attorney General, Austin Knudsen, has filed an appeal against a federal judge's ruling that blocked the state's ban on TikTok. The ban was initially set to take effect on January 1, but U.S. District Judge Donald Molloy issued a preliminary injunction to prevent it, citing concerns about the law's constitutionality and its overreach of state authority. Previously, TikTok and Knudsen's office had no immediate comment on the matter.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Montana appeals federal court ruling blocking state ban on TikTok.</li>    <li>Theme: Montana's challenge to a court decision that prevented its TikTok ban, highlighting legal and political implications.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The state's insistence on its authority to regulate technology platforms; the ongoing debate over TikTok's potential security risks.</li>    <li>Main information: Montana Attorney General's appeal to the Ninth Circuit; Judge Molloy's preliminary injunction against the ban; concerns about TikTok's data handling and Chinese influence.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  蒙大拿州总检察长奥斯汀·纳德森提起上诉，反对联邦法官阻止该州禁止TikTok的裁决。该禁令最初定于 1 月 1 日生效，但美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊签发了一项初步禁令予以阻止，理由是该法律的合宪性问题及其对州权力的越权。此前，TikTok和纳德森的办公室对此事没有任何立即的评论。  <ul>    <li>摘要：蒙大拿州上诉联邦法院裁决阻止该州禁止 TikTok 的禁令。</li>    <li>主题：蒙大拿州对阻止其禁止 TikTok 的法院裁决提出质疑，突显出法律和政治影响。</li>    <li>观点：该州坚持其监管技术平台的权力；关于 TikTok 潜在安全风险的持续争论。</li>    <li>主要信息：蒙大拿州总检察长向第九巡回法院提出上诉；莫洛伊法官对该禁令发布初步禁令；对 TikTok 数据处理和中国影响的担忧。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>preliminary (adj.) - /prɪˈlɪmɪnəri/ 暂时的，初步的。    <p>原文例句：Montana’s ban had been set to take effect January 1 but US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban on the Chinese-owned app. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词形容词，意思是“暂时的，初步的”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊于 11 月 30 日发布的初步禁令，以阻止蒙大拿州第一项禁止使用短视频共享应用程序 TikTok 的同类州禁令生效。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sweeping (adj.) - /ˈswiːpɪŋ/ 全面的，广泛的。    <p>原文例句：Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government and the state’s action was too sweeping.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词形容词，意思是“全面的，广泛的”。在这个例句中，它指的是蒙大拿州寻求行使联邦政府持有的外交政策权力，并且该州的行动过于广泛。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>effective (adj.) - /ɪˈfɛktɪv/ 有效的，有效的。    <p>原文例句：Former President Donald Trump in 2020 sought to bar new downloads of TikTok and Chinese-owned WeChat, but a series of court decisions blocked the effective ban from taking effect.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词形容词，意思是“有效的，有效的”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普于 2020 年寻求禁止新下载 TikTok 和中国拥有的微信，但一系列法院裁决阻止了该有效禁令生效。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take effect - 生效，起效。    <p>原文例句：Montana’s ban had been set to take effect January 1 but US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是动词词组，意思是“生效，起效”。在这个例句中，它指的是蒙大拿州的禁令原定于 1 月 1 日生效，但美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊于 11 月 30 日发布了一项初步禁令，以阻止该禁令。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>bar foreign-owned apps - 禁止外国拥有应用程序。    <p>原文例句：TikTok has faced efforts by some in Congress to ban the app or give the Biden administration powers to impose restrictions or bar foreign-owned apps, but those efforts have stalled.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是动词词组，意思是“禁止外国拥有应用程序”。在这个例句中，它指的是 TikTok 面临着国会中一些人的努力，他们试图禁止该应用程序或赋予拜登政府权力对外国拥有的应用程序施加限制或禁止它们，但这些努力已经停滞不前。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TikTok said in earlier court filings it “has not shared, and would not share, US user data with the Chinese government, and has taken substantial measures to protect the privacy and security of TikTok users”. - TikTok在早些时候提交的法庭文件中表示“它没有与中国政府共享，也不会共享美国用户数据，并已采取大量措施来保护TikTok用户的隐私和安全”。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是TikTok said it has not shared, and would not share, US user data with the Chinese government，其中主语是TikTok，谓语是said，宾语是it has not shared, and would not share, US user data with the Chinese government。and has taken substantial measures to protect the privacy and security of TikTok users是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示TikTok采取的措施或方式，即已采取大量措施来保护TikTok用户的隐私和安全。这个句子的意思是说，TikTok在早些时候提交的法庭文件中表示“它没有与中国政府共享，也不会共享美国用户数据，并已采取大量措施来保护TikTok用户的隐私和安全”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态对句子主语或谓语的修饰和补充。    <p>原文例句：US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语作状语是分词短语在句中作状语，对句子主语或谓语进行修饰和补充。结构是：现在分词短语、过去分词短语或不定式短语作状语。在这个例句中，saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊发布初步禁令的原因或根据，即蒙大拿州的法律“越权”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态对句子主语或谓语的修饰和补充，动作或状态发生在谓语动作或状态之前。    <p>原文例句：TikTok and Knudsen’s office did not immediately comment. </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在分词短语作状语是现在分词短语在句中作状语，对句子主语或谓语进行修饰和补充，动作或状态发生在谓语动作或状态之前。结构是：doing something。在这个例句中，not immediately comment是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示TikTok 和 Knudsen 的办公室没有立即发表评论这一动作发生在谓语动作或状态之前。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice that the state is appealing the ruling to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals</li>
<li>US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/30bc701c-1f60-4548-af24-f042020ea411_d56c4cec.jpg" /><figcaption>The US flag and TikTok logo are seen in this illustration photo taken June 2, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Montana said on Tuesday it was appealing a decision by a US judge in November to block Montana’s first-of-its kind state ban on the use of short-video sharing app TikTok.</p><p>Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice that the state is appealing the ruling to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals.</p><p>Montana’s ban had been set to take effect January 1 but US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban on the Chinese-owned app, saying Montana’s law “violates the Constitution in more ways than one” and “oversteps state power”.</p><p>TikTok and Knudsen’s office did not immediately comment. Molloy had previously said preliminary pretrial statements were due by January 16.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246313/taiwan-elections-tiktok-teams-fact-checkers-stop-disinformation-site" title="">TikTok teams up with fact checkers to stop election disinformation on site</a></h3><p>TikTok users in Montana also had filed suit last year to block the ban approved by the state legislature that cited concerns about the personal data of Montana users and potential Chinese spying.</p><p>TikTok said in earlier court filings it “has not shared, and would not share, US user data with the Chinese government, and has taken substantial measures to protect the privacy and security of TikTok users”. Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government and the state’s action was too sweeping.</p><p>TikTok has faced efforts by some in Congress to ban the app or give the Biden administration powers to impose restrictions or bar foreign-owned apps, but those efforts have stalled.</p><p>Many states and the US government have barred TikTok on government-owned devices, but only Montana has sought to completely bar the app’s use.</p><p>Former President Donald Trump in 2020 sought to bar new downloads of TikTok and Chinese-owned WeChat, but a series of court decisions blocked the effective ban from taking effect.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple hits 7-week low after Barclays downgrade on demand concerns</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Apple's shares saw a significant increase of nearly 50 percent in 2023, reaching a record high in mid-December. However, the company has been facing challenges due to a demand slowdown since early last year and has projected holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street's expectations. Recent concerns about weak demand for Apple's devices in 2024 have led to a drop in the company's stock price.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's stock performance in 2023 and concerns about its device demand.</li>    <li>Theme: The rise and recent fall of Apple's stock, impacted by market conditions and demand slowdown.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Analysts' perspectives on Apple's stock performance and factors affecting its value.</li>    <li>Main information: Apple's stock surge in 2023, Barclays' downgrade, impact on S&P 500, demand concerns, and Apple's services business.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  苹果公司股票在2023年大幅上涨近50%，于12月中旬创下历史新高。然而，公司自去年初以来一直面临需求放缓的挑战，并预测假日季度的销售额低于华尔街预期。对于2024年苹果设备需求疲软的担忧导致公司股价下跌。  <ul>    <li>摘要：2023年苹果股票表现以及对其设备需求的担忧。</li>    <li>主题：苹果股票的涨跌，受市场状况和需求放缓影响。</li>    <li>观点：分析师对苹果股票表现及其价值影响的看法。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果股票在2023年的飙升，巴克莱的降级，对标普500指数的影响，需求担忧以及苹果的服务业务。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rout (n.) - /raʊt/ 溃败，大败。    <p>原文例句：The stock rout on Tuesday erased more than US$100 billion of Apple’s market capitalisation, as its shares closed at US$185.64.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古法语route，意为“溃败，大败”。在这个例句中，它描述了周二的股票大跌，导致苹果公司市值损失超过1000亿美元，股价收于185.64美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>subdued (adj.) - /səbˈduːd/ 平静的，不活泼的。    <p>原文例句：Long is rated four out of five stars for his recommendation accuracy on Apple, according to LSEG data.The brokerage also warned risks were mounting for Apple’s services business, which has come under the scanner in countries including the United States over app store practices.The business has often outpaced growth in Apple’s hardware segment in recent years and now accounts for nearly a quarter of the company’s total revenue.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古法语subduer，意为“使平息，使安静”。在这个例句中，它描述了苹果的服务业务面临的风险不断增加，分析师认为这种情况在最近几年已经超过了苹果硬件部门的增长，目前占公司总收入的近四分之一。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>market weight - 市场权重。    <P>原文例句：The stock accounts for a hefty 7 per cent of the S&P 500’s market weight – the broader index was dragged 0.56 per cent lower on Tuesday. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由market（市场）和weight（权重）构成的，表示“市场权重”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果股票在标普500指数中的权重。这个句子的意思是说，苹果股票占标普500指数市场权重的7%，周二大盘下跌0.56%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Long is rated four out of five stars for his recommendation accuracy on Apple, according to LSEG data. - 据LSEG数据，Long因其对苹果的推荐准确性被评为五星级中的四星级。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Long is rated four out of five stars for his recommendation accuracy on Apple，其中主语是Long，谓语是is rated，宾语是four out of five stars。for his recommendation accuracy on Apple是一个介词短语作原因状语，表示Long之所以被评为四星级，是因为他对苹果的推荐准确性。这个句子的意思是说，据LSEG数据，Long因其对苹果的推荐准确性被评为五星级中的四星级。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral” and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160. - 巴克莱将该股票评级从“中性”降至“减持”，并将12个月的价格目标从161美元下调1美元至160美元。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral”，其中主语是Barclays，谓语是downgraded，宾语是the stock。and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160是一个并列连词短语，表示巴克莱还将12个月的价格目标从161美元下调1美元至160美元。这个句子的意思是说，巴克莱将该股票评级从“中性”降至“减持”，并将12个月的价格目标从161美元下调1美元至160美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式短语 - 表示目的或原因。    <p>原文例句：Analysts, on average, rate the iPhone maker “buy”, with a median price target of US$200. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个以不定式（to + 动词原形）开头的短语，表示目的或原因。在这个例句中，它是to appeal的不定式短语，表示为了吸引。这个句子的意思是说，分析师平均将iPhone制造商评级为“买入”，给出200美元的中间价目标。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。在这个例句中，it表示苹果公司从去年年初就开始一直面临需求放缓的问题。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple’s shares rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech led the markets</li>
<li>The company has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/c4cb126e-9510-44c7-ac21-a1b02c5e460b_dea8d679.jpg" /><figcaption>Apple signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange, January 2, 2023.  Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Apple on Tuesday fell nearly 3.6 per cent to a seven-week low after Barclays downgraded the shares of the world’s most valuable company on concerns that demand for its devices from the iPhone to the Mac will remain weak in 2024.</p><p>Barclays is the second brokerage to have the equivalent of a “sell” rating on the stock, which now has its most number of bearish recommendations in at least two years, according to LSEG data.</p><p>The stock accounts for a hefty 7 per cent of the S&amp;P 500’s market weight – the broader index was dragged 0.56 per cent lower on Tuesday. Apple rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech led the markets.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245817/apple-ramps-vision-pro-production-aiming-launch-february" title="">Apple ramps up Vision Pro production, aiming for launch by February</a></h3><p>Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates. Its performance in China has also been a worry after the revival of local rival Huawei.</p><p>“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long said in a client note, pointing to the China weakness as well as subdued demand in developed markets.</p><p>Long is rated four out of five stars for his recommendation accuracy on Apple, according to LSEG data.</p><p>The brokerage also warned risks were mounting for Apple’s services business, which has come under the scanner in countries including the United States over app store practices.</p><p>The business has often outpaced growth in Apple’s hardware segment in recent years and now accounts for nearly a quarter of the company’s total revenue.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3246322/us-import-ban-certain-apple-watch-models-takes-effect-over-patent-clash" title="">Apple to appeal US watch ban in patent dispute</a></h3><p>The stock rout on Tuesday erased more than US$100 billion of Apple’s market capitalisation, as its shares closed at US$185.64.</p><p>Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral” and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160. Before Tuesday, Itau BBA’s “sell” was the only bearish rating on Apple since July 2022.</p><p>Analysts, on average, rate the iPhone maker “buy”, with a median price target of US$200. The company trades at about 28.7 times its 12-month forward earnings estimates, much higher than the S&amp;P 500’s 19.8.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Veteran Chinese video gaming official steps down in wake of market rout linked to proposed rule changes, sources say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Feng Shixin, the publication bureau chief of the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, has resigned following the proposed regulations that led to a significant decline in Chinese gaming stocks. Feng’s departure is seen as a potential sign of China’s reconsideration of the proposed restrictions. Meanwhile, the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) has approved 105 new video games for sale in China in December, indicating a supportive gesture to the gaming industry.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese official Feng Shixin resigns after proposed video game regulations cause market turmoil.</li>    <li>Theme: Feng’s resignation and the NPPA’s recent actions signal a possible shift in China’s approach to regulating the video game industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The proposed regulations aimed to control spending and limit the potential negative impact of video games, while the recent approvals and supportive statements indicate a more balanced approach.</li>    <li>Main information: Feng’s resignation, the NPPA’s draft rules and subsequent clarifications, the approval of new games, and China’s previous strict regulations on video games.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  据悉，中共中央宣传部出版局局长冯仕新已辞去其官方职务。此前，中国游戏监督部门发布的监管草案导致中国游戏股大跌。冯仕新离职被视为中国可能收回上个月部分针对视频游戏消费者支出的限制性提案的一个迹象，由于其严厉程度，该提案震惊了市场。知情人士称，国家新闻出版署（NPPA）是直接向宣传部门负责的机构，负责监管中国视频游戏产业，目前尚未立即回应置评请求。中国视频游戏监管机构在监管措施引发市场动荡后发声冯仕新的离职发生在NPPA于12月23日发布限制视频游戏支出的监管草案草案后，该草案引发了包括腾讯控股和网易在内等中国游戏行业领军企业股票的全球抛售潮，旨在限制视频游戏支出。根据公布的提案（向公众征求反馈意见至1月22日），电子游戏开发商必须采取措施限制用户支出，禁止对每日登录和新充值等行为给予“过度”奖励。拟议规则变更的时间和严重程度给本已脆弱的中国股市投资者信心带来了新的打击。中国排名第二的游戏运营商网易在单个交易日内暴跌近四分之一，腾讯下跌逾12%。新的规定似乎与北京最近对视频游戏行业的态度转变（此前对其进行了严厉打击）及其努力稳定股市情绪和支持该国私营部门的广泛努力不一致。在试图控制损失时，NPPA随后表示，拟议的监管规定旨在“健康发展”游戏产业，并将“修改和完善”这些规定。与此同时，该监管机构已于12月批准了105款新电子游戏在中国销售，为17个月以来最多，此举对其年销售额于2023年总计达3000亿元人民币（合400亿美元）的行业构成支持姿态。冯仕新是一位资深监管人员。作为出版局副局长，他于2018、2019和2020年连续三年在中国游戏产业年会上发表主旨演讲，该会议是官员和高管每年一次的聚会。2020年12月，冯仕新敦促中国游戏公司警惕游戏内容，不要“为任何有害内容提供渠道”。在2023年12月的最近一次年会上，NPPA官员杨方在冯仕新将任务委托给她后发表了主题演讲。自宣传部门于2018年从其他部委手中接管监管机构以来，中国已建立了一个完善的游戏监管体系。所有在线视频游戏都必须经过严格审查才能获得许可证，然后才能向公众发布并实现盈利，并且所有玩家都必须进行实名注册。此前略有放松管制之前，中国当局已将电子游戏视为“精神鸦片”，并实施了多项规定，以避免未成年人沉迷并促进行业健康发展。2021年夏季，中国对18岁以下玩家实施了每周三小时的游戏时间上限——每周五、六、日晚上8点至9点。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国官员冯仕新在提出的视频游戏监管条例导致市场动荡后辞职。</li>    <li>主题：冯仕新的辞职和NPPA最近的行动表明，中国调整了对视频游戏行业的监管方式。</li>    <li>观点：拟议的条例旨在控制支出并限制视频游戏的潜在负面影响，而最近的批准和支持性声明表明采取了更加平衡的方式。</li>    <li>主要信息：冯仕新的辞职、NPPA的草案规则和随后的澄清、新游戏的批准以及中国之前对视频游戏的严格监管。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>deadline (n.) - /ˈdɛdlɑːɪn/ 最后期限。    <p>原文例句：The deadline to submit applications for the new research program is 15 March. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由dead（死的，结束的）和line（线，界限）组成，表示“截止日期，最后期限”。在这个例句中，它表示提交新研究项目申请的截止日期是3月15日。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>scope (n.) - /skəʊp/ 范围，射程。    <p>原文例句：The new law has a broad scope, covering many aspects of online activity. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由古英语的scopp（观察者）演变而来，表示“范围，射程，领域”。在这个例句中，它表示新法律的范围很广，涵盖了在线活动的许多方面。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>regulatory authority - 监督权。    <P>原文例句：The regulatory authority has the power to investigate companies and impose fines. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由regulatory（监管的），authority（权力）和authority（权力）组成的，表示“监管权，监督权”。在这个例句中，它表示监管机构有权调查公司并处以罚款。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Feng Shixin has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, people say. - 据悉，冯仕新已辞去其共产党中央宣传部出版局局长的官方职务。<p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾句，主语是Feng Shixin，谓语是has left，宾语是his official role。left是一个过去分词，表示冯仕新已经辞去了他的官方职务。at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department是一个介词短语，表示冯仕新在共产党中央宣传部的职务。people say是一个插入语，表示这个消息是由知情人士透露的。这个句子的意思是说，据悉，冯仕新已辞去其共产党中央宣传部出版局局长的官方职务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>表示地点的介词 - 表示地点的介词有：in, on, at, above, below, beside, behind, in front of, next to, near, over, round, through, under。    <p>原文例句：The new law was passed by the government in 2020. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个介词短语in 2020表示法律是在2020年通过的。in是一个表示地点的介词，表示在一个地方。在这个例句中，它表示法律是在2020年通过的。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>情态动词 - 情态动词有：can, could, may, might, must, should, will, would。    <p>原文例句：You should submit your application before the deadline. </p>    <p>语法讲解：情态动词should用在主语后，表示建议或劝告。在这个例句中，it表示应该在截止日期前提交申请。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Feng Shixin has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, people say</li>
<li>Move comes as Beijing attempts to limit the damage from draft rules from watchdog aimed at reining back spending on video games</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/c1897329-2f24-429e-bd01-4e017c08984b_511f253b.jpg" /><figcaption>Feng Shixin has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, people say. Photo: Xinhua </figcaption></figure><p>A key Chinese official involved in oversight of the country’s video gaming industry has stepped down after proposed regulation last month wiped out billions of dollars of value from Chinese gaming stocks, according to people familiar with the situation.</p><p>Feng Shixin, a long-serving official, has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, one person told the South China Morning Post, asking not to be identified due to the sensitivity of the matter.</p><p>A second person, who also asked for anonymity, said Feng’s departure was a sign that China may walk back some of last month’s proposed restrictions on consumer spending in video games, which surprised the market due to their severity.</p><p>The National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA), the agency that answers directly to the propaganda authority in overseeing China’s video gaming industry, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246161/chinas-video-gaming-watchdog-speaks-out-after-draft-spending-rules-roil-market" title="">China’s video gaming watchdog speaks out after spending rules roil market</a></h3><p>Feng’s departure comes as Beijing attempts to limit the damage from the NPPA’s disclosure on December 23 of draft rules aimed at reining back spending on video games, which triggered a global sell-off of China gaming stocks, including leading players such as Tencent Holdings and NetEase.</p><p>According to the published proposals, which are open to public feedback until January 22, video game developers would have to implement measures to cap user spending, with bans on “excessive” rewards for activity such as daily logins and top-ups for fresh spending by consumers.</p><p>The timing and severity of the proposed rule changes dealt a fresh blow to already-fragile investor confidence in Chinese stocks. NetEase, the country’s No. 2 gaming operator, fell by nearly a quarter in a single trading day, with Tencent dropping over 12 per cent.</p><p>The new rules appeared to be at odds with a recent change in Beijing’s tone towards the video gaming industry – previously subject to a harsh crackdown – and broad efforts by the government to stabilise stock market sentiment and support the country’s private sector.</p><p>In an attempt at damage control, the NPPA subsequently said the proposed regulation changes were aimed at “healthy development” of the gaming industry and that it would “revise and improve” the rules.</p><p>Meanwhile, the regulator approved 105 new <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">video games</a> for sale in China for December, the most in 17 months, in a supportive gesture to an industry with combined annual sales of 300 billion yuan (US$40 billion) in 2023.</p><p>Feng is a veteran regulator. He delivered keynote speeches at the China Gaming Industry Annual Conference, the yearly gathering of officials and executives for three consecutive years in 2018, 2019 and 2020 as a deputy publication bureau chief. In December 2020, Feng urged China’s gaming companies to be vigilant about gaming content and not to “provide channels for any harmful content”.</p><p>At the latest annual conference in December 2023, Yang Fang, an official from the NPPA, delivered the keynote speech after Feng delegated the task to her.</p><p>China has developed a sophisticated regulatory system for video gaming since the propaganda department took over the regulatory authority in 2018 from other ministries. All online video games must go through rigorous screening to obtain licences before being released to the public and monetised, and all players are required to have real-name registration.</p><p>Prior to a recent easing, Chinese authorities had deemed video gaming as “spiritual opium” and implemented several rules to avoid addiction among minors and to promote healthy growth of the industry.</p><p>In the summer of 2021, China imposed a play time ceiling of three hours per week – from 8pm to 9pm on Fridays, Saturdays and Sundays – for players under the age of 18.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chip industry giant ASML blocked by US, Netherlands from shipping equipment to China ahead of export deadline</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247042/chip-industry-giant-asml-blocked-us-netherlands-shipping-equipment-china-ahead-export-deadline</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Concerns are growing as the Netherlands revokes licenses for ASML's DUV lithography system exports to China, a move seen as a blow to China's tech ambitions.</li>    <li>China's Foreign Ministry decried the US's "hegemonic and bullying behavior" and urged the Netherlands to adhere to fair market principles.</li>    <li>Despite ongoing pressure from the US, ASML secured three licenses to export less advanced DUV systems to China before new restrictions took effect in January.</li>    <li>China's imports of critical chip-making lithography systems from the Netherlands surged in November, with a 1,050% increase in value.</li>    <li>However, ASML anticipates minimal financial impact from the license revocation and recent US export controls, based on their latest financial report.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>荷兰取消了向中国出口ASML DUV光刻系统的许可证，引起了广泛关注，这被视为打击中国技术野心的举动。</li>    <li>中国外交部谴责美国的“霸权主义和欺凌行为”，敦促荷兰坚持公平市场原则。</li>    <li>尽管美国持续施压，ASML在1月实施新限制之前获得了三张许可证，可以向中国出口不太先进的DUV系统。</li>    <li>11月，中国从荷兰进口的关键芯片制造光刻系统激增，价值增长了1050%。</li>    <li>然而，ASML预计许可证被吊销和最近的美国出口管制对其实际财务影响很小，这一观点与其最新财务报告一致。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revoke (v.) - /rɪˈvoʊk/ 撤销，废除。    <p>原文例句：A license for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government, impacting a small number of customers in China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：revoke这个词的意思是“撤销，废除”。它来自拉丁语revocare，意思是“召回”。在这个例句中，它被用来表示荷兰政府部分撤销了向中国出口NXT:2050i和NXT:2100i [深紫外 (DUV)]光刻系统。撤销这一许可证的原因是为了阻止中国获得这些先进的光刻系统，从而限制其芯片制造能力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>hegemonic (adj.) - /hɛdʒɪˈmɒnɪk/ 霸权的，支配的。    <p>原文例句：On Tuesday, Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesman Wang Wenbin condemned the “hegemonic and bullying behaviour” from the US, urging the Netherlands to uphold fair market principles and honour its contractual obligations.</p>    <p>例句讲解：hegemonic这个词的意思是“霸权的，支配的”。它来自希腊语“hegemonia”，意思是“领导权”。在这个例句中，它被用来形容美国的“霸权主义和欺凌行为”。中国外交部发言人谴责美国的这种行为，并敦促荷兰坚持公平市场原则，履行其合同义务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>monopoly (n.) - /məˈnɑːpəli/ 垄断，独占。    <p>原文例句：ASML has a near monopoly on the machines.</p>    <p>例句讲解：monopoly这个词的意思是“垄断，独占”。它来自希腊语“monos”，意思是“单一”，“polein”，意思是“售卖”。在这个例句中，它被用来表示ASML在光刻机市场上占据近乎垄断的地位。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stockpile (n.) - /ˈstɑːkpɑɪl/ 库存，储备。    <p>原文例句：China has been importing and stockpiling record numbers of chip-making equipment from abroad.</p>    <p>例句讲解：stockpile这个词的意思是“库存，储备”。它由“stock”（储存）和“pile”（堆积）两个词组成。在这个例句中，它被用来描述中国从国外进口并储备芯片制造设备的行为。这种行为主要是为了应对美国对中国芯片制造行业施加的限制。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ASML said in a statement on Monday that a licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government, impacting a small number of customers in China. - ASML在周一的一份声明中表示，荷兰政府最近部分吊销了2023年NXT:2050i和NXT:2100i [深紫外(DUV)]光刻系统发货的许可证，影响了中国的一些客户。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是ASML said in a statement on Monday，其中主语是ASML，谓语是said in a statement on Monday，宾语是that a licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government, impacting a small number of customers in China。a licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰that a licence，表示该许可证最近被荷兰政府部分吊销了。impacting a small number of customers in China是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰said in a statement on Monday，表示该公司周一的一份声明说，部分吊销许可证的行为影响了中国的一些客户。这个句子的意思是说，ASML在周一的一份声明中表示，荷兰政府最近部分吊销了2023年NXT:2050i和NXT:2100i [深紫外(DUV)]光刻系统发货的许可证，影响了中国的一些客户。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>在句中使用否定词 - 表示否定。    <p>原文例句：China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Wang Wenbin, gestures during a press conference in Beijing on January 2, 2024, where he discussed the suspension on some exports of Dutch company ASML to China.</p>    <p>语法讲解：否定词在句中很常见，用于否定句子的意义。最常见的否定词是“not”。在疑问句和否定句中，否定词通常放在助动词之前。在这个例句中，“not”被用来否定“discussed”这个动词。这个句子的意思是说，中国外交部发言人王文斌在2024年1月2日的北京新闻发布会上对荷兰公司ASML部分出口中国被暂停一事发表了讲话。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The maker of critical lithography systems said a licence to export some machines to China was partially revoked, but does not expect an impact on bottom line</li>
<li>The Chinese Foreign Ministry slammed the ‘hegemonic and bullying behaviour’ of the US and urged the Netherlands to uphold fair market principles</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/04ce0805-1869-40cf-9ab0-deeaa9b9e4ca_60c0c0ac.jpg" /><figcaption>The logo of chip equipment maker ASML seen at its booth during Semicon China, a trade fair for the semiconductor industry, in Shanghai on June 29, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Dutch chip-making equipment manufacturer ASML was forced to cancel some shipments to China after having licences partially revoked, in a blow to the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls">apparent efforts to stockpile</a> related technology ahead of new restrictions.</p><p>“A licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government, impacting a small number of customers in China,” the company said in a statement on Monday.</p><p>On Tuesday, Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesman Wang Wenbin condemned the “hegemonic and bullying behaviour” from the US, urging the Netherlands to uphold fair market principles and honour its contractual obligations.</p><p>Under US pressure, ASML already restricts Chinese clients from buying its more advanced extreme ultraviolet (EUV) lithography systems, which are used to produce the world’s most cutting-edge chips. ASML has a near monopoly on the machines.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Wang Wenbin, gestures during a press conference in Beijing on January 2, 2024, where he discussed the suspension on some exports of Dutch company ASML to China. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/608cf9f2-a296-426f-8d3a-a814ac9f96ea_5af09944.jpg" title="China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Wang Wenbin, gestures during a press conference in Beijing on January 2, 2024, where he discussed the suspension on some exports of Dutch company ASML to China. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Wang Wenbin, gestures during a press conference in Beijing on January 2, 2024, where he discussed the suspension on some exports of Dutch company ASML to China. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>However, from September, the Dutch equipment maker had been able to apply for licences to ship some of its less advanced DUV systems to China ahead of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls">new restrictions</a> that came into effect on January 1. The Dutch manufacturer received three such licences.</p><p>Lithography tools are complex projection systems that are considered the most important equipment needed in the process of producing integrated circuits. China is considered years behind in this tech, and has so far struggled to close the gap with leading firms despite heavy government investment.</p><p>Ahead of the Dutch restrictions, and following the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy">expanded US export restrictions</a> on DUV machines in October, Chinese manufacturers have been importing and stockpiling <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened">record numbers</a> of chip-making equipment from abroad.</p><p>China imported 42 lithography systems in November for US$816.8 million, with companies in the Netherlands and Japan accounting for nearly the entire amount spent on such imports.</p><p>China’s imports of critical chip-making lithography systems from the Netherlands, in particular, surged 1,050 per cent in value that month. The Netherlands is the biggest exporter of lithography machines, almost all of which come from ASML – though the company does not have the same hold on the DUV market as on EUV.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened" title="">China’s imports of Dutch chip-making equipment surged tenfold in November</a></h3><p>After a teardown of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a>’ latest 5G smartphone, the Mate 60 Pro, concluded that Chinese chip maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductor-manufacturing-international-corporation-smic" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductor-manufacturing-international-corporation-smic">Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC)</a> produced the device’s advanced 7-nanometre chip using DUV lithography machines, some <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain">experts predicted</a> more would be done to restrict China’s access to such technology.</p><p>Citing anonymous sources, Bloomberg reported on Tuesday that US President <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/people/joe-biden" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/people/joe-biden">Joe Biden</a>’s administration had requested that ASML cancel several shipments of DUV systems to China weeks ahead of new rules coming into force this month.</p><p>A spokeswoman from ASML declined to comment on that timeline, but noted that it was unlikely that the company would receive new licences for the NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i DUV machines in 2024.</p><p>“In recent discussions with the US government, ASML has obtained further clarification of the scope and impact of the US export control regulations,” the equipment maker said in its Monday statement.</p><p>“ASML is fully committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations, including export control legislation in the countries in which we operate,” it added.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>In recent years, China has been ASML’s third-largest market after Taiwan and South Korea, but it jumped to first place in the third quarter of 2023, accounting for 46 per cent of sales. This was up from 24 per cent in the previous quarter and 8 per cent in the first quarter.</p><p>In November, Shen Bo, senior vice-president of ASML and president of its China arm, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240290/dutch-chip-equipment-giant-asml-looks-speed-delivery-mature-lithography-machines-china-clients" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240290/dutch-chip-equipment-giant-asml-looks-speed-delivery-mature-lithography-machines-china-clients">reportedly signalled</a> that the company was working to speed up deliveries to China to meet demand for DUV machines. At the time, the company had a backlog of €35 billion (US$37 billion) from orders made in 2021 and 2022, which included orders from China, he added.</p><p>In an investor call the previous month, ASML CEO Peter Wennink said the company had fulfilled less than 50 per cent of Chinese clients’ orders in the previous two years, but shifting demand from other customers created an opportunity to fulfil more orders in the country.</p><p>In its most recent statement, ASML said it did not expect the licence revocation or the latest US export controls to have a material impact on its 2023 financial outlook, echoing similar sentiments expressed in its latest financial report.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Baidu’s move to cancel YY Live acquisition amid fierce market competition, tougher regulation a boon to firm’s AI business expansion, analysts say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247038/baidus-move-cancel-yy-live-acquisition-amid-fierce-market-competition-tougher-regulation-boon-firms</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Baidu's decision to terminate its acquisition of Joyy's YY Live shows its focus on AI development, amid China's growing emphasis on generative AI.</li>    <li>Analysts say the move wasn't unexpected, reflecting Baidu's focus on generative AI and the success of its Ernie Bot chatbot.</li>    <li>Baidu aims to strengthen its AI-centric strategy and expects sustained revenue and profit growth through its Ernie ecosystem.</li>    <li>Joyy, facing legal advice, claims the deal was substantially completed in 2021 and plans to consider all options.</li>    <li>YY Live, a pioneer in China's live-streaming sector, now faces challenges due to competition and tighter regulations in the industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>百度终止收购欢聚YY直播业务，凸显其对人工智能发展的关注，呼应中国日益重视的生成式人工智能。</li>    <li>分析师认为，此举并不意外，反映了百度对生成式人工智能的关注以及其文心一言聊天机器人的成功。</li>    <li>百度旨在强化其以人工智能为中心的发展战略，并预期通过其文心生态系统实现持续的收入和利润增长。</li>    <li>欢聚寻求法律咨询，声称该交易已于2021年实质完成，计划考虑所有可行选项。</li>    <li>YY直播作为中国直播行业的先驱，目前正面临来自行业竞争和监管趋严的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>lapse (v.) - /læps/ 终止，失效。    <p>原文例句：This move was “not totally unexpected, given investors have been waiting for more details in past years”, Jefferies equity analysts Thomas Chong and Zoey Zong said in a research note on Monday, following Baidu’s announcement.    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，意为“滑倒，坠落”。在这个例句中，它指的是Baidu的YY直播收购交易由于在2023年12月31日之前未能获得必要的监管批准而失效。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sustained (adj.) - /səˈsteɪnd/ 持续的，持久的。    <p>原文例句：Baidu’s Hong Kong-listed shares edged down 0.7 per cent to HK$115.3 (US$14.76) on Tuesday.    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，意为“维持，支撑”。在这个例句中，它指的是百度的香港上市股票周二小幅下跌0.7%，至每股115.3港元（14.76美元）。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>set the stage for - 为……设定舞台，为……奠定基础。    <P>原文例句：co-founder, chairman and chief executive Robin Li Yanhong said in the firm’s third-quarter earnings report is setting “the stage for sustained multi-year revenue and profit expansion within our Ernie and Ernie Bot ecosystem”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由set（设置），the（冠词），stage（舞台）和for（为）构成的，表示“为……设定舞台，为……奠定基础”。在这个例句中，它表示联合创始人、董事长兼首席执行官李彦宏在公司的第三季度收益报告中说：“为我们的Ernie和Ernie Bot生态系统中持续多年的收入和利润增长奠定了基础”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In a Hong Kong stock exchange filing on Monday, Baidu said its affiliate Moon SPV exercised the right to terminate the US$3.6 billion acquisition of YY Live from Singapore-based Joyy because the deal lapsed, as it failed to meet certain conditions that include obtaining the necessary regulatory approvals from government authorities as of December 31, 2023. - 在周一提交给香港证券交易所的文件中，百度表示，其关联公司Moon SPV行使了终止以36亿美元收购总部位于新加坡的欢聚YY旗下的YY直播的权利，原因是该交易已失效，因为它未能满足某些条件，包括截至2023年12月31日获得政府当局必要的监管批准。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Baidu said its affiliate Moon SPV exercised the right to terminate the US$3.6 billion acquisition of YY Live from Singapore-based Joyy，其中主语是Baidu，谓语是said，宾语是its affiliate Moon SPV exercised the right to terminate the US$3.6 billion acquisition of YY Live from Singapore-based Joyy。because the deal lapsed, as it failed to meet certain conditions that include obtaining the necessary regulatory approvals from government authorities as of December 31, 2023是一个原因状语从句，解释了百度为什么终止收购YY直播。这个句子的意思是说，在周一提交给香港证券交易所的文件中，百度表示，其关联公司Moon SPV行使了终止以36亿美元收购总部位于新加坡的欢聚YY旗下的YY直播的权利，原因是该交易已失效，因为它未能满足某些条件，包括截至2023年12月31日获得政府当局必要的监管批准。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列结构 - 用于连接两个或多个语法上平等的元素。    <p>原文例句：Baidu’s decision to terminate its acquisition of social media firm Joyy’s live-streaming business shows the internet search giant’s sharpened focus on artificial intelligence (AI) development initiatives, according to analysts, as Chinese companies race to cash in on the technology and help boost the country’s economic recovery.    <p>语法讲解：这是一个并列结构，由两个并列的句子组成：Baidu’s decision to terminate its acquisition of social media firm Joyy’s live-streaming business shows the internet search giant’s sharpened focus on artificial intelligence (AI) development initiatives和as Chinese companies race to cash in on the technology and help boost the country’s economic recovery。这两个句子之间用逗号分隔，连接词as表示原因。这个句子的意思是说，据分析师称，百度决定终止收购社交媒体公司欢聚YY的直播业务，表明这家互联网搜索巨头更加关注人工智能（AI）开发计划，因为中国公司竞相从这项技术中获利并帮助提振该国的经济复苏。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>原因从句 - 用于解释或说明另一个句子或从句的原因。    <p>原文例句：Baidu’s Hong Kong-listed shares edged down 0.7 per cent to HK$115.3 (US$14.76) on Tuesday.    <p>语法讲解：这是一个原因从句，由because the deal lapsed, as it failed to meet certain conditions that include obtaining the necessary regulatory approvals from government authorities as of December 31, 2023组成。这个从句解释了百度香港上市股票周二小幅下跌0.7%的原因，即交易失效，因为它未能满足某些条件，包括截至2023年12月31日获得政府当局必要的监管批准。这个句子的意思是说，百度香港上市股票周二小幅下跌0.7%，至每股115.3港元（14.76美元），原因是交易失效，因为它未能满足某些条件，包括截至2023年12月31日获得政府当局必要的监管批准。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Cancelling the YY Live acquisition is expected to help Baidu put more teeth into its artificial intelligence-centric business and product strategy</li>
<li>That move was ‘not totally unexpected’ amid changes in China’s internet sector, where the growing focus has been on generative AI, analysts said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/0c0aab40-f9c0-4f96-af99-649dd4a00b3d_8d4efc03.jpg" /><figcaption>Internet search giant Baidu has been sharpening its focus on artificial intelligence development initiatives. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>’s decision to terminate its acquisition of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> firm Joyy’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/live-streaming" target="_self" title="">live-streaming</a> business shows the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> search giant’s sharpened focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) development initiatives, according to analysts, as Chinese companies <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3239981/baidu-launches-paid-version-ernie-bot-chinese-firms-rush-make-money-their-generative-ai-chatbots" target="_self" title="">race to cash in on the technology</a> and help <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3224050/can-ai-give-china-upper-hand-surpass-us-and-become-worlds-top-economy-after-chatgpt-changed-game" target="_self" title="">boost the country’s economic recovery</a>.</p><p>In a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong-stock-market" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong stock exchange</a> filing on Monday, Baidu said its affiliate Moon SPV exercised the right to terminate the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3110190/baidu-buys-live-streaming-service-yy-it-seeks-catch-rivals-such" target="_self" title="">US$3.6 billion acquisition of YY Live</a> from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/singapore" target="_self" title="">Singapore</a>-based Joyy because the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246921/baidus-live-streaming-ambitions-dealt-blow-lapse-us36-billion-deal-buy-joyys-yy-live" target="_self" title="">deal lapsed, as it failed to meet certain conditions</a> that include obtaining the necessary regulatory approvals from government authorities as of December 31, 2023.</p><p>This move was “not totally unexpected, given investors have been waiting for more details in past years”, Jefferies equity analysts Thomas Chong and Zoey Zong said in a research note on Monday, following Baidu’s announcement. They indicated that China’s internet sector “has been undergoing changes”, which reflects Baidu’s focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">generative AI</a>.</p><p>“For Baidu, Ernie Bot [has already] achieved a milestone in user base and [helps] reconstruct all [of the company’s] products with AI,” the Jefferies analysts said in their report, citing an announcement made during the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238197/baidu-says-ai-chatbot-ernie-now-matches-openais-gpt-4-unveils-new-enterprise-tools" target="_self" title="">Baidu World 2023 conference in Beijing</a> last October.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours. The company’s more basic artificial intelligence chatbot, Ernie 3.5 remains free of charge to the public. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1192" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/efbd36b2-fd43-498a-9fc7-a6ca3fe68665_3190cbb8.jpg" title="Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours. The company’s more basic artificial intelligence chatbot, Ernie 3.5 remains free of charge to the public. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours. The company’s more basic artificial intelligence chatbot, Ernie 3.5 remains free of charge to the public. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>By cancelling the YY Live deal, Baidu could put more teeth into its AI-centric business and product strategy, which co-founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3211124/baidu-beats-fourth-quarter-estimates-internet-search-giant-bets-future-developing-chinas-answer?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Robin Li Yanhong</a> said in the firm’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242461/baidu-forecasts-ai-revenue-growth-and-limited-short-term-impact-us-chip-curbs" target="_self" title="">third-quarter earnings report</a> is setting “the stage for sustained multi-year revenue and profit expansion within our Ernie and Ernie Bot ecosystem”.</p><p>In the company’s earnings call in November, Li said Ernie Bot was handling tens of millions of queries daily three months into its public roll-out, while thousands of enterprises have adopted Baidu’s AI services. As of December 28, Ernie Bot already amassed more than 100 million users, according to Baidu.</p><p>Still, Baidu aims to discuss with Joyy the next steps after the termination of the YY Live share purchase agreement. Baidu’s Hong Kong-listed shares edged down 0.7 per cent to HK$115.3 (US$14.76) on Tuesday.</p><p>Joyy, however, “is seeking legal advice” and “will consider all options at its disposal”. The company claims that the deal, which was entered into in November 2020, was “substantially completed” in February 2021, with certain matters to be completed in future.</p><p>The market cap of Nasdaq-listed Joyy has shrunk by a third over the past three years. The firm’s shares closed at US$39.7 on December 29, which was lower than its November 2020 level of around US$60.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246921/baidus-live-streaming-ambitions-dealt-blow-lapse-us36-billion-deal-buy-joyys-yy-live" title="">Baidu’s bid to buy Joyy’s live-streaming business lapses</a></h3><p>On microblogging service <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/weibo" target="_self" title="">Weibo</a>, Beijing-based angel investor Timothy Guo Tao said in a post that “fierce competition and tougher regulation on live streaming” services on the mainland could have also played a part in Baidu’s decision to bring the YY Live deal to an end.</p><p>In November, YY Live’s monthly active users totalled 16 million, lower than <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/douyu" target="_self" title="">Douyu International</a>’s 31 million and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/huya" target="_self" title="">Huya</a>’s 23 million, according to market intelligence firm Analysys. In July 2021, the Chinese government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3140625/chinas-antitrust-regulator-blocks-tencents-us53-billion-merger-game" target="_self" title="">blocked the US$5.3 billion merger</a> of video game streamers Douyu and Huya.</p><p>Even though YY Live is a pioneer of China’s live-streaming sector, it has been overtaken by younger market players like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243683/douyin-chinese-version-tiktok-testing-paid-videos-again-some-users-push-back" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Kuaishou Technology</a>, which are China’s top two short video platforms that also provide live- streaming features.</p><p>Joyy’s YY Live had also been the target of criticism from US hedge fund Muddy Waters, which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3110485/muddy-waters-targets-chinese-social-media-company-joyy-days-after" target="_self" title="">labelled Joyy “a multibillion-dollar fraud”</a> in a report just days after Baidu entered the deal to buy YY Live. The American short seller claimed that up to 90 per cent of YY Live’s live-streaming revenue was fraudulent. Joyy refuted the report, asserting that it “contained numerous errors, unsubstantiated statements and misleading conclusions”.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>With Baidu’s deal cancelled, YY Live must now “rethink its competition strategy”, said Chen Yuxin, analyst at LeadLeo Research Institute.</p><p>YY Live, according to Chen, has become a laggard in the live-streaming industry, where it has neither expanded into e-commerce nor transformed into a strong social media platform in China.</p><p>Tighter scrutiny by mainland regulators on live-streaming services could also be more challenging for YY Live to compete. Chen said <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242432/video-game-streamer-douyu-confirms-ceos-arrest-china-after-weeks-speculation-about-gambling-content" target="_self" title="">the arrest of Douyu chief executive Chen Shaojie</a> in November on suspicion of opening a casino “rang a bell to the entire industry that the authority will further strengthen regulation of the live-streaming industry”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
