<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China’s ‘king of software’, Wang Wenjing, steps down as president of enterprise management systems firm Yonyou amid mounting losses</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247446/chinas-king-software-wang-wenjing-steps-down-president-enterprise-management-systems-firm-yonyou</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese tech billionaire Wang Wenjing stepped down as president of Yonyou Network Technology due to sluggish sales and losses, but retains his roles as chairman and chief executive. The company is undergoing a senior management shuffle in an attempt to turn around its business after two years of stagnant revenue growth. Despite ranking among the world's top ERP software providers, Yonyou has been shifting its focus from selling software licenses to providing services via a software-as-a-service model. The move reflects China's push for digitalization, with Yonyou initiating organizational changes to cater to specific industries and expand its reach.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Yonyou Network Technology's management reshuffle aims to address poor financial performance and align with China's digitalization drive.</li>    <li>Theme: Struggling tech company Yonyou seeks to recover from stagnant growth and widening losses through strategic changes.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The company's shift towards a service-based model and focus on vertical industries signal its response to market dynamics and government initiatives.</li>    <li>Main information: Wang Wenjing's resignation as president, Yonyou's repositioning in the market, and the impact of China's digitalization push on the company.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国科技亿万富翁王文京因销售疲软和亏损辞去用友网络科技总裁一职，但他仍保留董事长兼首席执行官的角色。该公司正在进行高级管理层改组，试图在收入增长停滞两年后扭转其业务颓势。尽管在全球ERP软件供应商中排名靠前，用友却一直在将重点从销售软件许可证转向通过软件即服务模式提供服务。此举反映了中国大力推进数字化进程，用友也因此发起组织变革，以迎合特定行业需求并扩大其影响力。  <ul>    <li>摘要：用友网络科技进行管理层改组，旨在解决财务业绩不佳的问题，并与中国推进数字化的进程保持一致。</li>    <li>主题：陷入困境的科技公司用友试图通过战略调整，从增长停滞和亏损扩大的困境中复苏。</li>    <li>观点：公司转向服务型模式并专注于垂直行业的做法表明，其对市场动态和政府举措做出了回应。</li>    <li>主要信息：王文京辞去总裁职务，用友在市场中的重新定位，以及中国推进数字化进程对公司产生的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sluggish (adj.) - /ˈslʌgɪʃ/ 缓慢的，迟钝的。    <p>原文例句：China’s weak macroeconomic environment has driven a round of poor earnings from cybersecurity and finance software stocks, Yonyou’s third-quarter results last year – with “positive revenue growth across all segments” – “indicate that ERP demand has been resilient”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由sluggish（缓慢的）和-ish（形容词后缀，表示具有……的性质）构成，表示“缓慢的，迟钝的”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国疲软的宏观经济环境导致网络安全和财务软件股票的收益不佳，而用友去年第三季度的业绩却出现了“所有细分领域的正向收入增长”，这表明ERP的需求一直保持弹性。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>resilience (n.) - /rɪˈzɪliəns/ 恢复力，弹性。    <p>原文例句： Jefferies’ November research note noted that Yonyou’s third-quarter results last year – with “positive revenue growth across all segments” – “indicate that ERP demand has been resilient”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由re-（再次）和silire（跳跃）组成，意为“再次跳起，恢复力，弹性”。在这个例句中，它指的是杰富瑞11月份的研究报告指出，用友去年第三季度的业绩出现了“所有细分领域的正向收入增长”，这表明ERP的需求一直保持弹性。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>software-as-a-service (n.) - /ˈsɑːftˌweər æz ə ˈsɜːrvɪs/ 软件即服务。    <p>原文例句： In recent years, Yonyou changed its focus from selling licences of its ERP and other enterprise management software to collecting service fees by providing these systems via a software-as-a-service model called Yonyou BIP. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由software（软件），as（作为），a（一个），service（服务）和model（模型）构成的，表示“软件即服务”。在这个例句中，它指的是近年来，用友将重点从销售其ERP和其他企业管理软件的许可证转向通过名为用友BIP的软件即服务模型提供这些系统来收取服务费。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>turn around - 扭转，化解。    <p>原文例句：The senior management shuffle at Yonyou reflects the company’s effort to try and turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth and widening losses, as fresh opportunities beckon from Beijing’s digitalisation drive. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由turn（转动）和around（周围，四周）构成的，表示“扭转，化解”。在这个例句中，它指的是用友的高级管理层改组反映了该公司试图在收入增长停滞两年和亏损扩大的情况下扭转其业务颓势，因为北京的数字化进程带来了新的机遇。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms - 中国推动12个领域的数字经济发展，目标瞄准金融、科技、农业。<p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的简单句，主语是China，谓语是sets sights on，宾语是finance, tech, farms。sets sights on是一个动词短语，表示“把目标瞄准”。这个句子的意思是说，中国推动12个领域的数字经济发展，目标瞄准金融、科技、农业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去的某个时间点之前已经发生或完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Wang had tendered his resignation with immediate effect, according to Yonyou’s filing with the Shanghai Stock Exchange on Wednesday. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去完成时态的句子，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had是have的过去式，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示在过去的某个时间点之前已经发生或完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示王文京根据用友周三向上海证券交易所提交的文件，已立即递交辞呈。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Tech billionaire Wang, 60, will remain in his roles as Yonyou chairman and chief executive, overseeing corporate strategy and product development</li>
<li>The senior management shuffle at Yonyou reflects the firm’s effort to turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/6c7f31d3-f7f3-4577-a795-008077b768f9_4bcd59c9.jpg" /><figcaption>Yonyou Network Technology founder Wang Wenjing retains his roles as chairman and chief executive at the Beijing-based enterprise management systems company. Photo: Weibo</figcaption></figure><p>Tech billionaire <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/347601/ufsoft-creates-fast-fortune-and-billion-dollar-goal" target="_self" title="">Wang Wenjing</a>, who was once known as China’s “king of software”, has stepped down as president of enterprise management systems provider Yonyou Network Technology, as the company he founded in 1988 continues to struggle with sluggish sales and mounting losses amid the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3241783/chinas-2023-gdp-forecasts-twisted-and-turned-prognosticators-puzzled-over-countrys-future" target="_self" title="">weak post-pandemic economic recovery</a>.</p><p>Wang had tendered his resignation with immediate effect, according to Yonyou’s filing with the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai-stock-index" target="_self" title="">Shanghai Stock Exchange</a> on Wednesday. “The company’s board expresses its sincere gratitude to Wang for his contribution,” the Beijing-based firm said.</p><p>The 60-year-old Wang – with a net worth of US$3.1 billion as of January 5, according to Forbes – will remain in his roles as Yonyou chairman and chief executive, overseeing corporate strategy and product development, according to a separate statement released by the firm.</p><p>Veteran Yonyou executive Chen Qiangbin, 48, takes over as company president, with a focus on operations and management, according to the company. After joining Yonyou in 2000, Chen was involved in software development, sales and then served as general manager at the firm’s branch offices in Beijing, northern Hebei province and southwestern Sichuan province.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/9f56e087-6a3a-4e69-b9a6-4ca4b123727b_b201e52d.jpg" title="Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Yonyou Network Technology, formerly known as Ufida, has been mainland China’s largest enterprise management software provider for many years. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Yonyou, ranked by research firm Gartner as one of the world’s top 10 enterprise resource planning (ERP) software providers, saw its shares close down 2.48 per cent to 16.49 yuan (US$2.32) on Friday.</p><p>ERP refers to software designed to automate business processes, as well as provide insights and internal controls, often in real time. It manages operations including accounting and finance, procurement, supply chain, manufacturing, human resources and collaboration.</p><p>In recent years, Yonyou changed its focus from selling licences of its ERP and other enterprise management software to collecting service fees by providing these systems via a software-as-a-service model called Yonyou BIP. By 2022, cloud-based services accounted for nearly 70 per cent of the firm’s revenue.</p><p>Still, the senior management shuffle at Yonyou reflects the company’s effort to try and turn around its business after about two years of stagnant revenue growth and widening losses, as fresh opportunities beckon from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" target="_self" title="">Beijing’s digitalisation drive</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" title="">China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms</a></h3><p>Yonyou initiated one of its largest organisational changes last year, when it set up 23 industry client and solution business units to cover a range of industries including manufacturing, consumer products, energy, logistics and the public sector. The move was expected to make its operations more focused on vertical industries, instead of regional markets.</p><p>Even as China’s weak macroeconomic environment has driven a round of poor earnings from cybersecurity and finance software stocks, Yonyou’s third-quarter results last year – with “positive revenue growth across all segments” – “indicate that ERP demand has been resilient”, according to a November research note by Jefferies.</p><p>While it reported 2 per cent revenue growth in the first three quarters of last year, Yonyou saw its losses widen 91 per cent year on year to 1 billion yuan.</p><p>Wang, who was 24 when he founded Yonyou <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/242891/software-rewards-u-turn-decision" target="_self" title="">after leaving a job in government</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/article/496999/software-firm-hopes-name-will-score-goal" target="_self" title="">initially provided accounting software</a> to businesses and quickly became a dominant player in that market. When Yonyou – first known as Ufsoft and then Ufida – expanded into ERP and other enterprise management systems, it surpassed the performance of major foreign ERP players like Oracle and SAP in the Chinese market.</p><p>Yonyou currently has more than 230 branch offices worldwide – including in the mainland, Hong Kong, Macau, Australia, New Zealand and a number of countries in Southeast Asia.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>McDonald’s China and Cainiao partner on RFID chips to improve supply chain efficiencies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247447/mcdonalds-china-and-cainiao-partner-rfid-chips-improve-supply-chain-efficiencies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  McDonald's China partners with Cainiao, Alibaba's logistics arm, to leverage RFID technology and digitization in its supply chain. This collaboration aims to improve supply chain efficiency, reduce stocktaking time, and enhance inventory accuracy. The trial project of RFID technology reduced stocktaking time from 1 hour to 15 minutes, boosting efficiency and data accuracy. Cainiao's RFID tags employ built-in microchips that transmit data via radio frequency signals. Beyond RFID, McDonald's and Cainiao plan to explore digitization and automation technologies. This partnership comes as Cainiao prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong, seeking to raise at least US$1 billion.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: McDonald's China and Cainiao collaborate to enhance supply chain efficiency using RFID and digitization.</li>    <li>Theme: Leveraging RFID technology and digitization to optimize supply chain operations in the fast-food industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of RFID in improving supply chain tracking, inventory management, and overall efficiency gains.</li>    <li>Main information: Collaboration details, RFID trial project results, Cainiao's IPO plans, and McDonald's digitization efforts.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  麦当劳中国与阿里巴巴旗下物流公司菜鸟网络合作，在供应链中利用射频识别（RFID）技术和其他技术来提高供应链效率。根据双方周四签署的协议，麦当劳中国将在其供应链中部署菜鸟的RFID技术，在食品包装上使用内置标签。杭州这家物流公司的一份声明称，这项技术使企业可以跟踪产品，从工厂到餐厅。声明称，RFID技术的试点项目帮助餐厅将每日盘点时间从1小时减少到15分钟，同时将库存数据的准确性提高了30%。阿里巴巴物流子公司菜鸟在收购百世集团后，通过海外并购提升海外地位。RFID是继条形码和二维码之后的第三代识别技术，已广泛应用于供应链追踪。由于内嵌有微芯片，数据通过射频信号传输。菜鸟表示，麦当劳和菜鸟除了部署RFID技术以提高库存和物流效率之外，还将在供应链中探索数字化和自动化技术。麦当劳中国与菜鸟的合作正值后者准备在香港进行首次公开募股（IPO）之际，菜鸟已于去年9月向该市的证券交易所提交了A1申请。据《南华早报》当月的一篇报道援引消息人士称，菜鸟的目标是筹集至少10亿美元，具体视市场情况而定。此次上市是阿里巴巴集团范围重组的一部分，因为这家电子商务巨头寻求在业务竞争加剧的情况下解放决策权。阿里巴巴还拥有《南华早报》。菜鸟成立于2013年，是阿里巴巴庞大电子商务帝国的物流骨干，2023年每天处理超过400万个跨境包裹。3月份宣布的重组中，阿里巴巴宣布将分拆菜鸟。菜鸟于2021年推出自己的标签，进军RFID领域，据称该标签的识别准确率可达99.9%。该公司去年4月宣布，仅仅两年时间里，该公司已生产并销售了超过1亿个RFID标签。麦当劳中国拥有5500多家餐厅和20多万名员工，每年为超过10亿名顾客提供服务。该公司还在加紧努力，使其在中国实现数字化运营，中国是这家快餐巨头在全球的第二大市场。上个月，麦当劳中国表示，将与华为技术合作，基于HarmonyOS的下一版本构建一款原生应用程序，HarmonyOS是中国电信设备和智能手机巨头自研的移动平台。  <ul>    <li>摘要：麦当劳中国与菜鸟合作，利用射频识别（RFID）和其他技术提高供应链效率。</li>    <li>主题：利用射频识别技术和数字化优化快餐行业的供应链运营。</li>    <li>观点：射频识别在改进供应链跟踪、库存管理和整体效率提升方面的意义。</li>    <li>主要信息：合作细节、射频识别试点项目结果、菜鸟IPO计划，以及麦当劳的数字化努力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>recognition (n.) - /ˌrekəɡˈnɪʃən/ 识别，辨认。    <p>原文例句：Cainiao moved into the RFID field with the launch of its own tags in 2021, which it said could achieve 99.9 per cent recognition accuracy. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由re-（重新）和cognitio（了解，知识）组成，表示“重新了解，识别，辨认”。在这个例句中，它指的是菜鸟在2021年推出的RFID标签的识别准确率可达99.9%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>accuracy (n.) - /ˈækjʊrəsi/ 准确性，精确性。    <p>原文例句：The trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes while improving the accuracy of inventory data by 30 per cent, according to the statement. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由accuratus（准确的）组成，表示“准确性，精确性”。在这个例句中，它指的是RFID技术试点项目在将每日盘点时间从1小时减少到15分钟的同时，将库存数据的准确性提高了30%。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>RFID technology -射频识别技术。    <P>原文例句：McDonald’s China unit has partnered with Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics business, to improve supply chain efficiency using radio frequency identification (RFID) chips and other technologies.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由radio frequency identification（射频识别）和technology（技术）组成的，表示“射频识别技术”。在这个例句中，它指的是麦当劳中国与菜鸟网络合作，利用射频识别技术和其他技术来提高供应链效率。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Under a deal signed on Thursday, McDonald’s China will deploy Cainiao’s RFID technology in its supply chain with built-in tags on food packages, allowing the company to track products from factories to restaurants, according to a statement by the Hangzhou-based logistics firm. - 根据杭州这家物流公司的一份声明，根据周四签署的一项协议，麦当劳中国将在其供应链中部署菜鸟的RFID技术，在食品包装上使用内置标签，使公司能够追踪产品从工厂到餐厅的整个过程。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是McDonald’s China will deploy Cainiao’s RFID technology in its supply chain，其中主语是McDonald’s China，谓语是will deploy，宾语是Cainiao’s RFID technology。Under a deal signed on Thursday是一个介词短语作状语，表示在周四签署的一项协议下。with built-in tags on food packages是一个介词短语作状语，表示在食品包装上使用内置标签。allowing the company to track products from factories to restaurants是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示使公司能够追踪产品从工厂到餐厅的整个过程。这个句子的意思是说，根据杭州这家物流公司的一份声明，根据周四签署的一项协议，麦当劳中国将在其供应链中部署菜鸟的RFID技术，在食品包装上使用内置标签，使公司能够追踪产品从工厂到餐厅的整个过程。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间或动作完成或发生之前已经发生或完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：McDonald’s China has a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词。这种时态表示在过去某个时间或动作完成或发生之前已经发生或完成的动作或状态，强调动作或状态在过去某个时间之前已经完成或结束。在这个例句中，它表示麦当劳中国拥有超过5,500家餐厅和超过20万名员工，每年为超过10亿名顾客提供服务，这一情况或状态在过去一段时间内已经存在并持续到现在。</p></li>    <ul><li>A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants</li>
<li>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/d5e1a0a3-a5e3-492f-b311-a67d3c5f12ec_d1186b0d.jpg" /><figcaption>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for an initial public offering in Hong Kong. Photo: Reuters </figcaption></figure><p>McDonald’s China unit has partnered with Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics business, to improve supply chain efficiency using radio frequency identification (RFID) chips and other technologies.</p><p>Under a deal signed on Thursday, McDonald’s China will deploy Cainiao’s RFID technology in its supply chain with built-in tags on food packages, allowing the company to track products from factories to restaurants, according to a statement by the Hangzhou-based logistics firm.</p><p>A trial project of the RFID technology helped reduce the time needed for stocktaking each day from 1 hour to 15 minutes for restaurants while improving the accuracy of inventory data by 30 per cent, according to the statement.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240676/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-will-enhance-its-overseas-presence-proposed-buyout-local-rival-best" title="">Alibaba logistics spin-off Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout</a></h3><p>RFID is a third-generation identification technology, after bar codes and QR codes, and has been widely adopted in supply chain tracking. With a built-in microchip, data is transmitted through radio frequency signals.</p><p>Apart from deploying RFID technology to improve efficiency in inventory and logistics, McDonald’s and Cainiao will also explore digitisation and automation technologies in the supply chain, Cainiao said.</p><p>The deal between McDonald’s China and Cainiao comes as the logistics firm prepares for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3235860/alibabas-cainiao-files-us1-billion-ipo-helping-hong-kong-land-worlds-second-biggest-listing-2023" target="_self" title="">an initial public offering (IPO) in Hong Kong</a> after submitting its A1 filing to the city’s stock exchange last September.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month. The listing is part of a group-wide restructuring of Alibaba as the e-commerce titan seeks to free up decision- making amid increased competition across its businesses. Alibaba also owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Established in 2013, Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s huge e-commerce empire, handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023. Alibaba announced it would spin Cainiao off in the restructuring announced in March.</p><p>Cainiao moved into the RFID field with the launch of its own tags in 2021, which it said could achieve 99.9 per cent recognition accuracy. The company announced in April last year that it had produced and sold over 100 million RFID tags in just two years.</p><p>McDonald’s China has a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year. It has also been stepping up efforts to digitise its operations in the country, which is the fast-food giant’s second-largest market globally.</p><p>Last month, McDonald’s China said it would work with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> to build a native app based on the next iteration of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3136017/will-huaweis-harmony-operating-system-end-global-duopoly-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS</a>, the Chinese telecommunications equipment and smartphone giant’s self-developed mobile platform.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China unveils 3-year ‘data action plan’ as Beijing seeks to boost growth through tech</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247423/china-unveils-3-year-data-action-plan-beijing-seeks-boost-growth-through-tech</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In order to promote the development of data industry and cultivate new growth momentum for the economy, China has released a three-year action plan, aiming to establish over 300 typical application scenarios and expand the data industry by 20% annually by 2026. The initiative calls for utilizing China's advantages in market size, abundant data resources, and use cases, and addressing challenges such as low data quality, poor circulation, and untapped application potential. The plan involves mobilizing data resources to support the development of Chinese AI language models, creating high-quality datasets for AI training, and promoting data utilization in 12 key sectors, including finance, technology, agriculture, and transportation.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: A three-year action plan for China's data economy aims to promote industry growth, address challenges, and boost data utilization.</li>    <li>Theme: China's efforts to cultivate a data-driven economy by leveraging market advantages and resolving data-related issues.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of data in driving economic development and the need for a coordinated approach to data management and utilization.</li>    <li>Main information: Goals to establish 300 application scenarios, expand data industry by 20% annually, mobilize data resources for AI development, create high-quality datasets, and promote data use in key sectors.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  为推动数据产业发展，培育经济发展新动能，中国发布三年行动方案，计划到2026年培育形成300个以上典型应用场景，每年实现数据产业增加值增长20%以上。该举措呼吁利用中国在市场规模、数据资源丰富、使用案例等方面的优势，解决数据质量不高、流通不畅、应用潜力未充分挖掘等挑战。该计划涉及调动数据资源支持中国人工智能语言模型的开发，创建高质量的人工智能训练数据集，以及促进数据在金融、技术、农业、交通等12个重点行业的应用。中国的新数据战略旨在缩小与美国在人工智能发展上的差距，尽管面临着包括先进芯片获取受限等一系列挑战。  <ul>    <li>摘要：针对数据经济，中国设立三年行动方案，旨在推动行业发展，解决挑战，促进数据应用。</li>    <li>主题：中国利用市场优势、解决数据问题，努力培育以数据为驱动的经济。</li>    <li>观点：数据在经济发展中的重要性，以及对数据管理和使用的统筹需求。</li>    <li>主要信息：到2026年目标完成300个应用场景建设，每年数据产业增加值增长20%，动员数据资源支持人工智能开发，创建高质量的数据集，并在金融、技术、农业等主要行业促进数据应用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>cultivate (v.) - /ˈkʌltɪveɪt/ 培育，发展。    <p>原文例句：The initiative is aimed at “cultivating” a new driving force for China’s economic development, leveraging the country’s advantages including a sizeable market, and abundant data resources and use cases, the NDA said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由cum（一起，共同）和agere（做，耕种）组成，表示“一起耕种，共同努力，培育”。在这个例句中，它指的是培育中国经济发展的新动力，利用中国的市场规模、数据资源和使用案例等优势。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>abundant (adj.) - /əˈbʌndənt/ 丰富的，充足的。    <p>原文例句：The agency’s plan involves mobilising data resources to support development of China’s own artificial intelligence (AI) large language models - the technology used to train AI applications like ChatGPT. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由ab（从，远离）和undare（波浪，浪涌）组成，表示“浪涌而至，充足，丰富”。在这个例句中，它指的是丰富的数据资源，即中国拥有大量的数据资源，可以支持人工智能的发展。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>artificial intelligence (AI) - 人工智能（AI）。    <P>原文例句：The agency’s plan involves mobilising data resources to support development of China’s own artificial intelligence (AI) large language models - the technology used to train AI applications like ChatGPT. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由artificial（人造的，人为的）和intelligence（智力）构成的，表示“人造的智能，即机器或计算机表现出的智慧”。在这个例句中，它指的是人工智能（AI），即中国正在发展自己的人工智能语言模型，以支持其人工智能的开发。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>unleash economic value - 释放经济价值。    <P>原文例句：The goal was to unleash economic value while ensuring security and privacy.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由unleash（释放，解除束缚）和economic value（经济价值）构成的，表示“释放经济价值，即通过利用数据创造价值”。在这个例句中，它指的是释放经济价值，即中国希望通过利用数据来创造经济价值，同时确保安全和隐私。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>While the country’s internet watchdog, the Cyberspace Administration of China, has put in place laws and regulations governing data security, Beijing did not have a government body overseeing development policies for data until the establishment of the NDA. - 虽然中国网络监管机构，即中国网络空间管理局，已经制定了管理数据安全的法律法规，但在建立国家数据管理局之前，北京一直没有一个政府机构负责监督数据的发展政策。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Beijing did not have a government body overseeing development policies for data until the establishment of the NDA，其中主语是Beijing，谓语是did not have，宾语是a government body overseeing development policies for data。While the country’s internet watchdog, the Cyberspace Administration of China, has put in place laws and regulations governing data security是一个独立的主句，它相当于一个条件状语从句，修饰主句。这个句子的意思是说，虽然中国网络监管机构，即中国网络空间管理局，已经制定了管理数据安全的法律法规，但在建立国家数据管理局之前，北京一直没有一个政府机构负责监督数据的发展政策。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由语法的间接受词引起的。    <p>原文例句：The data industry is expected to prosper in China over the next three years, and is expected to grow by 20 percent every year.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个例句中，prosper和grow都是被动语态动词，prosper的原型是prosper，grow的原型是grow。被动语态是由be动词和过去分词构成的，表示动作或状态是由语法的间接受词引起的。在这个例句中，prosper in China over the next three years表示在未来三年内在中国发展，grow by 20 percent every year表示每年增长20%。这个句子的意思是说，预计未来三年数据产业将在中国蓬勃发展，每年增长20%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。    <p>原文例句：China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个例句中的sets sights on finance, tech, farms是一个现在完成时态动词，sets的原型是set，sights的原型是sight，farm的原型是farm。现在完成时态是由has/have和过去分词构成的，表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，sets sights on finance, tech, farms表示集中精力于金融、技术、农业。这个句子的意思是说，中国正在推进数字经济对12个行业的推动，集中精力于金融、技术、农业等领域。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China aims to build more than 300 ‘representative’ application scenarios by 2026, and grow its data industry by 20 per cent every year</li>
<li>The digital economy still faces challenges including low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped applications potential</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/7195ef42-b909-415f-a96d-069d4c81cfa9_a08669f1.jpg" /><figcaption>A visitor shakes hands with a humanoid robot during the China International Digital Economy Expo 2023 in Hebei Province. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China’s newly established data administration, an agency created by Beijing to make data an effective production factor, has unveiled a three-year action plan to use the country’s massive troves of information to boost its economy.</p><p>According to the plan published by the National Data Administration (NDA) on Thursday, China aims to build more than 300 “representative” application scenarios by 2026, grow its data industry by 20 per cent every year, and multiply data trading volume.</p><p>The initiative is aimed at “cultivating” a new driving force for China’s economic development, leveraging the country’s advantages including a sizeable market, and abundant data resources and use cases, the NDA said.</p><p>The agency’s plan involves mobilising data resources to support development of China’s own artificial intelligence (AI) large language models - the technology used to train AI applications like ChatGPT. It will also increase efforts to have research institutions and leading enterprises build industry databases to create high quality datasets for training AI models.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" title="">China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms</a></h3><p>The blueprint comes at a time when China’s digital economy, having developed rapidly in recent years, still faces challenges including the low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped potential for applications, it said.</p><p>The NDA was announced in March last year as Beijing ramped up efforts in managing the country’s growing pool of data that is fragmented across different sectors and industries. The goal was to unleash economic value while ensuring security and privacy.</p><p>While the country’s internet watchdog, the Cyberspace Administration of China, has put in place laws and regulations governing data security, Beijing did not have a government body overseeing development policies for data until the establishment of the NDA.</p><p>The new administration, which officially began operations in October, is tasked with “coordinating and promoting the construction of data infrastructure, coordinating the integration, sharing, development and utilisation of data resources” across China’s economy and society, it said in March 2023.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246289/china-turns-spotlight-digital-economy-quest-common-prosperity-under-president-xi-jinping" title="">China’s focuses on digital economy to drive ‘common prosperity’ under Xi</a></h3><p>The agency, established under China’s top economic planner, the National Development and Reform Commission, is headed by information technology (IT) veteran Liu Liehong, former chairman of state-owned telecommunications network operator China Unicom.</p><p>The three-year plan will “guide and encourage” different types of private capital to invest in the data industry, and support data brokers in raising capital by going public.</p><p>The NDA also singled out 12 industries that should make better use of data, including manufacturing, agriculture, commerce, transport, finance and IT.</p><p>China’s new data strategies come as it seeks to catch up with the US in the development of AI, despite facing a host of challenges including restricted access to advanced chips.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong-listed Chinese miner CMOC takes Glencore’s cobalt crown as output jumps 170% in 2023</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247376/hong-kong-listed-chinese-miner-cmoc-takes-glencores-cobalt-crown-output-jumps-170-2023</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In 2023, China's CMOC Group, a leading cobalt producer, significantly increased its output, surpassing Glencore as the world's top producer of cobalt. The soaring production, particularly at CMOC's Kisanfu mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo, helped drive down cobalt prices, exacerbating an existing market surplus and contributing to a 30% price decline. Meanwhile, CMOC's copper output also surged, making it one of the world's top producers of the metal.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: CMOC's increased cobalt production impacts the global market.</li>    <li>Theme: The rise of CMOC as a major cobalt producer and its impact on the market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of cobalt in electric vehicle batteries and the growing demand for electric vehicles.</li>    <li>Main information: CMOC's production surge, particularly at the Kisanfu mine; the resulting drop in cobalt prices; and CMOC's position as the world's top copper producer.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023年，中国领先的钴生产商中国钼业集团大幅提高了其产量，超越嘉能可成为全球最大的钴生产商。产量激增，尤其是在刚果民主共和国的中国钼业集团Kisanfu矿，这有助于拉低钴价，加剧了现有的市场过剩，并导致价格下降30%。同时，中国钼业集团的铜产量也大幅增长，使其成为全球最大的铜生产商之一。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国钼业集团提高钴产量，影响全球市场。</li>    <li>主题：中国钼业集团成为主要钴生产商及其对市场的影响。</li>    <li>观点：钴在电动汽车电池中的重要性以及对电动汽车不断增长的需求。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国钼业集团的产量激增，尤其是在Kisanfu矿；由此导致的钴价下跌；以及中国钼业集团作为全球最大铜生产商的地位。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>slump (n.) - /slʌmp/ 下跌，衰退。    <p>原文例句：Soaring output at CMOC’s US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于古英语单词“slumpe”，意为“倒塌”。在这个例句中，它指的是钴价的急剧下降。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>  <li>surplus (n.) - /ˈsɜːrplʌs/ 过剩，余额。    <p>原文例句：The market was already in one of its biggest ever surpluses as 2023 began, and the additional output helped drive a 30 per cent slump in prices over the year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于拉丁语单词“superplus”，意为“超过”。在这个例句中，它指的是钴市场的过剩。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>bring … back into balance - 使……恢复平衡。    <p>原文例句：Glencore had started to stockpile surplus at its operations in Congo in a bid to bring the market back into balance.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由bring（带来），back（回到），into（进入），balance（平衡）组成，意为“使恢复平衡”。在这个例句中，它指的是嘉能可在刚果的业务开始囤积过剩的钴，目的是使市场恢复平衡。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Soaring output at the US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year - 美国18亿美元的Kisanfu矿的产量飙升，引发了去年钴价格的急剧下跌。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Soaring output，谓语是helped trigger，宾语是a sharp slump in cobalt prices。其中Soaring output是一个现在分词短语，作主语，表示产量飙升。helped trigger是一个过去式动词，作谓语，表示帮助引发。a sharp slump in cobalt prices是一个名词短语，作宾语，表示钴价格的急剧下跌。这个句子的意思是说，美国18亿美元的Kisanfu矿的产量飙升，引发了去年钴价格的急剧下跌。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Glencore had started to stockpile surplus at its operations in Congo in a bid to bring the market back into balance.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示嘉能可在刚果的业务已经开始囤积过剩的钴，目的是使市场恢复平衡。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The company’s output of the key metal in EV batteries exceeded its own guidance by more than 20 per cent</li>
<li>Soaring output at CMOC’s US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/978ac785-70c2-47f2-8569-299b57f5feb3_f7bc69b7.jpg" /><figcaption>Excavators and drillers work in an open pit at Tenke Fungurume, a copper and cobalt mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>China’s CMOC Group boosted its cobalt output by more than 170 per cent last year, with surging production at a new mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo helping the company leapfrog Glencore as the world’s top producer of the key battery metal.</p><p>Hong Kong-listed CMOC produced 55,526 tonnes of cobalt in 2023, it said in a filing on Thursday. In October, Glencore forecast output of as much as 42,000 tonnes. While investors and traders had been expecting a large increase at CMOC’s massive Kisanfu mine – which came online in the second quarter – the full-year result exceeded the company’s own production guidance by more than 20 per cent.</p><p>Soaring output at the US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year, alongside rising production in Indonesia and a rebound in exports from CMOC’s other operation in Congo, Tenke-Fungurume. The market was already in one of its biggest ever surpluses as 2023 began, and the additional output helped drive a 30 per cent slump in prices over the year.</p><p>The mismatch between supply and demand became so acute that by midyear Glencore had started to stockpile surplus at its operations in Congo in a bid to bring the market back into balance. Glencore is set to announce its full production results next month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/bc0491e6-2aee-4541-8141-aa5c1fb6228a_1126e908.jpg" title="An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>CMOC’s copper output also jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes, establishing it as one of the world’s top producers at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output.</p><p>Cobalt is a material used in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3234469/global-ev-transition-accelerates-falling-battery-costs-hasten-purchase-price-parity-further-blow" target="_self" title="">NCM (lithium, nickel, cobalt and manganese) batteries</a> powering electric cars, which offer vehicles a longer driving range than nickel-based LFP (lithium, iron and phosphate) counterparts.</p><p>Global consultancy AlixPartners forecast in a research report in July that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicles (EVs)</a> would account for 34 per cent of global sales by 2028 and make up 61 per cent of sales in 2035, compared to 14 per cent in 2022.</p><p>In China, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243806/li-auto-xpeng-pace-chinese-ev-makers-race-towards-2023-sales-record-amid-all-time-high-monthly" target="_self" title="">EV penetration rate</a> exceeded 40 per cent in 2023 amid motorists’ rising penchant for environmentally friendly cars featuring autonomous driving technology and digital cockpits.</p><p>Mainland China is now the world’s largest automotive and EV market, with sales of battery-powered cars accounting for about 60 per cent of the global total.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246699/chinese-battery-maker-gotion-starts-making-energy-storage-packs-fremont-plant-kicking-made-america" title="">Chinese EV battery maker Gotion starts making energy storage packs in US</a></h3><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3237220/chinese-ev-makers-course-smashing-85-million-2023-sales-target-mainland-industry-players-and" target="_self" title="">Electric vehicle (EV) sales on the mainland</a>, however, are seen growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from the projected 30 per cent increase in 2023.</p><p>Seoul-based consultancy SNE Research said in a report last February that electric cars with a driving range of more than 300 kilometres were sold at about US$30,000, on par with prices of petrol-powered vehicles, which helped EVs gain popularity around the globe.</p><p><em>Additional reporting by</em> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/author/daniel-ren" target="_self" title=""><em>Daniel Ren</em></a></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Qualcomm unveils chip for mixed reality to compete with Apple’s Vision Pro</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247367/qualcomm-unveils-chip-mixed-reality-compete-apples-vision-pro</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Qualcomm announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets, which will be used by Samsung and Google. This chip can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, improving image quality, reducing eye fatigue, and enabling new features. The market for mixed-reality devices was boosted by Apple's announcement of its own headset, and Qualcomm's chips have been central to other companies' efforts in this space. Augmented reality imposes graphics and written content on top of a person's view of the world, while virtual reality places a consumer in a closed digital world. The Snapdragon XR2+ chip's improved performance will allow for 4K-resolution images and enhanced perception, making it potentially useful in easing surgical patients' fears.  <ul>  <li>Abstract: Qualcomm's new Snapdragon XR2+ chip for virtual and mixed-reality headsets promises improved performance and features.</li>  <li>Theme: The chip's capabilities and potential applications in the growing mixed-reality market.</li>  <li>Viewpoint: The significance of mixed-reality technology and Qualcomm's role in driving its adoption.</li>  <li>Main information: Features and benefits of the Snapdragon XR2+ chip; its use by Samsung and Google; applications in augmented and virtual reality; potential for easing surgical patients' fears.</li></ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  高通宣布推出专为虚拟现实和混合现实头显设计的骁龙XR2+芯片，该芯片将被三星和谷歌使用。这款芯片可以运行12个或更多的高清摄像头，提高图像质量，减少眼睛疲劳，并启用新功能。混合现实设备市场因苹果宣布推出自己的头显而得到提振，高通的芯片一直是其他公司在这方面努力的核心。增强现实将图形和书面内容叠加在人们对世界的看法之上，而虚拟现实将消费者置于封闭的数字世界中。骁龙XR2+芯片的性能提升将允许4K分辨率的图像和增强的感知，使其在缓解手术患者的恐惧方面具有潜在的用处。  <ul>    <li>摘要：高通专为虚拟和混合现实头显设计的全新骁龙XR2+芯片有望实现更高的性能与特性。</li>    <li>主题：该款芯片的功能及其在不断增长的混合现实市场中的潜在应用。</li>    <li>观点：混合现实技术的意义和高通在推动其应用中所起的作用。</li>    <li>主要信息：骁龙XR2+芯片的功能和优势；三星和谷歌对其的使用；在增强现实和虚拟现实中的应用；缓解手术患者恐惧的潜力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>headset (n.) - 耳机，头戴式装置。    <p>原文例句：Qualcomm announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro.</p>    <p>例句讲解：在这个例句中，headsets指的是虚拟现实和混合现实头戴式装置，是人们戴在头上的设备，可以提供虚拟现实或混合现实体验。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>graphics (n.) - 图形，计算机图形。    <p>原文例句：Augmented reality imposes graphics and written content on top of a person’s view of the world. </p>    <p>例句讲解：在这个例句中，graphics指的是计算机图形，是指使用计算机技术创建的图像，可以是二维或三维的。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>resolution (n.) - 分辨率，解析度。    <p>原文例句：Headsets with the XR2+ will use processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors to project 4K-resolution images on each lens.</p>    <p>例句讲解：在这个例句中，resolution指的是分辨率，是指图像的清晰度和精细程度，通常用像素的数量或每英寸像素数（PPI）来表示。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take off (v.) - 起飞，腾飞，开始流行。    <p>原文例句：The market for devices that project information onto the user’s view of the physical world was fired up last year by Apple’s announcement that it would sell a mixed-reality headset. Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off.</p>    <p>例句讲解：在这个例句中，take off的意思是开始流行，是指一种产品或服务开始受到人们的欢迎和追捧。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>motion sickness (n.) - 晕车，晕船，晕机。    <p>原文例句：That improvement in quality will ease eye fatigue from reading text, reduce the potential for motion sickness and let device makers implement new features, he said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：在这个例句中，motion sickness指的是晕车、晕船或晕机等，是由于身体在运动过程中感受到的加速度和减速度而引起的不适反应。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>key to (n.) - 关键，重要因素。    <p>原文例句：Virtual reality could be key to easing fears in surgical patients: study</p>    <p>例句讲解：在这个例句中，key to的意思是关键或重要因素，是指对某件事情起决定性作用的因素。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The market for devices that project information onto the user’s view of the physical world was fired up last year by Apple’s announcement that it would sell a mixed-reality headset. - 市场对将信息投射到用户对物理世界的视图中的设备的需求去年因苹果宣布将销售混合现实耳机而被激发。    <p>句子分析：这是一个被动句，主语是The market，谓语是被动语态的fired up，宾语是devices that project information onto the user’s view of the physical world。last year by Apple’s announcement that it would sell a mixed-reality headset是一个介词短语，作状语，修饰fired up，表示去年苹果宣布将销售混合现实头显这一事件是导致市场需求激增的原因。这个句子的意思是说，去年苹果宣布将销售混合现实头显，这一事件激发了用户对将信息投射到其物理世界视图中的设备的需求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去完成时态，结构是：had + been + 现在分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间之前已经完成，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示该公司过去几年来一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在还在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The chip design firm said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung and Google</li>
<li>Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off</li>
</ul><p>Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors, announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro.</p><p>The San Diego, California-based chip design firm said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung Electronics and Alphabet’s Google on products under development.</p><p>The market for devices that project information onto the user’s view of the physical world was fired up last year by Apple’s announcement that it would sell a mixed-reality headset. Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off.</p><p>Augmented reality imposes graphics and written content on top of a person’s view of the world. Virtual reality places a consumer in a closed digital world. Apple’s coming Vision Pro and Meta Platforms' most-recent Quest 3 headset mix the technologies. Previous versions of Qualcomm’s XR chip have been featured in devices from Microsoft and Meta.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3240824/can-virtual-reality-ease-surgery-fears-patients-hong-kong-study-may-have-answer" title="">Virtual reality could be key to easing fears in surgical patients: study</a></h3><p>Headsets with the XR2+ will use processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors to project 4K-resolution images on each lens, according to Qualcomm’s Said Bakadir, a senior director of product management.</p><p>That improvement in quality will ease eye fatigue from reading text, reduce the potential for motion sickness and let device makers implement new features, he said. The chip’s ability to handle more cameras will aid in-depth perception and the eye tracking required to orient the user in the real world and recognise items.</p><p>“A lot of people want more juice to do more things,” Bakadir said. “People want to push the platform even higher.”</p><p>Qualcomm is working with a number of partners in addition to Google and Samsung, and announcements from customers may come as soon as next week’s CES show with products available as early as this year, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>OpenAI in talks with dozens of publishers to license content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  OpenAI 与 Politico 的母公司 Axel Springer 签订了价值数千万美元的多年许可协议。OpenAI正在与数十家出版商讨论授权其文章的交易，这是一个比以前已知的更广泛的努力，因为这家初创公司正在寻找内容来训练其人工智能 (AI) 模型。OpenAI 最近与 Politico 的母公司 Axel Springer 签订了价值数千万美元的多年许可协议。去年 7 月，OpenAI 宣布与美联社达成了一笔未公开金额的协议。这些交易对 OpenAI 的未来至关重要，因为它在构建模型所需的最新准确数据与对其数据来源日益严格的审查之间取得了平衡。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: OpenAI and media companies' licensing deals and challenges.</li>    <li>Theme: OpenAI's efforts to secure content for training its AI models through licensing agreements with publishers.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The differing perspectives of OpenAI and publishers on the use of copyrighted content for AI training.</li>    <li>Main information: OpenAI's ongoing negotiations with multiple publishers; the recent licensing deal with Axel Springer; the lawsuit filed by The New York Times against OpenAI and Microsoft for unauthorized use of content.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  OpenAI与Politico的母公司Axel Springer签署了数千万美元的多年授权协议。OpenAI正在与数十家出版商讨论授权其文章的交易，这是一个比以前已知的更广泛的努力，因为这家初创公司正在寻找内容来训练其人工智能（AI）模型。OpenAI最近与Politico的母公司Axel Springer签署了数千万美元的多年授权协议。去年7月，OpenAI宣布与美联社达成了一笔未公开金额的协议。这些交易对OpenAI的未来至关重要，因为它在构建模型所需的最新准确数据与对其数据来源日益严格的审查之间取得了平衡。  <ul>    <li>摘要：OpenAI与媒体公司之间的授权交易和挑战。</li>    <li>主题：OpenAI通过与出版商达成授权协议为训练其AI模型获取内容的努力。</li>    <li>观点：OpenAI和出版商对使用受版权保护的内容进行AI训练的不同看法。</li>    <li>主要信息：OpenAI与多家出版商正在进行的谈判；最近与Axel Springer达成的授权协议；纽约时报因未经授权使用内容而对OpenAI和微软提起的诉讼。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ink (v.) - /ɪŋk/ 签署，同意。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语，意思是“用墨水书写或签名”。在这个例句中，它用作动词，表示OpenAI与Politico的母公司Axel Springer签署了一项价值数千万美元的多年许可协议。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>strike (v.) - /straɪk/ 达成，达成（协议）。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI said it is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles, a broader effort than was previously known, as the start-up looks for content to train its artificial intelligence (AI) models.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古英语，意思是“用武器击打”。在这个例句中，它用作动词，表示OpenAI正在与数十家出版商谈判，以达成授权其文章的协议，这是一项比以前已知的更广泛的努力，因为这家初创公司正在寻找内容来训练其人工智能（AI）模型。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take into account - 考虑，考虑到。    <p>原文例句：But last week, one of the companies it had been in talks with, The New York Times Co, sued OpenAI and Microsoft for using the publication’s articles without permission.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由take（拿，取）,into（到，进入）和account（账户，注意）组成，表示“考虑到，考虑”。在这个例句中，它表示纽约时报公司上周起诉OpenAI和微软未经许可使用其出版物中的文章。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>OpenAI said it is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles, a broader effort than was previously known, as the start-up looks for content to train its artificial intelligence (AI) models. - OpenAI表示，该公司正在与数十家出版商谈判，以达成授权其文章的协议，这是一项比以前已知的更广泛的努力，因为这家初创公司正在寻找内容来训练其人工智能（AI）模型。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是OpenAI said it is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles，其中主语是OpenAI，谓语是said，宾语是it is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles。as the start-up looks for content to train its artificial intelligence (AI) models是一个时间状语从句，表示这个动作发生的时间，即OpenAI正在寻找内容来训练其人工智能（AI）模型。a broader effort than was previously known是一个同位语从句，解释striking deals to license their articles，表示这是一个比以前已知的更广泛的努力。这个句子的意思是说，OpenAI表示，该公司正在与数十家出版商谈判，以达成授权其文章的协议，这是一项比以前已知的更广泛的努力，因为这家初创公司正在寻找内容来训练其人工智能（AI）模型。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句型 - 为了强调或突出句子中的某个成分，将句子中的某些成分提前。    <p>原文例句：In July, OpenAI announced an agreement with the Associated Press for an undisclosed amount.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句型，将状语In July提前到句首，以突出其重要性。这种句型在英语中很常见，可以用来强调或突出句子中的某个成分。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>嵌入式从句 - 在主句中插入一个从句，以提供更多信息或细节。    <p>原文例句：The Times, however, disagrees with OpenAI’s stance, arguing that ChatGPT is flat out copying its journalists’ work without paying for it.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个嵌入式从句，在主句The Times, however, disagrees with OpenAI’s stance中插入了一个从句arguing that ChatGPT is flat out copying its journalists’ work without paying for it，以提供更多信息或细节。这种句型在英语中也很常见，可以用来在主句中插入一个从句，以提供更多信息或细节。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars</li>
<li>One of the companies it had been in talks with, The New York Times, sued OpenAI and Microsoft for using articles without permission</li>
</ul><p>OpenAI said it is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles, a broader effort than was previously known, as the start-up looks for content to train its artificial intelligence (AI) models.</p><p>“We are in the middle of many negotiations and discussions with many publishers. They are active. They are very positive. They’re progressing well,” Tom Rubin, OpenAI’s chief of intellectual property and content, told Bloomberg News. “You’ve seen deals announced, and there will be more in the future.”</p><p>OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars, a person familiar with the matter previously told Bloomberg. In July, OpenAI announced an agreement with the Associated Press for an undisclosed amount. These deals are key to OpenAI’s future, as it is balancing the need for updated, accurate data to build its models with growing scrutiny about where that data is sourced from.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246524/chinese-ai-champion-sensetime-introduces-go-playing-robot-japan-south-korea" title="">Chinese AI champion SenseTime introduces Go playing robot to Japan, South Korea</a></h3><p>But last week, one of the companies it had been in talks with, The New York Times Co, sued OpenAI and Microsoft for using the publication’s articles without permission.</p><p>The suit poses an existential challenge to OpenAI’s business. If the Times wins the case, OpenAI may not only owe billions of dollars, but could also be forced to destroy any of its training data that includes work from the Times, a costly and complicated task. More immediately, however, the lawsuit complicates OpenAI’s deal-making efforts with the media industry.</p><p>“The current situation is vastly different than the situations that publishers faced in the past with search engines and social media,” Rubin said. “Here, the content is used for training a model. It’s not used to reproduce the content. It’s not used to replace the content.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246667/chinas-cloud-market-growth-plateaus-despite-big-ai-push" title="">China’s cloud market growth plateaus despite big AI push</a></h3><p>The Times, however, disagrees with OpenAI’s stance, arguing that ChatGPT is flat out copying its journalists’ work without paying for it.</p><p>In its lawsuit, the publisher showed examples in which ChatGPT spit out entire paragraphs of nearly verbatim text from The New York Times (although some have pointed out that in certain examples, it was specifically prompting ChatGPT to reproduce Times content). The publisher argues that is proof OpenAI used New York Times data.</p><p>“If Microsoft and OpenAI want to use our work for commercial purposes, the law requires that they first obtain our permission,” The New York Times said in a statement. “They have not done so.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong-based AI-driven company sells potential breast cancer drug in deal whose value could exceed US$500 million</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247263/hong-kong-based-ai-driven-company-sells-potential-breast-cancer-drug-deal-whose-value-could-exceed</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Insilico Medicine, an AI-driven drug discovery company based in Hong Kong, has granted the exclusive global rights of a novel small molecule inhibitor for the potential treatment of hormone-sensitive cancers to the Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group.</li>    <li>The deal has the potential to reach a total value of over US$500 million, with a US$12 million upfront payment and royalties.</li>    <li>The agreement reflects the increasing role of artificial intelligence in revolutionizing drug discovery, enhancing efficiency and accuracy.</li>    <li>The AI-driven drug discovery market is expected to grow significantly in the coming years, reaching an estimated value of US$7.1 billion by 2030.</li>    <li>Breast cancer is the most prevalent cancer globally and the leading cause of cancer-related deaths among women, highlighting the significance of this collaboration.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>英斯力科，一家位于香港的AI驱动药物研发公司，已将一种新型小分子抑制剂的独家全球权利授予总部位于意大利的制药公司美纳里尼集团，用于潜在治疗激素敏感性癌症。</li>    <li>这项协议的总价值可能超过5亿美元，包括1200万美元的前期付款和版税。</li>    <li>该协议反映了人工智能在革新药物发现方面的日益重要的作用，它可以提高效率和准确性。</li>    <li>预计人工智能驱动的药物发现市场在未来几年将大幅增长，到2030年将达到71亿美元的估值。</li>    <li>乳腺癌是全球最普遍的癌症，也是女性癌症相关死亡的主要原因，突显了此次合作的重要性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>compound (adj.) - /ˈkɒmpaʊnd/ 复合的，成分复杂的。    <p>原文例句：The combined value of the deal includes all development, regulatory, and commercial milestones.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由com-（一起，合并）和pōnere（放，置）组成，意为“把…结合起来，使……复合”。在这个例句中，它描述了这笔交易的综合价值包括所有开发、监管和商业里程碑。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>synthetic (adj.) - /ˈsɪnθətɪk/ 合成的，人造的。    <p>原文例句：AI has emerged as a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery by enhancing efficiency and accuracy while reducing the time-consuming aspects of research and development, experts say. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于希腊语，由sun-（一起，合作）和tithenai（放置）组成，意为“把…结合起来，使……合成”。在这个例句中，它指的是人工智能作为一种催化剂，通过提高效率和准确性，同时减少研究和开发中耗时的方面，从而革新药物发现。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>so as to - 为了，以至于。    <p>原文例句：Stemline Therapeutics, a wholly owned unit of Menarini, will make a US$12 million upfront payment to Insilico under the agreement, which will be followed by sales royalties worth up to “double digits”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：so as to与in order to的意思一样，表示“为了，以至于”。在这个例句中，它表示美纳里尼的全资子公司 Stemline Therapeutics 将根据协议向 Insilico 支付 1200 万美元的预付款，然后是价值高达“两位数”的销售特许权使用费。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Insilico Medicine, a Hong Kong-based AI-driven drug discovery company that intends to list in Hong Kong after it unveiled an initial public offering plan (IPO) last year, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group in a deal that could reach a value of over US$500 million.<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂的长句，包含多个从句。主句是Insilico Medicine has sold its preclinical drug candidate，其中主语是Insilico Medicine，谓语是has sold，宾语是its preclinical drug candidate。last year是一个时间状语，表示去年。after it unveiled an initial public offering plan (IPO)是一个时间状语从句，表示在它公布首次公开募股计划之后。to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group是一个介词短语，作宾语表示给意大利制药公司美纳里尼集团。in a deal that could reach a value of over US$500 million是一个结果状语从句，表示在一个可能价值超过 5 亿美元的交易中。这个句子的意思是说，英斯力科是一家位于香港的人工智能驱动药物发现公司，该公司计划在去年公布首次公开募股计划后在香港上市，已将用于治疗乳腺癌的临床前候选药物出售给意大利制药公司美纳里尼集团，这笔交易的价值可能超过 5 亿美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>情态动词 - 表示说话人的态度、意愿等。    <p>原文例句：The AI-driven drug discovery market is projected to grow at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 23.72 per cent from 2023 to 2030, reaching an estimated value of US$7.1 billion by 2030, according to US-based Vantage Market Research. </p>    <p>语法讲解：情态动词可以表示说话人的能力、可能、许可、意愿、建议、命令等多种含义。在这个例句中，情态动词is projected to表示对未来的预测或估计，即人工智能驱动的药物发现市场预计将从2023年到2030年以23.72%的复合年增长率增长，到2030年将达到71亿美元的估值。</p></li>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：The company has raised more than US$400 million via private markets.</p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句型通常使用“强调句型”和“强调句型”两种结构。在这个例句中，强调句型是“It是强调句型，其中“It”是形式主语，真正的主语是the company，谓语是has raised。more than US$400 million是宾语，介词短语via private markets是状语，表示通过私人市场。这个句子的意思是说，该公司已通过私人市场筹集了超过 4 亿美元的资金。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Insilico grants Italy’s Menarini Group, the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule inhibitor, as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers</li>
<li>Breast cancer, a hormone-sensitive cancer, is the most common cancer worldwide, and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the WHO</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/0aa273cd-964f-49d2-be3b-69223d5b9a88_d8bebbd1.jpg" /><figcaption>null</figcaption></figure><p>Insilico Medicine, a Hong Kong-based AI-driven drug discovery company that intends to list in Hong Kong after it unveiled an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3225736/hong-kong-based-biotech-insilico-medicine-shifts-ipo-plan-city-new-york" target="_self" title="">initial public offering plan</a> (IPO) last year, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group in a deal that could reach a value of over US$500 million.</p><p>Stemline Therapeutics, a wholly owned unit of Menarini, will make a US$12 million upfront payment to Insilico under the agreement, which will be followed by sales royalties worth up to “double digits”. The combined value of the deal includes all development, regulatory, and commercial milestones.</p><p>The agreement comes at a time when cutting-edge technology is playing a greater role in drug discovery. AI has emerged as a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery by enhancing efficiency and accuracy while reducing the time-consuming aspects of research and development, experts say.</p><p>The AI-driven drug discovery market is projected to grow at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 23.72 per cent from 2023 to 2030, reaching an estimated value of US$7.1 billion by 2030, according to US-based Vantage Market Research.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/8d6c5116-f305-4968-8ef3-f757c1373823_34f54c2a.jpg" title="An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The technology expedites the process of identifying potential drugs, according to Insilico’s founder and co-CEO, Dr Alex Zhavoronkov.</p><p>Under the exclusive licensing agreement, Insilico has granted Stemline the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule KAT6A inhibitor as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers and other oncology indications.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3199001/sanofi-signs-research-tie-hong-kongs-insilico-medicine-accelerate-ai-powered-drug-discovery" title="">Sanofi signs with Hong Kong biotech firm Insilico to spur AI drug discovery</a></h3><p>Breast cancer is the most common cancer worldwide and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the World Health Organization.</p><p>The global breast cancer market is projected to hit around US$73.68 billion by 2032 with a registered CAGR of 9.9 per cent, according to Precedence Research.</p><p>“The partnership at the early stage preclinical trial is truly optimal when the partner is very committed,” said Zhavoronkov.</p><p>Menarini, an international pharmaceutical and diagnostics company with a turnover of more than US$4.4 billion and operations in 140 countries, sees the collaboration with Insilico as an opportunity to explore new treatment approaches and potentially unlock transformative cancer therapies, according to CEO Elcin Barker Ergun.</p><p>Insilico, founded by Zhavoronkov in 2014, has a pipeline that consists of 31 programmes for 29 drug targets in cancer, fibrosis, immunity, central nervous system and ageing-related diseases.</p><p>In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence.</p><p>Zhavoronkov declined to reveal a timeline for its IPO but said market sentiment was a concern.</p><p>Insilico has a presence in the markets of the US, Greater China, Canada and the Middle East. It launched the Generative AI and Quantum Computing Research and Development Center in Abu Dhabi in February 2023.</p><p>To date, the company has raised more than US$400 million via private markets. In 2022, it secured series D financing of US$95 million from investors such as Prosperity7, a growth venture fund of Saudi Arabia’s Aramco, and others including B Capital Group, Warburg Pincus, and Hong Kong-based Qiming Ventures.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese EV maker Hozon predicts fivefold jump in overseas sales as growth slows in hyper-competitive domestic market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247305/chinese-ev-maker-hozon-predicts-fivefold-jump-overseas-sales-growth-slows-hyper-competitive-domestic</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hozon New Energy Automobile, a Chinese electric vehicle (EV) start-up, aims to increase its overseas sales five-fold in 2024.</li>    <li>The company plans to deliver 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia.</li>    <li>Hozon has started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand and plans to open a second assembly facility outside China in the second quarter.</li>    <li>With the EV market in China becoming increasingly competitive, Hozon plans to expand its global presence and aims to sell 1 million EVs in 2026, including 400,000 outside mainland China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国电动汽车 (EV) 初创企业合众新能源汽车预计其在海外的汽车销售将会在2024年增长五倍，这主要得益于中国汽车制造商信心增强，转向国际销售来应对国内经济放缓。</li>    <li>这家总部位于上海的公司计划今年在60个海外市场（主要在东南亚）交付总计10万辆汽车，其泰国和印度尼西亚的组装厂已开始运营。</li>    <li>据副总裁周江表示，按此水平，海外销售额将占合众2024年总交付量的三分之一，预计交付量将达到30万辆。</li>    <li>他表示：“从整体来看，中国制造的电动汽车在全球消费者中都颇受欢迎。此外，我们对公司设计和制造面向所有人的电动汽车的全球视野充满信心。”</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>vice-president (n.) - /ˌvaɪs ˈprɛzɪdənt/ 副总裁。    <p>原文例句：At that level, overseas sales would account for a third of Hozon’s total deliveries in 2024, which are likely to hit 300,000 units, he said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由vice（副，次）和president（总统，董事长）组成，意思是“副总裁”。在这个例句中，它指的是合众新能源汽车的副总裁周江。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>target (v.) - /ˈtɑːrɡɪt/ 把……作为目标。    <p>原文例句：The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars aims to deliver a total 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由targe（瞄准）和-et（小，小的）组成，意思是“把……作为目标”。在这个例句中，它指的是合众新能源汽车的目标是在今年向60个海外市场（主要在东南亚）交付总计10万辆汽车。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>assembly (n.) - /əˈsɛmbli/ 装配，组装。    <p>原文例句：The plant, with an annual capacity of 20,000 units, produces right-hand-drive versions of Neta vehicles.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由assemble（组装）和-y（状态，过程）组成，意思是“装配，组装”。在这个例句中，它指的是合众新能源汽车在泰国的第一家海外工厂，该工厂的年产能为2万辆，生产右驾版的Neta汽车。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>electric vehicle (EV) - 电动汽车。    <p>原文例句：Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由electric（电的，电力的）和vehicle（车辆）组成，意思是“电动汽车”。在这个例句中，它指的是合众新能源汽车生产的电动汽车正在上海等待运往海外。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>assembly plant - 装配厂。    <p>原文例句：Hozon’s second assembly facility outside China will be operational by the second quarter.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由assembly（装配，组装）和plant（工厂）组成，意思是“装配厂”。在这个例句中，它指的是合众新能源汽车在海外的第二家装配厂，预计将于第二季度投入运营。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hozon delivered a total of 127,496 vehicles to domestic and overseas customers in 2023, down 16 per cent year on year. - 合众2023年向国内外客户交付了总计127,496辆汽车，同比下降16%。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Hozon delivered a total of 127,496 vehicles，其中主语是Hozon，谓语是delivered，宾语是a total of 127,496 vehicles。down 16 per cent year on year是一个过去分词短语作状语，修饰Hozon delivered，表示合众2023年向国内外客户交付的汽车数量比去年同期下降了16%。这个句子的意思是说，合众2023年向国内外客户交付了总计127,496辆汽车，同比下降了16%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The plant, with an annual capacity of 20,000 units, produces right-hand-drive versions of Neta vehicles.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示这家工厂的年产能为2万辆，一直持续到目前，仍在生产右驾版的Neta汽车。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>比较级和最高级 - 用于比较两个或多个对象或事物的差异。    <p>原文例句：EV sales in mainland China are seen growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, slowing from the projected 30 per cent increase in 2023. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个比较句，比较的是2024年和2023年的电动汽车销售增长率。其中20 per cent year on year是比较级，表示2024年的电动汽车销售增长率比2023年低了10个百分点。30 per cent increase是最高级，表示2023年的电动汽车销售增长率是最高的。这个句子的意思是说，2024年中国大陆的电动汽车销售预计将增长20%，低于2023年预计的30%的增长率。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars aims to deliver 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia</li>
<li>Company started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand in November, about two months ahead of schedule</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/2f9a94ae-4006-4789-9e96-32506d8ef0a5_7020747c.jpg" /><figcaption>Performers present a Hozon NETA V during a launch ceremony in Bangkok, Thailand, on August 24, 2022. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> start-up Hozon New Energy Automobile expects its sales outside mainland China to jump five-fold in 2024 as the country’s increasingly confident carmakers look to international sales to counter slowing growth at home.</p><p>The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars, aims to deliver a total 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia, as it starts operations of assembly plants in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243541/chinese-ev-maker-hozon-kicks-operations-its-first-overseas-factory-thailand-it-steps-push-southeast" target="_self" title="">Thailand</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3230821/hozon-steps-plans-develop-right-hand-drive-neta-electric-cars-indonesia-it-pushes-ahead-its-hong" target="_self" title="">Indonesia</a>, according to vice-president Zhou Jiang.</p><p>At that level, overseas sales would account for a third of Hozon’s total deliveries in 2024, which are likely to hit 300,000 units, he said.</p><p>“Overall, Chinese-made electric cars are well received by customers around the world,” he said in a media briefing on Thursday. “Moreover, we are confident of our company’s global perspective with the goal of designing and manufacturing EVs for all the people.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo" class="image-inline caption" height="1328" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/338ee101-bc2d-48a2-8f3d-5ae81ace116c_515c76ff.jpg" title="Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo" width="2000" /><figcaption>Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo</figcaption></figure></div><p>At the end of November, Hozon, also known as Neta Auto, started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand, about two months ahead of schedule. The plant, with an annual capacity of 20,000 units, produces right-hand-drive versions of Neta vehicles.</p><p>Hozon’s second assembly facility outside China will be operational by the second quarter, Zhou said.</p><p>“Owing to a slowing domestic market, Chinese EV makers whose brands and vehicles can attract foreign buyers will step up their overseas expansion in the coming years,” said Eric Han, a ­senior ­manager at Suolei, an advisory firm in Shanghai. “Indeed, they enjoy a higher profit margin in other markets because of price competition at home.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247229/short-sellers-target-byd-worlds-top-ev-maker-rivalry-intensifies" title="">Short sellers target BYD, world’s top EV maker, as rivalry intensifies</a></h3><p>Neta is a variation of the name Nezha, a protection deity in Chinese mythology. The brand falls into the category of budget EVs in China, aimed at middle- and low-income drivers who prefer battery-powered vehicles to cars powered by petrol-guzzling internal combustion engines.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246896/chinese-ev-makers-face-day-reckoning-2024-competition-and-price-war-force-out-underperformers" target="_self" title="">EV sales in mainland China</a> are seen growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from the projected 30 per cent increase in 2023.</p><p>With the EV market crowded with 200 players, a new round of price cuts is in effect, with top players like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest maker</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3229066/xpeng-gets-volkswagens-us700-million-investment-jointly-develop-evs-worlds-largest-vehicle-market" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> offering discounts to lure buyers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/markets/article/3247151/china-evs-xpeng-and-li-auto-roll-out-x9-and-mega-mpvs-aimed-rich-buyers-bid-dominate-segment" title="">China EVs: Xpeng and Li Auto roll out minivan models with focus on rich buyers</a></h3><p>Hozon delivered a total of 127,496 vehicles to domestic and overseas customers in 2023, down 16 per cent year on year.</p><p>In August, the company announced it had <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3232811/chinese-ev-start-hozon-raises-us960-million-pre-ipo-financing-looks-expand-footprint-home-and-abroad" target="_self" title="">raised 7 billion yuan (US$986 million)</a> in a crossover financing deal, without disclosing the names of the investors.</p><p>Crossover financing typically gives a start-up more time and capital to develop its business before an initial public offering (IPO). Investors normally close cross-financing deals at a discounted price while gaining a foothold in the prospective IPO.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>Hozon reported a net loss of 6.9 billion yuan in 2022, 138 per cent wider than a 2.9 billion yuan loss in the previous year, according to the annual report of 360 Security Technology, one of the EV company’s investors.</p><p>Zhou said the carmaker targets total sales of 1 million EVs in 2026, including 400,000 outside mainland China. It also plans to build plants in markets like the Middle East, Africa and South America, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China is on track to be world AI leader by 2030, with Hong Kong’s help</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3247052/china-track-be-world-ai-leader-2030-hong-kongs-help</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  China sets an ambitious goal to become a global leader in artificial intelligence (AI) by 2030, aiming to leverage its advantages in AI research, talent, infrastructure, and data. Meanwhile, Hong Kong can play a significant role in China's AI development by offering talent and funding.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China seeks to establish itself as a global AI leader, with Hong Kong contributing to its growth.</li>    <li>Theme: China's burgeoning AI industry, the role of Hong Kong in providing talent and funding.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of multilateral AI governance initiatives, balancing technology advancement with responsible regulation.</li>    <li>Main information: China's AI market, firms, and tech are expanding rapidly, propelled by supportive policies and vast data resources; the Global AI Governance Initiative emphasizes people-centered development, inclusiveness, and risk assessment; Hong Kong's strengths in talent attraction and funding through its universities and the Greater Bay Area.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary：</h2>  中国定下了到 2030 年成为全球人工智能 (AI) 领军者的宏伟目标，旨在利用其在人工智能研究、人才、基础设施和数据方面的优势。同时，香港可以在中国的人工智能发展中发挥重要作用，为其提供人才和资金支持。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国致力于确立其全球人工智能领导者的地位，而香港将助其发展。</li>    <li>主题：中国蓬勃发展的人工智能产业，香港在提供人才和资金方面的作用。</li>    <li>观点：多边人工智能治理举措的重要意义，平衡技术进步与负责任管理。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国的人工智能市场、企业和技术正在迅速发展，这得益于良好的政策支持和海量的数据资源；全球人工智能治理倡议强调以人为本的发展、包容性和风险评估；香港的优势在于通过其大学和粤港澳大湾区来吸引人才和提供资金。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>undisputed (adj.) - /ˌʌndɪˈspjuːtɪd/ 无争议的，无人反驳的。    <p>原文例句：According to a recent Nikkei study, “China is the undisputed champion in artificial intelligence research papers … far surpassing the US in both quantity and quality”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由un-（否定）和dispute（争论，争议）构成的，表示“没有争议，无人反驳”。在这个例句中，它描述了中国在人工智能研究论文中是“无争议的冠军”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>digitalization (n.) - /ˌdɪdʒɪtəlaɪˈzeɪʃən/ 数字化，数字技术。    <p>原文例句：From a regulatory perspective, China has taken a further step towards digitalisation and innovation. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由digital（数字的）和ization（化）构成的，表示“使数字化的过程”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国在数字技术和创新方面采取了进一步的措施。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>inclusive (adj.) - /ɪnˈkluːsɪv/ 包容的，包括所有人的。    <p>原文例句：The initiative calls for a “people-centred” approach to AI (i.e., developing AI for the good of humanity and its progress), more inclusiveness and fairness in AI development so countries can benefit regardless of their political or economic situation, ...</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由in-（进入）和clusive（包含，包括）构成的，表示“包括所有人的”。在这个例句中，它指的是全球人工智能治理倡议呼吁更多包容性和公平性，以便所有国家都能够受益于人工智能的发展。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>global race - 全球竞赛。    <P>原文例句：If we are in the midst of a global race for artificial intelligence (AI) breakthroughs, China is definitely a key player.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由global（全球）和race（比赛）构成的，表示“全球竞赛”。在这个例句中，它指的人工智能领域正在进行一场全球竞赛。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>people-centered approach-以人为本的方式。    <P>原文例句：The initiative calls for a “people-centred” approach to AI (i.e., developing AI for the good of humanity and its progress).</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由people-centered（以人为中心）和approach（方式）构成的，表示“以人为本的方式”。在这个例句中，它指的人工智能治理倡议呼吁采用以人为本的方式来发展人工智能。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China is the undisputed champion in artificial intelligence research papers … far surpassing the US in both quantity and quality. - 中国在人工智能研究论文方面是“无争议的冠军”，在数量和质量上都远远超过了美国。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是China，谓语是is，宾语是the undisputed champion in artificial intelligence research papers。far surpassing the US in both quantity and quality是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示中国在人工智能研究论文方面远远超过美国。这个句子的意思是说，中国在人工智能研究论文方面是“无争议的冠军”，在数量和质量上都远远超过了美国。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>名词性从句 -  在从句中充当名词成分的从句。    <p>原文例句：President Xi Jinping proposed the Global AI Governance Initiative for countries participating in the Belt and Road Initiative. - 习近平主席为参与一带一路倡议的国家提出了全球人工智能治理倡议。</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个名词性从句，在句中充当宾语，修饰名词initiative。从句的主语是President Xi Jinping，谓语是proposed，宾语是the Global AI Governance Initiative。这个句子的意思是说，习近平主席为参与一带一路倡议的国家提出了全球人工智能治理倡议。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China’s AI market, firms and tech are growing strongly, while the regulatory climate is maturing. Hong Kong can contribute by providing AI talent and funding</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/ccb3683c-5993-48ba-ab9c-122ea06719a8_5241b49e.jpg" /><figcaption>A woman stands in front of a poster during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai on July 6 last year. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>If we are in the midst of a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3236727/expect-chinas-regulators-help-ai-firms-race-against-us-european-peers" target="_self" title="">global race</a> for artificial intelligence (AI) breakthroughs, China is definitely a key player. While 2023 has been a year of AI hype – especially for generative AI, amid the popularity of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> – the industry has been of interest to most countries for years and will only become more important.</p><p>According to the 2023 AI Index Report by the Stanford Institute for Human-Centred Artificial Intelligence, global investment in AI has significantly increased over the last decade. By 2022, private investment in AI had grown to 18 times greater than in 2013.</p><p>Back in 2017, China made AI a national priority, stating its ambition to become “the world’s premier artificial intelligence innovation centre” by 2030.</p><p>According to the State Council’s 2017 guidelines, AI should be used to promote China’s technology, economy and social welfare, maintain national security and contribute to the world. The guidelines also said: “AI should be applied in the public service and social management to build a safer, more comfortable and convenient society.”</p><p>Why are nations racing to achieve AI dominance? One reason is that AI is a foundational technology with the capacity to increase productivity, boost competitiveness and help solve social challenges.</p><p>So what does the AI industry in China look like? According to a recent Nikkei study, “China is the undisputed champion in artificial intelligence research papers … far surpassing the US in both quantity and quality”.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>China’s AI market is projected to reach US$38.89 billion this year, and will grow by a compound annual rate of 18 per cent to reach US$104.7 billion by 2030. This is less than the US market, the world’s largest at a projected US$106.5 billion this year.</p><p>In addition, China has more than 4,300 AI enterprises and at least 238 <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241659/chinese-tech-companies-frenzy-over-ai-large-language-models-huge-waste-resources-baidu-ceo-says" target="_self" title="">large language models</a> (LLMs) – deep-learning AI algorithms based on very large data sets – with tech giants such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3239981/baidu-launches-paid-version-ernie-bot-chinese-firms-rush-make-money-their-generative-ai-chatbots" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3244693/alibaba-research-unit-unveils-llm-tailored-southeast-asia-e-commerce-giant-pushes-ai-fast-growth" target="_self" title="">Alibaba</a> (owner of the South China Morning Post) <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239432/tencent-using-hunyuan-ai-model-180-services-amid-competition-local-rivals-baidu-and-alibaba" target="_self" title="">Tencent</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238698/alibaba-tencent-and-other-major-chinese-backers-invest-us342-million-start-zhipu-ai-tech-sector-sees" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239031/iflytek-says-its-large-language-model-outperforms-chatgpt-chinese-ai-firm-vows-counter-us-chip-curbs" target="_self" title="">iFlyTek</a> all venturing into the field.</p><p>It is fair to say China can indeed become a world leader in AI by 2030. This is especially given its number of AI companies, number of people working in them, advanced AI infrastructure and supportive policies.</p><p>Furthermore, China has 975 million smartphone users, by far the highest in any country, meaning it generates a vast amount of digital information – and data plays a paramount role in developing AI.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>From a regulatory perspective, China has taken a further step towards digitalisation and innovation. At the third Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation, President Xi Jinping proposed the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238360/belt-and-road-forum-china-launches-ai-framework-urging-equal-rights-and-opportunities-all-nations" target="_self" title="">Global AI Governance Initiative</a> for countries participating in the Belt and Road Initiative.</p><p>The initiative calls for a “people-centred” approach to AI (i.e., developing AI for the good of humanity and its progress), more inclusiveness and fairness in AI development so countries can benefit regardless of their political or economic situation, testing and assessment systems based on AI risk levels, and regulation reform to protect privacy and data security.</p><p>Even though Global AI Governance Initiative is not the first multilateral forum on AI, it is undoubtedly one of the bigger ones, with potential implications for the AI regulatory scene across the globe.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3216079/how-hong-kong-can-play-role-preventing-ai-armageddon" title="">How Hong Kong can play a role in preventing AI Armageddon</a></h3><p>Meanwhile, Hong Kong has a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226804/hong-kongs-financial-secretary-tells-waic-city-has-key-role-play-chinas-ai-development" target="_self" title="">key role</a> to play in China’s AI development. Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po has said the city can contribute by providing talent and funding.</p><p>At the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai in July, Chan <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226804/hong-kongs-financial-secretary-tells-waic-city-has-key-role-play-chinas-ai-development" target="_self" title="">said</a> Hong Kong had advantages when it came to attracting talent in the current geopolitical landscape: “Our universities have brought together scientific researchers from the mainland and around the world, and the Hong Kong government has given a lot of policy and financial support in the past few years.”</p><p>Moreover, Chan added, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3241373/guangdong-authorities-unveil-new-data-transfer-guidelines-amid-push-build-greater-bay-area-ai-hub" target="_self" title="">Greater Bay Area</a> has formed “the whole industrial chain of AI from research to market application”.</p><p>To sum up, China will probably become the global AI leader and Hong Kong has a role to play in this. China’s AI industry is powerful and will keep on growing. While it is still too early to say if the Global AI Governance Initiative will be a success, it is relevant that China starts leveraging the Belt and Road Initiative.</p><p><strong>Dr Oriol Caudevilla is an honorary fellow at the Asian Institute of International Financial Law at the University of Hong Kong and a board director at the Global Impact FinTech Forum. The views do not necessarily reflect those of any of the organisations the author collaborates with</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba reduces stake in GoGoX amid Hong Kong logistics services firm’s mounting losses, as it faces cutthroat competition on the mainland</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247308/alibaba-reduces-stake-gogox-amid-hong-kong-logistics-services-firms-mounting-losses-it-faces</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Alibaba has reduced its stake in GoGoX, a Hong Kong-listed logistics company, amidst increasing competition and regulatory pressure in China's intracity delivery market. GoGoX has faced losses since 2018 due to stiff competition and international expansion. The company's market value has plunged by over 90% since its Hong Kong trading debut in 2022.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Alibaba cuts stake in GoGoX logistics amid market challenges.</li>    <li>Theme: Escalating competition, regulatory scrutiny, and financial struggles confront GoGoX's logistics operations.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Alibaba's stake reduction demonstrates the difficulties faced by logistics companies in China's competitive and regulated market.</li>    <li>Main information: Alibaba's stake reduction history; GoGoX's financial losses, market value decline, and international operations; market competition from rivals like Huolala, Didi Chuxing, and Full Truck Alliance; regulatory scrutiny of price subsidies and drivers' rights.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  阿里巴巴已减持香港上市物流公司GoGoX的股份，原因是中国同城配送市场竞争日益激烈、监管压力加大。自2018年以来，由于激烈的竞争和国际扩张，GoGoX一直面临亏损。自2022年在香港上市以来，该公司的市值已缩水超过90％。  <ul>    <li>摘要：市场挑战下阿里巴巴减持GoGoX物流公司股份。</li>    <li>主题：不断升级的竞争、监管审查和财务困境，共同面对GoGoX物流业务。</li>    <li>观点：阿里巴巴的减持表明在中国竞争激烈且受监管的市场中，物流公司面临的困难。</li>    <li>主要信息：阿里巴巴减持历史；GoGoX的财务亏损、市值下跌和国际业务；来自货拉拉、滴滴出行、满帮集团等对手的市场竞争；监管部门对价格补贴和司机权益的审查。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue - (n.) /ˈrev·əˌn(y)uː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：Citigroup Inc reported a 28% plunge in quarterly revenue on Wednesday, as a slump in dealmaking and trading revenue overshadowed a gain in wealth management. </p>    <p>例句讲解：revenue的基本意思是“收入”或“收益”，它来源于古法语单词revenu，意思是“收入”，这个词本身来源于拉丁语reditus，意思是“返回”或“归来”。在这个例句中，Citigroup Inc的收入在季度中下降了28%，这是因为并购和交易收入的下降掩盖了财富管理的增长。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>compete - (v.) /kəmˈpiːt/ 竞争，竞赛。    <p>原文例句：The company competes with several other ride-hailing services, including Uber, Lyft, and Didi Chuxing.</p>    <p>例句讲解：compete的基本意思是“竞争”或“竞赛”，来源于拉丁语compete，意思是“一起寻求”。在这个例句中，这家公司与其他几家叫车服务竞争，包括Uber、Lyft和滴滴出行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sector - (n.) /ˈsek·tər/ 部门，领域。    <p>原文例句：The company operates in the technology sector and has offices in several countries.</p>    <p>例句讲解：sector的基本意思是“部门”或“领域”，来源于拉丁语sector，意思是“切开”或“分开”。在这个例句中，这家公司在科技领域运营，并且在几个国家设有办事处。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>initiative - (n.) /ɪˈnɪʃ·əˌtiv/ 主动性，倡议。    <p>原文例句：The company launched a new initiative to reduce its carbon footprint.</p>    <p>例句讲解：initiative的基本意思是“主动性”或“倡议”，来源于拉丁语initiativus，意思是“初始的”或“开创性的”。在这个例句中，这家公司发起了一项新的倡议来减少其碳足迹。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>scrutiny - (n.) /ˈskruː·tə·ni/ 审查，仔细检查。    <p>原文例句：The company's financial statements are under scrutiny by the SEC.</p>    <p>例句讲解：scrutiny的基本意思是“审查”或“仔细检查”，来源于拉丁语scrutinium，意思是“调查”或“检查”。在这个例句中，这家公司的财务报表正在接受美国证券交易委员会的审查。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>subsidy - (n.) /ˈsəb·səˌdi/ 补贴，补助。    <p>原文例句：The government provides subsidies to farmers to help them cover the costs of production.</p>    <p>例句讲解：subsidy的基本意思是“补贴”或“补助”，来源于拉丁语subsidium，意思是“援助”或“支持”。在这个例句中，政府向农民提供补贴，帮助他们支付生产成本。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stake holder - (n.) 利益相关者。    <p>原文例句：Stakeholders, including investors and employees, are closely monitoring the company's financial situation. </p>    <p>例句讲解：利益相关者，包括投资者和员工，正在密切关注该公司的财务状况。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Citigroup Inc reported a 28% plunge in quarterly revenue on Wednesday, as a slump in dealmaking and trading revenue overshadowed a gain in wealth management. (季度收入暴跌28%，并购、交易收入低迷掩盖了财富管理的增长。)<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Citigroup Inc reported a 28% plunge in quarterly revenue on Wednesday，其中主语是Citigroup Inc，谓语是reported，宾语是a 28% plunge in quarterly revenue on Wednesday。as a slump in dealmaking and trading revenue overshadowed a gain in wealth management是一个从句，作原因状语，表示季度收入暴跌的原因是并购、交易收入低迷掩盖了财富管理的增长。这个句子的意思是说，花旗集团周三报告称，季度收入暴跌28%，因为并购和交易收入的下降掩盖了财富管理的增长。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示一种假设或不真实的情况。<p>原文例句：If we had known about the problem sooner, we could have fixed it. （如果我们早点知道这个问题，我们就能解决它了。）</p><p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气句，表示一种假设或不真实的情况。结构是：if + 过去完成时， could have + 过去分词。在这个例句中，if we had known about the problem sooner表示一种假设的情况，即如果我们早点知道这个问题，could have fixed it表示一种可能发生的情况，即我们就能解决它了。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 比较两个事物或多个事物之间的差异或相似性。<p>原文例句：The new product is better than the old one. （新产品比旧产品好。）</p><p>语法讲解：这是一个比较级句，表示两个事物或多个事物之间的差异或相似性。结构是：比较级 + than + 被比较的事物。在这个例句中，better than表示一种比较，即新产品比旧产品好。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Alibaba has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, leaving it with an 8.89 per cent equity holding as of December</li>
<li>GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/2c781207-f507-4907-bf84-a2425ae1e9fa_2a843a15.jpg" /><figcaption>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022. Image: GoGoX</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> has further reduced its stake in Hong Kong-listed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/transport-and-logistics" target="_self" title="">logistics</a> service provider <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/gogovan" target="_self" title="">GoGoX Holdings</a>, which is facing cutthroat competition and regulatory pressure in the mainland’s intracity delivery courier market.</p><p>Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, slashing its equity holding to 8.89 per cent as of late December from 12.23 per cent in mid-2023, according to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong-stock-market" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong stock exchange</a> records.</p><p>Following those moves, the biggest shareholder of GoGoX remains billionaire Yao Jinbo – the founder, chairman and chief executive of mainland Chinese online classifieds giant 58.com – with a 38.69 per cent share. GoGoX co-founder Chen Xiaohua, with a 5.95 per cent stake, retains his position as the company’s third-biggest shareholder.</p><p>Founded as GoGoVan in Hong Kong in 2013, GoGoX <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/china-tech/article/2108658/gogovan-become-hong-kongs-first-us1-billion-start-after-merger-58" target="_self" title="">became the city’s first unicorn in 2017</a> after its merger with short-distance freight service platform operator 58 Suyun. Still, GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/ab59b907-e9a0-49bd-b7d8-bd576851c04c_8a6158cb.jpg" title="GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX" width="2000" /><figcaption>GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX</figcaption></figure></div><p>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3182875/gogox-shares-rise-hkex-trading-debut-listing-hong-kongs" target="_self" title="">its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022</a>. Its share price closed up 6.8 per cent to HK$0.63 on Thursday.</p><p>The company – which expects to remain in the red this year, according to its 2022 prospectus – narrowed its losses to 642.9 million yuan (US$90.37 million) in the first half of 2023, from 1.05 billion yuan in the same period in 2022.</p><p>GoGoX also went through a major management reshuffle in December, as founder Chen resigned from his chairman role. The company tapped Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, another co-founder and the co-chief executive of GoGoX, as its new chairman.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hangzhou" target="_self" title="">Hangzhou</a>-based Alibaba’s partial divestment initiative at GoGoX comes amid its preparations for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3235860/alibabas-cainiao-files-us1-billion-ipo-helping-hong-kong-land-worlds-second-biggest-listing-2023" target="_self" title="">initial public offering (IPO) of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network</a>, which submitted its A1 filing to the Hong Kong stock exchange last September.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee" class="image-inline caption" height="1298" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/daae0416-e269-4485-a0b4-cb91724c76ec_051879a6.jpg" title="Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee" width="2000" /><figcaption>Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee</figcaption></figure></div><p>Alibaba is trying to stop the bleeding with its stake cut, as its initial goal with the GoGoX investment was to gain financial returns through the listing and create synergy with its own services, according to Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangdong-based consultancy iiMedia.</p><p>“This is still a market with huge demand and many opportunities even with the price wars, similar to those in the bike-sharing and ride-hailing sectors,” Zhang said. “So the bigger problem is more likely to lie within the operation of GoGoX, which will need revolutionary measures to reverse its losses.”</p><p>At present, GoGoX is competing in a crowded on-demand cargo delivery services market on the mainland, where its hometown rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246071/chinese-tech-ipos-watch-2024-global-fast-fashion-online-retailer-shein-leads-pack" target="_self" title="">Lalatech Holdings</a> operates Huolala. Competition has become more intense in recent years after traditional logistics firms and ride-hailing companies also set up similar app-based courier delivery operations.</p><p>Chinese ride-hailing giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/didi-chuxing" target="_self" title="">Didi Chuxing</a>, for example, started its own intracity freight service in 2020 and launched its autonomous trucking business Kargobot in April last year. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3137463/full-truck-chinas-uber-trucks-raise-us157-billion-us" target="_self" title="">Full Truck Alliance</a>, known as China’s “Uber for trucks” and focused on long-haul logistics services, in April launched its Sheng Sheng brand dedicated to same-city delivery.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240676/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-will-enhance-its-overseas-presence-proposed-buyout-local-rival-best" title="">Alibaba logistics spin-off Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout</a></h3><p>Huolala currently leads the mainland’s intracity courier delivery services market with a 61 per cent share, according to Frost &amp; Sullivan data cited in the prospectus of Lalatech, which is eyeing a Hong Kong IPO.</p><p>Similar to on-demand services like ride hailing, the early stage of competition in intracity freight services has relied heavily on subsidies for users.</p><p>That “cash-burning” business model, however, has faced increased scrutiny from regulators, who recently summoned Lalatech for talks regarding drivers’ rights and unfair price cuts.</p><p>GoGoX and other courier delivery services providers have also received “reminders” from regulators about their operations in the past year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Amid US tech war, Premier Li Qiang urges China to focus on application of core technologies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  李强总理本周访问湖北省期间，参观了一所大学以及半导体、激光和化工制造商。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 李强总理呼吁在与美国持续的技术战争中，加强学术界与企业界的合作。</li>    <li>Theme: 李强总理在为期两天的湖北省考察中，推动核心技术在中国的自力更生驱动下实现“更多、更好”的市场应用。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 在持续升级的技术冷战中，中国需要加强高校与企业合作，促进科研成果向市场转化的效率。</li>    <li>Main information: 李强总理访问了湖北省武汉市的华工激光工程有限公司和长江存储科技有限公司，强调了将科研成果转化为市场生产的必要性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  李强总理本周对湖北省进行了为期两天的访问，期间参观了一所大学以及半导体、激光和化工制造商。  <ul>    <li>摘要：李强总理呼吁在与美国持续的技术战争中，加强学术界与企业界的合作。</li>    <li>主题：李强总理在为期两天的湖北省考察中，推动核心技术在中国的自力更生驱动下实现“更多、更好”的市场应用。</li>    <li>观点：在持续升级的技术冷战中，中国需要加强高校与企业合作，促进科研成果向市场转化的效率。</li>    <li>主要信息：李强总理访问了湖北省武汉市的华工激光工程有限公司和长江存储科技有限公司，强调了将科研成果转化为市场生产的必要性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>collaboration (n.) - /kəˌlæbəˈreɪʃən/ 协作，合作。    <p>原文例句：Premier Li Qiang called for improved collaboration between academia and business. </p>    <p>例句讲解：collaboration的词根lab（被夺取）与词缀-oration（行为或方式）结合，表示“共同合作的行为或方式”。在这个例句中，它指的是李强总理呼吁加强学术界与企业界的合作。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>urgency (n.) - /ˈɜːdʒənsi/ 紧迫性，紧急性。    <p>原文例句：The world’s second-largest economy is in urgent need of stabilisation. </p>    <p>例句讲解：urgency由urgent（紧急的）和词缀-cy（状态）构成，表示“紧急状态”。在这个例句中，它指的是世界第二大经济体迫切需要稳定。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sustainability (n.) - /səˌsteɪnəˈbɪləti/ 可持续性，可持续发展。    <p>原文例句：Li also encouraged companies to promote China’s sustainability by focusing on the circular economy. </p>    <p>例句讲解：sustainability由sustain（维持，支持）和词缀-ability（能力）构成，表示“维持或支持某事物的能力”。在这个例句中，它指的是李强总理鼓励企业通过关注循环经济来促进中国的可持续发展。</p></li>  </ul>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>economic start - 经济启动。    <p>原文例句：“We must expedite the development of productivity driven by emerging technology, and kick-start a robust economic start of the year.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：economic start是一个由economic（经济的）和start（开始）组成的复合名词，表示“经济的启动”。在这个例句中，它指的是李强总理要求加快新兴技术驱动的生产力发展，并启动一个强劲的经济开局。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>He called for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States. - 他呼吁在与美国持续的技术战争中加强学术界与企业界的合作。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是He called for improved collaboration，其中主语是He，谓语是called for，宾语是improved collaboration。介词短语amid the ongoing tech war with the United States作状语，表示在与美国持续的技术战争中。improved collaboration between academia and business是一个由improved（改进的），collaboration（合作），between（介词，在……之间），academia（学术界）和business（企业界）组成的名词短语，作宾语。这个句子的意思是说，李强总理呼吁在与美国持续的技术战争中加强学术界与企业界的合作。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列连词 - 连接两个或多个词、短语或句子。    <p>原文例句：“We must expedite the development of productivity driven by emerging technology, and kick-start a robust economic start of the year."</p>    <p>语法讲解：并列连词是连接词或短语的词，如and、or、but等。在这个例句中，and连接了两个句子，表示“我们必须加快新兴技术驱动的生产力发展，并启动一个强劲的经济开局”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 表示对某个词、短语或句子进行强调。    <p>原文例句：“The world’s second-largest economy is in urgent need of stabilisation. "</p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句型通常使用be动词+形容词或副词+名词或代词的结构。在这个例句中，be动词是is，形容词是urgent，名词是need，表示“世界第二大经济体迫切需要稳定”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central province of Hubei this week</li>
<li>He called for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/3a8be64d-f864-409e-859c-0eef4d4f4ae3_9e966ee7.jpg" /><figcaption>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central Hubei province this week.</figcaption></figure><p>Premier Li Qiang pushed for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive during a two-day tour of Hubei province this week, with the world’s second-largest economy in urgent need of stabilisation to quell investor concerns and lift market confidence.</p><p>“We must expedite the development of productivity driven by emerging technology, and kick-start a robust economic start of the year,” he said in a statement following the tour of the central province on Tuesday and Wednesday, according to the official Xinhua News Agency.</p><p>Hubei is a key part of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3237870/xi-jinping-tells-chinas-biggest-economic-zone-balance-growth-and-security-and-no-more-mega-projects" target="_self" title="">Yangtze River Economic Belt,</a> which is one of President Xi Jinping’s key regional development strategies. It includes 11 provinces and municipalities, and accounts for over 40 per cent of China’s population and economic size.</p><p>“We need to improve collaboration between academia and business, by introducing more precise and supportive measures, thus fluidly turning scientific research into market production,” the premier said after visiting HGLaser Engineering and semiconductor manufacturer Yangtze Memory Technologies Corporation (YMTC) in the provincial capital of Wuhan.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245242/amid-us-tech-war-china-stuck-middle-technology-trap-it-time-open-its-doors-wider" title="">Time to open its doors wider, or will China fall into a middle-technology trap?</a></h3><p>Given the escalating <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245242/amid-us-tech-war-china-stuck-middle-technology-trap-it-time-open-its-doors-wider" target="_self" title="">containment efforts by the United States,</a> Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology.</p><p>Development was also mentioned as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3244856/chinas-development-biggest-political-priority-key-econ-meeting-leaders-vow-counter-risks-lift" target="_self" title="">China’s biggest priority</a> for 2024 at the tone-setting central economic work conference in mid-December.</p><p>HGLaser introduced China’s first fully domestically produced chip-cutting machine in July, according to the WeChat account of Donghu New Technology Development Zone in Wuhan.</p><p>But unlike China’s leading memory chip maker, YMTC, HGLaser has not been sanctioned by the US. YMTC was added to the US trade blacklist <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3203494/us-adds-36-chinese-companies-export-blacklist-including-countrys-top-flash-memory-chip-maker?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">in December 2022.</a></p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>During his two-day tour, Li also inspected Wuhan University’s laboratory on high-resolution Earth observation and the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3241788/chinas-gps-beidou-navigation-system-recognised-global-standard-commercial-aviation-important" target="_self" title="">BeiDou navigation system.</a></p><p>The home-grown BeiDou system, which is China’s equivalent to the US’ Global Positioning System (GPS), can be applied to agriculture, forestry and meteorology.</p><p>China, though, has long suffered from loose cooperation between academia, including universities and research institutes, and enterprises focused on market applications.</p><p>The cooperation issues include poor communication and insufficient resource sharing, which creates obstacles affecting the transformation of inventions in China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3241788/chinas-gps-beidou-navigation-system-recognised-global-standard-commercial-aviation-important" title="">‘Important milestone’: China’s GPS-like BeiDou navigation system hits new height</a></h3><p>As of the end of 2022, only 3.9 per cent of inventions at Chinese universities were industrialised, according to the latest data available by the China National Intellectual Property Administration, compared to around 50 per cent in the US.</p><p>Li also visited water conservancy projects and a chemical company focusing on green development in Yichang, as well as a battery industrial estate set up by Guangdong Brunp Recycling Technology, a subsidiary under China’s leading lithium battery maker, Contemporary Amperex Technology (CATL).</p><p>CATL is a supplier to several carmakers, including Tesla, BMW and Volkswagen.</p><p>The premier also encouraged companies to promote China’s sustainability by focusing on the circular economy to drive companies up the value chain.</p><p>The circular economy model seeks to minimise wasting resources and environmental impact by extending the life cycle of products.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>PDD halts development of local services offering to avoid head-on competition with Meituan and Ele.me, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247286/pdd-halts-development-local-services-offering-avoid-head-competition-meituan-and-eleme-report-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Pinduoduo (PDD) has halted its plans to launch local services offerings under its community group-buying unit, avoiding direct competition with tech giants Meituan, Alibaba, and ByteDance in the 35 trillion yuan market by 2025. PDD had invested in developing the service, including signing up physical stores and hiring a dedicated team, but faced challenges with the profitability of its Duoduo Maicai business, which is a leader in community group-buying but suffers from low gross margins.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: PDD abandons local services plans to avoid competition in China's 35 trillion yuan industry.</li>    <li>Theme: The intense competition among Chinese tech companies for dominance in the local services sector.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: PDD's strategic decision to focus on overseas expansion with its Temu app, citing profitability issues as a factor in halting the local services venture.</li>    <li>Main information: PDD's initial plans for the local services offering, its efforts to establish the service, the challenges faced with Duoduo Maicai's profitability, and the dominant position of rivals like Meituan and Alibaba.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  拼多多已暂停其在社区团购部门多多买菜下推出本地生活服务产品的计划，避免与美团、阿里巴巴、字节跳动等科技巨头在 2025 年市场规模预计达 35 万亿元人民币的市场中正面竞争。拼多多曾投入资源开发该服务，包括签约实体门店和组建专门团队，但其多多买菜业务在盈利方面面临挑战，该业务是社区团购的领导者，但毛利率较低。  <ul>    <li>摘要：拼多多放弃本地生活服务计划，以避免在中国 35 万亿行业竞争。</li>    <li>主题：中国科技公司为争夺本地生活服务领域的主导地位而进行的激烈竞争。</li>    <li>观点：拼多多出于盈利问题因素而决定专注于海外扩张其 Temu 应用，以此作为暂停本地生活服务业务的原因。</li>    <li>主要信息：拼多多最初的本地生活服务产品计划、其为建立该服务所做的努力、多多买菜的盈利面临的挑战，以及美团和阿里巴巴等竞争对手的主导地位。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rivalry (n.) - /ˈraɪvəlri/ 竞争，敌对。    <p>原文例句：Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025. - 美团、阿里巴巴和 TikTok 所有者字节跳动一直在争夺 2025 年预计价值 35 万亿元人民币的本地服务市场的主导地位。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词指的是两个或多个个人或群体之间为了争夺权力、地位、资源或利益而进行的竞争。在这个例句中，它指的是美团、阿里巴巴和字节跳动等公司为了争夺本地服务市场的份额而进行的竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>dominance (n.) - /ˈdɑːmɪnəns/ 优势，主导。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba has been seeking to catch up with the merger of its Koubei restaurant rating service and navigation app Amap. - 阿里巴巴一直在努力赶上其口碑餐厅评级服务和导航应用高德地图的合并。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词指的是在某个领域或方面占据优势或主导地位。在这个例句中，它指的是阿里巴巴一直努力赶上口碑餐厅评级服务和导航应用高德地图的合并，以在本地服务市场获得优势或主导地位。</p></li>   </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>community group-buying - 社区团购。    <P>原文例句：PDD had planned to launch the service – which facilitates in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets – in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, LatePost reported. - LatePost 报道称，PDD 计划于 2024 年 2 月在其社区团购部门多多买菜下推出该服务，这项服务将便于进行酒店预订和电影票等店内订单。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组指的是一群人组织起来，以更优惠的价格从当地供应商那里购买商品和服务。在这个例句中，它指的是拼多多计划在其社区团购部门多多买菜下推出该服务，该服务将便于进行酒店预订和电影票等店内订单。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>PDD, whose market cap overtook Alibaba in November after the firm beat revenue estimates, had planned to launch the service – which facilitates in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets – in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, - 拼多多于 11 月超过阿里巴巴的市值后，计划于 2024 年 2 月在其社区团购部门多多买菜下推出这项服务，该服务便于进行包括酒店预订和电影票在内的店内订单。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复杂的句子，包含一个主句和一个定语从句。主句是PDD had planned to launch the service，其中主语是PDD，谓语是had planned to launch，宾语是the service。定语从句是which facilitates in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets，其中关系代词which指代the service，谓语是facilitates，宾语是in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets。这个句子的意思是，拼多多计划于 2024 年 2 月在其社区团购部门多多买菜下推出这项服务，该服务便于进行包括酒店预订和电影票在内的店内订单。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：PDD had planned to launch the service – which facilitates in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets – in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, - 拼多多计划于 2024 年 2 月在其社区团购部门多多买菜下推出这项服务，该服务便于进行包括酒店预订和电影票在内的店内订单。</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。它的结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。在这个例句中，have been + planned表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在（即2024年2月）的计划。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去的某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：PDD, whose market cap overtook Alibaba in November after the firm beat revenue estimates, - 拼多多于 11 月超过阿里巴巴的市值后。</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去完成时态表示在过去的某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。它的结构是：had + been + 过去分词。在这个例句中，had + overtaken表示拼多多在11月之前已经超过了阿里巴巴的市值。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>PDD had planned to launch local services offering in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, report says</li>
<li>Chinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in local services market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/416b82eb-4e16-46af-8cd9-c30d0a415c2f_5ba32be4.jpg" /><figcaption>Chinese Big Tech firms have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025. Photo: AFP </figcaption></figure><p>E-commerce giant PDD Holdings has halted work on its local life services offering, avoiding head-to-head rivalry with Meituan, Alibaba Group Holding and ByteDance, whose Douyin short video app has also dipped a toe into the sector.</p><p>PDD has “completely halted [development of] the local services business”, according to Chinese media outlet LatePost. PDD did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p>PDD, whose market cap overtook Alibaba in November after the firm beat revenue estimates, had planned to launch the service – which facilitates in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets – in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, LatePost reported. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>PDD had leveraged Duoduo Maicai’s business development team of around 3,000 people to sign up bricks-and-mortar outlets, such as restaurants and tourist attractions, the report said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244976/amazon-doubles-down-china-e-commerce-strategy-rivals-shein-temu-gain-traction" title="">Amazon doubles down on China e-commerce strategy as Shein, Temu gain traction</a></h3><p>However, PDD’s management has not been completely satisfied with the performance of Duoduo Maicai, which was established in 2020 in the midst of the Covid-19 pandemic. It enables residents in a community to purchase groceries and other daily essentials in bulk, bringing prices down.</p><p>Although the unit has become an industry leader, it is not profitable due to low gross margins, according to the LatePost report, which cited a PDD executive. Duoduo Maicai is nevertheless expected to remain operational despite the halting of local life services, according to Chinese news portal Sina.</p><p>Chinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan (US$4.9 trillion) by 2025, according to estimates by market intelligence firm iResearch.</p><p>Meituan, which merged with restaurant review site Dianping and bike-sharing start-up Mobike, currently leads the sector with a range of food delivery, taxi-ride and hotel reservation services.</p><p>Alibaba has been seeking to catch up with the merger of its Koubei restaurant rating service and navigation app Amap. Alibaba’s local services segment also runs food delivery unit <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3048045/chinas-eleme-deliver-food-100-restaurants-frontline-medical-staff?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Ele.me</a>, grocery delivery service Taoxianda, and online travel platform Fliggy.</p><p>ByteDance’s Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has leveraged its more than 600 million daily active users to make <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3207434/bytedance-primes-short-video-app-douyin-challenge-meituan-demand-local-services-amid-chinas-push?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">aggressive moves in segments of on-demand e-commerce</a>. The company set up a centre dedicated to developing local services in 2020.</p><p>Abandoning the local services market comes as PDD continues to expand aggressively overseas with its Temu app, now available in the United States, Japan and several other markets. The budget shopping platform helped drive an almost doubling of PDD’s third-quarter revenue to 68.8 billion yuan.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Microsoft to show off Copilot AI key for Windows keyboards at CES, in first change to layout since 1994</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247280/microsoft-show-copilot-ai-key-windows-keyboards-ces-first-change-layout-1994</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Microsoft is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to quickly access its AI assistant. This new key is a symbol of the company's commitment to integrating AI into its products. Microsoft aims to make AI an integral part of Windows, from the operating system to the hardware. The Copilot key will enable users to generate images, write emails, and summarize text with the help of AI. The company sees 2024 as "the year of the AI PC" and has been retooling its products to incorporate AI technology.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Microsoft unveils Copilot key on Windows keyboards for easy access to AI assistance.</li>    <li>Theme: Microsoft's dedication to integrating AI into Windows and its products.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: AI's role in shaping the future of computing and productivity.</li>    <li>Main information: Introduction of the Copilot key; Microsoft's vision of "the year of the AI PC"; expansion of AI capabilities across various software and services.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  微软正在 Windows 键盘上增加一个协作者功能键，以便用户快速访问其人工智能助手。这个新按键是公司致力于将人工智能集成到其产品中的标志。微软的目标是使人工智能成为 Windows 不可或缺的一部分，从操作系统到硬件。协作者功能键将使用户能够借助人工智能生成图像、编写电子邮件和总结文本。该公司认为 2024 年是“人工智能电脑年”，并且一直在对其产品进行改造以纳入人工智能技术。    <ul>    <li>摘要：微软在 Windows 键盘上推出协作者功能键，以便轻松访问人工智能助手。</li>    <li>主题：微软致力于将人工智能集成到 Windows 及其产品中。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能在塑造计算和生产力的未来中的作用。</li>    <li>主要信息：引入协作者功能键；微软对“人工智能电脑年”的愿景；在各种软件和服务中扩展人工智能功能。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li> Copilot (n.) - /ˈkəʊpaɪlət/ 副驾驶员，协作者。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft said it is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to allow users to immediately call up its artificial intelligence assistant. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由co-（共同，一起）和pilot（飞行员，驾驶员）构成，表示“共同驾驶，合作驾驶，协作者”。在这个例句中，它指的是微软在Windows键盘上添加的Copilot键，该键可以允许用户立即调用其人工智能助手。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>seamlessly (adv.) - /ˈsiːmləsli/ 无缝地，毫无间断地。    <p>原文例句：“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由seamless（无缝的，毫无间断的）和-ly（构成副词的后缀）构成，表示“无缝地，毫无间断地”。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能将无缝地融入到Windows系统、芯片和硬件中。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>call up - 呼叫，召集。    <P>原文例句：Microsoft said it is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to allow users to immediately call up its artificial intelligence assistant. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由call（呼叫）和up（向上，起来）构成的，表示“呼叫，召集”。在这个例句中，它表示微软在Windows键盘上添加了Copilot键，允许用户立即调用其人工智能助手。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves, but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets. - 这些标签本身并没有太大意义，但微软在过去一年中致力于改造其最大的产品，使其围绕能够从大量数据集中生成新内容的人工智能技术展开。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products，其中主语是Microsoft，谓语是has spent，宾语是the past year retooling its biggest products。Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves是一个让步状语从句，表示那些标签本身并没有太大意义。but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets是一个转折状语从句，表示但微软在过去一年中致力于改造其最大的产品，使其围绕能够从大量数据集中生成新内容的人工智能技术展开。这个句子的意思是说，那些标签本身并没有太大意义，但微软在过去一年中致力于改造其最大的产品，使其围绕能够从大量数据集中生成新内容的人工智能技术展开。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则变化形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示微软从过去的这几年开始一直致力于改造其最大的产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>定语从句 - 定语从句是在复合句中修饰先行词的名词或代词的句子。    <p>原文例句：That includes a plant that will make mechanical enclosures for iPhones and a semiconductor equipment manufacturing plant it will operate with Applied Materials, the government said at the time. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个定语从句，修饰先行词a plant。定语从句的结构是：that + 主语 + 谓语，其中主语和谓语要根据先行词的时态和语态进行变化。在这个例句中，先行词a plant是单数，所以主语will make mechanical enclosures for iPhones and a semiconductor equipment manufacturing plant是单数，谓语will operate是将来时。这个定语从句的意思是说：该工厂将生产iPhone的机械外壳，并与Applied Materials公司合作运营一家半导体设备制造厂。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Start key</li>
<li>The tech giant sees 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’ and has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/e31b152f-c194-4f64-8148-b14c9b1dd6e5_1adc5e70.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft said it is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to allow users to immediately call up its artificial intelligence assistant. Photo: YouTube / Windows</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft</a> is adding a button to the Windows keyboard to activate its AI Copilot service, with the first devices to sport the new key available this month.</p><p>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Windows/Start key in 1994, underscoring the company’s commitment to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a>. Microsoft’s hardware partners will show off Windows 11 computers with the Copilot button over the coming days at the CES technology conference and, over time, it will become a required feature.</p><p>The short cut will help users create images, write emails and summarise text with the help of AI.</p><p>“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234530/microsoft-sees-booming-enterprise-ai-demand-hong-kong-amid-us-china-tech-war-threatens-cloud" title="">Microsoft touts booming enterprise AI demand in Hong Kong amid cloud push</a></h3><p>The Redmond, Washington-based company sees 2024 as “the year of the AI PC”, according to Mehdi, mirroring the budding trend among smartphone makers to tout their latest models as “AI phones”. Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves, but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets. That list now includes Windows, Office, Bing search, security software and customer and finance products. The work heavily leverages the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">GPT-4 technology</a> from OpenAI, in which Microsoft has invested US$13 billion.</p><p>For device makers, Microsoft’s push into AI services has not yet translated into a boost for sales, as the novel Copilot features are being rolled out to new and existing devices alike. Mehdi’s promise of weaving AI into hardware and silicon may signal more pressure on consumers to upgrade as Microsoft evolves and improves its AI proposition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
