<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Nokia set to exit telecommunications joint venture with Huawei amid US-China tensions</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249181/nokia-set-exit-telecommunications-joint-venture-huawei-amid-us-china-tensions</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nokia sells its majority share in TD Tech, a joint venture with Huawei, to a group including state-owned entities in China.</li>    <li>The sale follows a failed attempt to sell the stake to a different buyer last year, which was opposed by Huawei.</li>    <li>Huawei has been the de facto controller of TD Tech, which has been selling rebranded Huawei phones since 2021.</li>    <li>The deal is subject to government approval and public feedback until January 28.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>诺基亚将与华为合资的TD Tech的大部分股份出售给一个包括国有实体在内的集团，等待政府最终批准。</li>    <li>此前，该公司去年试图将股份出售给另一家买家，但遭到华为的反对，导致交易失败。</li>    <li>华为一直是TD Tech的实际控制者，自2021年以来一直销售重新贴牌的华为手机。</li>    <li>该交易需要政府批准，并征求公众意见，截至1月28日。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>de facto (adv.) - /ˌdiː ˈfæktəʊ/ 事实上。    <p>原文例句：Huawei has long been considered the de facto controller of TD Tech, which has been selling rebranded phones from the Chinese giant since 2021.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“de facto”是拉丁语短语“de facto”的缩写，意思是“事实上”或“实际上”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为一直被认为是TD Tech的实际控制者，尽管它不是TD Tech的多数股东。</p></li>    <li>rebrand (v.) - /riːˈbrænd/ 重新命名或改变品牌形象。    <p>原文例句：TD Tech in 2021 started selling what amounted to rebranded Huawei phones under its own brand.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“rebrand”是一个动词，意思是“重新命名或改变品牌形象”。在这个例句中，它指的是TD Tech从2021年开始销售重新命名或改变品牌形象的华为手机，使用自己的品牌。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sanction (n.) - /ˈsæŋkʃən/ 制裁，处罚。</li>    <p>原文例句：Sanctions imposed by Washington currently bar companies from selling to Huawei advanced chips made with US-origin technology, which includes MediaTek processors made by Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co, the world’s largest contract chip maker.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“sanction”是一个名词，意思是“制裁，处罚”。在这个例句中，它指的是华盛顿实施的制裁，禁止公司向华为出售使用美国技术制造的高端芯片，其中包括由世界最大的芯片代工制造商台积电制造的联发科处理器。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>home-grown (adj.) - /həʊm ˈgrəʊn/ 本土的，国产的。</li>    <p>原文例句：Despite the US restrictions, Huawei last year launched its Mate 60 Pro, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G processor.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“home-grown”是一个形容词，意思是“本土的，国产的”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为去年推出的Mate 60 Pro手机，配备了先进的国产5G处理器。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>public feedback - 公众意见反馈。</li>    <p>原文例句：Regulators said they had no antitrust concerns on the deal and would solicit public feedback until January 28.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“public feedback”是一个词组，意思是“公众意见反馈”。在这个例句中，它指的是监管机构表示他们对这笔交易没有反垄断担忧，并将征求公众意见，截至1月28日。</p></li>    <li>market intelligence firm - 市场情报公司。</li>    <p>原文例句：Data from market intelligence firm Counterpoint Research showed.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“market intelligence firm”是一个词组，意思是“市场情报公司”。在这个例句中，它指的是市场情报公司Counterpoint Research的数据显示。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>US-origin technology - 美国原产技术。</li>    <p>原文例句：Sanctions imposed by Washington currently bar companies from selling to Huawei advanced chips made with US-origin technology, which includes MediaTek processors made by Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co, the world’s largest contract chip maker.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“US-origin technology”是一个词组，意思是“美国原产技术”。在这个例句中，它指的是华盛顿实施的制裁，禁止公司向华为出售使用美国原产技术制造的高端芯片，其中包括由世界最大的芯片代工制造商台积电制造的联发科处理器。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>When Nokia last year tried to sell its majority stake to Shanghai-listed ink maker New East New Materials, Huawei threatened to stop licensing technology to TD Tech.    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huawei threatened to stop licensing technology to TD Tech，其中主语是Huawei，谓语是threatened to stop，宾语是licensing technology to TD Tech。When Nokia last year tried to sell its majority stake to Shanghai-listed ink maker New East New Materials是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示当诺基亚去年试图将其多数股权出售给上海上市的墨水制造商New East New Materials时。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去时态 - 表示过去发生的事件或状态。</li>    <p>原文例句：Huawei had a 14 per cent share in the Chinese smartphone market in the third quarter last year, putting it in fifth place behind its spin-off Honor and rivals Oppo, Vivo and Apple, data from market intelligence firm Counterpoint Research showed.</p>    <p>语法讲解：“had”是过去时态的助动词，“put”是过去分词。过去时态是用来描述过去发生的事情或情况。它通常使用助动词“had”或“was”加上过去分词。在这个例句中，“had”表示华为在去年第三季度的中国智能手机市场份额是14%，使其排名第五，落后于其分拆出来的荣耀以及竞争对手OPPO、vivo和苹果。</p></li>    <li>被动语态 - 表示主语是被动接受动作或状态的。</li>    <p>原文例句：TD Tech, founded in 2005, had been a joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens until 2007, when Siemens sold half of its stake to Nokia. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，“had been”是过去完成时的助动词，“sold”是过去分词。被动语态是指主语是被动接受动作或状态的。它通常使用助动词“be”加上过去分词。在这个例句中，“had been”表示TD Tech从2005年成立到2007年一直是华为和德国科技集团西门子的合资企业，直到西门子将其一半的股份出售给诺基亚。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Finnish company will sell its majority stake in TD Tech to a group that includes state-owned entities, pending final government approval</li>
<li>Huawei has long been considered the de facto controller of TD Tech, which has been selling rebranded phones from the Chinese giant since 2021</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/96782c3a-8a2e-4d29-8e59-79d66ccfe5a6_def6fa44.jpg" /><figcaption>The Nokia headquarters in Espoo, Finland. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Finnish telecoms equipment giant Nokia has found new buyers for its majority stake in a Beijing-based joint venture with Huawei Technologies, after a proposed deal fell through last year following strong protest by the Chinese partner.</p><p>Under the latest agreement, wireless technology firm TD Tech will be jointly controlled by Huawei and a group of entities that include the government-owned Chengdu High-Tech Investment Group and Chengdu Gaoxin Jicui Technology Co, as well as venture capital firm Huagai, according to a disclosure published on Friday by the State Administration for Market Regulation (SAMR).</p><p>The document did not reveal how much equity each of the new participants will hold. Before the sale, Nokia owned 51 per cent of TD Tech, while Huawei held 49 per cent.</p><p>Regulators said they had no antitrust concerns on the deal and would solicit public feedback until January 28. Huawei and TD Tech together control no more than 10 per cent of China’s smartphone market, according to the SAMR, which did not specify the time frame for that data.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/36a09b3c-7803-48e6-a443-6a2cec7d849d_34f54c2a.jpg" title="An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Huawei had a 14 per cent share in the Chinese smartphone market in the third quarter last year, putting it in fifth place behind its spin-off Honor and rivals Oppo, Vivo and Apple, data from market intelligence firm Counterpoint Research showed.</p><p>TD Tech, founded in 2005, had been a joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens until 2007, when Siemens sold half of its stake to Nokia. In 2013, Siemens divested all its shares, making Nokia the major shareholder.</p><p>Known for its wireless communications equipment, including 4G and 5G networking gear, TD Tech has a presence in more than 100 countries serving 8 million industry customers, according to its website.</p><p>While Nokia had been the majority owner of the joint venture, Huawei has been the de facto controller, according to industry observers.</p><p>“The management are former Huawei employees, with product solutions based on Huawei products but fine-tuned for the industry market,” Yang Guang, an analyst covering the telecoms sector at research firm Omdia, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3216677/huawei-opposition-nokia-sale-joint-venture-threatens-finnish-firms-exit-us-china-tensions-weigh-deal" target="_self" title="">said last year</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3216677/huawei-opposition-nokia-sale-joint-venture-threatens-finnish-firms-exit-us-china-tensions-weigh-deal" title="">Huawei opposition to Nokia sale of joint venture threatens Finnish firm’s exit</a></h3><p>When Nokia last year tried to sell its majority stake to Shanghai-listed ink maker New East New Materials, Huawei threatened to stop licensing technology to TD Tech. That deal ultimately collapsed.</p><p>Huawei likely did not want to lose control of TD Tech, which could help the Chinese tech giant circumvent some US sanctions and help it address certain market segments more efficiently, Yang said at the time.</p><p>TD Tech in 2021 started selling what amounted to rebranded Huawei phones under its own brand. They included the M40 5G, which used a 7-nanometre chip from Taiwan-based MediaTek instead of Huawei’s own Kirin processors.</p><p>Sanctions imposed by Washington currently bar companies from selling to Huawei advanced chips made with US-origin technology, which includes MediaTek processors made by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a>, the world’s largest contract chip maker.</p><p>Despite the US restrictions, Huawei last year launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233636/huaweis-mate-60-pro-will-help-it-take-lost-ground-china-can-it-help-smartphone-giant-regain-global" target="_self" title="">its Mate 60 Pro</a>, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G processor.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China convenes Huawei, Tencent, Baidu to draft metaverse standards in bid to become global technology leader</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3249180/china-convenes-huawei-tencent-baidu-draft-metaverse-standards-bid-become-global-technology-leader</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  China has established a working group of 60 experts, including those from the private sector, government, and academia, to develop standards for the metaverse industry. This group aims to promote the healthy and orderly development of the metaverse sector by building, maintaining, and promoting metaverse industry standards, encouraging local companies to participate in international standard-setting activities, and training talent.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China forms a working group to establish metaverse standards, signaling its ambition to lead in this emerging field.</li>    <li>Theme: Collaboration among industry, government, and academia in China to develop metaverse standards.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of establishing standards for the ethical and secure development of the metaverse industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Composition of the working group, its objectives, and the government's support for the metaverse sector.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国成立了一个由60位专家组成的专家组，其中包括来自私营部门、政府和学术界的专家，负责制定元宇宙行业的标准。此专家组旨在通过制定、维护和推广元宇宙行业标准，鼓励本地公司参与国际标准制定活动，培训人才，来促进元宇宙产业的健康有序发展。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国成立专家组制定元宇宙标准，彰显出其在该新兴领域中抢占领导地位的雄心。</li>    <li>主题：中国产界、政界和学界合作，制定元宇宙标准。</li>    <li>观点：制定标准对于元宇宙产业的伦理和安全发展至关重要。</li>    <li>主要信息：专家组组成、目标、政府对元宇宙行业的扶持。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>metaverse (n.) - /ˈmetəvɜːs/ 元宇宙，元界。    <p>原文例句：China has formed a working group to establish metaverse standards.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由meta（超越）和verse（宇宙）组成，指一个虚拟的三维世界，人们可以在其中进行各种活动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>standard (n.) - /ˈstændərd/ 标准，规范。    <p>原文例句：The group is tasked with building, maintaining and promoting metaverse industry standards.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是指一种参考模式或规范，通常被广泛接受和使用。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>play a role in - 起作用，发挥作用。    <P>原文例句：The Metaverse Standards Forum could play a role in strengthening global cooperation on metaverse standards. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由play（扮演，表演），a（一个），role（角色，作用）和in（在……里面）组成，表示“在……中起作用”。在这个例句中，它表示元宇宙标准论坛可以在加强全球元宇宙标准合作方面发挥作用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>take the lead in - 带头，领头。    <P>原文例句：China is also taking the lead in international cooperation on metaverse standards. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由take（拿，取），the（定冠词），lead（铅，领导）和in（在……里面）组成，表示“在……中带头，领头”。在这个例句中，它表示中国也在元宇宙标准的国际合作中发挥着领导作用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The MIIT in September proposed to form a working group to “guide the healthy and orderly development of the metaverse industry through standard regulation”, cautioning that the sector was facing ethical and security challenges. - 工信部在9月提议成立一个工作组，“通过标准规范引导元宇宙产业健康有序发展”，并提醒该行业正面临着伦理和安全挑战。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，包含一个主句和两个从句。主句是“工信部在9月提议成立一个工作组”，其中主语是“工信部”，谓语是“提议成立一个工作组”。“通过标准规范引导元宇宙产业健康有序发展”是一个目的状语从句，修饰“成立一个工作组”，表示成立工作组的目的或意图。“并提醒该行业正面临着伦理和安全挑战”是一个并列状语从句，修饰“提议成立一个工作组”，表示成立工作组时需要考虑的事情。这个句子的意思是说，工信部在9月提议成立一个工作组，以便通过标准规范引导元宇宙产业健康有序发展，同时提醒该行业正面临着伦理和安全挑战。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The group would be tasked with “building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards”, “promoting the standards” and “training talent”, the regulator said in its proposal. -该规范规定，该小组的任务是“建立和维护元宇宙行业标准体系”、“推广标准”和“培训人才”。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，包含一个主句和三个同位语从句。主句是“该小组的任务是”，其中主语是“该小组”，谓语是“是”。“建立和维护元宇宙行业标准体系”是一个同位语从句，修饰“任务”，表示任务的内容之一。“推广标准”是一个同位语从句，修饰“任务”，表示任务的内容之一。“培训人才”是一个同位语从句，修饰“任务”，表示任务的内容之一。这个句子的意思是说，该小组的任务是建立和维护元宇宙行业标准体系，推广标准，培训人才。</p></li>      </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态的承受者。    <p>原文例句：The group was tasked with building, maintaining and promoting metaverse industry standards.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态的结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则变化形式。被动语态通常用于强调动作或状态的承受者，或者当动作的执行者不重要或未知时。在这个例句中，be用的是was，表示过去时态，过去分词是tasked，表示该小组被赋予了建立、维护和推广元宇宙行业标准的任务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>不定式 - 表示一种动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The group would be tasked with “building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards”, “promoting the standards” and “training talent”, the regulator said in its proposal.</p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式的结构是：to + 动词原形。不定式可以表示一种动作或状态，也可以表示目的、结果、原因等。在这个例句中，不定式是“building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards”, “promoting the standards”和“training talent”，分别表示建立和维护元宇宙行业标准体系、推广标准和培训人才。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The working group consists of 60 experts, including those from the private sector as well as government officials and academic researchers</li>
<li>The group is tasked with building, maintaining and promoting metaverse industry standards, China’s technology regulator says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/56f4a36f-d5d5-434d-8326-ac2adaa5400e_7b70980f.jpg" /><figcaption>China has formed a working group to establish metaverse standards. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) has assembled 60 experts, including some from the country’s largest technology firms, to form a new working group to establish standards for the metaverse sector.</p><p>Representatives from telecoms equipment giant Huawei Technologies, video gaming titans Tencent Holdings and NetEase, web search and artificial intelligence champion Baidu, financial technology firm Ant Group and computer maker Lenovo Group are among those on the list published by the MIIT on Friday.</p><p>Ant is an affiliate of Alibaba Group Holding, owner of the Post.</p><p>Other members include MIIT officials and researchers from Peking University, Fudan University and other renowned institutions in the country.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>The MIIT in September proposed to form a working group to “guide the healthy and orderly development of the metaverse industry through standard regulation”, cautioning that the sector was facing ethical and security challenges.</p><p>The group would be tasked with “building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards”, “promoting the standards” and “training talent”, the regulator said in its proposal.</p><p>Besides focusing on domestic standards, the group would also “encourage local companies and institutions to deeply engage in international standard-setting activities”.</p><p>The metaverse, a loosely-defined term that refers to a virtual three-dimensional world, has become a trending topic in the past few years.</p><p>US social media giant Facebook changed its name to Meta Platforms in 2021. CEO and founder Mark Zuckerberg explained during the rebranding announcement that he sought to embrace “the next chapter for the internet”.</p><p>In 2022, Meta, Microsoft and others founded the Metaverse Standards Forum, which also comprises Huawei, Tencent and some other Chinese tech giants.</p><p>Beijing is hoping to become a leader in the emerging field. Five authorities, including the MIIT, released a joint plan last year to nurture at least <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3233933/china-wants-metaverse-firms-global-influence-and-plans-five-industrial-clusters-2025" target="_self" title="">three metaverse companies “with global influence”</a> by 2025.</p><p>Several local governments have made it a priority to develop the metaverse sector.</p><p>Beijing’s eastern Tongzhou district, considered a “sub-centre” of the capital city, has vowed to incorporate more than 100 metaverse-related firms by the end of the year.</p><p>Shanghai has planned to set up both government-backed and private funds dedicated to metaverse development. The first one, established in late 2022, raised an initial sum of 1 billion yuan (US$140 million).</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
