<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>ChatGPT boosted user numbers and time spent on Microsoft’s Bing, but fails to dent Google’s search dominance</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249012/chatgpt-boosted-user-numbers-and-time-spent-microsofts-bing-fails-dent-googles-search-dominance</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Microsoft Bing's market share has increased slightly since integrating ChatGPT, but it remains a small player compared to Google.</li>    <li>Microsoft believes generative AI will revolutionize search and is adding more AI tools to Bing, such as DALL-E 3.</li>    <li>Google has been developing its own AI tools and plans to integrate them into its search engine this year.</li>    <li>Experts believe generative AI will change how people search for information online, but Microsoft needs a flywheel effect to challenge Google's dominance.</li>    <li>Microsoft is also betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their spending, offering better outcomes and deeper insights.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>微软必应自集成ChatGPT以来，市场份额略有上升，但与谷歌相比仍是小玩家。</li>    <li>微软认为生成式人工智能将彻底改变搜索，并正在向必应添加更多人工智能工具，例如 DALL-E 3。</li>    <li>谷歌一直在开发其内部的人工智能工具，并计划在今年将其集成到其搜索引擎中。</li>    <li>专家认为，生成式人工智能将改变人们在线搜索信息的方式，但微软需要飞轮效应来挑战谷歌的统治地位。</li>    <li>微软还押注生成式人工智能将改变广告商分配其支出的方式，提供更好的结果和更深入的见解。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>market share - 市场份额。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft’s search engine ended 2023 with just 3.4 per cent of the global search market, according to data analytics firm StatCounter. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由market（市场）和share（份额）组成，表示“市场份额”。在这个例句中，它表示微软的搜索引擎在2023年底的全球搜索市场份额仅为3.4%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>generative AI - 生成式人工智能。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft is betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由generative（生成）和AI（人工智能）组成，表示“生成式人工智能”。在这个例句中，它表示微软认为生成式人工智能将改变广告商如何分配他们的搜索支出。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>flywheel effect - 飞轮效应。    <p>原文例句：“We are at the gold rush moment when it comes to AI and search,” said Shane Greenstein, an economist and professor at Harvard Business School, who has studied the commercialisation of the internet. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由flywheel（飞轮）和effect（效应）组成，表示“飞轮效应”。在这个例句中，它表示Shane Greenstein认为，人工智能和搜索现在正处于淘金时刻。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>upend the market - 颠覆市场。    <p>原文例句：When Microsoft announced it was baking ChatGPT into its Bing search engine last February, bullish analysts declared the move an “iPhone moment” that could upend the search market and chip away at Google’s dominance. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由upend（颠覆）和market（市场）组成，表示“颠覆市场”。在这个例句中，它表示微软宣布将ChatGPT集成到其必应搜索引擎中，这被一些乐观分析师称为“iPhone时刻”，可能颠覆搜索市场并削弱谷歌的统治地位。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sea change - 沧海桑田，巨变。    <p>原文例句：“The entire search category is now going through a sea change,” chief executive officer Satya Nadella said at the time. “That opportunity comes very few times.” </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由sea（海洋）和change（变化）组成，表示“沧海桑田，巨变”。在这个例句中，它表示整个搜索领域正在发生根本性的变化，这种机会非常难得。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Microsoft is betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending. - 微软认为生成式人工智能将改变广告商如何分配他们的搜索支出。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Microsoft is betting，其中主语是Microsoft，谓语是is betting，宾语是that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending。that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending是一个宾语从句，其中主语是generative AI，谓语是will change，宾语是how advertisers allocate their search spending。这个句子的意思是说，微软认为生成式人工智能将改变广告商如何分配他们的搜索支出。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Google has been developing its own AI tools and plans to integrate them into its search engine this year. - 谷歌一直在开发自己的内部人工智能工具，并计划在今年将其集成到搜索引擎中。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Google，谓语是has been developing，宾语是its own AI tools。and plans to integrate them into its search engine this year是一个并列连词，连接了两个句子，表示谷歌计划在今年将这些内部人工智能工具集成到其搜索引擎中。这个句子的意思是说，谷歌一直在开发自己的内部人工智能工具，并计划在今年将其集成到搜索引擎中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作定语 - 表示对名词或代词的修饰和限定。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，现在分词短语on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman作定语，修饰名词Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella，表示微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉与OpenAI首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼一起在舞台上。这个语法结构可以用来对名词或代词进行详细描述和限定。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作状语 - 表示对动词或形容词的修饰和补充。    <p>原文例句：But Microsoft’s search engine ended 2023 with just 3.4 per cent of the global search market, according to data analytics firm StatCounter, up less than 1 percentage point since the ChatGPT announcement. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，过去分词短语up less than 1 percentage point since the ChatGPT announcement作状语，修饰谓语动词ended，表示自ChatGPT发布以来，微软的搜索引擎的全球搜索市场份额仅增加了不到1个百分点。这个语法结构可以用来对动词或形容词进行详细描述和补充。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The market share of Microsoft’s search engine rose less than 1 percentage point since the ChatGPT announcement</li>
<li>Microsoft is betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/f958a4b4-35bc-43ff-923e-d785b6e45d9d_84591264.jpg" /><figcaption>The Microsoft Bing app. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>When Microsoft announced it was baking ChatGPT into its Bing search engine last February, bullish analysts declared the move an “iPhone moment” that could upend the search market and chip away at Google’s dominance.</p><p>“The entire search category is now going through a sea change,” chief executive officer Satya Nadella said at the time. “That opportunity comes very few times.”</p><p>Almost a year later, the sea has yet to change.</p><p>The new Bing – powered by OpenAI’s generative artificial intelligence (AI) technology – dazzled internet users with conversational replies to queries asked in a natural way.</p><p>But Microsoft’s search engine ended 2023 with just 3.4 per cent of the global search market, according to data analytics firm StatCounter, up less than 1 percentage point since the ChatGPT announcement.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1416" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/081a8c1b-b628-46e0-b984-6897c60d3a63_b10d85c3.jpg" title="Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>Bing has long struggled for relevance and attracted more mockery than recognition over the years as a serious alternative to Google. Multiple rebrandings and redesigns since its 2009 debut did little to boost Bing’s popularity.</p><p>A month before Microsoft infused the search engine with generative AI, people were spending 33 per cent less time using it than they had 12 months earlier, according to SensorTower.</p><p>The ChatGPT reboot at least helped reverse those declines. In the second quarter of 2023, US monthly active users more than doubled year over year to 3.1 million, according to a Bloomberg Intelligence analysis of SensorTower mobile app data.</p><p>Overall, users were spending 84 per cent more time on the search engine, the data show. By year-end, Bing’s monthly active users had increased steadily to 4.4 million, according to SensorTower.</p><p>To build on the momentum, Microsoft has been adding more AI tools to Bing. In October, the company integrated the latest version of OpenAI’s image-generating model, DALL-E 3. Visitors can use it to create realistic-looking images with simple text prompts.</p><p>The offering does nothing to enhance Bing’s search abilities. But its addition generated a spike in usage, according to Jordi Ribas, Microsoft’s corporate vice-president of search and AI.</p><p>“We noticed an increase in usage by 10 times and that took us by surprise because if you think about it, DALL-E 2 was already quite good,” he said in an interview. “It really made a difference in the engagement and the users that came to our product.”</p><p>Yusuf Mehdi, Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, declined to specify how many active users Bing has.</p><p>“Look, it’s still early days and new behaviours are being built,” he said. “We’re still learning new things, but have millions and millions of people using the new tools.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" class="image-inline caption" height="1257" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/751251ee-f99c-42e4-bf34-d1aa45378b12_882215d8.jpg" title="Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" width="2000" /><figcaption>Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even as the Bing team adds crowd-pleasers, Google has been racing to develop its own AI tools.</p><p>In May, it launched an experimental version of its search engine called the “search generative experience”, which delivers conversational responses atop the familiar list of links. Dubbed SGE for short, it is still not widely available. However, Google plans to embed its most powerful large language model, Gemini, into SGE sometime this year.</p><p>The Alphabet division also retains considerable advantages. It has more than 90 per cent of the market and is the default search engine on Apple hardware, including iPhones, giving Google crucial critical mass. The more people who use it, the more the search engine knows and the more Google can use that data to deliver and rank results in a way people find useful.</p><p>The retooling of search by both technology giants reflects a shared conviction that generative AI will fundamentally change the way people seek and receive answers online.</p><p>For Microsoft, the shift is an opportunity to propel Bing forward. But the incremental gains so far make clear that buzzy AI features alone probably will not transform it into a formidable search player.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>“We are at the gold rush moment when it comes to AI and search,” said Shane Greenstein, an economist and professor at Harvard Business School, who has studied the commercialisation of the internet.</p><p>“At the moment, I doubt AI will move the needle because, in search, you need a flywheel: the more searches you have, the better answers are. Google is the only firm who has this dynamic well-established.”</p><p>Still, Greenstein said Bing, being the underdog, has more latitude to experiment. “Google has to be careful not to hurt its brand and product when it comes to testing new AI tools,” he said. “Bing can afford to take the risk. It has nothing to lose.”</p><p>Microsoft is also betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending. The current ad model rests on costs-per-click, but AI-powered searches are getting consumers to answers faster and more directly without a litany of blue links, according to marketing chief Mehdi.</p><p>“We have advertisers telling us they’re getting better outcomes as a result of our AI efforts and are deeply interested in how this works,” he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Reddit aims to launch IPO in March, sources say, in first stock market debut of a social media firm since 2019</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248999/reddit-aims-launch-ipo-march-sources-say-first-stock-market-debut-social-media-firm-2019</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Reddit plans to launch its IPO in March after years in the making.</li>    <li>Theme: Reddit is set to go public in March, despite facing competition from other major social media platforms.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Evaluate the potential for Reddit’s IPO to succeed, considering the company's revenue growth and user engagement.</li>    <li>Main information: Reddit's preparations for its IPO, including filing, roadshow, and offering details; the company's history, revenue model, and profitability challenges.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>摘要：Reddit计划在酝酿多年后于3月份启动其首次公开募股（IPO）。</li>    <li>主题：Reddit定于3月上市，尽管面临其他主要社交媒体平台的竞争。</li>    <li>观点：评估Reddit的IPO成功的可能性，考虑公司的收入增长和用户参与度。</li>    <li>主要信息：Reddit为其IPO所做的准备，包括备案、路演和发行细节；公司的历史、收入模式和盈利挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>solicit (v.) - /səˈlɪsɪt/ 征求，请求。    <p>原文例句：Reddit said last year it would charge companies for access to its application programming interface, which is used by technology companies to train large-language models used in artificial intelligence. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Late Latin，由sollicitare（恳求，请求）构成，表示“恳求，请求，征求”。在这个例句中，它指的是Reddit去年表示将向公司收取访问其应用程序编程接口的费用，该接口被科技公司用于训练人工智能中使用的大型语言模型。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>outlook (n.) - /ˈaʊtˌlʊk/ 前景，展望。    <p>原文例句：Reddit expected to generate slightly over US$800 million in advertising revenue in 2023, up more than 20 per cent from a year earlier, The Information reported last month.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，由ut（向外）和locian（看）组成，表示“向外看，展望”。在这个例句中，它指的是Reddit预计2023年的广告收入将略高于8亿美元，比去年同期增长超过20%，该信息是在上个月由The Information报道的。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>primary revenue stream - 主要收入来源。    <p>原文例句：The company, which generates its revenue primarily through advertising...</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由primary（主要的）和revenue stream（收入来源）构成，表示“主要的收入来源”。在这个例句中，它指的是该公司主要的收入来源是广告。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>initial public offering (IPO) - 首次公开募股。    <p>原文例句：Social media platform Reddit has drawn up detailed plans to launch its initial public offering (IPO) in March, moving forward with a listing it has been eyeing for more than three years,...</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由initial（最初的），public（公开的），offering（发行）和IPO（首次公开募股）构成，表示“首次公开募股”。在这个例句中，它指的是社交媒体平台Reddit已经制定了详细的计划，准备在3月份启动其首次公开募股，继续推进其已筹备三年的上市计划。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP - Reddit联合创始人亚历克西斯·奥哈尼安和他的妻子、网球明星塞雷娜·威廉姆斯，2022年。照片：Invision/AP<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Alexis Ohanian，谓语是with，宾语是his wife, tennis star Serena Williams。in 2022是一个时间状语，表示2022年。Photo: Invision/AP是一个独立成分，表示照片的来源。这个句子的意思是说，Reddit联合创始人亚历克西斯·奥哈尼安和他的妻子、网球明星塞雷娜·威廉姆斯在2022年被Invision/AP拍摄的照片。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词结构 - 分词结构是一种非谓语结构，由分词和修饰语构成，可以用来修饰名词或代词。    <p>原文例句：Social media platform Reddit has drawn up detailed plans to launch its initial public offering (IPO) in March, moving forward with a listing it has been eyeing for more than three years,...</p>    <p>语法讲解：在示例句子中，“drawn up”是一个分词结构，它由过去分词“drawn”和过去分词的补语“detailed plans”构成。这个分词结构用来修饰名词“Reddit”，表示Reddit已经制定了详细的计划。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>情态动词 - 情态动词是用来表示说话人的态度、能力或意愿的动词。    <p>原文例句：Reddit said last year it would charge companies for access to its application programming interface, which is used by technology companies to train large-language models used in artificial intelligence. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在示例句子中，“would”是一个情态动词，它用来表示Reddit的意愿。这个情态动词表示Reddit打算向公司收取访问其应用程序编程接口的费用。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Reddit is planning to make its public filing in February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March, sources say</li>
<li>The company, which generates its revenue primarily through advertising, has yet to turn a profit, co-founder Steve Huffman said last June</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/ceae1676-ec0a-453c-90b8-caa1d3c7da8a_ae468ee4.jpg" /><figcaption>Reddit is hoping to launch its IPO as soon as March, according to people familiar with the matter. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Social media platform Reddit has drawn up detailed plans to launch its initial public offering (IPO) in March, moving forward with a listing it has been eyeing for more than three years, according to people familiar with the matter.</p><p>It would be the first IPO of a major social media company since Pinterest’s debut in 2019, and would come as Reddit and its peers face stiff competition for advertising dollars from the likes of TikTok and Facebook.</p><p>The offering would also test the willingness of some Reddit users to back the company’s stock market debut. Many investors posting on the platform have helped fuel dozens of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3119536/gamestop-frenzy-how-reddit-nerds-sparked-wall" target="_self" title="">“meme” stock rallies</a> in the last three years, from retailer GameStop to movie operator AMC Entertainment Holdings.</p><p>Reddit, which filed confidentially for its IPO in December 2021, is planning to make its public filing in late February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March, two of the sources said.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP" class="image-inline caption" height="2581" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/a63256c8-0f58-4d2a-92c3-f97df71b18ee_a6b611e2.jpg" title="Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP" width="2000" /><figcaption>Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The San Francisco-based company, which was valued at about US$10 billion in a funding round in 2021, is seeking to sell about 10 per cent of its shares in the IPO, the sources added. It will decide on what IPO valuation it will pursue closer to the time of the listing, according to the sources.</p><p>The sources cautioned that Reddit’s IPO plans could be pushed back, as has happened in the past, and asked not to be identified discussing confidential deliberations.</p><p>A Reddit spokesperson declined to comment.</p><p>Founded in 2005 by web developer Steve Huffman and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3087871/reddit-co-founder-alexis-ohanian-resigns-urges-black-board" target="_self" title="">entrepreneur Alexis Ohanian</a>, Reddit became best known for its niche discussion groups and its users voting “up” or “down” on the content posted by other members.</p><p>The company, which generates its revenue primarily through advertising and also offers premium access for US$5.99 per month, has yet to turn a profit, Huffman said in a Reddit post last June.</p><p>In the past, the company has attributed its losses to investing in the platform and its users engaging less with advertising on its site than other social media.</p><p>The company held back from pulling the IPO trigger until it came closer to profitability. Bouts of market volatility that shut down the IPO market for much of the last two years also contributed to it delaying its plans.</p><p>Reddit expected to generate slightly over US$800 million in advertising revenue in 2023, up more than 20 per cent from a year earlier, The Information reported last month.</p><p>Reddit said last year it would charge companies for access to its application programming interface, which is used by technology companies to train <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">large-language models used in artificial intelligence</a>. The move upset some users who rely on third-party apps to access Reddit.</p><p>Large social media stocks have rebounded over the past year, driven mainly by a rally in technology stocks as interest rates peaked. Shares of Meta Platforms, which operates Facebook, have more than trebled in value over the past 12 months, while Snap’s shares rose 60 per cent over the same period.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China remains a tough market to stage a comeback for world’s former top smartphone vendor Samsung</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248969/china-remains-tough-market-stage-comeback-worlds-former-top-smartphone-vendor-samsung</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the Chinese smartphone market, especially with its foldable handsets, aiming to regain its former glory.</li>    <li>The company faced setbacks in China due to the Galaxy Note 7 battery issue, declining market share, and competition from domestic brands.</li>    <li>Samsung is trying to make a comeback in China by working with local tech companies and prioritizing the high-end market.</li>    <li>Despite its efforts, Samsung's prospects in China are affected by the ongoing US-China tech war and the popularity of domestic brands.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>三星已将重点转移至中国智能手机市场的顶端市场，特别是其可折叠手机，旨在重拾昔日荣耀。</li>    <li>由于三星 Galaxy Note 7 电池问题、市场份额下降以及国内品牌的竞争，该公司在中国市场遭遇挫折。</li>    <li>三星正试图通过与中国本地科技公司合作，优先考虑高端市场，在中国市场卷土重来。</li>    <li>尽管三星进行了努力，但其在中国市场的前景仍受到持续的中美科技战以及国内品牌流行的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>priority (n.) - /praɪˈɒrɪti/ 优先权，优先事项。    <p>原文例句：Over the past several years, Samsung has shut down multiple production bases on the mainland, including its last smartphone plant in Huizhou, a city in southern Guangdong province, and last personal computer factory in Suzhou, a bustling metropolis in Jiangsu. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由prior（先前的，优先的）和-ity（性质，状态）构成的，表示“优先权，优先事项”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星过去几年间关闭了多家生产基地，其中包括其在广东省惠州市的最后一座智能手机工厂和在江苏省苏州市的最后一座个人电脑工厂。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>competitor (n.) - /kəmˈpɛtɪtə(r)/ 竞争者，对手。    <p>原文例句：He also indicated that major Chinese vendors – including Huawei, Xiaomi, Oppo and Vivo – rose to become strong domestic and international competitors.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语competere（争夺，竞争），表示“竞争者，对手”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为、小米、OPPO和vivo等国内主要供应商崛起成为国内和国际上的强劲竞争对手。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>segment (n.) - /ˈsɛgmənt/ 部分，区段，环节。    <p>原文例句：Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland’s smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语segmentum（一段，一部分），表示“部分，区段，环节”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星已经将重点转移到中国大陆智能手机市场的高端部分，特别是其可折叠手机。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Samsung was once the biggest smartphone vendor on the mainland, with a market share of about 20 per cent in 2013.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示三星曾经是中国大陆最大的智能手机供应商，2013年的市场份额约为20% 。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>But Samsung, which was unseated by Apple in terms of annual smartphone shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023, still has ambitions to return to its former glory on the mainland. - 但三星在2023年首次在全球年度智能手机出货量上被苹果超越后，仍有野心重返中国大陆的昔日辉煌。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Samsung still has ambitions to return，其中主语是Samsung，谓语是has ambitions to return，宾语是to return。which was unseated by Apple in terms of annual smartphone shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023是一个非限制性定语从句，作主语Samsung的定语，表示三星在2023年首次在全球年度智能手机出货量上被苹果超越。这个句子的意思是说，但三星在2023年首次在全球年度智能手机出货量上被苹果超越后，仍有野心重返中国大陆的昔日辉煌。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列连词 - 用于连接两个或更多语法地位平等的句子成分或句子，表示并列关系。    <p>原文例句：Samsung’s mission has become more difficult amid the mainland’s shaky post-pandemic economic recovery.Still, Samsung’s mission has become more difficult amid the mainland’s shaky post-pandemic economic recovery.</p>    <p>语法讲解：并列连词是用来连接两个或更多语法地位平等的句子成分或句子，表示并列关系。常见的并列连词有and（和）、but（但是）、or（或）、so（所以）、for（因为）等。在这个例句中，but是并列连词，表示转折关系，把两个句子连接起来，意思是：三星的使命变得更加困难，因为中国大陆后疫情时期的经济复苏不稳定。但是，三星的使命变得更加困难，因为中国大陆后疫情时期的经济复苏不稳定。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>主语从句 - 指充当主语的从句。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy Z Fold5 and Z Flip5 3D foldable smartphone displays are seen at the company’s flagship store in Shanghai on October 23, 2023. </p>    <p>语法讲解：主语从句是指充当主语的从句，它可以由that引导，也可以由疑问词引导。在这个例句中，主语从句是Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy Z Fold5 and Z Flip5 3D foldable smartphone displays are seen at the company’s flagship store in Shanghai on October 23, 2023.。这个主语从句充当了整个句子的主语，说明了该公司在2023年10月23日在上海的旗舰店展示了三星电子Galaxy Z Fold5和Z Flip5 3D可折叠智能手机显示屏。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland’s smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets</li>
<li>The company has closed various production bases in China, including its last smartphone plant in Huizhou and last personal computer factory in Suzhou</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/bf4f1a5f-c528-4f08-b9c2-588ca952e7dd_16946b13.jpg" /><figcaption>Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy Z Fold5 and Z Flip5 3D foldable smartphone displays are seen at the company’s flagship store in Shanghai on October 23, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>A resident of eastern Jiangsu province, 48-year-old Shen Ling used to own a number of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphones</a> in the 2010s, attracted by the devices’ well-designed appearance and popularity among consumers across mainland China.</p><p>“It was once an age of glory for Samsung in China, when so many of my friends were using the brand for its high-end market standing,” Shen said. “I also chose to buy a Samsung phone at that time for the same reason.”</p><p>But Samsung’s strong run in the world’s largest smartphone market took a disastrous turn in late 2016, when the company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/enterprises/article/2027114/samsung-permanently-shuts-note-7-production" target="_self" title="">permanently halted production of its Galaxy Note 7 handset</a> amid increased concerns about the device catching fire. That followed widespread criticism from Chinese consumers after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/2023711/samsung-insists-note-7-china-safe-after-6th-reported-battery-explosion" target="_self" title="">several incidents where the handset’s battery exploded</a>. In January 2017, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korean</a> electronics giant admitted that those incidents were <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/2064560/samsungs-galaxy-note-7-fires-caused-battery-design-manufacturing-issues" target="_self" title="">caused by battery manufacturing and design issues</a> after an internal investigation.</p><p>“The harm to Samsung’s image was devastating,” Shen said. “It made me unsure if I could trust the quality of its future handsets.” Shen finally decided to switch to a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> smartphone in 2020.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/08229e1a-0baf-487d-a0d0-871525d20f84_5b21820d.jpg" title="A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook</figcaption></figure></div><p>Samsung was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/social-gadgets/article/2134770/how-samsung-went-no-1-also-ran-chinas-smartphone-market-and-can" target="_self" title="">once the biggest smartphone vendor on the mainland</a>, with a market share of about 20 per cent in 2013. The Korean firm ranked dead last among the market’s major handset vendors by 2018, with just a 1 per cent share and has since remained around that level.</p><p>The company’s fall in mainland China’s smartphone market was partly due to “a combination of inappropriate operations leading to a damaged reputation”, said Ivan Lam, a senior analyst for Counterpoint Research. He also indicated that major Chinese vendors – including Huawei, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/vivo" target="_self" title="">Vivo</a> – rose to become strong domestic and international competitors.</p><p>But Samsung, which was unseated by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> in terms of annual smartphone shipments worldwide <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above?utm_source=rss_feed" target="_self" title="">for the first time in 2023</a>, still has ambitions to return to its former glory on the mainland.</p><p>While Huawei has largely retreated from the Korean market primarily because of local consumers’ loyalty to homegrown Android handsets, Samsung is slowly trying to stage a comeback in China. Still, Samsung’s mission has become more difficult amid the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248694/china-gdp-beijings-long-do-list-boost-economy-2024" target="_self" title="">shaky post-pandemic economic recovery</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>“Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end market in China, particularly with the introduction of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foldable-phones" target="_self" title="">foldable models</a>,” Counterpoint’s Lam said. “The current strategy for Samsung in China appears to be characterised by conservatism, stability and continuity.”</p><p>Over the past few years, Samsung continued to launch new smartphone models on the mainland. It has also been working with some Chinese Big Tech companies, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>, to help step up localisation of its smartphones’ content ecosystem.</p><p>The reason Samsung did not fully leave mainland China was obvious: the country remains the world’s largest computing, smartphone, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> market. Continued operation in the vast market has become more important for the Korean conglomerate, as its sales have been hit hard by sluggish global consumer electronics demand.</p><p>In its earnings guidance released last week, Samsung said it expected to post its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" target="_self" title="">sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit</a>. The company estimated that its operating earnings for 2023 plunged 84.9 per cent year on year to 6.54 trillion won (US$4.86 billion), while annual revenue was expected to drop 14.6 per cent to 258.16 trillion won.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" title="">Samsung profit tumbles 35% as chip weakness persists</a></h3><p>Samsung’s sharpened focus on the premium segment of China’s smartphone market has managed to attract a growing number of new users. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a> university student Cynthia Xia, for example, started using Samsung’s foldable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3192963/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-4-vs-motorola-razr-foldable-smartphones" target="_self" title="">Galaxy Z Flip 4</a> smartphone in 2022.</p><p>“I was totally attracted by the design and its flexibility to adopt customised settings,” Xia said. “I think no other brands are doing as well as Samsung in foldable phones.”</p><p>Still, Samsung’s outlook in the world’s second-largest economy is complicated by the ongoing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/us-china-tech-war-rivalry/news" target="_self" title="">US-China tech war</a>, which has cast a shadow over the Korean firm’s supply chain network on the mainland.</p><p>Although Samsung, along with memory chip rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3218776/south-korean-chip-maker-sk-hynix-denies-reports-it-selling-firms-dalian-flash-memory-fab-assuring" target="_self" title="">SK Hynix</a>, last year secured indefinite waivers from Washington to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3237485/tech-war-us-waiver-china-export-restrictions-advanced-semiconductor-equipment-south-koreas-samsung" target="_self" title="">ship advanced semiconductor-manufacturing equipment</a> for their China plants, the tech conglomerate has been downsizing its production facilities and number of employees in the country.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3014564/samsungs-last-china-smartphone-factory-closing-raising" title="">Will closing last Samsung smartphone factory hurt China’s role in global value chain?</a></h3><p>Over the past several years, Samsung has shut down multiple production bases on the mainland, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3014564/samsungs-last-china-smartphone-factory-closing-raising" target="_self" title="">its last smartphone plant</a> in Huizhou, a city in southern Guangdong province, and last personal computer factory in Suzhou, a bustling metropolis in Jiangsu. The company had 17,891 employees on the mainland in 2022, which was in stark contrast to its peak of 63,316 in 2013, according to Samsung’s Sustainability Report.</p><p>The relocation of Samsung’s factories from the mainland showed how the company “strategically deprioritised the Chinese market, resulting in reduced investment in brand and channel building”, Counterpoint’s Lam said.</p><p>With Samsung’s recently launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248863/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-smartphones-come-google-gemini-ai-technology-fight-apple-iphones" target="_self" title="">Galaxy 24 series, which features artificial intelligence technology</a>, all eyes are on how the company can help revive and bring change to the global smartphone market.</p><p>Still, that new handset is not expected to make a big splash on the mainland.</p><p>“None of my friends are using Samsung’s phones nowadays, so why wouldn’t I stick with domestic brands when they offer similar functionalities at lower prices?” Shen from Jiangsu said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei releases preview version of updated HarmonyOS Next as it accelerates shift away from Android</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248956/huawei-releases-preview-version-updated-harmonyos-next-it-accelerates-shift-away-android</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Huawei has released the developer preview version of its HarmonyOS Next operating system, aiming to rival Google's Android and Apple's iOS in the Chinese market. Over 200 industry partners are developing native HarmonyOS apps, and Huawei plans to have 5,000 partners by 2024. HarmonyOS Next will be launched for commercial use in Q4 2023. Huawei is investing in developer support and ecosystem building to promote the adoption of HarmonyOS.  <ul>    <li>HarmonyOS Next developer preview released.</li>    <li>200+ industry partners developing native HarmonyOS apps.</li>    <li>HarmonyOS Next to launch commercially in Q4 2023.</li>    <li>Huawei investing in developer support and ecosystem building.</li>    <li>HarmonyOS adoption growing, currently on 800 million devices.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  华为HarmonyOS Next版本开发预览版已于星期四发布，旨在在中国市场上与谷歌的安卓系统和苹果的IOS系统相抗衡。超过200家行业合作伙伴正在开发HarmonyOS原生应用，华为计划在2024年之前拥有5000家合作伙伴。HarmonyOS Next将于2023年第四季度正式商用。华为正在投资开发者支持和生态系统建设，以促进HarmonyOS的采用。HarmonyOS的采用率正在增长，目前已在8亿台设备上运行。  <ul>    <li>HarmonyOS Next版本开发预览版已发布。</li>    <li>200多家行业合作伙伴正在开发HarmonyOS原生应用。</li>    <li>HarmonyOS Next将于2023年第四季度正式商用。</li>    <li>华为正在投资开发者支持和生态系统建设。</li>    <li>HarmonyOS的采用率正在增长，目前已在8亿台设备上运行。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>robust (adj.) - /rəˈbʌst/ 强壮，健壮。    <p>原文例句：To encourage development of a more robust ecosystem for HarmonyOS, Huawei will also work with more than 280 companies and over 300 educational institutions to cultivate developers for the operating system, according to a company release.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由robus（橡树）构成，意为“强壮，健壮”。在这个例句中，它指的是一个更强大的HarmonyOS生态系统，即华为将与280多家公司和300多家教育机构合作，为操作系统培养开发者，以促进HarmonyOS生态系统的稳固和强大。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>tipped (v.) - /tɪpt/ 倾斜，倾覆。    <p>原文例句：Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle English，由tippen（倾倒，翻倒）构成，意为“倾斜，倾覆”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为的HarmonyOS有可能在2024年超越苹果的iOS，即根据TechInsights的报告，华为的HarmonyOS有可能在2024年超过苹果的iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rival (v.) - /ˈraɪvəl/ 竞争，抗衡。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies has unveiled the latest version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS for developers, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant takes on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于Old French，由river（竞争）构成，意为“竞争，抗衡”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为的HarmonyOS将与谷歌的Android和苹果的iOS竞争，即华为的HarmonyOS将与谷歌的Android和苹果的iOS竞争，争取在中国市场上获得更大的份额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday. - HarmonyOS Next开发预览版于星期四向编码人员开放。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个主动语态的句子，主语是The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next，谓语是was made available，宾语是to coders。made available是make available的过去式，意为“使能够获得，使可用”。在这个句子中，它指的是HarmonyOS Next开发预览版于星期四向编码人员开放，即HarmonyOS Next开发预览版于星期四向编码人员开放，供他们测试和开发应用程序。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 把通常放在句首的主语和谓语动词颠倒位置，以强调句子的某些成分。</li>    <p>原文例句：Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native apps for HarmonyOS - 超过200家行业合作伙伴已经开始为HarmonyOS开发原生应用程序。</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，把通常放在句首的主语Over 200 industry partners和谓语动词have initiated颠倒位置，以强调句子的某些成分，即超过200家行业合作伙伴已经开始为HarmonyOS开发原生应用程序。这种句型常用于强调句子的某个成分，使之更引人注目，更具感染力。</p>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday</li>
<li>Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native apps for HarmonyOS</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/f12f9442-2dd3-4de3-a881-63405dd3a097_26cc2667.jpg" /><figcaption>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has unveiled the latest version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS for developers, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant takes on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p><p>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday, and the operating system will be launched for commercial use in the fourth quarter of this year, Huawei said at its developer conference.</p><p>HarmonyOS Next, billed as a major upgrade to Huawei’s mobile platform, will no longer support Android-based applications.</p><p>Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native HarmonyOS apps, and the company aims to get 5,000 partners on board by the end of 2024, Zhu Yonggang, president of Huawei Consumer Business Cloud Services, said at the Thursday event.</p><p>Meituan, the delivery services giant, has already finished the first version of its HarmonyOS app in the first batch of development partners, while other internet firms, such as lifestyle social media platform Xiaohongshu and online mapping service Amap, have also made progress.</p><p>Amap is backed by Alibaba Group Holding, the Post’s owner.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" title="">Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights</a></h3><p>To encourage development of a more robust ecosystem for HarmonyOS, Huawei will also work with more than 280 companies and over 300 educational institutions to cultivate developers for the operating system, according to a company release.</p><p>Huawei will also invest 7 billion yuan (US$983 million) to support innovation in areas from HarmonyOS native apps to Software Development Kit (SDK), a toolset used to help developers build apps for a particular platform, according to posts published on HarmonyOS’s official Weibo account.</p><p>The adoption of HarmonyOS has been growing. Since its launch in August 2019, HarmonyOS currently runs on over 800 million devices, according to Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group, speaking at the Thursday event.</p><p>HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List. Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>Driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment with its P60 Pro model, HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year, according to a report by TechInsights earlier this month.</p><p><em>Additional reporting by Ben Jiang</em></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sheryl Sandberg, who helped turn Facebook into digital advertising empire, to leave company board</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248977/sheryl-sandberg-who-helped-turn-facebook-digital-advertising-empire-leave-company-board</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Sheryl Sandberg, the former COO of Meta (formerly Facebook), has announced her departure from the company's board of directors. Sandberg joined Facebook in 2008, four years before the company went public, and has been instrumental in its growth and success. During her tenure, she oversaw many key initiatives, including the company's advertising business, and was responsible for managing some of its biggest missteps. Sandberg's resignation comes amid ongoing scrutiny of Meta's business practices and its impact on society. She plans to continue serving as an advisor to the company and focus on her philanthropic efforts, including a girls' leadership program aimed at addressing gender inequities.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Sheryl Sandberg steps down from Meta board after 14 years, marking a significant departure for the company.</li>    <li>Theme: Sandberg's departure highlights the evolving landscape of Meta, its leadership, and the challenges it faces.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Sandberg's resignation as COO and now board member reflects Meta's ongoing transformation and the need for fresh perspectives.</li>    <li>Main information: Sandberg's contributions to Meta's growth, her role in key company decisions, and her future plans for philanthropic endeavors.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  雪莉·桑德伯格，Meta（前身为Facebook）的前首席运营官，宣布辞去公司董事会成员的职务。桑德伯格于2008年加入Facebook，比公司上市早了四年，并一直在公司的成长和成功中发挥着关键作用。任职期间，她负责管理许多关键的举措，包括公司的广告业务，并负责管理公司的一些重大失误。桑德伯格的辞职正值人们对Meta商业行为及其对社会影响的持续审查之际。她计划继续担任公司的顾问，并将重点放在她的慈善事业上，包括一个旨在解决性别不平等问题的女孩领导力项目。  <ul>    <li>摘要：雪莉·桑德伯格在Meta工作14年后辞去董事会成员职务，标志着公司的一个重大离职。</li>    <li>主题：桑德伯格的离开凸显了Meta不断变化的格局、它的领导层以及它所面临的挑战。</li>    <li>观点：桑德伯格辞去首席运营官，现在又辞去董事会成员一职，反映了Meta正在发生转型以及需要新的视角。</li>    <li>主要信息：桑德伯格对Meta增长的贡献，她在公司关键决策中的作用，以及她未来的慈善事业计划。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>instrumental (adj.) - /ˌɪnstrʊˈmɛnt(ə)l/ 有用的，重要的。    <p>原文例句：Sheryl Sandberg, the former COO of Meta (formerly Facebook), has announced her departure from the company's board of directors. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由in-（在……里面）和strumentum（工具）组成，意为“有助于实现某种目的”。在这个例句中，它描述了雪莉·桑德伯格在Meta的董事会中发挥了重要的作用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>initiative (n.) - /ɪˈnɪʃətɪv/ 主动，举措。    <p>原文例句：During her tenure, she oversaw many key initiatives, including the company's advertising business, and was responsible for managing some of its biggest missteps. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由in-（在……里面）和ire（去）组成，意为“开始，采取行动”。在这个例句中，它指的是雪莉·桑德伯格在Meta期间负责监督的许多关键举措。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>mark a significant departure - 标志着重大离职。    <P>原文例句：Sheryl Sandberg steps down from Meta board after 14 years, marking a significant departure for the company. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由mark（标记），significant（重要的）和departure（离开，离去）构成的，表示“标志着重要的离开”。在这个例句中，它表示雪莉·桑德伯格在Meta工作14年后辞去董事会成员职务，标志着公司的一个重大离职。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>ongoing transformation - 正在发生的转型。    <P>原文例句：Sandberg's resignation as COO and now board member reflects Meta's ongoing transformation and the need for fresh perspectives. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词词组是由ongoing（正在进行的），transformation（转型）和need for fresh perspectives（需要新的视角）构成的，表示“正在发生的转型和需要新的视角”。在这个例句中，它表示桑德伯格辞去首席运营官，现在又辞去董事会成员一职，反映了Meta正在发生转型以及需要新的视角。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Sandberg's resignation comes amid ongoing scrutiny of Meta's business practices and its impact on society.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Sandberg's resignation comes，其中主语是Sandberg's resignation，谓语是comes。amid ongoing scrutiny of Meta's business practices and its impact on society是一个介词短语作状语，修饰Sandberg's resignation，表示桑德伯格的辞职正值人们对Meta商业行为及其对社会影响的持续审查之际。这个句子的意思是说，桑德伯格的辞职正值人们对Meta商业行为及其对社会影响的持续审查之际。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：She had served as COO of Facebook, and then Meta, for 14-and-a-half years and as a board member for 12 years.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示雪莉·桑德伯格曾在Facebook和Meta担任首席运营官14年零6个月，并在董事会任职12年。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Sandberg left Google to join Facebook in 2008, 4 years before the company went public and was the number 2 executive at Meta under CEO Mark Zuckerberg</li>
<li>She stepped down as COO of Meta in 2022 but remained a member of the company board. Sandberg said she will continue to serve as an adviser to Meta</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/d30b61be-bbea-4726-8b0d-53c086bdcd8c_20c6fc3d.jpg" /><figcaption>Sheryl Sandberg on Thursday announced she is stepping down from the board of Meta. Photo: Reuters </figcaption></figure><p>Sheryl Sandberg, who helped to transform Facebook from a tech start-up into a digital advertising empire, will step down from the board of Meta, Facebook’s parent company.</p><p>“With a heart filled with gratitude and a mind filled with memories, I let the Meta board know that I will not stand for re-election this May,” Sandberg wrote in a Facebook post.</p><p>Sandberg left <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/google" target="_self" title="">Google</a> to join <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/facebook" target="_self" title="">Facebook</a> in 2008, four years before the company went public. As the number two executive at Meta under CEO <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mark-zuckerberg" target="_self" title="">Mark Zuckerberg</a>, Sandberg also took a lot of heat for some of its biggest missteps.</p><p>She stepped down as chief operating officer of Meta in 2022 but remained a member of the company board. She had served as COO of Facebook, and then Meta, for 14-and-a-half years and as a board member for 12 years.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3180106/key-facebook-force-sheryl-sandberg-stepping-down" title="">Key Facebook force Sheryl Sandberg stepping down</a></h3><p>“Under Mark’s leadership, Javi Olivan, Justin Osofsky, Nicola Mendelsohn and their teams have proven beyond a doubt that the Meta business is strong and well-positioned for the future, so this feels like the right time to step away,” Sandberg wrote.</p><p>Sandberg said she will continue to serve as an adviser to the company.</p><p>Last year Sandberg announced that she was launching a girls’ leadership programme through her foundation to respond to what she calls stubborn gender inequities. The programme includes a middle-school curriculum as well as resources for adults.</p><p>Lean In is a project of the Sandberg Goldberg Bernthal Family Foundation, the private foundation Sandberg started with her late husband, Dave Goldberg.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese state media calls for crackdown on deceptive pricing in live-streaming e-commerce</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248938/chinese-state-media-calls-crackdown-deceptive-pricing-live-streaming-e-commerce</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  In order to attract customers amid fierce competition, some merchants engaged in live-streaming e-commerce in China have been accused of price fraud, including marking up the original price and offering fake discounts. The Economic Daily calls for tighter regulatory scrutiny of these deceptive tactics, which hinder the healthy development of the economy and damage the reputation of the live-streaming industry.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Price fraud in live-streaming e-commerce needs stricter oversight.</li>    <li>Theme: Live-streamers engaging in deceitful pricing tactics to attract customers and boost sales, calling for enhanced regulation.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The negative impact of price fraud on consumers, the e-commerce industry, and the need for stronger government intervention.</li>    <li>Main information: Fabricating original prices, fake discounts, penalties for price manipulation, calls for improved regulations, responsibilities of platforms, merchants, and broadcasters, growth of live-streaming e-commerce in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  随着我国电商从业者越来越多地转向直播带货，直播领域的价格欺诈行为逐渐受到质疑和关注。其中部分主播采用标高原价和虚构折扣等手段吸引消费者，严重损害了消费者的合法权益，破坏了直播电商行业自身的声誉。针对上述问题，《经济日报》发文呼吁监管部门加强对直播电商领域价格欺诈行为的监管，推动行业健康发展。  <ul>    <li>摘要：要求对直播领域的欺诈促销进行更加严格的监管.</li>    <li>主题：一些主播为吸引顾客和促进销售采用欺骗性的价格策略，有必要进行加强行业监管。</li>    <li>观点：价格欺诈对消费者、电子商务行业及加强政府干预的必要性的负面影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：捏造原始价格，欺骗性折扣，价格操纵处罚，改进法规的呼吁，平台，商家和广播公司的责任，直播电子商务在中国的发展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Scrutiny (n.) - 仔细检查，审视。    <p>原文例句：The Economic Daily calls for tighter regulatory scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语“scrutinium”，意为“调查，审查”。在这个例句中，它指的是更严格的监管审查，即对直播带货中欺骗性定价策略进行更严格的调查和审查。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Manipulation (n.) - 操纵，操控。    <p>原文例句：The responsibilities of e-commerce platforms, merchants and broadcasters should be clarified in these cases, the media outlet said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语“manipulare”，意为“用手操作”。在这个例句中，它指的是操纵，即明确电子商务平台、商家和主播在这些情况下的责任。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Mark up (v.) - 标高，加价。    <p>原文例句：Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由“mark”（标记）和“up”（向上）组成，意为“标高，加价”。在这个例句中，它指的是标高原始价格，即捏造或抬高原始价格。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years, with sales jumping 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023, reaching 2.2 trillion yuan (US$311 billion), accounting for 18.1 per cent of all online shopping in China, according to data from the Ministry of Commerce.  - 直播电子商务近年来呈现爆发式增长，2023 年前 10 个月销售额同比增长 58.9%，达到 2.2 万亿元人民币（3110 亿美元），占中国所有在线购物的 18.1%，数据来自商务部。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth，其中主语是Live-streaming e-commerce，谓语是has seen，宾语是exponential growth。recent years是一个时间状语，修饰exponential growth，表示近年来。with sales jumping 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023是一个介词短语作状语，修饰exponential growth，表示销售额同比增长 58.9%。reaching 2.2 trillion yuan (US$311 billion)是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰exponential growth，表示达到 2.2 万亿元人民币（3110 亿美元）。accounting for 18.1 per cent of all online shopping in China是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰exponential growth，表示占中国所有在线购物的 18.1%。according to data from the Ministry of Commerce是一个介词短语作状语，修饰exponential growth，表示根据商务部的数据。这个句子的意思是说，直播电子商务近年来呈现爆发式增长，2023 年前 10 个月销售额同比增长 58.9%，达到 2.2 万亿元人民币（3110 亿美元），占中国所有在线购物的 18.1%，数据来自商务部。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示主语的动作或状态是由其他的人或物造成的。    <p>原文例句：The Economic Daily calls for tighter regulatory scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是tighter regulatory scrutiny，谓语是calls for，宾语是deceptive pricing tactics。介词短语in live streaming是一个介词短语作状语，修饰calls for，表示在直播带货中。这个句子的意思是说，经济日报呼吁监管机构加强对直播带货中欺骗性定价策略的监管。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission</li>
<li>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years, with sales jumping 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/da9d4337-120c-49ea-b242-d1f49b587f18_9b05dbbb.jpg" /><figcaption>TikTok Shop and an online influencer prepare for a live-streaming session of selling goods from the Consumer Electronics Show (CES), Las Vegas, January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese state media Economic Daily has called for tighter regulatory scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming, as the country’s e-commerce players increasingly turn to these campaigns to lure customers and drive sales amid fierce competition and macro-economic headwinds.</p><p>In an opinion piece on Thursday, the official media blasted some live streamers for misleading consumers with tactics such as fake price comparisons and exaggerations, adding that more than 5,000 broadcasters were penalised last year for price manipulation.</p><p>Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247160/bytedances-douyin-makes-instant-refunds-mandatory-following-pdd-taobao-and-jdcom-amid-fierce-e" title="">Chinese version of TikTok makes instant refunds mandatory amid e-commerce rivalry</a></h3><p>“Live-streaming e-commerce has become an important part of the digital economy, but price fraud and other chaotic practices have hindered the high-quality development of the economy,” the article said. These tactics not only hurt consumers’ rights but also damaged the reputation of the live-streaming industry, it added.</p><p>The Economic Daily urged the government to improve regulations for the sector and increase the penalties for price fraud. The responsibilities of e-commerce platforms, merchants and broadcasters should be clarified in these cases, the media outlet said.</p><p>E-commerce platforms need to take the initiative to crack down on dubious live-streaming practices, the article urged, and they should impose harsher penalties and even ban those that repeatedly commit violations.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above" title="">Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with broad iPhone discounts</a></h3><p>The call for stricter oversight comes as e-commerce platforms are increasingly relying on live streaming to attract consumers amid fierce domestic competition and weaker consumer spending.</p><p>Key players in the field include traditional e-commerce platforms such as Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao, as well as short video apps like ByteDance’s Douyin and Kuaishou Technology. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years. Sales in the sector jumped 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023, reaching 2.2 trillion yuan (US$311 billion), accounting for 18.1 per cent of all online shopping in China, according to data from the Ministry of Commerce.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1309" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/754d97a1-4883-40b6-b755-d027eb815bcf_113d2948.jpg" title="A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>However, the rapid growth has invited increasing regulatory attention. In April 2021, the Cyberspace Administration of China and six other regulators jointly released rules aimed at curbing malpractice such as selling fake products, falsifying view numbers and promoting pyramid schemes.</p><p>Last month People’s Daily, the chief mouthpiece of the Chinese Communist Party, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3243239/peoples-daily-calls-tighter-control-live-streaming-e-commerce-china-controversies-mount" target="_self" title="">called for tighter oversight of live-streaming e-commerce</a>. The paper said misconduct in the live-streaming industry, from fraudulent advertising to misleading pricing, should be addressed and punished for the sake of the sector’s healthy and sustained growth.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TikTok owner ByteDance looks to expand in US, Canada and Australia amid rising competition and political headwinds</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248932/tiktok-owner-bytedance-looks-expand-us-canada-and-australia-amid-rising-competition-and-political</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese company ByteDance, the owner of TikTok, is planning to expand its operations in the United States, Canada, and Australia. The company is actively seeking talented individuals, primarily computer engineers, to join its expanded teams. In addition to hiring new employees, ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to support the expansion efforts. The company's goal is to maintain its business momentum and compete effectively in the tech industry despite rising competition and political challenges.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: ByteDance, owner of TikTok, seeks global expansion to drive growth and face challenges.</li>    <li>Theme: ByteDance's strategic move to strengthen its presence in key markets by expanding its operations.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: ByteDance's commitment to hiring talent and leveraging technology for growth amidst a competitive environment.</li>    <li>Main information: Expansion plans in the US, Canada, and Australia; recruitment of computer engineers; transfer of existing employees; focus on apps like TikTok, CapCut, and Lemon8.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国的短视频应用TikTok的母公司字节跳动正在计划扩展在美国、加拿大和澳大利亚的业务。这家公司正在积极招聘有才华的人才，主要是计算机工程师，加入其不断扩大的团队。除了招聘新员工，字节跳动还在将现有员工从其他地区调动，以支持其业务拓展工作。这家公司的目标是，持续增长其业务动能，在日益激烈的竞争以及政治挑战中，保持有效地竞争。  <ul>    <li>摘要：字节跳动，TikTok的所有者，寻求全球扩张以推动其增长，并面对挑战。</li>    <li>主题：字节跳动通过扩展业务来强化其在关键市场存在感的战略性举措。</li>    <li>观点：字节跳动在竞争激烈的环境下，致力于招募人才并利用技术进行增长的承诺。</li>    <li>主要信息：在美国、加拿大和澳大利亚制定扩张计划；招募计算机工程师；将现有员工调动；专注于TikTok、剪映和Lemon8等应用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>momentum (n.) - /ˌmoʊˈmɛntəm/ 动量，发展势头。    <p>原文例句：The expansion comes as ByteDance seeks to maintain its business momentum amid rising competition and political headwinds. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由movere（移动）和mentum（手段，结果）组成，意为“使运动，势头”。在这个例句中，它指的是字节跳动在面对日益激烈的竞争和政治困境时，寻求保持其业务的发展势头。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>tenfold (adv.) - 十倍地，十倍。    <p>原文例句：It has set an ambitious target for its US shopping operation to increase tenfold to US$17.5 billion in gross merchandise volume this year, according to a Bloomberg report.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由ten（十）和fold（折叠）组成的，意为“十倍地，十倍”。在这个例句中，它描述了字节跳动为其美国购物业务设定的雄心勃勃的目标，即今年的商品交易总额将增长十倍，达到175亿美元。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>gross merchandise volume - 商品交易总额。    <P>原文例句：It has set an ambitious target for its US shopping operation to increase tenfold to US$17.5 billion in gross merchandise volume this year, according to a Bloomberg report. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指在特定时间段内通过电子商务平台销售的商品或服务的总价值。在这个例句中，它指的是字节跳动对其美国购物业务设定的商品交易总额目标，即今年将增长十倍，达到175亿美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company is in talks to sublease a large office building on Coleman Avenue in San Jose, California, according to a report by the Bay Area News Group last week. - 该公司正在洽谈转租加州圣何塞科尔曼大街的一栋大型办公楼，据上周湾区新闻集团报道。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The company is in talks to sublease a large office building，其中主语是The company，谓语是is in talks to sublease，宾语是a large office building。on Coleman Avenue in San Jose, California是一个地点状语，表示在加州圣何塞的科尔曼大街。according to a report by the Bay Area News Group last week是一个时间状语，表示根据上周湾区新闻集团的报道。这个句子的意思是说，该公司正在洽谈转租加州圣何塞科尔曼大街的一栋大型办公楼，据上周湾区新闻集团报道。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的现在动作或事件。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在时态，表示正在进行的现在动作或事件。结构是：am/is/are + 现在分词。其中am/is/are要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。在这个例句中，它表示字节跳动正在将现有员工从其他地区调动到一些新地点。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式 - 表示一种动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：According to a March report by Baijing, a blog that covers Chinese companies doing business overseas. CapCut’s MAU has hit 200 million.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个动词形式，表示一种动作或状态。结构是：to + 动词原形。在这个例句中，它表示根据3月份白鲸的一份报告，一家报道中国公司在海外开展业务的博客，CapCut的月活跃用户已达到2亿。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In addition to US, ByteDance is looking for talent to join its expanded operations in Canada and Australia to work on apps including TikTok</li>
<li>ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/6f1c2685-a484-454c-8ac6-1cbb7274395c_40276094.jpg" /><figcaption>TikTok owner ByteDance looks to expand in US, Canada and Australia. Photo: AFP  </figcaption></figure><p>ByteDance, which owns global short video hit TikTok, is looking to expand in Silicon Valley in the United States, and also in Canada and Australia as the sector continues to boom and amid rising competition.</p><p>The company is in talks to sublease a large office building on Coleman Avenue in San Jose, California, according to a report by the Bay Area News Group last week.</p><p>Meanwhile, it is looking for talent – mainly computer engineers – to join its expanded operations in Canada and Australia to work on apps including TikTok, video editor CapCut and social media and lifestyle app Lemon8, according to a report on Thursday by Chinese media outlet Jiemian.</p><p>In addition to hiring new staff, ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations. For example, it has relocated 120 people working across product, operations, and research and development from China to Canada and Australia, according to the Jiemian report.</p><p>ByteDance did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>The expansion comes as ByteDance seeks to maintain its business momentum amid rising competition and political headwinds.</p><p>Its flagship app TikTok said in 2021 that its monthly active users (MAU) surpassed 1 billion. CapCut’s MAU has hit 200 million, according to a March report by Baijing, a blog that covers Chinese companies doing business overseas.</p><p>Although ByteDance has retreated in video gaming, it is doubling down on e-commerce by leveraging the popularity of TikTok. It has set an ambitious target for its US shopping operation to increase tenfold to US$17.5 billion in gross merchandise volume this year, according to a Bloomberg report.</p><p>The company’s overall revenue expanded around 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing projected growth at Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings, according to a December Bloomberg report.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance’s Douyin steps up oversight of live-streaming hosts, closing 290,000 accounts last year for ‘harmful’ content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248921/bytedances-douyin-steps-oversight-live-streaming-hosts-closing-290000-accounts-last-year-harmful</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese regulators have strengthened supervision over live streaming activities due to issues like vulgar language and challenges that cause public disturbance.</li>    <li>Douyin, China's popular short video app, has taken measures to address these issues.</li>    <li>The company shut down accounts of hosts who engaged in inappropriate practices like outdoor live streaming with vulgar content and enticing viewers to spend more money.</li>    <li>Collaborating with authorities, Douyin has removed accounts involved in harmful activities and arrested criminal suspects.</li>    <li>The platform has introduced a new host rating system and is using AI-powered virtual hosts with transparent identity verification.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国监管机构对直播行业进行整顿，原因是直播活动中存在脏话、骚扰路人的情况，引起了社会问题。</li>    <li>字节跳动旗下的抖音作为中国知名的短视频平台，采取了多项措施整顿直播行业乱象。</li>    <li>抖音封禁了大量存在不当行为的主播账号，包括一些大主播，原因是他们进行了不合适的直播行为，例如在户外直播中使用低俗语言，诱导观众花钱等。</li>    <li>抖音还与地方政府合作，清除了一批有害的直播活动，并逮捕了犯罪嫌疑人。</li>    <li>抖音推出了新的主播评级系统，并利用AI驱动的虚拟主播，并对虚拟主播背后的个人进行身份核实，以保证透明度。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tightened (v.): 强化，收紧。    <p>原文例句：Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：tightened是tighten的过去分词形式，表示“强化，收紧”。在这个例句中，它被用来描述中国监管机构对直播行业的监管力度不断加强。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>improper (adj.): 不合适的，不恰当的。    <p>原文例句：The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts, including some top influencers, as the platform sought to weed out practices it deemed harmful, such as outdoor live-streaming containing vulgar content, improper challenge games among hosts, as well as enticing viewers to spend more money.</p>    <p>例句讲解：improper是proper的反义词，表示“不合适的，不恰当的”。在这个例句中，它被用来形容一些网络直播主播的行为不规范，包括在户外直播中使用低俗语言、组织不恰当的挑战游戏，以及诱导观众花钱等。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>crackdown (n.): 镇压，严厉打击。    <p>原文例句：The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts, including some top influencers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：crackdown是crack和down的组合，表示“镇压，严厉打击”。在这个例句中，它被用来描述网络直播行业整治行动，旨在关闭大量违规网络直播账号。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rein in (v.): 控制住，约束。    <p>原文例句：Douyin, the sibling app of ByteDance’s global short video hit TikTok, said it imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023 to rein in inappropriate practices.</p>    <p>例句讲解：rein in是rein和in的组合，表示“控制住，约束”。在这个例句中，它被用来描述抖音平台对网络直播主播及其行为进行额外的监督，以遏制不恰当的行为。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>harmful practices (n.): 有害的行为，不良的行为。    <p>原文例句：The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts, including some top influencers, as the platform sought to weed out practices it deemed harmful, such as outdoor live-streaming containing vulgar content, improper challenge games among hosts, as well as enticing viewers to spend more money.</p>    <p>例句讲解：harmful practices是指对他人或社会造成危害的行为。在这个例句中，它被用来描述网络直播平台上存在的一些不良行为，包括在户外直播中使用低俗语言、组织不恰当的挑战游戏，以及诱导观众花钱等。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Douyin, the sibling app of ByteDance’s global short video hit TikTok, said it imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023 to rein in inappropriate practices. - 抖音表示，为了遏制不当行为，2023年对其直播主播及其活动进行了额外的监督。    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Douyin said it imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023 to rein in inappropriate practices.。其中，主语是Douyin，谓语是said，宾语是it imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023 to rein in inappropriate practices.。关于主句，imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示抖音对直播主播及其活动进行了额外的监督，to rein in inappropriate practices是一个不定式作目的状语，表示为了遏制不当行为。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是一种时态，由have/has和过去分词构成。在例句中，has been making表示公司一直生产iPhone和其他产品，至今持续了好几年。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作状语 - 表示动作、状态、方式等。    <p>原文例句：Douyin, the sibling app of ByteDance’s global short video hit TikTok, said it imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023 to rein in inappropriate practices.</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去分词短语可以作状语，表示动作、状态、方式等。在例句中，imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023是一个过去分词短语，作状语，表示抖音对其直播主播及其活动进行了额外的监督，rein in inappropriate practices也是一个过去分词短语，作目的状语，表示为了遏制不当行为。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Some outdoor live streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions</li>
<li>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was worth US$98.2 billion in 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/9a28fd60-8832-4f14-b4c3-01657424e7b0_5660f465.jpg" /><figcaption>An advertisement for Douyin seen at a bus stop in China. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure><p>Douyin, the sibling app of ByteDance’s global short video hit TikTok, said it imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023 to rein in inappropriate practices.</p><p>The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts, including some top influencers, as the platform sought to weed out practices it deemed harmful, such as outdoor live-streaming containing vulgar content, improper challenge games among hosts, as well as enticing viewers to spend more money, the company said in a post published to its official WeChat account on Tuesday.</p><p>Some outdoor live-streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions, according to the post.</p><p>In a joint effort with local authorities in Changsha, the capital of central Hunan province, Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>The banned hosts had engaged in “harmful” outdoor live-streaming activities in Changsha, a major tourist spot which attracted live-streamers who wanted to broadcast its bustling nightlife.</p><p>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was forecast to have made 700 billion yuan (US$98.2 billion) in 2023, according to Statista.</p><p>Improper challenge games and enticed spending were also issues raised by the Cyberspace Administration of China over the past two years, as part of the top Chinese internet watchdog’s campaigns to root out malicious online content.</p><p>Douyin’s live-streaming clampdown also targeted live streamers who were promoting scams, gambling and pornographic content on the platform. Nearly two-thirds, or 190,000, of the hosts banned last year were involved in such activities.</p><p>Through efforts with the Chinese police, more than 300 criminal suspects have been arrested, Douyin said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3247755/watched-strangers-china-mother-live-streams-son-9-doing-homework-says-he-works-3-times-faster" title="">Chinese mother live-streams son, 9, doing homework so he is not distracted</a></h3><p>However, the crackdown is taking a toll on some hosts, who said they were incidentally banned as part of the measures. One host, based in the central province of Anhui, who requested anonymity for fear of retribution by the platform, told the South China Morning Post on Thursday that while she agreed with Douyin’s efforts, it was easy for some veteran hosts to get caught up, adding that losing access to accounts that took years to build up is a high cost.</p><p>Douyin did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Thursday.</p><p>The platform has also been improving the way it manages live streamers. Last September, it introduced a revamped host rating system to take into account multiple factors such as the severity of the alleged malpractice, and the hosts’ level of influence and popularity.</p><p>Meanwhile, verified hosts generating “good” content would be rewarded with support from Douyin to create a “healthy and positive” environment for live-streaming activities.</p><p>The rising trend of using artificial intelligence (AI)-powered virtual hosts has also caught Douyin’s attention. The short video app has put in place rules to require more transparency, with additional identity checks required for the individuals behind such virtual hosts.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1332" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0141f38e-3a8c-4a47-84ce-4ce5fdc448a3_3366798b.jpg" title="In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>More than 765 million Chinese internet users had tuned into live sessions across various online services as of last June, according to data from the China Internet Network Information Centre, representing around 70 per cent of the country’s total 1.079 billion netizens.</p><p>The widespread adoption of live-streaming services has included people of all ages, including minors and seniors, two groups which Douyin said it was paying special attention to.</p><p>Douyin has introduced restrictions that prevent minors from hosting live sessions or tipping other hosts. It also has safeguards that intervene when its system determines an elderly user is falling prey to online scams on its app.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Private-equity investors to return to China in search of M&amp;A deals in 2024, Bain &amp; Co says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248937/private-equity-investors-return-china-search-ma-deals-2024-bain-co-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Global and domestic private-equity investors are returning to Chinese mergers and acquisitions (M&A) market after three consecutive years of decline.</li>    <li>New talks on deal making have resurfaced since the second half of 2023. </li>    <li>It may take longer to conclude the deals, but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted this year.</li>    <li>Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for GDP, consumer inflation, and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March.</li>    <li>Chinese M&A activity is set for a rebound, but 2024 won’t be business as usual.</li>   </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>全球和国内私募股权投资者在连续三年下滑后重返中国并购(M&A)市场。</li>    <li>自2023年下半年以来，关于达成交易的新谈判浮出水面。</li>    <li>达成交易可能需要更长时间，但可以肯定的是，今年将进行更多交易。</li>    <li>北京将于3月公布2024年GDP、消费者通货膨胀和财政赤字的年度增长目标。</li>    <li>中国并购活动有望反弹，但2024年不会像往常一样开展业务。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>   <li>resurface (v.) - /ˌriːsərˈfeɪs/ 重现，浮出水面。    <p>原文例句：New talks on deal making [have] resurfaced since the second half of 2023,” he said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由re-（再次）和surface（表面）构成的，表示“再次出现，浮出水面”。在这个例句中，它指的是新的交易谈判自2023年下半年以来重新出现。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>unveil (v.) - /ʌnˈveɪl/ 揭示，公布。    <p>原文例句：Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for GDP, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由un-（否定）和veil（面纱）组成，表示“揭开面纱，揭示，公布”。在这个句子中，它表示北京将于3月公布2024年GDP、消费者通货膨胀和财政赤字的年度增长目标。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>spur (v.) - /spɜːr/ 刺激，促进。    <p>原文例句：The central government will also prepare new supportive policies to spur the mainland’s economy, he added. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由古英语spurra（马刺）演变而来，表示“刺激，促进”。在这个句子中，它表示中央政府还将准备新的支持政策来刺激大陆经济。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>   <li>take effect - 生效。    <p>原文例句：Moreover, Kang Yi, head of China’s National Bureau of Statistics, said during a press conference on Wednesday that some incentives Beijing rolled out last year – such as the plan to issue 1 trillion yuan (US$139 billion) worth of special treasury bonds – will take effect in 2024. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由take（拿，取）和effect（效果，影响）组成，表示“生效，产生效果”。在这个例句中，它表示中国国家统计局局长康义在星期三的新闻发布会上说，北京去年推出的一些激励措施——比如发行1万亿元特别国债的计划——将在2024年生效。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>dry powder - 可用资金。    <p>原文例句：Private-equity dry powder soared to an unprecedented US$2.59 trillion globally as of December 1 last year, an 8 per cent increase over December 2022’s total of US$2.39 trillion, data by S&P Global and Preqin shows.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由dry（干的，无水的）和powder（粉末）组成，在金融领域表示“可用资金”。在这个例句中，它表示根据S&P Global和Preqin的数据，截至去年12月1日，全球私募股权可动资金达到创纪录的2.59万亿美元，比2022年12月的2.39万亿美元增加了8%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“New talks on deal making [have] resurfaced since the second half of 2023,” he said. - “自2023年下半年以来，关于达成交易的新谈判浮出水面。”他说。<p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是New talks on deal making，谓语是have resurfaced，宾语是since the second half of 2023。这个句子的意思是说，自2023年下半年以来，关于达成交易的新谈判浮出水面。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>   <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for GDP, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, when the annual session of the National People’s Congress is held. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示北京将于3月公布2024年GDP、消费者通货膨胀和财政赤字的年度增长目标，届时全国人民代表大会年度会议将举行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人的建议、愿望、假设等。    <p>原文例句：Global M&A: deal makers to miss US$3 trillion mark for first time in 10 years</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个语法结构，表示说话人的建议、愿望、假设等。这种结构通常使用情态动词（如could、should、would、might等）或虚拟语气助动词（如will、would、should等）+ 动词原形。在这个例句中，它表示全球并购：交易撮合者10年来首次错失3万亿美元大关。这个句子使用情态动词will + 动词原形miss来表示说话人的假设或预测。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>It may take longer to conclude deals, ‘but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted’ in 2024, Bain executive says</li>
<li>Mainland China M&amp;A deals dropped to a nine-year low last year amid a third straight year of declines, Refinitiv data shows</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/3af570e6-afc9-4398-8253-c7bffe73cf71_6190bf99.jpg" /><figcaption>The Liuiazui financial hub in Shanghai. Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for GDP, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, at the National People’s Congress. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Global and domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3246654/china-ma-activity-set-rebound-2024-amid-renewed-overseas-interest-it-wont-be-business-usual-heres" target="_self" title="">private-equity investors</a> are making a comeback to the Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mergers-acquisitions" target="_self" title="">mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;A)</a> market following three straight years of decline, as they look to profit from an economic recovery, global consultancy Bain &amp; Co said.</p><p>Private-equity investors will focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247667/chinese-stocks-darkest-days-may-be-over-earnings-rebound-property-recovery-seen-lifting-gloom-2024" target="_self" title="">improving profitability and bolstering revenue</a> from their portfolio firms, rather than potential frothy valuations, when they are making investment decisions, said Zhou Hao, head of the firm’s Greater China private equity and M&amp;A practice.</p><p>“New talks on deal making [have] resurfaced since the second half of 2023,” he said. “It may take longer to conclude the deals, but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted this year.”</p><p>Bain’s statement is significant because, despite a drop in deal volumes, mainland China still accounted for 41 per cent of deals in the Asia-Pacific region in the first half of 2023, according to S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence.</p><p>Mainland China reported 5,156 M&amp;A deals in 2023, with a combined value of US$301 billion, according to Refinitiv data. This was a nine-year low and a third straight year of declines, in terms of deal volumes.</p><p>US dollar-denominated private-equity funds that have at least half their capital invested in China raised US$1.4 billion in the first half of last year, down about 90 per cent from a year earlier, according to Preqin data.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3248558/asset-manager-blackstone-expand-private-equity-headcount-singapore-southeast-asia-push" title="">Asset manager Blackstone to expand private-equity headcount in Singapore</a></h3><p>However, earlier this month, UBS forecast that profit growth for Chinese listed companies will jump to 8 per cent in 2024 from 3 per cent last year, buoyed by a recovery in the world’s second-largest economy.</p><p>Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for gross domestic product, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, when the annual session of the National People’s Congress is held.</p><p>Moreover, Kang Yi, head of China’s National Bureau of Statistics, said during a press conference on Wednesday that some incentives Beijing rolled out last year – such as the plan to issue 1 trillion yuan (US$139 billion) worth of special treasury bonds – will take effect in 2024. The central government will also prepare new supportive policies to spur the mainland’s economy, he added.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3246654/china-ma-activity-set-rebound-2024-amid-renewed-overseas-interest-it-wont-be-business-usual-heres" title="">China M&amp;A activity set for rebound but 2024 won’t be business as usual</a></h3><p>Most investors with massive amounts of dry powder prefer large-scale businesses to small, high-growth firms, as they chase stable and sustainable returns in a fast-changing market, Bain said.</p><p>Private-equity dry powder soared to an unprecedented US$2.59 trillion globally as of December 1 last year, an 8 per cent increase over December 2022’s total of US$2.39 trillion, data by S&amp;P Global and Preqin shows.</p><p>Bain said in a research report released on Thursday that buyout funds mainly benefited from higher valuations of portfolio firms in China amid increasing price-to-earnings multiples, because investors in new rounds of financing were convinced of their future growth potential.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3245604/global-ma-deal-makers-miss-us3-trillion-mark-first-time-10-years" title="">Global M&amp;A: deal makers to miss US$3 trillion mark for first time in 10 years</a></h3><p>Higher valuations contributed to 55 per cent of the total returns private-equity funds reaped in China from 2012 to 2022, Bain said. Revenue increases contributed to 37 per cent of total returns while only 8 per cent of the returns were derived from profit rises.</p><p>Middle Eastern countries that are eager to shift from fossil fuel-based economies are pursuing opportunities for China inbound M&amp;A deals, particularly in the new energy and electric-vehicles (EV) sectors.</p><p>In October, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3239304/chinese-self-driving-technology-start-ponyai-gets-us100-million-investment-saudi-arabias-smart-city" target="_self" title="">Saudi Arabian smart city developer Neom</a> invested US$100 million in Chinese autonomous driving technology start-up Pony.ai to help fund its research and development and finance its operations.</p><p>On December 18, Chinese EV maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3242863/chinese-ev-maker-nio-sees-ai-robots-replacing-30-cent-workforce-2027-improve-efficiency-cut-costs" target="_self" title="">Nio</a> announced it had raised US$2.2 billion from CYVN Holdings, a fund backed by the Abu Dhabi government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s lottery players bet on AI chatbots to give winning numbers, but none are millionaires yet</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248909/chinas-lottery-players-bet-ai-chatbots-give-winning-numbers-none-are-millionaires-yet</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese social media users share their experiences using generative AI to pick lottery numbers, yet AI chatbots fail to turn them into millionaires. </li>    <li>Gu Xiangnan, a user from Anhui province, tried using numbers generated by Google's Gemini-Pro to buy lottery tickets and won small sums.</li>    <li>Despite interest in AI for lottery predictions, experts emphasize the random nature of lotteries and discourage taking them too seriously as an investment.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国社交媒体用户分享了他们使用生成式人工智能来挑选彩票号码的经历，但人工智能聊天机器人并未让他们成为百万富翁。</li>    <li>来自安徽省的顾湘楠用户尝试使用谷歌的双子座职业版生成的数据来购买彩票，赢得小额奖金。</li>    <li>尽管人们对人工智能进行彩票预测感兴趣，但专家强调彩票的随机性，并劝阻人们将其视为一项投资而过于认真。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>peer (n.) - /pɪər/ 同龄人，伙伴。    <p>原文例句：ChatGPT and its peers are known for giving smart answers to a variety of questions. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语pera（同伴），表示“同龄人，伙伴，等级或地位相等的人”。在这个例句中，它指的是与ChatGPT类似的人工智能聊天机器人。</p></li>    <li>sophisticated (adj.) - /səʊˈfɪstɪkeɪtɪd/ 精致的，复杂的。    <p>原文例句：While sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语sophisticatus（骗取，欺骗），表示“复杂的，精致的，精巧的，熟练的”。在这个例句中，它描述了复杂的人工智能算法，强调它们在预测幸运数字方面与人类相比没有特别的优势。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>pick out - 挑选，选择。    <p>原文例句：She first fed the chatbot with two years’ worth of historical data from Super Lotto. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由pick（挑选）和out（出来）组成的，表示“从一堆东西中挑选，选择”。在这个例句中，它指的是用户将两年的超级大乐透历史数据输入聊天机器人。</p></li>    <li>turn into - 变为，变成。    <p>原文例句：some internet users in China recently found that lottery numbers generated by artificial intelligence (AI) chatbots have yet to turn them into millionaires. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由turn（转动）和into（进入）组成的，表示“变成，变为”。在这个例句中，它指的是一些中国互联网用户发现由人工智能聊天机器人生成的彩票号码还没有让他们变成百万富翁。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China, which logged annual lottery sales of around 600 billion yuan last year, is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets. - 中国去年彩票年销量约为6000亿元人民币，估计有近2亿人定期购买体育彩票和福利彩票。<p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是China is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets，其中主语是China，谓语是is estimated to have，宾语是nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets。which logged annual lottery sales of around 600 billion yuan last year是一个定语从句，修饰China，表示中国去年彩票年销量约为6000亿元人民币。这个句子的意思是说，中国去年彩票年销量约为6000亿元人民币，估计有近2亿人定期购买体育彩票和福利彩票。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示与事实相反的假设或愿望。    <p>原文例句：If sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气结构，结构是：if + 虚拟语气。其中if表示“如果”，虚拟语气表示与事实相反的假设或愿望。在这个例句中，它表示如果复杂的人工智能算法在预测幸运数字方面与人类相比没有特别的优势。这个句子的意思是说，如果复杂的人工智能算法在预测幸运数字方面与人类相比没有特别的优势，那么人们就不会使用人工智能来提高中彩票的几率。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Chinese social media users share their experiences using generative AI to pick lottery numbers</li>
<li>The country is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/ef431a3d-68c7-4027-852b-cc9d3567841e_0b6e9536.jpg" /><figcaption>A lottery shop in Beijing. Photo: SCMP/Simon Song</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT and its peers</a> are known for giving smart answers to a variety of questions, but some internet users in China recently found that lottery numbers generated by artificial intelligence (AI) chatbots have yet to turn them into millionaires.</p><p>In one post that went viral on the Instagram-like platform Xiaohongshu, user Gu Xiangnan from eastern Anhui province shared her experience buying lottery tickets using numbers generated by Google’s Gemini-Pro.</p><p>She first fed the chatbot with two years’ worth of historical data from Super Lotto, one of the most popular of its kind in China that asks players to select five numbers from a set of 35 balls and two bonus numbers from another set of 12 balls.</p><p>Among the five combinations picked by Gemini, two of them each contained two winning numbers, while another two each had one correct bonus number. Gu won no money.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Gu also said she previously spent 20 yuan (US$2.8) betting on Union Lotto, another popular lottery in China, using the same approach, winning 5 yuan in total.</p><p>“Although it was just for fun, there is something worth looking into,” she said.</p><p>Lotteries are designed to be random, meaning that picking the right numbers from millions of possible combinations depends entirely on luck. While sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers, it has not stopped people from using AI to try to boost their chances.</p><p>The Xiaohongshu post was liked by more than 5,000 users, with some commenting that they also won small sums using numbers suggested by generative AI. Gemini-Pro and OpenAI’s ChatGPT are officially unavailable in China, although they can be accessed using a virtual private network.</p><p>China, which logged annual lottery sales of around 600 billion yuan last year, is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets.</p><p>People in other parts of the world have also been turning to generative AI for lottery number suggestions.</p><p>In April, Thai man Patthawikorn Boonrin claimed on TikTok that he won 2,000 baht (US$56) using ChatGPT, according to digital media Mashable. A month later, Singaporean man Aaron Tan won a US$40 cash prize with ChatGPT-generated numbers, according to news portal Yahoo.</p><p>Also in May, Paris-based data scientist Rohith Teja bought a 2.5 euro (US$2.7) lottery ticket using random numbers given by ChatGPT, winning 6 euros. Another ticket that he purchased using numbers generated by ChatGPT through analysing historical data contained no winning numbers at all.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3243129/how-chinas-lottery-boom-reflects-long-and-challenging-road-its-economic-recovery" title="">How China’s lottery boom reflects a ‘long and challenging’ economic recovery</a></h3><p>“The lottery is a highly randomised event that cannot be predicted by any predictive model,” Teja concluded in his blog.</p><p>In the case of Gu, the Xiaohongshu user, Gemini explained to her that it tried to predict lottery results by picking recent lucky numbers that also won more frequently in the past.</p><p>While the chatbot said its selection “had a certain degree of randomness as well as a certain degree of regularity”, it advised against taking the lottery too seriously.</p><p>“Treat lottery as a recreational activity, not a way to invest or make money. Good luck,” it said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple chip supplier TSMC expects a return to ‘healthy growth’, backing hopes for global tech recovery in 2024</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248918/apple-chip-supplier-tsmc-expects-return-healthy-growth-backing-hopes-global-tech-recovery-2024</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  TSMC, the world's largest contract chip manufacturer, expects an at least 8 percent growth in revenue to US$18.8 billion in the March quarter, after a years-long slump in tech demand. It projects a return to solid growth this year and plans to increase capital expenditure to US$28 billion to US$32 billion, indicating an anticipated recovery in smartphone and computing demand.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: TSMC anticipates revenue growth and increased capital spending, suggesting a recovery in tech demand, especially in AI processors.</li>    <li>Theme: TSMC's positive outlook after a period of decline, driven by growing demand for AI chips and advanced packaging technology.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: TSMC's strong position in the contract chip making market, despite challenges in the consumer electronics industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Revenue growth projection, capital expenditure plans, potential return to gross margin, and market dynamics.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  台积电，全球最大的芯片代工制造商，预计本季营收将至少增长 8%，达到 188 亿美元，此前经历了多年的技术需求低迷。预计今年营收将恢复稳健增长，并计划将资本支出从 2023 年的 300 亿美元提高到 280 亿至 320 亿美元，这表明全球最具价值的芯片制造商预计智能手机和计算需求将复苏。作为苹果和 Nvidia Corp 的主要半导体供应商，台积电预计本季度营收将增长至少 8%，达到 188 亿美元，而预期为 182 亿美元左右。该公司还计划将资本支出从 2023 年的 300 亿美元提高到 280 亿至 320 亿美元。虽然台积电的前景并未完全超越最乐观的预期，但这是在技术需求低迷多年之后做出的。然而在最近几周已经出现了芯片制造业复苏的迹象。半导体行业协会估计，在连续下滑一年多之后，11 月份的芯片销量有所上升。台积电首席执行官魏哲家重申，他预计今年将恢复“健康增长”。台积电可望在今年实现低至中20%区间的营收增长。这标志着去年小幅下滑后出现了反弹。  <ul>    <li>摘要：台积电预期营收增长并增加资本支出，表明技术需求复苏，尤其是在 AI 处理器方面。</li>    <li>主题：台积电在一段时间下滑后前景乐观，得益于对 AI 芯片和先进封装技术的需求不断增长。</li>    <li>观点：台积电在芯片代工市场上的强势地位，尽管消费电子行业面临挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：营收增长预测、资本支出计划、潜在的毛利率回归以及市场动态。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>slump (n.) - 大幅下跌，萧条    <p>原文例句：years-long slump in tech demand    <p>例句讲解：The term "slump" is used to describe a significant decline or downturn. In economics, it often refers to a prolonged period of weak economic activity, characterized by decreases in output, employment, and spending. In this sentence, "slump" describes the extended period of declining demand for technology products.</p></li>    <li>anticipate (v.) - 预期，预料    <p>原文例句：anticipates a recovery in smartphone and computing demand    <p>例句讲解：The verb "anticipate" means to expect or foresee something. It implies a degree of certainty or confidence about a future event occurring. In this sentence, it refers to TSMC's expectation of an improvement in demand for smartphones and computing devices.</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>return to solid growth - 恢复稳健增长    <p>原文例句：Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co expects a return to solid growth this quarter    <p>例句讲解：This phrase refers to a period of consistent and substantial economic growth following a period of decline or stagnation. "Return" suggests a reversal of the previous trend, while "solid" emphasizes the strength and stability of the expected growth.</p></li>    <li>year-over-year basis - 同比，按年计算    <p>原文例句：Our business has bottomed out on a year-over-year basis    <p>例句讲解：The term "year-over-year basis" is commonly used in financial and economic contexts to compare the current year's performance with the performance of the previous year during the same period. It allows for a direct comparison, highlighting any changes or trends over time.</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TSMC’s revenue should grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year, he said. - 他表示，今年台积电的营收应以低至中20%区间增长。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单的陈述句，主语是"TSMC's revenue"，谓语是"should grow"，宾语是"in the low- to mid-20 per cent range"，状语是"this year"。这句话的意思是，台积电今年的营收预计将以低至中20%区间增长。</p></li>    <li>Several analysts downgraded Apple on expectations of soft demand, and Jefferies has said the iPhone sales slump in China is likely to deepen. - 多位分析师因预期需求低迷而下调了对苹果的评级，Jefferies表示，中国iPhone销量下滑可能会加剧。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，由两个并列句组成，第一个分句的主语是"Several analysts"，谓语是"downgraded Apple"，宾语是"on expectations of soft demand"；第二个分句的主语是"Jefferies"，谓语是"has said"，宾语是"the iPhone sales slump in China is likely to deepen"。这句话的意思是，多位分析师因预期需求低迷而下调了对苹果的评级，Jefferies表示，中国iPhone销量下滑可能会加剧。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达假设、愿望、猜测或不确定性    <p>原文例句：The Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co logo seen atop a building at the Hsinchu Science Park in Hsinchu, Taiwan, on January 9, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种用于表达假设、愿望、猜测或不确定性的语法结构。它通常通过在句子中使用"should"、"would"、"could"、"might"、"may"等助动词来实现。在引用的句子中，"seen"使用了虚拟语气，表示看到了台积电的标志，但这句话并不是在陈述这个事实，而是在描述一幅照片。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>TSMC, the world’s largest contract chip manufacturer, projected revenue growth of at least 8 per cent to US$18.8 billion in the March quarter</li>
<li>The Taiwanese company’s outlook comes after a years-long slump in tech demand</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/1ba9ec97-57a0-404c-8f10-74bfd74536c6_76fe20b5.jpg" /><figcaption>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co expects revenue to grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year. Image: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc" target="_self" title="">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a> (TSMC) expects a return to solid growth this quarter and gave itself room to raise capital spending this year, suggesting the world’s most valuable chip maker anticipates a recovery in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> and computing demand.</p><p>The main <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> supplier to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/nvidia" target="_self" title="">Nvidia Corp</a> projected revenue growth of at least 8 per cent to US$18.8 billion in the March quarter, versus expectations for around US$18.2 billion. It is also budgeting capital expenditure of US$28 billion to US$32 billion, potentially up from US$30 billion in 2023.</p><p>The Taiwanese company’s outlook, while not quite surpassing the most bullish estimates, comes after a years-long slump in tech demand. But signs of a recovery for the chip-making sector have emerged in recent weeks. The Semiconductor Industry Association estimated chip sales increased in November after more than a year of declines.</p><p>TSMC chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3206603/apple-supplier-tsmc-worlds-biggest-contract-chip-maker-keep-spending-check-amid-weak-global" target="_self" title="">C C Wei</a> reiterated that he expects a return to “healthy growth” this year.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co logo seen atop a building at the Hsinchu Science Park in Hsinchu, Taiwan, on January 9, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1332" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/fa4428f2-8ef6-41b6-af8b-803745c49428_6c52fb99.jpg" title="The Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co logo seen atop a building at the Hsinchu Science Park in Hsinchu, Taiwan, on January 9, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co logo seen atop a building at the Hsinchu Science Park in Hsinchu, Taiwan, on January 9, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>TSMC, which also counts Android chip design firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/qualcomm" target="_self" title="">Qualcomm</a> among its biggest customers, got a boost from frenzied demand for Nvidia’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) processors in 2023.</p><p>It reported net income for the fourth quarter of NT$238.7 billion (US$7.6 billion), beating the average analyst estimate. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247936/tsmc-halts-revenue-drop-beats-expectations-brisk-demand-ai-chips-nvidia-advanced-micro-devices" target="_self" title="">Revenue was US$625.5 billion</a>, TSMC reported earlier, matching the previous holiday quarter and arresting a series of falls.</p><p>“Our business has bottomed out on a year-over-year basis, and we expect 2024 to be a healthy growth year for TSMC,” Wei said.</p><p>TSMC’s revenue should grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year, he said. That marks a rebound from the modest decline of last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247936/tsmc-halts-revenue-drop-beats-expectations-brisk-demand-ai-chips-nvidia-advanced-micro-devices" title="">Chip-making giant TSMC halts revenue drop on brisk AI demand</a></h3><p>“TSMC could lead global chip foundries through 2023-24 industry headwinds, thanks to growing AI chip demand and migration to next-gen process nodes such as N3 in second half of 2023 and N2 by 2025,” Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Charles Shum said in a research note.</p><p>“Although the smartphone and PC chip market remains stagnant, TSMC’s advanced packaging tech, both 2.5D and 3D, fortifies its position in the contract-chip making market, allowing a potential return to a 53 per cent gross margin following a brief second-half downturn.”</p><p>Over the course of 2023, TSMC moderated its capital expenditure plans as the consumer electronics industry grappled with a glut of unsold inventory.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246852/competitive-pay-tsmc-plant-may-ripple-across-japan-beat-inflation" title="">Competitive pay at TSMC plant may ripple across Japan, beat inflation</a></h3><p>But uncertainty persists. This month, fellow contract semiconductor maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> posted its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" target="_self" title="">sixth successive quarter of declining operating profit</a>, as it weathered the impact of muted consumer demand in its own smartphone and memory chip businesses.</p><p>Questions also overshadow mainland China, the world’s largest computing, smartphone, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> and semiconductor market.</p><p>Apple – long one of TSMC’s most important customers – faced headwinds with its latest generation of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhones</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" target="_self" title="">Several analysts downgraded Apple</a> on expectations of soft demand, and Jefferies has said the iPhone sales slump in China is likely to deepen. The US company has also been hit by a widening <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3233603/china-orders-government-workers-stop-using-iphones-amid-heightened-tensions-us" target="_self" title="">ban on foreign-device use among Chinese government agencies</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/state-owned-enterprises" target="_self" title="">state-owned enterprises</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong’s green tech hub goal: nurture start-ups, identify advantages and create talent pool, fintech body says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3248875/hong-kongs-green-tech-hub-goal-nurture-start-ups-identify-advantages-and-create-talent-pool-fintech</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong aims to become a green technology and finance hub, leveraging China's expertise in electric vehicles, renewable energy, and hydrogen energy.</li>    <li>Government and private sector collaboration is crucial to fund start-ups, attract talent, and create a risk-taking mindset.</li>    <li>Hong Kong lacks sufficient early-stage funding for green tech start-ups, limiting their growth potential.</li>    <li>Expanding government financial assistance programs and fostering a risk-taking mindset are essential to drive innovation and attract talent.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>香港的目标是成为绿色技术和金融中心，利用中国在电动汽车、可再生能源和氢能方面的专业知识。</li>    <li>政府和私营部门的合作对于资助初创企业，吸引人才和创造冒险精神至关重要。</li>    <li>香港缺乏足够的绿色科技初创企业的早期资金，限制了它们的增长潜力。</li>    <li>扩大政府的财政援助计划和培养敢于冒险的精神对于激发创新和吸引人才至关重要。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>nurture (v.) - 培养，抚养。    <p>原文例句：The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于古英语nurturen，意思是“抚养，照顾，培育”。在这个例句中，它指的是培养和发展人才库，即培养和发展具有绿色技术领域专业知识的人才。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sub-sector (n.) - 子行业。    <p>原文例句：“We need to identify sub-sectors where we feel Hong Kong has certain advantages.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词由sub-（在……之下的，从属的）和sector（部门，行业）组成，意思是“子行业，细分行业”。在这个例句中，它指的是香港在绿色技术领域中具有某些优势的子行业，即香港在绿色技术领域中具有竞争优势或发展潜力的细分行业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>seed funding - 种子资金。    <p>原文例句：“Some green tech start-ups that have done well after getting seed funding of HK$10 million (US$1.3 million) to HK$20 million have struggled to raise additional financing to fund expansion.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由seed（种子）和funding（资金）组成，意思是“种子资金，创业初期资金”。在这个例句中，它指的是绿色科技初创企业在创业初期获得的资金，即绿色科技初创企业在创业初期为启动业务而募集的资金。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong’s ambition to become an international centre for both green tech and green finance was highlighted by Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po in his budget speech last February.</li><p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是Hong Kong’s ambition，谓语是was highlighted，宾语是by Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po in his budget speech last February。这个句子表示，香港的野心是成为一个国际绿色科技和绿色金融中心，这一点在去年2月的预算演讲中由财政司司长陈茂波强调。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设或愿望。    <p>原文例句：“If efforts are concentrated on supporting start-ups and leveraging China’s expertise in crucial technologies, Hong Kong’s aim of becoming a green technology and finance centre can become a reality.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气的句子，其中if引导了一个条件状语从句，表示如果努力集中在支持初创企业和利用中国在关键技术方面的专业知识，那么香港成为绿色技术和金融中心的目標就可以成为现实。这个句子的意思是说，如果努力集中在支持初创企业和利用中国在关键技术方面的专业知识，那么香港成为绿色技术和金融中心的目標就可以成为现实。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Public-private collaboration to fund start-ups, attracting and nurturing talent can help city achieve green tech, finance hub goal: FinTech Association of Hong Kong</li>
<li>City must leverage China’s dominance in fields such as electric vehicles and renewable energy to its advantage, non-profit’s Sandeep Sethi says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/a4b626bb-229f-49f8-979e-4aaf7649c6cd_f97275b3.jpg" /><figcaption>The Hong Kong government has stated its ambition to become a leading green tech and green finance hub. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>Hong Kong’s aim of becoming a green technology and finance centre can become a reality if efforts are concentrated on supporting start-ups and leveraging China’s expertise in crucial technologies, according to the FinTech Association of Hong Kong.</p><p>The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset, said Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee.</p><p>“Various cities are trying to promote themselves as green tech centres” said Sethi, who is also an independent consultant and a former executive at Deutsche Bank. “We feel it is important for Hong Kong to put that flag up and say we are the leading green tech centre. We need to identify sub-sectors where we feel Hong Kong has certain advantages.”</p><p>Given China’s leadership position in electric vehicles, renewable energy and hydrogen, these sectors can be initial targets for collaborations, he added.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/90970213-f607-4ca0-9991-68a291db888d_798e21ed.jpg" title="FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung" width="2000" /><figcaption>FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung</figcaption></figure></div><p>Hong Kong’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3211122/budget-2023-hong-kong-launches-initiatives-become-global-green-innovation-finance-centre" target="_self" title="">ambition</a> to become an international centre for both green tech and green finance was highlighted by Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po in his budget speech last February. Previously, the focus was on building the city into a leading green and sustainable finance hub in Asia.</p><p>The government followed up its intention by setting up a green technology and finance development committee, comprising leaders from the finance, technology, academic and professional services sectors in June.</p><p>Next month, the government is hosting the Hong Kong GreenTech Week, which aims to bring together green tech businesses and investors from around the world, according to co-organiser Green Development Institute.</p><p>On a more basic level, Hong Kong can do better by providing early-stage funding for start-ups involved in areas such as low-carbon energy products, greenhouse gas emissions and tools for collecting and analysing data on physical climate risks, said Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/78343ebc-5f85-4434-9186-b91134e46289_798e21ed.jpg" title="Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung" width="2000" /><figcaption>Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Some green tech start-ups that have done well after getting seed funding of HK$10 million (US$1.3 million) to HK$20 million have struggled to raise additional financing to fund expansion,” said Barford, who is also the Hong Kong financial services consulting data and analytics lead at consultancy EY.</p><p>The government should consider expanding its financial assistance programmes, which would encourage family offices and institutional investors to take part in fundraising by start-ups, he added.</p><p>Towards that end the Hong Kong government is providing assistance. The different research and development funding schemes overseen by the Innovation and Technology Commission had provided total funding of some HK$400 million to about 130 green tech R&amp;D projects as of last June, according to the Environment and Ecology Bureau.</p><p>The bureau also administers a HK$400 million Green Tech Fund that supports R&amp;D projects in net-zero electricity generation, energy savings, green buildings, green transport and waste reduction. Some 30 projects have received HK$132.5 million since the fund was set up in 2020.</p><p>The government’s Hong Kong Science and Technology Parks Corporation and Cyberport have also set up separate funds to co-invest with angel investors and venture capital funds in start-ups at their respective industry parks.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3244092/hong-kong-regains-appeal-among-global-financial-talent-opportunities-open-fintech-esg-and-markets" title="">Hong Kong regains appeal among global talent amid demand in fintech, ESG</a></h3><p>“There is a gap between the intention and the actual projects that get financed,” said Sethi. “A lot of these are new technology projects where it is hard to prove the business case and profitability. This is where public-private collaborative funding can help.”</p><p>Other difficulties facing the government and industries include growing the talent pool, Sethi said.</p><p>Some 80 per cent of senior finance executives in the city, surveyed late last year by the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, said recruiting green and sustainable finance professionals was more difficult compared with other job functions. Talent retention and acquisition was the second most pressing issue after disclosure regulations.</p><p>Fostering a risk-taking mindset is another challenge, according to Sethi.</p><p>“In a lot of Asian countries, the education systems are focused on preparing students to get stable jobs, but in tech we need entrepreneurs who are willing to take risks,” he said. “It takes years and perhaps generations to change the mindset.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s Vision Pro headset will be missing a Netflix app at launch in February</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248870/apples-vision-pro-headset-will-be-missing-netflix-app-launch-february</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Netflix will not be releasing an app for Apple's upcoming Vision Pro headset, opting instead for web browser access. This means users will not be able to download content for offline viewing or access custom environments. Netflix's decision reflects its competitive stance with Apple in the streaming industry and its wait-and-see approach to the headset's success.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Netflix's decision not to develop a Vision Pro app highlights its competitive stance with Apple and cautious approach to the headset's potential.</li>    <li>Theme: Netflix's strategic choices in the face of Apple's Vision Pro headset launch, including the implications for user experience and industry dynamics.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of Netflix's decision in the context of the streaming industry's evolving landscape and the competition between tech giants.</li>    <li>Main information: Netflix's decision not to create a Vision Pro app; users' inability to download content or access custom environments; Netflix's competitive position in the streaming market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  Netflix 决定不为即将推出的 Apple Vision Pro 头显发布应用程序，而是选择使用网页浏览器访问。这意味着用户将无法下载内容以供离线观看或访问自定义环境。 Netflix 的决定反映了其在流媒体行业与 Apple 的竞争立场，以及其对头显成功的观望态度。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Netflix 决定不开发 Vision Pro 应用程序凸显了其与 Apple 的竞争立场以及对头显潜力的谨慎态度。</li>    <li>主题：Netflix 在 Apple Vision Pro 头显发布背景下的战略选择，包括对用户体验和行业动态的影响。</li>    <li>观点：Netflix 决定在流媒体行业不断变化的格局和科技巨头之间的竞争背景下的意义。</li>    <li>主要信息：Netflix 决定不创建 Vision Pro 应用程序；用户无法下载内容或访问自定义环境；Netflix 在流媒体市场中的竞争地位。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>headset (n.) - /ˈhɛdsɛt/ 头戴式耳机。    <p>原文例句：The Vision Pro headset seen at an unveiling event in Cupertino, California last June. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由head（头部）和set（集合）组成，表示“头戴式耳机”。在这个例句中，它指的是在去年六月份在加利福尼亚州库比蒂诺举行的发布会上展示的Vision Pro头戴式耳机。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>platform (n.) - /ˈplætfɔːm/ 平台。    <p>原文例句：Rather than designing a Vision Pro app – or even just supporting its existing iPad app on the platform – Netflix is essentially taking a pass. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古代法语，表示“平台，讲台”。在这个例句中，它指的是Netflix没有为Vision Pro设计应用程序，也没有在其平台上支持现有的iPad应用程序。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take a pass (v.)  - 略过，不参加。    <P>原文例句：Rather than designing a Vision Pro app – or even just supporting its existing iPad app on the platform – Netflix is essentially taking a pass. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由take（拿，接受）和pass（通过，传球）组成，表示“略过，不参加”。在这个例句中，它表示Netflix没有为Vision Pro设计应用程序，也没有在其平台上支持现有的iPad应用程序。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>key app - 关键的应用程序。    <p>原文例句：It is plausible Netflix does not want to help boost a rival by giving it a key app for its upcoming launch. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由key（关键的）和app（应用程序）组成的，表示“关键的应用程序”。在这个例句中，它指的是Netflix可能不希望通过为苹果公司即将推出的产品提供关键应用程序来帮助其竞争对手。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Netflix is not planning to launch an app for Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset, marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world’s biggest video subscription service. - Netflix不计划为苹果即将推出的Vision Pro头显推出应用程序，这标志着全球最大的视频订阅服务对这项新技术的高调拒绝。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Netflix is not planning to launch an app，其中主语是Netflix，谓语是不定式to launch an app，宾语是for Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset。marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world’s biggest video subscription service是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示Netflix不计划为苹果即将推出的Vision Pro头显推出应用程序这一行为是对这项新技术的高调拒绝。这个句子的意思是说，Netflix不计划为苹果即将推出的Vision Pro头显推出应用程序，这标志着全球最大的视频订阅服务对这项新技术的高调拒绝。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>主动语态 - 表示主语是动作的实施者。    <p>原文例句：Apple is banking on entertainment content to help market the nascent and pricey technology. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个主动语态的句子，主语是Apple，谓语是is banking on，宾语是entertainment content to help market the nascent and pricey technology。这个句子的意思是说，苹果公司指望娱乐内容来帮助营销这项新兴且昂贵的技术。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示主语是动作的承受者。    <p>原文例句：The Vision Pro will run two main types of apps: new software written specifically for the device’s interface or existing iPad applications. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是two main types of apps，谓语是被动语态的will run，宾语是new software written specifically for the device’s interface or existing iPad applications。这个句子的意思是说，Vision Pro将运行两类主要应用程序：专门为该设备界面编写的软件或现有的iPad应用程序。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Rather than designing a Vision Pro app or supporting its existing iPad app on the platform, Netflix says users can watch its content on a web browser</li>
<li>The approach means Vision Pro users will not be able to download Netflix content to watch offline on an aeroplane</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0daed4bb-8aac-444e-9863-2f6975c1c780_21ab5745.jpg" /><figcaption>The Apple Vision Pro headset seen at an unveiling event in Cupertino, California last June. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netflix" target="_self" title="">Netflix</a> is not planning to launch an app for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3223224/apples-vision-pro-best-ar-and-vr-mixed-reality-headset-market-and-represents-future-computing-even" target="_self" title="">Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset</a>, marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world’s biggest video subscription service.</p><p>Rather than designing a Vision Pro app – or even just supporting its existing iPad app on the platform – Netflix is essentially taking a pass. The company, which competes with Apple in streaming, said in a statement that users interested in watching its content on the device can do so from the web.</p><p>It is a sizeable omission for the US$3,499 headset, which debuts on February 2. Apple is banking on entertainment content to help market the nascent and pricey technology, and Netflix is a must-have streaming service for many consumers.</p><p>Netflix also offers apps for Apple’s other devices, including the iPhone and iPad, though it does not participate in the company’s TV app.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1329" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/27470cf7-0ad7-471c-936b-45ab61159d8c_ce1fbea2.jpg" title="The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Vision Pro will run two main types of apps: new software written specifically for the device’s interface or existing iPad applications. Apple has sought to make it easy to transfer developers’ current iPad apps over to the new platform, aiming to quickly amass a wide range of Vision Pro software.</p><p>The fact that Netflix is not even willing to support the iPad approach suggests that it is taking a wait-and-see stance with the headset. It is also a bit of a reversal for the company, which said in July that it would support its iPad app on the Vision Pro. Even then, though, Netflix did not plan to release software specifically for the headset’s operating system, visionOS.</p><p>“Our members will be able to enjoy Netflix on the web browser on the Vision Pro, similar to how our members can enjoy Netflix on Macs,” Los Gatos, California-based Netflix said in the statement. Apple declined to comment.</p><p>In contrast with its Vision Pro strategy, Netflix did develop an app for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236053/meta-launches-quest-3-vr-and-ar-headset-just-ahead-apples-vision-pro" target="_self" title="">Meta Platforms’ Quest headsets</a>, though it has not been updated in years.</p><p>The approach means it will be harder for users to access Netflix on the Vision Pro. And they will not be able to download Netflix content to watch offline, potentially making it more of a pain to use on an aeroplane.</p><p>The lack of an app also means Netflix watchers will not have access to custom environments for streaming. That means Netflix cannot create specialised immersive backdrops for its users to watch videos in.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="998" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/946981d0-f40f-4bc7-b1f9-bd435067d043_6ca422b1.jpg" title="An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>While Netflix and Apple do not compete in TV hardware, they are both currently vying for subscribers in the streaming industry.</p><p>Apple is a small player in this category, with less than 10 per cent of the US market. But it has been gathering award wins in the space, and the two companies compete over talent and production deals. It is plausible Netflix does not want to help boost a rival by giving it a key app for its upcoming launch.</p><p>Apple has been marketing the Vision Pro as an entertainment device in the run-up to pre-orders beginning on Friday.</p><p>The Cupertino, California-based company said earlier this week that the headset would have many entertainment options beyond its own TV+ service. That includes programming from Disney+, Max, Peacock, ESPN and Amazon Prime Video, among others.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung Galaxy S24 series smartphones come with Google Gemini AI technology to fight Apple iPhones</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248863/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-smartphones-come-google-gemini-ai-technology-fight-apple-iphones</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Samsung unveils its new Galaxy S24 smartphone series with enhanced AI features, such as real-time translation, voice recording transcription, web article summarization, handwriting correction, and generative AI for photo editing, to compete with Apple's upcoming iPhones.<br>.<br>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung's New Galaxy S24 Series Redefines Smartphone AI Capabilities.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's technological advancements in AI features give it an edge over competitors, aiming to regain market share lost to Apple.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of AI integration in smartphones and its potential to revolutionize user experience, as well as the ongoing rivalry between Samsung and Apple in the smartphone market.</li>    <li>Main information: Unveiling of the Galaxy S24, S24+, and S24 Ultra with Gemini AI technology from Google; features such as live translation, transcription, summarization, handwriting correction, and generative AI; slimmer bezels, brighter displays, and upgraded camera systems; partnership with Google for exclusive generative AI offerings; release date of January 31st, with pre-orders starting on the same day.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  三星推出新款Galaxy S24智能手机系列，具有增强的AI功能，如实时翻译、语音录音转录、网页文章摘要、手写纠正和用于照片编辑的生成式AI，以与苹果即将推出的iPhone竞争。<br>.<br>  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星新款Galaxy S24系列重新定义智能手机AI功能。</li>    <li>主题：三星在人工智能技术方面的进步给了它领先于竞争对手的优势，并旨在夺回让给了苹果的市场份额。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能集成在智能手机中的重要性及其革新用户体验的潜力，以及三星和苹果在智能手机市场中持续的竞争。</li>    <li>主要信息：采用来自谷歌的Gemini人工智能技术的Galaxy S24、S24+和S24 Ultra手机发布；实时翻译、转录、摘要、手写纠正和生成式人工智能等功能；更窄的边框、更亮的显示屏，以及升级后的摄像头系统；与谷歌合作独家提供生成式人工智能产品；1月31日发布，当天开始预订。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revamp (v.) - /ˈrɪvæmp/ 革新，改造，翻新。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones, betting that the technology can give it an advantage over Apple’s iPhone.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由re-（重新）和vamp（使焕然一新）组成，表示“革新，改造，翻新”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星电子正在转向人工智能（AI）功能来改造其旗舰Galaxy智能手机，赌这种技术可以使之在与苹果iPhone的竞争中占优势。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>bezel (n.) - /ˈbɛzəl/ 边框，边框，外框。    <p>原文例句：The borders around the displays are 42 per cent thinner, and the screen is 40 per cent brighter than the phone’s predecessor.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古法语besel，表示“边框，边框，外框”。在这个例句中，它指的是手机屏幕周围的边框。这句话的意思是，与手机的前代产品相比，这款手机屏幕周围的边框减少了42%，而且屏幕更亮了40%。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>get fired - 被解雇，被开除。    <p>原文例句：If you get fired then I will get fired. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由get（得到，获得）和fired（解雇，开除）组成，表示“被解雇，被开除”。在这个例句中，它指的是“然被开除了”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>get a head start - 获得领先优势，抢先一步。    <p>原文例句：Samsung looks to reverse its fortunes by getting a several-month head start on AI. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由get（得到，获得）和a head start（领先优势）组成，表示“获得领先优势，抢先一步”。在这个例句中，它指的是“三星通过在人工智能领域获得几个月的领先优势来扭转其颓势”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The S24 Ultra replaces one of its 10-megapixel telephoto cameras with a 50-megapixel version. - S24 Ultra将其10百万像素的长焦摄像头之一替换为50百万像素的版本。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是The S24 Ultra，谓语是replaces，宾语是one of its 10-megapixel telephoto cameras，介词短语with a 50-megapixel version是谓语replaces的补语。这个句子的意思是：S24 Ultra将其10百万像素的长焦摄像头之一替换为50百万像素的版本。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级和最高级 - 形容词和副词的比较级和最高级用于比较两个或多个事物或人的质量或程度。    <p>原文例句：That component offers the latest Wi-fi capabilities and will handle AI-assisted features such as live translation and transcription, Qualcomm said.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级和最高级是形容词和副词的变形，用于比较两个或多个事物或人的质量或程度。比较级通常用“more”或“less”加形容词或副词的形式表示，最高级通常用“most”或“least”加形容词或副词的形式表示。在这个例句中，“latest”是形容词“late”的最高级，表示“最晚的，最新的”。这句话的意思是，该组件提供了最新的Wi-fi功能，并将处理AI辅助的功能，如实时翻译和转录，高通表示。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones, betting that the technology can give it an advantage over Apple’s iPhone.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。其结构为：have/has been + 现在分词。在这个例句中，“is turning”是现在完成时的形式，表示三星电子正在转向使用人工智能（AI）功能来改造其旗舰Galaxy智能手机，并且这种状态一直持续到现在。这句话的意思是，三星电子正在转向使用人工智能（AI）功能来改造其旗舰Galaxy智能手机，赌这种技术可以使之在与苹果iPhone的竞争中占优势。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra can live-translate phone calls, transcribe voice recordings, summarise web articles and fix handwriting</li>
<li>Apple is not expected to showcase its latest plans for artificial intelligence until June, ahead of new iPhones arriving around September</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0bde60ec-206d-4f06-b93f-8cfac56d664e_ad59a457.jpg" /><figcaption>An influencer poses with Samsung’s new phones at the Galaxy Unpacked event in San Jose, California. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones, betting that the technology can give it an advantage over Apple’s iPhone.</p><p>At its Unpacked conference Wednesday in San Jose, California, Samsung unveiled the Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra phones, which all add AI tools based on the Gemini technology from Alphabet’s Google.</p><p>The devices can live-translate phone calls, transcribe voice recordings, summarise web articles, fix handwriting and use generative AI to fill in parts of photos.</p><p>The launch is one of the most ambitious attempts to weave AI into a smartphone’s interface and features. The new devices also provide Google with a chance to put its most advanced software in the hands of more users, a potential edge in its fight for AI dominance with Microsoft and start-up OpenAI.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="From left to right, Samsung’s Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra smartphones. Photo: AP Photo" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/4ab7c02b-e978-4125-8c59-49f05c81b629_1126e908.jpg" title="From left to right, Samsung’s Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra smartphones. Photo: AP Photo" width="2000" /><figcaption>From left to right, Samsung’s Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra smartphones. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure></div><p>The AI features are the highlight of the new phones, but the devices are also getting slimmer bezels and brighter displays. Samsung is paying special attention to its top-end model, the S24 Ultra. That product, which starts at US$1,299, will have a new titanium frame, matching the iPhone 15 Pro models released in September.</p><p>The borders around the displays are 42 per cent thinner, and the screen is 40 per cent brighter than the phone’s predecessor. It also sports flatter edges and a front-facing camera cut-out that is 11 per cent smaller.</p><p>The US$799 S24 and US$999 S24+ come in aluminium and get slightly larger screens than their predecessors, moving from 6.1-inch and 6.6-inch panels to 6.2-inch and 6.7-inch displays, respectively. The S24 Ultra, like the S23 Ultra, has a 6.8-inch screen.</p><p>Qualcomm is providing the main chip of the new Samsung phones in at least some regions. The S24 line-up will be based on its Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 applications processor, the company said in a separate statement. That component offers the latest Wi-fi capabilities and will handle AI-assisted features such as live translation and transcription, Qualcomm said.</p><p>The new models come at a crucial time for Samsung, which is contending with market share losses and a broader smartphone slump. Last year, it lost its crown as the No 1 smartphone supplier to Apple, marking the first time Samsung has not led the market since 2010.</p><p>Samsung’s phone shipments declined nearly 14 per cent to 226.6 million units in 2023, according to research firm IDC. Apple, on the other hand, saw unit shipments increase 3.7 per cent to 234.6 million.</p><p>Samsung looks to reverse its fortunes by getting a several-month head start on AI. Apple is not expected to showcase its latest plans for artificial intelligence until June, ahead of new iPhones arriving around September. The new Galaxy phones come out on January 31, with pre-orders starting Wednesday.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Interpreter application on a Samsung S24 Ultra smartphone. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/6f875bae-b575-4bd1-9cab-fc3b1f6d77c4_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="The Interpreter application on a Samsung S24 Ultra smartphone. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Interpreter application on a Samsung S24 Ultra smartphone. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Samsung decided to adopt the Gemini AI technology after surveying offerings from competitors, according to Thomas Kurian, head of Google’s cloud computing unit. As part of a multi-year agreement, Google will be the sole provider of generative AI for Samsung’s phones and applications, including features for taking notes and recording audio, according to Kurian.</p><p>“This is a validation of the quality of our models,” Kurian said. “They were free to choose whoever they wanted.”</p><p>Users will be able to switch between two options: one called Gemini Nano that runs on the phone itself and a higher-powered Pro version that uses cloud computing. That flexibility helped Google’s offerings stand out from the competition, Kurian said.</p><p>In conjunction with Samsung’s announcements, Google also introduced a feature called “Circle to Search,” which lets people search anything on their phone screens without switching apps.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/1452f636-7686-4413-86a3-f946ab0883d5_34f54c2a.jpg" title="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Users of Google’s Android operating system can scribble or circle on top of images, text or video in the app they are on – say, YouTube Shorts or TikTok – to find out more information about the item. The feature is launching globally on the new Galaxy S24, as well as on Google’s own Pixel 8 smartphones on January 31.</p><p>AI features on the Samsung devices will also let users change the language of a message depending on the context, such as whether it is a work memo or social media post. And new capabilities for Android Auto – Google’s in-car interface – will summarise incoming text messages and other alerts.</p><p>The companies are also applying AI to the phones’ camera systems, which are getting upgraded with new sensors, with tools to make photos sharper. The S24 Ultra replaces one of its 10-megapixel telephoto cameras with a 50-megapixel version. The S24 and S24+, meanwhile, include the same camera specifications as their predecessors.</p><p>The S24 Ultra comes with as much as 1 terabyte of storage, while the S24+ tops out at 512 gigabytes. The S24 has as much as 256GB of space. The S24+ and S24 Ultra include 12GB of memory, which is used for shorter-term storage of data, while the regular S24 has 8GB.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
