<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Elon Musk’s Tesla loses US$94 billion in market valuation as winter sets in for global electric vehicle market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248400/elon-musks-tesla-loses-us94-billion-market-valuation-winter-sets-global-electric-vehicle-market</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  Elon Musk’s electric vehicle maker Tesla had a blockbuster 2023, but 2024 is starting on a different note. The company has lost more than US$94 billion in market valuation in the first two weeks of this year due to negative news, including price cuts for its made-in-China cars and rising labor costs. The challenges for Tesla are exacerbated by slowing growth in demand for EVs and increasing competition in the EV industry. Tesla's stock is experiencing its worst start to any year since 2016, and even CEO Elon Musk has seen his net worth shrink significantly. Tesla remains a key player in the global transition to electric vehicles, but its valuation may be too high for its current performance.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tesla's market valuation has plummeted due to negative news and challenges in the EV market.</li>    <li>Theme: Tesla's struggles in 2024 after a successful 2023, highlighting the company's challenges and the impact on its market valuation.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The role of negative news, slowing demand, rising competition, and production issues in Tesla's decline; the argument that Tesla's valuation is not justified by its current performance.</li>    <li>Main information: Tesla's market valuation loss of US$94 billion; Hertz Global Holdings' reversal on EVs; China price cuts; rising labor costs; slowing EV demand; Tesla's automotive gross margin decline; production suspension in Germany; Tesla's stock performance comparison; Elon Musk's net worth decrease; Tesla's position in the global EV transition.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary:</h2>  埃隆·马斯克的电动汽车制造商特斯拉在2023年风光无限，但2024年的开局却截然不同。由于包括中国制造汽车降价和劳动力成本上升在内的负面消息，该公司在今年的前两周市值蒸发了940亿美元以上。特斯拉面临的挑战还包括电动汽车需求增长放缓以及电动汽车行业竞争加剧。特斯拉的股票正经历自2016年以来最糟糕的开年表现，即使是首席执行官埃隆·马斯克的净资产也大幅缩水。特斯拉仍然是全球电动汽车转型中的关键参与者，但其估值可能对其当前表现来说过高。  <ul>    <li>摘要：由于负面新闻和电动汽车市场的挑战，特斯拉的市值暴跌。</li>    <li>主题：特斯拉在2023年取得成功后于2024年的挣扎，突显了该公司的挑战及其对市值的影响。</li>    <li>观点：负面新闻、需求放缓、竞争加剧和生产问题在特斯拉衰落中的作用；认为特斯拉的估值与其当前表现不符的论点。</li>    <li>主要信息：特斯拉市值损失940亿美元；赫兹全球控股公司对电动汽车的逆转；中国降价；劳动力成本上升；电动汽车需求放缓；特斯拉汽车毛利率下降；德国生产暂停；特斯拉股票表现对比；埃隆·马斯克净资产减少；特斯拉在全球电动汽车转型中的地位。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>plummet (v.) - /ˈplʌmɪt/ 暴跌。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由plum（李子）和-et（小）组成的，表示“像李子一样掉落”，引申为“暴跌”。在这个例句中，它表示特斯拉因红海的安全问题而大规模暂停了其德国柏林-勃兰登堡超级工厂的生产。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>exacerbate (v.) - /ɪɡˈzæsərbeɪt/ 加剧。    <p>原文例句：“We are going through a cyclical downturn for EVs, but competitive dynamics are exacerbating the cyclical pressures,” Ivana Delevska, chief investment officer at Spear Invest, said in an interview. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由ex-（使……变为）和acerbate（使恶化）构成的，表示“使恶化，加剧”。在这个例句中，它表示斯皮尔投资的首席投资官伊万娜·德莱夫斯卡说道：“我们正在经历电动汽车的周期性低迷，但竞争动态正在加剧周期性压力”。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>chime in - 发表意见，参与讨论。    <p>原文例句：Almost immediately after, carmakers and suppliers across the globe chimed in with their own downbeat forecasts. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由chime（钟声）和in（进入）构成的，表示“敲钟进入”，引申为“发表意见，参与讨论”。在这个例句中，它表示几乎紧随其后，全球的汽车制造商和供应商都发表了他们自己的悲观预测。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand. - 特斯拉自去年初以来一直在积极降价，以提振需求。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Tesla，谓语是has been cutting，宾语是prices on its cars。since early last year in an effort to boost demand是一个时间状语和目的状语，分别表示特斯拉自去年初以来一直在这样做，目的是为了提振需求。这个句子的意思是说，特斯拉自去年初以来一直在积极降价，以提振需求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装 - 为了强调或增加修辞效果而改变常规的语序。    <p>原文例句：Naturally, Musk is taking a big hit personally. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，常规语序应该是Musk is naturally taking a big hit personally。倒装句通常用于强调或增加修辞效果。在这个例句中，它表示毫无疑问，马斯克本人受到了沉重打击。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>形容词作宾语补足语 - 用于形容或给宾语提供更多信息。    <p>原文例句：The market capitalisation to start the year is the biggest Tesla has seen over a similar period since it went public in 2010. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个形容词作宾语补足语的例子。形容词biggest表示“最大的”，作宾语补足语，对宾语The market capitalisation to start the year进行了补充说明。这个句子的意思是说，自2010年上市以来，特斯拉在类似的时期内经历的最大市值损失出现在今年年初。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Tesla’s losses in the first two weeks of this year have come from a barrage of negative news, including another price cut for its made-in-China cars</li>
<li>The US carmaker has been cutting prices on its vehicles aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/83cb01fa-622e-4130-b271-fd9276597c55_850fb60a.jpg" /><figcaption>Tesla chief executive Elon Musk applauds the roll-out of new electric vehicles at the opening of the firm’s Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant  in Germany on March 22, 2022. Photo:  AP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> had a blockbuster 2023, as its shares more than doubled in 12 months. But 2024 is starting on a different note, with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/elon-musk" target="_self" title="">Elon Musk</a>’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle</a> (EV) maker off to its worst start to any year – ever.</p><p>The company has lost more than US$94 billion in market valuation in just the first two weeks of this year. It is not hard to figure out why, as the Austin, Texas-based EV maker has been pounded by a barrage of negative news: an about-face on EVs from the car rental giant Hertz Global Holdings, yet another price cut for its cars <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-manufacturing" target="_self" title="">made in China</a>, and signs of rising labour costs.</p><p>All of this comes in the face of slowing growth in demand for EVs, especially in the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>.</p><p>“Investors’ main concern on Tesla is stagnating growth,” Cowen analyst Jeffrey Osborne said in an interview. The price cuts in China only fan those concerns, because it is starting to look like “a race to the bottom for the EV industry given intense competition in that market”.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/b52c250b-b6c8-47e5-91ec-7f2278c772c1_a66cec46.jpg" title="A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The hit to Tesla’s market capitalisation to start the year is the biggest the company has seen over a similar period since it went public in 2010. In percentage terms, Tesla’s 12 per cent drop since the start of January is the worst since 2016, when the stock fell 14 per cent over the first nine trading days of the year.</p><p>To make matters worse, the odds of an imminent turnaround for the EV maker do not look good.</p><p>Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early 2023 in an effort to boost demand. But the result has been a steady erosion of its once-hefty profit margin. Tesla’s automotive gross margin ex-regulatory credits for the third quarter fell to 16.3 per cent from 27.9 per cent a year ago. And the pressure is only mounting, now that production workers at Tesla’s US plants are getting pay rises.</p><p>“We are going through a cyclical downturn for EVs, but competitive dynamics are exacerbating the cyclical pressures,” Ivana Delevska, chief investment officer at Spear Invest, said in an interview. “Price cuts and plummeting margins are all a function of these unfavourable competitive dynamics.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing" title="">Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</a></h3><p>Adding to the woes, Tesla has had to divert shipments destined for its Berlin plant after Western military actions and security concerns in the Red Sea, and is suspending most production at its plant near the German capital from January 29 to February 11, according to a person familiar with the matter.</p><p>Tesla first warned about the deceleration in EV demand during its October third-quarter earnings report. Almost immediately after, carmakers and suppliers across the globe chimed in with their own downbeat forecasts. Many carmakers dialled back their plans for expansion.</p><p>Then, earlier this month, Tesla reported its fourth-quarter delivery numbers. While they were better than what analysts expected, they put the company behind China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD Co</a> in global electric-car sales.</p><p>The result has been a rude awakening for Tesla investors. Last year, the stock was the eighth best performer in the S&amp;P 500. So far this year, it is the eighth worst.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="12 January 2024, Brandenburg, Gruenheide: The Tesla Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant. Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa" class="image-inline caption" height="1201" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/47b22035-65d8-46f4-a5cf-8ceaf3d20b48_c243b8f2.jpg" title="12 January 2024, Brandenburg, Gruenheide: The Tesla Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant. Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa" width="2000" /><figcaption>12 January 2024, Brandenburg, Gruenheide: The Tesla Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant. Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Naturally, Musk is taking a big hit personally. The world’s richest person, who gained more wealth last year than anyone else on the planet, has seen his net worth shrink by US$23 billion so far this year, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index.</p><p>Musk regained the top spot on Bloomberg’s wealth index last year, overtaking LVMH Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton founder and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226276/lvmh-boss-bernard-arnaults-visit-highlights-growing-importance-huge-mainland-chinese-market-luxury" target="_self" title="">Bernard Arnault</a>, but now <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon.com</a> founder and executive chairman <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jeff-bezos" target="_self" title="">Jeff Bezos</a> is rapidly closing in, with US$179 billion to Musk’s US$206 billion as of Friday’s close.</p><p>The bulk of Musk’s net worth comes from his 13 per cent stake in Tesla and about 304 million exercisable stock options. He also owns about 42 per cent of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/spacex" target="_self" title="">Space Exploration Technologies</a>, which is valued at about US$53 billion, according to Bloomberg’s wealth index.</p><p>With all that being said, Tesla remains a key player in the global transition from petrol-powered vehicles to largely electric ones. The reason: the company is so far ahead of its potential rivals. China’s BYD may have surpassed Tesla in the number of units sold, but it still lags in revenue and profits. And BYD does not sell cars in the US, where Tesla remains the market leader.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>In many ways, Tesla’s biggest problem may be its past success and the hope it generated. As investors piled into the stock, Tesla’s market capitalisation ballooned, making it way larger than any other car company in the world. However, with the shares priced for perfection, that also made them highly vulnerable to big reactions to any negative news.</p><p>That is why so many Tesla proponents argue that it should not be compared to regular car companies. To them, the ultimate true value of the company rests in the future and it is hope to develop the first truly <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/self-driving-cars-autonomous-vehicles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">self-driving vehicles</a>. The only problem is Tesla has been promising this for years, and most experts say the technology is still years, maybe even decades, away.</p><p>“Tesla has not been able to deliver on fully autonomous driving and AI promises, which are already embedded in the valuation,” Spear’s Delevska said. “Being simply another automotive manufacturer is not going to cut it for a US$750 billion valuation.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese etching tools giant AMEC sees 2023 sales rise more than 30% on strong demand from mainland semiconductor fabs</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248391/chinese-etching-tools-giant-amec-sees-2023-sales-rise-more-30-strong-demand-mainland-semiconductor</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Chinese etching tools giant Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment (AMEC) expects revenue last year to grow more than 30 per cent from 2022. This growth is attributed to core technology breakthroughs enabling the deployment of more chip-making gear to domestic semiconductor fabrication plants. AMEC's positive earnings guidance reflects its successful strategy to expand sales in China, driven by the need to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts due to US semiconductor sanctions.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: AMEC expects significant revenue growth in 2023 driven by strong domestic demand and technology advancements.</li>    <li>Theme: AMEC's success in replacing foreign-produced components with domestic parts amid US sanctions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of domestic innovation and self-reliance in the semiconductor industry.</li>    <li>Main information: AMEC's projected revenue growth, new orders, net profit increase, and market share gains.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  中国刻蚀设备巨头中微半导体预计去年收入将比2022年增长30%以上。这得益于核心技术突破，使该公司能够向国内半导体制造厂部署更多芯片制造设备。中微半导体积极的盈利预测反映出其成功的销售扩张战略，其驱动力是需要在美国半导体制裁背景下用国产零件替代国外生产的组件。  <ul>    <li>摘要：受益于强劲的国内需求和技术进步，中微半导体预计在2023年实现显著的营收增长。</li>    <li>主题：中微半导体在美国制裁下成功用国产零件替代国外生产的组件。</li>    <li>观点：半导体行业自主创新和自给自足的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：中微半导体预计的收入增长、新订单、净利润增长和市场份额增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.əˌnjuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：The company said sales of its core etching tools will account for 75 per cent of its total revenue last year</p>    <p>例句讲解：“revenue”表示公司从销售商品或提供服务中获得的收入或收益。在这个例句中，它指的是中微半导体去年核心刻蚀工具销售额占其总收入的75%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>semiconductor (n.) - /ˌsemiː.kənˈdʌk.tər/ 半导体。    <p>原文例句：AMEC’s positive earnings guidance reflects its successful strategy to expand sales on the mainland, months after founder, chairman and chief executive Gerald Yin Zhiyao said the firm had devised a detailed road map to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts amid tightened US semiconductor sanctions.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“semiconductor”是指一种具有导电性介于导体和绝缘体之间的材料，常用于制造电子元器件和集成电路。在这个例句中，它指的是中微半导体在美国半导体制裁背景下用国产零件替代国外生产的组件的战略。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>core technology - 核心技术。    <P>原文例句：core technology breakthroughs enabled the firm to deploy more chip-making gear to domestic semiconductor fabrication plants</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由core（核心）和technology（技术）组成，表示“核心技术”，即对产品或服务至关重要的关键技术。在这个例句中，它指的是中微半导体在核心技术上的突破，使该公司能够向国内半导体制造厂部署更多芯片制造设备。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>AMEC expects sales of its core etching tools, including so-called capacitively coupled plasma (CCP) and inductive coupled plasma (ICP), to account for 75 per cent of the firm’s total revenue last year, which would be up nearly 50 per cent to 4.7 billion yuan. - 中微半导体预计去年核心刻蚀工具销售额，包括电容耦合等离子体（CCP）和电感耦合等离子体（ICP），将占公司总收入的75%，这将比47亿元增长近50%。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是AMEC expects sales of its core etching tools to account for 75 per cent of the firm’s total revenue last year，其中主语是AMEC，谓语是expects，宾语是sales of its core etching tools to account for 75 per cent of the firm’s total revenue last year。包括so-called capacitively coupled plasma (CCP) and inductive coupled plasma (ICP)是一个分词短语作定语，修饰sales of its core etching tools，表示这些销售额包括电容耦合等离子体（CCP）和电感耦合等离子体（ICP）。which would be up nearly 50 per cent to 4.7 billion yuan是一个结果状语，表示这一增长将使销售额达到47亿元，比去年增长近50%。这个句子的意思是说，中微半导体预计去年核心刻蚀工具销售额，包括电容耦合等离子体（CCP）和电感耦合等离子体（ICP），将占公司总收入的75%，这将比47亿元增长近50%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词作宾语 - 表示过去发生的行为或状态对现在有影响。    <p>原文例句：AMEC’s positive earnings guidance reflects its successful strategy to expand sales on the mainland, months after founder, chairman and chief executive Gerald Yin Zhiyao said the firm had devised a detailed road map to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts amid tightened US semiconductor sanctions.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去分词作宾语的例子，其中reflects是reflect的过去分词，作谓语动词guidance的宾语，表示AMEC的积极盈利预测反映了该公司成功的销售扩张战略。said是say的过去分词，作谓语动词had devised的宾语，表示创始人、董事长兼首席执行官杰拉尔德·尹志尧说该公司已经制定了详细的路线图，以在收紧美国半导体制裁之际用国产零件替换国外生产的组件。这个句子的意思是说，AMEC的积极盈利预测反映了该公司成功的销售扩张战略，这是在创始人、董事长兼首席执行官杰拉尔德·尹志尧说该公司已经制定了详细的路线图，以在收紧美国半导体制裁之际用国产零件替换国外生产的组件之后几个月提出的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Shanghai-based AMEC expects its 2023 revenue to reach US$879 million, up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic orders</li>
<li>The company said sales of its core etching tools will account for 75 per cent of its total revenue last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/977166e1-00b7-4d05-941a-ada3e90b90d0_07dcf1ac.jpg" /><figcaption>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment workers at the company’s main production site in Shanghai. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese etching tools giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3232334/tech-war-china-chip-tool-firm-amecs-profit-boosted-strong-local-demand-it-reshuffles-tech-board-wake" target="_self" title="">Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment</a> (AMEC) expects revenue last year to grow more than 30 per cent from 2022, as core <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> breakthroughs enabled the firm to deploy more chip-making gear to domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> fabrication plants.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a>-based AMEC said in a regulatory filing on Sunday that its 2023 revenue is expected to reach 6.26 billion yuan (US$879 million), up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic demand. The company said it recorded 8.36 billion yuan worth of new orders, a 32.3 per cent year-on-year increase.</p><p>Net profit last year is projected to be from 1.7 billion yuan to 1.85 billion yuan, representing year-on-year growth of between 45 per cent and 58 per cent.</p><p>AMEC’s positive earnings guidance reflects its successful strategy to expand sales on the mainland, months after founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230803/us-wants-chinas-chip-industry-5-generations-behind-cutting-edge-head-equipment-maker-amec-says-wuxi" target="_self" title="">Gerald Yin Zhiyao</a> said the firm had devised a detailed road map to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy" target="_self" title="">tightened US semiconductor sanctions</a>.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/8dc83513-a48d-478e-9d86-f625246bf8fe_ada0205e.jpg" title="Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Yin had said 80 per cent of US-restricted components that AMEC used would be replaced with domestic parts by the end of last year. He expected the company to achieve a 100-per cent replacement rate in 2024.</p><p>AMEC shares in Shanghai closed down 2.07 per cent to 134.66 yuan last Friday.</p><p>With state-backed efforts to localise great swathes of China’s semiconductor supply chain, mainland semiconductor foundries have accelerated adoption of locally made equipment since October 2022, when Washington <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3195461/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-self-sufficiency-drive-under-siege-new" target="_self" title="">first tightened export controls</a> to cut off the country’s access to advanced chip-making gear from the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">US</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netherlands" target="_self" title="">the Netherlands</a>.</p><p>AMEC expects sales of its core etching tools, including so-called capacitively coupled plasma (CCP) and inductive coupled plasma (ICP), to account for 75 per cent of the firm’s total revenue last year, which would be up nearly 50 per cent to 4.7 billion yuan.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1414" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/646d3f0c-dcc0-4e3c-87fa-0e91b99b21a2_bfef4330.jpg" title="Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>AMEC said that its CCP and ICP equipment saw increased adoption by domestic foundry clients on the strength of the firm’s breakthroughs in core technologies last year.</p><p>Etching tools are some of the most important processing equipment used by semiconductor foundries. It is an area where China has strong players such as AMEC and state-backed Naura Technology Group.</p><p>AMEC’s domestic CCP equipment market share is projected to hit 60 per cent in the near future, up from 24 per cent in October 2022. The firm’s share in ICP gear sales on the mainland is predicted to reach 75 per cent from almost zero, according to company chief executive Yin, after once-dominant US chip equipment maker Lam Research saw its mainland sales drop sharply.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China price wars help spark US$157 billion rout in mainland consumer stocks, as firms including Alibaba, Yum China and BYD drag the market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248377/china-price-wars-help-spark-us157-billion-rout-mainland-consumer-stocks-firms-including-alibaba-yum</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Consumer stocks have underperformed on the MSCI China Index since September 2023.</li>    <li>Factors contributing to this decline include weak consumer demand, intense competition, and ongoing discounts by companies.</li>    <li>The market is expecting more clues on consumer confidence from pricing and sales data around the upcoming Lunar New Year.</li>    <li>Government actions, such as interest rate cuts and spending, are anticipated to support the economy and prevent deflation.</li>    <li>Challenges remain, including salary cuts, job losses, and the need for a long-term solution to address the weak demand.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>自 2023 年 9 月以来，消费类股票在 MSCI 中国指数中的表现最差。</li>    <li>导致这种下降的因素包括疲软的消费者需求、激烈的竞争以及公司正在进行的折扣。</li>    <li>市场正在从即将到来的农历新年前后的定价和销售数据中寻找更多有关消费者信心的线索。</li>    <li>人们预计政府行动，例如降息和支出，将支持经济并防止通货紧缩。</li>    <li>仍然存在挑战，包括降薪、失业以及需要长期解决方案来应对疲软的需求。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>relentless (adj.) - /rɪˈlentlɪs/ 不断的，无情的。    <p>原文例句：The seemingly relentless decline in prices of Chinese goods amid tepid consumer demand is denting expectations that corporate earnings can revive the flagging stock market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语relentus（不屈服的），意思是“不停止的，无情的”。在这个例句中，它用来形容中国商品价格不断下跌的情况，以及这种下跌对企业收益和股市复苏的负面影响。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>deflationary (adj.) - /ˌdefləˈʃən(ə)ri/ 通货紧缩的。    <p>原文例句：The bigger picture is that the weak demand is leading to a deflationary environment, which particularly bodes ill for businesses that cannot achieve higher volumes with lower prices.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由词根deflate（通货紧缩）和后缀-ion（表示过程或状态）组成的，意思是“通货紧缩的”。在这个例句中，它用来形容经济需求疲软导致价格持续下降的情况，以及这种情况对无法通过降低价格来增加销量的企业的不利影响。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>protracted (adj.) - /prəˈtræktɪd/ 延长的，长期的。    <p>原文例句：Fast-food companies are still locked in a protracted fight for customers, with some offering full meals for around US$3.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语protractus（拉长的），意思是“延长的，长期的”。在这个例句中，它用来形容快餐公司之间激烈的竞争，以及这种竞争已经持续了很长时间。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>wage a battle - 进行斗争，展开竞争。    <p>原文例句：Companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由wage（进行，从事）和battle（战斗，竞争）组成的，意思是“进行斗争，展开竞争”。在这个例句中，它用来形容公司之间展开激烈的促销战，以吸引因就业前景黯淡和房地产市场持续低迷而受到惊吓的消费者。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：While local brands, in general, have fared better than luxury and foreign brands in terms of widening discounts, we expect discounts to further widen into the first quarter this year on the back of seasonality effects.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面）和terms（条款，条件）组成的，意思是“就……而言，从……方面来说”。在这个例句中，它用来比较本土品牌和奢侈品及外国品牌在扩大折扣方面的表现，并预测由于季节性因素，折扣将在今年第一季度进一步扩大。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September, after the real estate measure. - 自 9 月末以来，消费者股票指标在 MSCI 中国指数中的表现最差，仅次于房地产指标。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index，其中主语是Gauges of consumer stocks，谓语是have been，宾语是the worst performers，状语是since the end of September。after the real estate measure是一个介词短语作后置定语，修饰Gauges of consumer stocks，表示在房地产指标之后。这个句子的意思是，自9月结束以来，消费者股票指标在MSCI中国指数中的表现最差，仅次于房地产指标。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态的句子，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示公司从过去的某个时间开始一直持续到现在的进行促销战， nhằm吸引因就业前景黯淡和房地产市场持续低迷而受到惊吓的消费者。这个句子的意思是，公司正在进行促销战，以吸引因就业前景黯淡和房地产市场持续低迷而受到惊吓的消费者。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词。这种语态表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的，强调动作或状态的承受者。在这个例句中，it表示特斯拉在中国降价以保持其在高端电动汽车市场的地位。这个句子的意思是，特斯拉在中国降价以保持其在高端电动汽车市场的地位。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023</li>
<li>The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include Alibaba, Yum China Holdings and BYD, which have all been offering big discounts</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/b3e8597a-be7a-4197-85aa-c1a7be1f6626_e063aefc.jpg" /><figcaption>People fly dragon-shaped kites on the Bund in front of buildings in Pudong’s Lujiazui Financial District in Shanghai on January 9, 2024. China’s stock market suffers from a lack of positive drivers ahead of the Lunar New Year. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>The seemingly relentless decline in prices of Chinese goods amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247712/chinas-retail-sales-weaken-year-falling-home-prices-jobs-outlook-feed-consumer-insecurity-ubs" target="_self" title="">tepid consumer demand</a> is denting expectations that corporate earnings can revive the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-stock-market" target="_self" title="">flagging stock market</a>.</p><p>From <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicles</a> (EVs) to fast food, companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3244649/china-inflation-4-takeaways-novembers-data-deflationary-pressure-heightened" target="_self" title="">Consumer prices</a> fell for a third-straight month in December, the longest streak since 2009, deepening concerns about companies’ profits and share prices.</p><p>“That’s all symbolic of a very weak consumption environment that includes lack of consumer confidence and weak income growth,” said Ng Xin-yao, an investment director for Asian equities at abrdn. “We are cautious on fourth-quarter earnings across most sectors, and would assume that continues in the first quarter unless the government starts doing something massive to support the economy.”</p><p>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/msci" target="_self" title="">MSCI China Index</a> since the end of September, after the real estate measure. The aggregate market value of companies included in the two consumer indexes has fallen by about US$157 billion since.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/c17c04b3-1a34-4b5f-9767-75f9273ed6e5_8a6158cb.jpg" title="Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include e-commerce giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, restaurant operator <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3209531/kfc-pizza-hut-operator-yum-china-open-1300-stores-worst-over-posts-earnings-decline-2022" target="_self" title="">Yum China Holdings</a> and EV maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD Co</a> – which have all been offering big discounts. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>The world’s second-largest stock market has started 2024 on a dismal note, with the MSCI China gauge already down more than 4 per cent so far this year. It capped a third straight annual decline in 2023.</p><p>“The bigger picture is that the weak demand is leading to a deflationary environment, which particularly bodes ill for businesses that cannot achieve higher volumes with lower prices,” said Daisy Li, a fund manager at EFG Asset Management HK.</p><p>The EV industry has been among the worst hit by intense competition as growth slows, with Chinese makers following the lead of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> in lowering prices to boost sales. BYD and local peers including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a> have shed billions of dollars in market value in the past few months.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing" title="">Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</a></h3><p>“Retail prices are falling fast,” Morgan Stanley analysts wrote in their 2024 outlook report for the Chinese EV sector. “While local brands, in general, have fared better than luxury and foreign brands in terms of widening discounts, we expect discounts to further widen into the first quarter this year on the back of seasonality effects.”</p><p>Even China’s vaunted <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants have been impacted, with Alibaba and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> seeing their stock prices tumble, as they wage a fierce battle for market share. The price war has made US-listed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247286/pdd-halts-development-local-services-offering-avoid-head-competition-meituan-and-eleme-report-says" target="_self" title="">PDD Holdings</a>, operator of discount sites <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="">Pinduoduo</a> on the mainland and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>, one of the rare bright spots in China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> industry.</p><p>Many economy and market observers are hoping for interest-rate cuts and government spending to help prevent the nation from entering a deflationary spiral.</p><p>Fund managers have said the next catalyst they are watching is pricing and sales data around the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/lunar-new-year" target="_self" title="">Lunar New Year</a> in February, which will offer more clues on consumer confidence.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>The next few weeks may also be key for policy action, given Chinese leaders will soon gear up for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/national-peoples-congress" target="_self" title="">National People’s Congress</a>. That annual legislative session, held in March, is where the government is expected to announce its official growth target for 2024.</p><p>A Morgan Stanley survey conducted late last month suggests seasonally better consumer sentiment ahead of the holidays. However, “sustainability is in doubt amid slowing economic recovery”, analysts including Lillian Lou wrote in a note.</p><p>Salary cuts and job losses have remained among the top concerns of households, they wrote, adding that the number of consumers anticipating the economy to worsen ticked up by two percentage points from November to 13 per cent.</p><p>In all, there is little hope for a quick fix. Citigroup expects consensus estimates to fall for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-ning-company-ltd" target="_self" title="">Li Ning</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3217413/anta-sports-seeks-us15-billion-equity-placement-market-discount-triggering-stocks-worst-sell-six" target="_self" title="">Anta Sports Products</a> around the upcoming results season, hurt by foreign competition and pushes into lower-tier cities with cheaper products.</p><p>Fast-food companies are still locked in a protracted fight for customers, with some offering full meals for around US$3. It is difficult to make money at such low prices.</p><p>“We expect industry margins to erode until the irrational price war ends,” Kevin Yin, an analyst at JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co., wrote in a note, while cutting estimates for Yum China. “No player is immune” to the headwinds created by the nation’s slowing demand growth, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Stanford students win hearts in China with US$32,000 household robot that can cook shrimp and wash pans</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248330/stanford-students-win-hearts-china-us32000-household-robot-can-cook-shrimp-and-wash-pans</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Mobile Aloha is a US$32,000 two-handed robot developed by Chinese scientists at Stanford University. It can be remotely controlled by a human user or work autonomously through imitation learning. The robot can perform tasks like cooking shrimp, rinsing a pan, lifting a glass of wine, and wiping spilled liquid with a success rate of at least 80%.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Mobile Aloha, a two-handed robot, can be controlled remotely or work autonomously through imitation learning, showcasing its ability to perform various tasks.</li>    <li>Theme: Unveiling the potential of the US$32,000 two-handed robot, Mobile Aloha, developed by Chinese scientists at Stanford University.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The growing significance of domestic robots in smart homes and the impact of AI and imitation learning in advancing robotics technology.</li>    <li>Main information: Mobile Aloha's capabilities, including cooking, cleaning, and object manipulation; the challenges faced during development; the robot's cost and open-source nature; the expanding market for domestic robots.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  Mobile Aloha是一款由斯坦福大学中国科学家研发的价值3.2万美元的双手机器人，可以通过人类用户远程操控或通过模仿学习自主工作。该机器人可以执行诸如烹饪虾、冲洗锅、端起酒杯和擦拭溢出的液体等任务，成功率至少为80%。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Mobile Aloha是一款双手机器人，可以通过远程操控或通过模仿学习自主工作，展示了其执行各种任务的能力。</li>    <li>主题：揭秘由斯坦福大学中国科学家研发的价值3.2万美元的双手机器人Mobile Aloha的潜力。</li>    <li>观点：家用机器人智能家居中的日益重要性以及人工智能和模仿学习对机器人技术发展的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：Mobile Aloha的能力，包括烹饪、清洁和物体操作；在开发过程中面临的挑战；机器人的成本和开源性质；家用机器人市场的扩张。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>autonomous (adj.) - /ˌɔːtəˈnɒməs/ 自主的，独立的。    <p>原文例句：Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Autonomous的意思是“独立的，自主的”，在这个句子里，它形容Mobile Aloha可以自主地通过模仿学习工作。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>imitation (n.) - /ˌɪmɪˈteɪʃ(ə)n/ 模仿，仿效。    <p>原文例句：Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Imitation的意思是“模仿，仿效”，在这个句子里，它指的是Mobile Aloha可以通过模仿人类的动作来学习工作。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>navigate (v.) - /ˈnævɪgeɪt/ 驾驶，导航。    <p>原文例句：The robot can walk at 1.42 meters per second, roughly equivalent to human speed, reach as high as 2 meters and extend one meter beyond its base, the team said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Navigate的意思是“驾驶，导航”，在这个句子里，它指的是机器人可以像人类一样行走，速度高达每秒1.42米，还能达到2米的高度，并能延伸一米远。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>   <li>reach out to - 联系，触及。</li>    <p>原文例句：Fu said he and Zhao, who have open-sourced the whole system, “don’t have any business plan at the moment”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Reach out to的意思是“联系，触及”，在这个句子里，它指的是Fu和赵还没有任何商业计划。</p></li>    </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Mobile Aloha, built by two computer-science PhD candidates from China, is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system，其中主语是Mobile Aloha，谓语是is，宾语是a two-handed system。built by two computer-science PhD candidates from China是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰Mobile Aloha，表示Mobile Aloha是由两个来自中国的计算机科学博士候选人建造的。can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning是一个并列结构，作Mobile Aloha的表语，表示Mobile Aloha可以被人类用户远程控制，也可以通过模仿学习自主工作。这个句子的意思是说，Mobile Aloha是一个由两个来自中国的计算机科学博士候选人建造的双手系统，它可以被人类用户远程控制，也可以通过模仿学习自主工作。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作定语 - 用于修饰名词或代词，表示该名词或代词所指的事物或人具有某种特征或状态。</li>    <p>原文例句：Mobile Aloha, built by two computer-science PhD candidates from China, is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，built by two computer-science PhD candidates from China是一个过去分词短语，作定语，修饰名词Mobile Aloha，表示Mobile Aloha是由两个来自中国的计算机科学博士候选人建造的。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>并列结构作表语 - 用于说明主语的性质、状态或特征。</li>    <p>原文例句：Mobile Aloha, built by two computer-science PhD candidates from China, is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning是一个并列结构，作表语，说明主语Mobile Aloha的性质或特征，即Mobile Aloha可以被人类用户远程控制，也可以通过模仿学习自主工作。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Mobile Aloha, a two-handed system, can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning</li>
<li>It is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, the inventors say</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/a5391667-ecfe-41e0-ba55-d4bcc8573340_5eb9826c.jpg" /><figcaption>Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning. Photo: Screenshot</figcaption></figure><p>A US$32,000 robot developed by a team at Stanford University has caught the attention of Chinese online users, after a video showing the two-handed robot cooking a three-course meal went viral.</p><p>Mobile Aloha, built by two computer-science PhD candidates from China, is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p><p>After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, according to the project’s website.</p><p>It took three months to develop the robot, according to Zipeng Fu, who co-leads the project with Tony Zhao, advised by Stanford assistant professor Chelsea Finn. Fu and Zhao are also student researchers at Google DeepMind, an artificial intelligence (AI) research laboratory.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Fu said they had to tackle both hardware and software challenges. To save cost, they assembled the machine on their own. The goal was to make a robot that could “complete complex home or office tasks that were not shown to be possible previously”.</p><p>The robot can walk at 1.42 metres per second, roughly equivalent to human speed, reach as high as 2 metres and extend one metre beyond its base, the team said.</p><p>When it comes to the software, the duo took a “data-driven AI approach using human demonstration data to teach the robot” instead of the traditional way of “tons of programming and manual tuning” that is not scalable, Fu said.</p><p>The robot cost US$32,000 to build, including on-board power and computing. Fu said he and Zhao, who have open-sourced the whole system, “don’t have any business plan at the moment”.</p><p>As the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ageing-society" target="_self" title="">global population gets older</a>, domestic robots are expected to play a critical role in the smart home ecosystem. The market is estimated to grow at an annual rate of nearly 20 per cent from US$8.6 billion this year to US$22.5 billion by 2029, according to market research firm Mordor Intelligence.</p><p>Global tech giants have been betting big on the sector. In 2021, American online retailer Amazon.com unveiled Astro, a nearly US$1,000 household robot designed for home monitoring. Japanese electronics giant Sony launched the latest generation of its Aibo robot dog in 2018, priced at around US$2,900.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s Big Tech firms from Tencent to Alibaba cut external investments further in 2023 amid troubled economy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248311/chinas-big-tech-firms-tencent-alibaba-cut-external-investments-further-2023-amid-troubled-economy</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  China's internet giants, including Alibaba, Tencent, and Baidu, saw a significant decline in their investment activities last year. A comprehensive Chinese consultancy report highlighted that the total investment deals made by these companies plunged by nearly 40% in 2023, reflecting the impact of economic slowdown, regulatory constraints, and geopolitical issues. Tencent experienced the most notable reduction, with a substantial decrease in investment contracts compared to previous years. Meanwhile, smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor in terms of deal count.  <ul>    <li>Main Information:      <ul>        <li>Overall decline in investment deals by Chinese internet giants.</li>        <li>Tencent faced the largest reduction in investments.</li>        <li>Xiaomi emerged as the top investor by number of deals.</li>        <li>Alibaba focused on advanced manufacturing investments.</li>        <li>AI-related investments gained traction among tech giants.</li>      </ul>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  阿里巴巴、腾讯和百度等中国互联网巨头去年的投资活动大幅减少。一份由中国咨询公司编制的综合报告显示，这些公司在 2023 年的投资交易总额下降了近 40%，反映了经济放缓、监管阻力和地缘政治问题的影响。腾讯的投资合同与前几年相比大幅减少，经历了最显着的下降。与此同时，智能手机制造商小米在交易数量上成为最大的投资者。  <ul>    <li>主要信息：      <ul>        <li>中国互联网巨头的投资交易总量下降。</li>        <li>腾讯面临最大的投资减少。</li>        <li>小米在交易数量上成为最大的投资者。</li>        <li>阿里巴巴专注于先进制造业投资。</li>        <li>人工智能相关投资在科技巨头中获得关注。</li>      </ul>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Amid - （介）在……期间，在……当中。    <p>原文例句：Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“amid”表示“在……期间，在……当中”。在这个例句中，“amid a series of regulatory tightening moves”表示“在监管收紧的一系列举措当中”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Champion - （名）冠军；（动）支持，拥护。    <p>原文例句：Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“champion”既可以作为名词，也可以作为动词。作为名词时，它表示“冠军”；作为动词时，它表示“支持，拥护”。在这个例句中，“the country’s internet champions”表示“这个国家的互联网冠军”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Watershed year - 分水岭年份    <p>原文例句：2021 was a watershed year for Chinese internet firms, as Beijing kicked off a campaign to rein in the “disorderly expansion of capital”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“watershed year”表示“分水岭年份”。在这个例句中，“2021 was a watershed year for Chinese internet firms”表示“2021年是中国互联网企业的转折之年”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding.    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是“the country’s internet champions have virtually stopped expanding”，其中主语是“the country’s internet champions”，谓语是“have virtually stopped expanding”。“Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves”是一个介词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示在监管收紧的一系列举措当中。 “whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts”是一个定语从句，修饰主语“the country’s internet champions”，表示这些互联网公司的市场规模曾经与它们的美国同行不相上下。这个句子的意思是说，在监管收紧的一系列举措当中，这个国家的互联网冠军——它们的市场规模曾经与它们的美国同行不相上下——已经基本停止了扩张。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 当某些句子成分需要突出强调时，可将该成分置于句首，并将谓语动词提至主语之前。    <p>原文例句：In that same month, Xiaomi invested in three start-ups in the vehicle and transport industry, according to ITJuzi.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，将状语“In that same month”置于句首，并将谓语动词“invested”提至主语“Xiaomi”之前，以突出强调状语所表示的时间。这个句子的意思是说，就在那个月，小米投资了汽车和运输行业的三家初创企业。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Total investment deals made by Alibaba, Tencent and Baidu plunged by nearly 40 per cent last year, data from ITJuzi shows</li>
<li>Smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor among its peers by number of investments, with 82 deals made in 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/44791123-3b25-419d-83ab-8b90abaff588_62f5b773.jpg" /><figcaption>The Tencent headquarters in Shenzhen. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>China’s internet giants from Alibaba Group Holding to Tencent Holdings slashed external investments last year amid an economic slowdown, regulatory headwinds and geopolitical tensions, according to data compiled by a Chinese consultancy.</p><p>Total investment deals made by Alibaba, Tencent and Baidu plunged by nearly 40 per cent to 102 in 2023, with Tencent – known for its expansive holdings in China’s internet sector – seeing the largest reduction in deals, data from ITJuzi showed.</p><p>The social media and video gaming titan struck 39 investment contracts with 37 companies last year, a sharp decline from the 95 and 299 deals it made in 2022 and 2021, respectively.</p><p>Web search and artificial intelligence (AI) firm Baidu participated in 24 investment deals last year, down from 52 in 2021. E-commerce giant Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, took part in 39 deals, a fall from 91 in 2021, according to ITJuzi.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/7597aa81-09a5-4a11-9eec-a437d76b7f0a_d667e456.jpg" title="The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure></div><p>2021 was a watershed year for Chinese internet firms, as Beijing kicked off a campaign to rein in the “disorderly expansion of capital”. Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding.</p><p>Tencent’s investments last year were mainly related to corporate services, healthcare and video games. Advanced manufacturing firms were Alibaba’s top picks, with eight related deals being struck by the Hangzhou-based company and its affiliates during the year.</p><p>Alibaba, which is grappling with anaemic consumer spending at home, made four investment deals in the e-commerce sector, three of them outside China.</p><p>AI was another investment favourite among Chinese tech giants last year, as they raced to build and promote their local rivals to OpenAI’s ChatGPT.</p><p>Tencent and Alibaba each backed seven and four AI start-ups developing large language models (LLMs), the technology which underpins chatbots like ChatGPT, which can understand complex questions and give humanlike responses.</p><p>Last year, Alibaba’s in-house research facility Damo Academy also launched a research laboratory to recruit more than a hundred postdoctoral candidates to work on cutting-edge areas, including AI and semiconductors.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1325" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/5991da2b-d385-4951-b2a1-8a232f9ce1c4_bc1c8442.jpg" title="Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Other major Chinese tech companies made even fewer investments.</p><p>TikTok owner ByteDance struck five external investment deals last year, while online shopping platform operator JD.com made just two.</p><p>ByteDance’s largest deal in 2023 was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244634/tiktok-restarts-e-commerce-indonesia-us15-billion-investment-goto-gojek-tokopedia-unit" target="_self" title="">a US$1.5 billion investment into Indonesia’s biggest e-commerce firm Tokopedia</a>, which allows the Beijing-based company to restart its local online shopping business after Indonesian regulators banned TikTok Shop.</p><p>Meanwhile, Chinese smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor by number of investments, with 82 deals made during the year.</p><p>The company, also based in Beijing, in December launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246558/xiaomi-unveils-its-first-ev-su7-setting-its-sights-tesla-highly-competitive-china-market" target="_self" title="">its first electric vehicle, the SU7</a>, designed to compete against the likes of Tesla and Porsche in China’s hotly contested car market.</p><p>In that same month, Xiaomi invested in three start-ups in the vehicle and transport industry, according to ITJuzi.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong needs to speed up approval of spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds after US launch, industry insiders say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248282/hong-kong-needs-speed-approval-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-after-us-launch-industry</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong aims to follow the US in authorizing spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs) to enhance its competitiveness in the global market. </li>    <li>Spot Bitcoin ETFs have gained popularity in the US, leading to increased pressure on Hong Kong regulators to approve similar products.</li>    <li>Industry experts believe the US's move will push Hong Kong to accelerate Bitcoin ETF applications in the coming months.</li>    <li>Hong Kong needs to act quickly to maintain its status as a global financial center and virtual asset hub in Asia. </li>    <li>China, on the other hand, is unlikely to follow suit due to its strict stance against cryptocurrencies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>香港拟仿效美国，授权发行现货加密货币交易所交易基金（ETF），以增强其在全球市场的竞争力。 </li>    <li>现货比特币ETF在美国颇受欢迎，这让香港监管机构面临着越来越大的压力，要求其批准类似产品。</li>    <li>业内专家认为，美国的这一举动将促使香港在未来几个月内加快比特币ETF的审批程序。</li>    <li>香港需要迅速行动，以维持其作为全球金融中心和亚洲虚拟资产中心的地位。 </li>    <li>另一方面，中国不太可能效仿，因为中国对加密货币持严格立场。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fund management firm - 基金管理公司。    <p>原文例句：Around 10 fund management firms are preparing to launch spot virtual asset-backed ETFs in Hong Kong, according to Chinese media Caixin’s interview on Wednesday of Livio Weng, chief operating officer at crypto trading app operator HashKey Group. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由fund（基金），management（管理），firm（公司）构成的，表示“基金管理公司”。在这个例句中，它指的是正在准备在香港推出现货虚拟资产支持的ETF的基金管理公司。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>cryptocurrency exchange - 加密货币交易所。    <p>原文例句：The SEC’s decision would make its peers “seriously consider whether similar ETFs would be permissible and desirable”.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由cryptocurrency（加密货币）和exchange（交易所）构成的，表示“加密货币交易所”。在这个例句中，它指的是那些需要认真考虑是否允许和需要类似ETF的加密货币交易所。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>virtual-asset hub - 虚拟资产中心。    <p>原文例句：Hong Kong aims to follow the US in authorizing spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs) to enhance its competitiveness in the global market and bolster its ambition to become a major virtual-asset hub in Asia, according to industry insiders.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由virtual-asset（虚拟资产）和hub（中心）构成的，表示“虚拟资产中心”。在这个例句中，它指的是那些需要认真考虑是否允许和需要类似ETF的加密货币交易所。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>be prepared to do sth. - 准备好做某事。    <P>原文例句：While the city’s Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) in December said it was prepared to authorise retail access to spot virtual asset ETFs, the actual launch of such products has already fallen behind the US, according to Wang Yi, the head of quantitative investment at CSOP Asset Management, which currently runs two cryptocurrency futures ETFs. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由be prepared（准备好）和to do sth.（做某事）构成的，表示“准备好做某事”。在这个例句中，它表示香港证券及期货事务监察委员会（SFC）在12月表示已准备好授权散户准入现货虚拟资产ETF。这个短语由be和prepared\to do sth.组成，其中be用作系动词，prepared表示准备好，to do sth.表示做某事。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>have access to sth. - 有权使用或获得某物。    <P>原文例句：Shanghai Jiao Tong University assistant professor Li Nan.    </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由have（有）和access（使用，获得）构成的，表示“有权使用或获得某物”。在这个例句中，it表示上海交通大学助理教授李楠。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong is likely to accelerate bitcoin ETF applications in the coming months. - 香港很可能在未来几个月内加速比特币ETF的申请。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是Hong Kong，谓语是is likely to accelerate bitcoin ETF applications in the coming months，其中is likely to accelerate表示“很可能会加速”，bitcoin ETF applications表示“比特币ETF申请”，in the coming months表示“在未来几个月内”。这个句子的意思是说，香港很可能会在未来几个月内加速比特币ETF的申请。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：US-listed spot bitcoin ETFs saw US$4.6 billion worth of shares trade hands on Thursday, according to a Reuters report that cited LSEG data, as investors jumped into the landmark products approved by the US securities regulator on Wednesday. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示美国证券监管机构于周三批准的具有里程碑意义的产品，吸引了投资者涌入，使在纽约证券交易所上市的现货比特币ETF在周四的股票交易额达到46亿美元。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、愿望或可能性等。    <p>原文例句：The SEC’s decision would make its peers “seriously consider whether similar ETFs would be permissible and desirable”.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语气，结构是：would/should/could + 动词原形。这种语气表示假设、愿望或可能性等。在这个例句中，it表示美国证券交易委员会的决定将使它的同行们“认真考虑类似的ETF是否允许和可取”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Hong Kong has fallen behind the US in authorising spot cryptocurrency ETFs, even though regulators in December said the city was prepared to do so</li>
<li>Industry insiders urge local regulators to step up approvals to strengthen the city’s competitiveness in the global cryptocurrency market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/3b2dd50a-a4ac-4010-9e13-b8b9d2dcf87f_4276bf76.jpg" /><figcaption>The successful launch of spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds in the US is expected to help move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong</a> should soon follow the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>’ lead in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">authorising spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a> (ETFs), bolstering the city’s ambition to become a major <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3197838/hong-kong-unveils-policies-develop-virtual-assets-industry-challenging-singapore-hub-status" target="_self" title="">virtual-asset hub in Asia</a>, according to industry insiders.</p><p>While the city’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/sfc" target="_self" title="">Securities and Futures Commission</a> (SFC) in December said it was prepared to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" target="_self" title="">authorise retail access to spot virtual asset ETFs</a>, the actual launch of such products has already fallen behind the US, according to Wang Yi, the head of quantitative investment at CSOP Asset Management, which currently runs two <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/digital-currencies" target="_self" title="">cryptocurrency</a> futures ETFs.</p><p>US-listed spot <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bitcoin" target="_self" title="">bitcoin</a> ETFs saw US$4.6 billion worth of shares trade hands on Thursday, according to a Reuters report that cited LSEG data, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248152/us-bitcoin-etfs-trades-soar-us46-billion-first-day-after-landmark-sec-approval" target="_self" title="">investors jumped into the landmark products</a> approved by the US securities regulator on Wednesday.</p><p>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust, Grayscale Bitcoin Trust and ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF, among others – began trading on Thursday, following the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">US Securities and Exchange Commission’s landmark approval</a> that is expected to help bring the cryptocurrency industry closer to the more regulated world of traditional finance.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/9cebdb57-e859-4c52-8114-95780d50fca8_a66cec46.jpg" title="Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The successful US launch of spot bitcoin ETFs is expected to help move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city.</p><p>Spot cryptocurrency ETFs enable investors to gain exposure to virtual assets without directly buying any crypto tokens.</p><p>These funds “give the crypto industry more legitimacy and also opens up more collaboration opportunities with mainstream finance”, said RJ Ke, a researcher with ethereum scaling start-up Taiko. “Hong Kong is likely to accelerate bitcoin ETF applications in the coming months.”</p><p>Around 10 fund management firms are preparing to launch spot virtual asset-backed ETFs in Hong Kong, according to Chinese media Caixin’s interview on Wednesday of Livio Weng, chief operating officer at <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239953/hong-kongs-hashkey-launches-first-crypto-trading-app-retail-investors-gives-away-new-token" target="_self" title="">crypto trading app operator HashKey Group</a>. Weng said that up to eight companies were at an “advanced stage” to launch.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" title="">US regulator SEC authorises spot bitcoin ETFs in cryptocurrency breakthrough</a></h3><p>Bitcoin jumped about 3.4 per cent to US$47,500, following the spot crypto ETF approvals in the US. That was nearly three times the level that the original cryptocurrency reached in November 2022, when <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3199385/crypto-exchange-giant-ftx-collapses-files-bankruptcy-protection-global-digital-currency-market-posts" target="_self" title="">failed crypto exchange FTX filed for bankruptcy</a> to send bitcoin’s price below US$17,000.</p><p>Hong Kong needs to launch spot virtual asset ETFs as soon as possible to “ensure that the city remains competitive in the global cryptocurrency market and strengthen its position as a global financial centre”, said Mao Shixing, also known as “Discus Fish”, who is the co-founder and chief executive of digital asset custody solutions provider Cobo.</p><p>Mao said the US approvals could impact other jurisdictions because “the SEC is one of the most influential and reputable financial regulators in the world”, adding that the agency’s initiatives “often serve as important references for financial regulators in other countries and regions”.</p><p>“However, each country and region has its own independent stance and regulatory objectives,” he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" title="">Hong Kong to push retail access to spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a></h3><p>Echoing the Cobo head’s view, Donald Day, chief operating officer at digital asset platform VDX, said the SEC’s decision would make its peers “seriously consider whether similar ETFs would be permissible and desirable”.</p><p>Day pointed out that the SFC’s statement in December about being prepared to authorise such funds has “in principle opened a pathway for issuers to launch spot crypto ETFs in Hong Kong”.</p><p>With the US, there are now nine markets around the world that have allowed the operation of spot crypto ETFs. The other markets include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/canada?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Canada</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/germany?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Germany</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/switzerland?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Switzerland</a>, and tax havens such as the Cayman Islands in the Caribbean and Jersey near the coast of northwestern France, according to market analytics firm CoinGecko.</p><p>Mainland China, however, is unlikely to follow suit.</p><p>In December, China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology said it will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" target="_self" title="">draft a national Web3 development plan</a> to suit the country’s needs. But the announcement did not mention cryptocurrencies even though Beijing maintains its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3216894/chinese-officials-pledge-support-hong-kongs-tech-web3-ambitions-digital-economy-summit?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">support for Hong Kong’s ambition to become a major virtual-asset hub</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" title="">Beijing to draft national Web3 development plan amid strict cryptocurrency ban</a></h3><p>The Chinese government banned banks from handling bitcoin in 2013 and forced cryptocurrency exchanges to move offshore in 2017. In 2021, the country’s regulators reiterated the state’s prohibition on all financial institutions from engaging in crypto-related activities.</p><p>China’s state media recently emphasised the risks involved in spot cryptocurrency ETFs.</p><p>The US approval of spot bitcoin ETFs “would make the cryptocurrency market even more frantic, providing fertile ground for illegal transactions such as money laundering”, according to a report by the International Financial News, a newspaper under the People’s Daily, which cited Shanghai Jiao Tong University assistant professor Li Nan.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
