<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China’s video gaming market ended 2023 battered and bruised, but can world-beating titles and innovation save the day?</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248249/chinas-video-gaming-market-ended-2023-battered-and-bruised-can-world-beating-titles-and-innovation</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  With the ending of China's Covid-19 containment policy at the end of 2022, the video game industry welcomed an increase in new releases and game approvals, while the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) continued to dominate the market with its focus on “social values”. Competition is heating up, with industry veterans Tencent and NetEase facing challenges from new competitors, but there is also room for innovation, as developers incorporate augmented and virtual reality, artificial intelligence, and generative AI into their games.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Post-pandemic recovery and CCP influence shape the Chinese video gaming market.</li>    <li>Theme: China's video game market sees growth and competition amid regulatory scrutiny and technological advancements.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: China's video game market is a promising sector for domestic developers, but faces challenges in terms of regulation, competition, and the need for innovation.</li>    <li>Main information: Industry growth in 2023, Tencent and NetEase's dominance, NPPA's draft rule on excessive spending, increasing use of AI in game development.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  随着中国于 2022 年底结束新冠疫情遏制政策，游戏行业迎来新版本发行和游戏批准数量的增加，而中国共产党（CCP）凭借其对“社会价值观”的关注继续主导市场。竞争日趋激烈，行业巨头腾讯和网易面临来自新竞争对手的挑战，但也有创新空间，因为开发者将增强现实和虚拟现实、人工智能和生成式 AI 纳入他们的游戏中。  <ul>    <li>摘要：后疫情复苏和 CCP 影响塑造了中国电子游戏市场。</li>    <li>主题：中国电子游戏市场在监管审查和技术进步中迎来增长和竞争。</li>    <li>观点：中国电子游戏市场对国内开发商来说是一个很有前途的领域，但面临着监管、竞争和创新需求方面的挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：2023 年行业增长、腾讯和网易的主导地位、NPPA 关于过度支出的征求意见稿、AI 在游戏开发中的使用日益增多。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue-generating (adj.) - 收入创收的；产生收入的。    <p>原文例句：The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings, released by Tencent Holdings in 2015.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由revenue（收入）和generating（产生）组成，意为“产生收入的”或“创收的”。在这个例句中，它指的是2023年收入最高的手机游戏是腾讯控股于2015年发布的《王者荣耀》。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>incentive (n.) - 激励措施；诱因。    <p>原文例句：Popular games like Tencent’s Honour of Kings and NetEase’s Eggy Party are less likely to be impacted, as both have relatively low average revenue per user, according to Niko Partners.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，意为“刺激”或“鼓励”。在这个例句中，它指的是腾讯的《王者荣耀》和网易的《蛋仔派对》这两种热门游戏不太可能受到影响，因为根据Niko Partners的数据，这两款游戏的平均每用户收入相对较低。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>cut the costs of - 减少成本。    <p>原文例句：Zencat Gaming’s Chen said that the use of AI tools to modify pictures, generate video and dub animated characters can cut the costs of overall video game development by roughly 20 per cent.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由cut（切割，降低）和the costs of（成本）组成，意为“减少成本”。在这个例句中，它指的是Zencat Gaming的陈说，使用人工智能工具修改图片、生成视频和配音动画角色可以将整个视频游戏开发成本降低大约20%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>However, in the wake of the market rout triggered by the NPPA’s action, Beijing attempted to limit the damage by stating its desire for “healthy” development of the industry. - 然而，面对 NPPA 行动引发的市场动荡，北京试图通过声明其希望行业“健康”发展来限制损失。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Beijing attempted to limit the damage，其中主语是Beijing，谓语是attempted to limit，宾语是damage。However是一个连接词，表示转折，将两个分句连接起来。in the wake of the market rout triggered by the NPPA’s action是一个介词短语作时间状语，表示在 NPPA 的行动引发市场动荡之后。by stating its desire for “healthy” development of the industry是一个介词短语作状语，表示通过声明其希望行业“健康”发展。这个句子的意思是说，然而，面对 NPPA 行动引发的市场动荡，北京试图通过声明其希望行业“健康”发展来限制损失。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词作状语 - 分词可以用来作状语，表示动作发生的时间、方式、原因等。    <p>原文例句：Amid an increase in regulatory oversight in recent years, China’s video gaming market has, in some ways, become walled off like the country’s television market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词Amid an increase in regulatory oversight in recent years是一个现在分词短语，作状语，表示动作发生的时间或情况。in some ways是一个副词短语，作状语，表示“在某些方面”。become walled off like the country’s television market是一个过去分词短语，作宾语补足语，表示“变得像国家电视市场一样被隔离”。这个句子的意思是说，近年来，随着监管监督的加强，中国电子游戏市场在某些方面变得像国家电视市场一样被隔离。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>条件状语从句 - 条件状语从句表示动作或状态发生的条件。    <p>原文例句：If passed in its present form, the rule change is expected to hit titles that rely heavily on loot boxes for monetisation or incentives for user acquisition.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子的主句是，The rule change is expected to hit titles that rely heavily on loot boxes for monetisation or incentives for user acquisition，其中主语是The rule change，谓语是expected，宾语是to hit titles that rely heavily on loot boxes for monetisation or incentives for user acquisition。If passed in its present form是一个条件状语从句，修饰主句，表示如果按目前的形式通过。这个句子的意思是说，如果按目前的形式通过，预计该规则的变化将打击严重依赖战利品箱进行货币化或用户获取激励的游戏。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Industry regulator ended the year with a draft rule change designed to curb excessive consumer spending on in-game items, sparking market rout</li>
<li>China-backed games continue to make headlines around the world, and many analysts see overseas opportunities for domestic video game firms</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/94beb22e-5bd3-49df-8e52-6405f925421a_939b4d96.jpg" /><figcaption>China-backed games continue to win awards and analysts see more overseas opportunities for domestic developers in 2024. Illustration: SCMP/Lau Ka-kuen</figcaption></figure><p>Although 2023 started with new hope, the year was not filled with fun for Chinese video gaming companies and players.</p><p>ByteDance, the deep-pocketed owner of TikTok that had aggressively acquired gaming operations, decided to throw in the towel and Blizzard Entertainment left the Chinese market after its 14-year-old partnership with NetEase ended.</p><p>Last but not least, the country’s video games regulator ended the year with a draft rule change designed to curb excessive consumer spending on items such as avatars and in-game weapons, wiping out around US$80 billion in market value from Chinese gaming stocks.</p><p>The total number of video game players in China has been peaking.</p><p>By the end of 2023 there were 668 million gamers in China, a tiny increase from the 666 million at the end of 2022. They jointly spent 303 billion yuan (US$42 billion) on games, or about US$63 per gamer last year – roughly a quarter of the amount spent by US gamers.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
<div>
</div>
</div><p>The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained <em>Honour of Kings</em>, released by Tencent Holdings in 2015.</p><p>Amid an increase in regulatory oversight in recent years, China’s video gaming market has, in some ways, become walled off like the country’s television market.</p><p>Censors scrutinise content and control licence approvals, and domestic gaming studios – including Tencent and NetEase – are increasingly expected to deliver Chinese “social values” with their titles. Meanwhile, the companies need to maintain an uneasy balance between maximising revenue for shareholders and protecting minors from gaming addiction.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/310b9ccf-967e-4db1-9a3a-f0047ea1bb08_cda5d6ab.jpg" title="Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Video gaming, once seen as a gold mine in China’s internet sector, was also hard hit by lay-offs and closures in the past year, according to industry insiders and executives.</p><p>“Every studio that I know is cutting costs, even industry leader Tencent,” said Mark Wu, who works for a gaming studio in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p><p>But does this herald another barren year for China’s video game market or is it just a much-needed bout of consolidation and recalibration for an industry that has been subject to wild swings of investment in recent years?</p><p>Earlier this month, the gaming unit of Tencent launched a “spring bamboo shoots” initiative to support low- and medium-budget projects, in a change from a previous focus on projects with heavy production costs, according to industry blog Youxiputao. Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246197/china-approves-105-video-games-christmas-miracle-does-not-revive-stocks-after-suggested-spending" title="">China’s Christmas gift to game developers: 105 approved titles, the most all year</a></h3><p>However, China-backed games continue to make headlines around the world.</p><p>In December The Game Awards (TGA) named <em>Baldur’s Gate 3, c</em>reated and published by Tencent-backed Belgian developer Larian Studios, as video game of the year. Another nominee for the award was <em>Alan Wake 2</em>, from Remedy Entertainment and published by Epic Games, both backed by Tencent.</p><p>Shanghai-based miHoYo – which cracked the global video games market with its hit title <em>Genshin Impact</em> in 2021 – saw its <em>Honkai: Star Rail</em> win TGA’s best mobile game and Apple’s iPhone game of the year in 2023.</p><p>Analysts expect Chinese studios to roll out more hits in 2024, although it remains to be seen whether the content will match up with Beijing’s desire for “excellent” video games that promote socialist values, highlight Chinese culture and demonstrate the country’s advanced technology.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Honkai: Star Rail has delivered another set of game awards for Shanghai-based studio miHoYo. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/37809897-88de-484d-a18e-024f1aadca30_a18f5966.jpg" title="Honkai: Star Rail has delivered another set of game awards for Shanghai-based studio miHoYo. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Honkai: Star Rail has delivered another set of game awards for Shanghai-based studio miHoYo. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>“In coming years, China’s gaming industry will be focused on producing premium titles and overseas expansion,” said Zhang Shule, an analyst with CBJ Think Tank. “Local developers are expected to step up R&amp;D efforts to make quality games, drawing on their experience and success in the domestic market.”</p><p>In another bright spot, it appears China is set to welcome the massively-popular <em>World of Warcraft</em> back, after developer Blizzard struck a new deal with old partner NetEase, according to a report by domestic media outlet 36Kr.</p><p>CBJ’s Zhang said that while there is still uncertainty about the “remarriage”, NetEase “does stand out in a crowd of options”. “Its experience from the last tie-up and operational edge will be a strong draw.”</p><p>Chinese mobile game user spending in 2023 remained at a level similar to that of 2022, as the market saw an influx of new titles with more games obtaining licences from authorities, according to Nan Lu, director of Asia-Pacific marketing at research firm Sensor Tower.</p><p>Similar spending levels have been recorded in overseas markets, such as the US, South Korea and Southeast Asia in the past year. Still, Sensor Tower has observed a gradual increase in global user spending since the Christmas and 2024 New Year holiday. “Overall, the overseas market continues to offer opportunities for Chinese developers in the coming years, especially those focused on hybrid casual genres,” added Lu.</p><p>According to data from the Game Publishing Committee of the China Audio-Video and Digital Publishing Association, the semi-official industry association, overseas revenue from China video game titles dropped 5.7 per cent in 2023 to US$16.3 billion.</p><p>Meanwhile, China’s video games industry is not an island and faces the same headwinds as the wider economy – namely weak domestic consumption amid an unsteady, post-pandemic recovery.</p><p>Matthew Chen, co-founder and chief operating officer of Chengdu-based Zencat Gaming in southwestern Sichuan province, said that players in China “are not spending that much money amid a slowing economy”.</p><p>UBS analyst Christine Peng said this week that heightened fears among consumers about salary cuts and job security have dragged down retail sales growth in the world’s second-largest economy. The Swiss bank expects China’s retail sales to climb 5.5 per cent in 2024, one percentage point lower than the estimated 6.5 per cent rise last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" title="">China to curb excess spending on video games in blow for world’s biggest market</a></h3><p>Wu, the Guangzhou-based video games worker, said that the end of strict pandemic controls in late 2022 led to some good signs in the first few months, but added “demand for gaming [subsequently] gave way to the need [to spend] on necessities”.</p><p>Meanwhile, the overall tone of policy towards the industry remains uncertain. As things stand, all online video games must go through rigorous screening to obtain licences before being released to the public and monetised, and all players are required to have real-name registration.</p><p>Earlier this week, Tencent announced its winter policy for players aged under 18 – they can only play its games online for a combined 16 hours between January 22 and February 24. The rule is designed to comply with Beijing’s 2021 move to impose a play time ceiling for minors.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings , released by Tencent Holdings in 2015. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1503" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/bc900708-65b5-4106-977a-84409ccb6f9e_f9f7aaf5.jpg" title="The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings , released by Tencent Holdings in 2015. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings , released by Tencent Holdings in 2015. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>But while Beijing has toned down its overall view of video games as “spiritual opium”, the industry was rocked at the end of last year when regulator the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) proposed in a draft rule that games must not offer rewards that entice people to spend excessively, such as for daily logins and funding top-ups.</p><p>The timing and severity of the proposed rule change dealt a fresh blow to already-fragile investor confidence in Chinese stocks. NetEase, the country’s No. 2 gaming operator, fell by nearly a quarter in a single trading day, with Tencent dropping over 12 per cent.</p><p>Zeng Xiaofeng, vice-president of industry research firm Niko Partners, expects the rule change – if passed in its present form – to hit titles that rely heavily on loot boxes for monetisation or incentives for user acquisition, and those that have a large number of high spenders.</p><p>Popular games like Tencent’s <em>Honour of Kings</em> and NetEase’s <em>Eggy Party</em> are less likely to be impacted, as both have relatively low average revenue per user, according to Niko Partners.</p><p>Around 26 per cent of China’s mobile game users are payers, while high spenders – which refers to players that spend 300 yuan (US$42) monthly – only account for 2.5 per cent of mobile gamers in China, according to Niko Partners.</p><p>However, in the wake of the market rout triggered by the NPPA’s action, Beijing attempted to limit the damage by stating its desire for “healthy” development of the industry.</p><p>Meanwhile, Feng Shixin, a key figure overseeing the industry, subsequently stepped down from his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, according to a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes" target="_self" title="">Post report</a> citing sources.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245240/bytedance-throws-towel-video-games-chinese-studio-mihoyo-claims-global-wins-honkai" title="">As ByteDance retreats in video games, miHoYo claims global wins with new title</a></h3><p>And Beijing approved 105 new video game licences in December, the most in 17 months. In 2023 the regulator issued 1,075 licences for domestic and foreign games, more than double the number in 2022. 98 imported titles also received the greenlight in 2023, up from 44 in 2022, and Niko Partners expects another increase this year.</p><p>CBJ’s Zhang says that in terms of innovation, local developers are likely to “leverage augmented and virtual reality equipment and software” as well as “artificial intelligence (AI) to make the same game playable across different platforms – mobile, desktop and consoles – for a more immersive gameplay experience”.</p><p>Meanwhile, many of the industry workers the Post interviewed have used generative AI, the technology popularised by OpenAI’s ChatGPT, to produce various gaming content, including text, images and video.</p><p>Zencat Gaming’s Chen said that the use of AI tools to modify pictures, generate video and dub animated characters can cut the costs of overall video game development by roughly 20 per cent.</p><p>This can be a double-edged sword though. As Wu, the Guangzhou-based industry worker pointed out, while the new technology can be a “great assistant” it may very well kill entry-level jobs.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech war: China chip imports fall in 2023 but semiconductors remain country’s largest item ahead of crude oil</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248269/tech-war-china-chip-imports-fall-2023-semiconductors-remain-countrys-largest-item-ahead-crude-oil</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In 2023, China's imports of integrated circuits (ICs) fell significantly in both volume and value due to economic headwinds and localization efforts. Despite the decline, semiconductors remained the country's largest import item, surpassing crude oil. The US's export control measures also contributed to the decrease in chip imports, as China is unable to directly purchase advanced chips from US companies like Nvidia. China is working to boost local chip production to reduce reliance on imports, with plans to expand mature chip production capacity and increase cooperation among domestic semiconductor players.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's declining IC imports reflect economic challenges and localization efforts.</li>    <li>Theme: China's chip imports fell in 2023 due to economic headwinds and US export controls, prompting localization efforts.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of semiconductor self-sufficiency for China's economy and technological progress.</li>    <li>Main information: Statistical data on China's IC imports; impact of economic headwinds and localization efforts; US export control measures; China's progress in boosting local chip production.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023 年，中国的集成电路 (IC) 进口量和价值均大幅下降，原因是经济不利因素和本土化努力。尽管有所下降，半导体仍是中国最大的进口项目，超过了原油。美国的出口管制措施也导致芯片进口减少，因为中国无法直接从英伟达等美国公司购买先进芯片。中国正在努力提高本地芯片产量，以减少对进口的依赖，并计划扩大成熟芯片的产能，增加国内半导体企业之间的合作。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国进口 IC 的下降反映了经济挑战和本土化努力。</li>    <li>主题：由于经济阻力因素和美国的出口管制，中国在 2023 年的芯片进口量下降，促使了本土化努力。</li>    <li>观点：半导体自给自足对中国经济和技术进步的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国集成电路进口的统计数据；经济阻力因素和本地化努力的影响；美国出口管制措施；中国在提高本地芯片产量方面取得的进展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fabless (adj.) - 指不拥有晶圆制造厂的半导体公司。    <p>原文例句：In October last year, the US further tightened the noose, cutting China’s access to workaround chips that Nvidia had tailor-made for mainland customers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由fab（晶圆制造厂）和less（没有）组成，表示“没有晶圆制造厂的”。在这个例句中，它指的是英伟达为中国客户专门定制的芯片。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>commodity (n.) - 大宗商品。    <p>原文例句：According to the customs data, China’s imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices, a proxy of garden-variety commodity chips, were also down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，有“便利，好处”的意思。在这个例句中，它指的是普通的大宗商品芯片，即广泛流通和交易的标准化商品。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>by comparison - 比较来说。    <P>原文例句：By comparison, the country spent US$337.5 billion importing crude oil last year, a fall of 7.7 per cent. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由by（通过，根据）和comparison（比较）构成的，表示“比较来说”。在这个例句中，它表示与进口原油相比，中国去年进口芯片的价值下降了15.4%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In October last year, the US further tightened the noose, cutting China’s access to workaround chips that Nvidia had tailor-made for mainland customers. - 去年 10 月，美国进一步收紧了对中国获取英伟达为中国客户专门定制的芯片的限制。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The US further tightened the noose，其中主语是The US，谓语是further tightened the noose，宾语是China’s access to workaround chips that Nvidia had tailor-made for mainland customers。cutting China’s access to workaround chips that Nvidia had tailor-made for mainland customers是一个过去分词短语作状语，修饰The US further tightened the noose，表示美国进一步收紧了对中国获取英伟达为中国客户专门定制的芯片的限制。这个句子的意思是说，去年 10 月，美国进一步收紧了对中国获取英伟达为中国客户专门定制的芯片的限制。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>so that 引导的目的状语从句 - 表示为了。    <p>原文例句：These efforts may also have contributed to the decline of imported chips as China added mature capacity to enable production of the vast majority of chips locally. </p>    <p>语法讲解：so that引导的目的状语从句，表示为了。结构是：so that + 主句。其中so that中的so是连词，that是引导目的状语从句的从属连词，主句是谓语动词后带宾语或宾补结构的句子。在这个例句中，so that引导的目的状语从句是to enable production of the vast majority of chips locally，表示为了使绝大多数芯片能够在本地生产。这个句子的意思是说，这些努力也可能导致进口芯片的减少，因为中国增加了成熟的产能，使绝大多数芯片能够在本地生产。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>情态动词 "can" 的用法 - 表示能力或可能性。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia reveals progress in China’s self-driving chip market as competition revs up</p>    <p>语法讲解：情态动词 "can" 有多种用法，其中一种是表示能力或可能性。结构是：主语 + can + 动词原形。在这个例句中，"can" 表示可能性，意思是英伟达在中国自动驾驶芯片市场上正在取得进展，因为竞争正在升温。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In 2023, China imported a total of 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion</li>
<li>Under rigid US export measures, China is unable to directly purchase advanced chips such as Nvidia’s H100 and A100 GPUs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/7a87b40d-bebc-417b-9aa1-baaa805bde8c_3c46d64f.jpg" /><figcaption>China chip imports fall in 2023 on economic headwinds and localisation efforts. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023, although semiconductors remained the mainland’s largest import item ahead of crude oil, according to customs data released on Friday.</p><p>In 2023, China imported a total of 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion, down 10.8 per cent by volume and 15.4 per cent in value from 2022, official data showed. By comparison, the country spent US$337.5 billion importing crude oil last year, a fall of 7.7 per cent.</p><p>The weaker imports of ICs and semiconductor devices reflect economic headwinds in the world’s second-largest economy last year, in particular China’s weak smartphone and laptop sales. Meanwhile, the data was also affected by China’s efforts to boost local output to cut reliance on imported chips.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248095/nvidia-reveals-progress-chinas-self-driving-chip-market-setting-competition-domestic-players" title="">Nvidia reveals progress in China’s self-driving chip market as competition revs up</a></h3><p>Under rigid US export control measures, China is unable to directly buy advanced chips, such as the H100 and A100 graphics processing units designed by US-based Nvidia. However, the country is making solid progress in boosting local output of legacy chips, including those being used in cars and home appliances, to satisfy domestic demand.</p><p>According to the customs data, China’s imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices, a proxy of garden-variety commodity chips, were also down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year.</p><p>The US intensified its export controls on China in October 2022, which caused widespread disruption for global fabless and semiconductor tools companies in their China-related businesses. In October last year, the US further tightened the noose, cutting China’s access to workaround chips that Nvidia had tailor-made for mainland customers.</p><p>In a state-backed drive to build a more resilient domestic chip supply chain, China’s semiconductor players have upped their localisation efforts with closer cooperation between the biggest companies. These efforts may also have contributed to the decline of imported chips as China added mature capacity to enable production of the vast majority of chips locally.</p><p>China currently has 44 semiconductor wafer fabs in operation and a further 22 under construction, Taiwan-based IC research company TrendForce said in a recent note. By the end of 2024, the capacity for mature chip production – defined as 28-nanometre and older technologies – will be expanded at 32 Chinese fabs.</p><p>The massive expansion, which has caused alarm in the US and EU, will see China’s global share of mature process capacity reach 39 per cent by 2027, up from 31 per cent in 2023, with room for further growth if equipment procurement proceeds smoothly, the TrendForce note said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tencent’s e-commerce drive takes off in 2023 on the back of super app WeChat’s short video and live streaming function</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248254/tencents-e-commerce-drive-takes-2023-back-super-app-wechats-short-video-and-live-streaming-function</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: WeChat Channels, a short video and live-streaming function within the popular Chinese social media app WeChat, has experienced significant growth in its e-commerce business, driven by the popularity of TikTok-style short video content.</li>    <li>Theme: WeChat Channels' success in live-streaming e-commerce, contributing to Tencent's overall growth and challenging competitors like Douyin and Kuaishou.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: WeChat Channels' potential to further expand its e-commerce business and advertising revenue, leveraging Tencent's vast user base and integrating with WeChat Pay.</li>    <li>Main information: WeChat Channels' triple GMV growth in 2023; Tencent's focus on short video as a key growth area; WeChat Channels' impact on Tencent's advertising revenue; expansion plans for live-streaming e-commerce and product categories.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>摘要：微信频道是微信中一个短视频和直播功能，它在电子商务业务中取得了显著增长，这得益于 TikTok 式的短视频内容的普及。</li>    <li>主题：微信频道在直播电子商务中的成功，为腾讯的整体增长做出了贡献，并对抖音、快手等竞争对手形成了挑战。</li>    <li>观点：微信频道进一步扩大其电子商务业务和广告收入的潜力，利用腾讯庞大的用户基础并与微信支付整合。</li>    <li>主要信息：微信频道 2023 年商品交易总额 (GMV) 增长三倍；腾讯将重点放在短视频作为关键增长领域；微信频道对腾讯广告收入的影响；直播电子商务和产品类别的扩张计划。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>gross merchandise volume (GMV) - /grəʊs ˈmɜːrtʃənˌdaɪz ˈvɒljʊm/ 商品交易总额。    <p>原文例句：WeChat’s short video and live streaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023, according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p>    <p>例句讲解：GMV 是指在一定时间内通过电子商务平台销售的商品或服务的总金额。在这个例句中，它指的是微信在 2023 年的商品交易总额，据报道，该平台的 GMV 增长了近三倍。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>social media giant - /ˈsəʊʃəl ˈmiːdɪə ˈdʒaɪənt/ 社交媒体巨头。    <p>原文例句：Tencent Holdings, China’s video gaming and social media giant, saw its ubiquitous super app WeChat achieve significant growth in its live-streaming e-commerce business last year, thanks to the popularity of its TikTok-style short video function.</p>    <p>例句讲解：social media giant 是指在社交媒体行业具有巨大影响力和市场份额的公司。在这个例句中，它指的是腾讯，这家公司是中国最大的社交媒体巨头之一。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take on - 挑战，竞争。    <P>原文例句：The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s internet industry, as Tencent quietly made inroads into the live-streaming e-commerce market to take on ByteDance-owned Douyin and Kuaishou Technology – the country’s two largest short video platforms.</p>    <p>例句讲解：take on 是一个短语动词，意思是“挑战，竞争”。在这个例句中，它表示腾讯正在挑战抖音和快手，这两家公司是中国最大的两家短视频平台。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>build up - 建立，发展。    <P>原文例句：Tencent also plans to expand its live-streaming e-commerce-related headcount and broaden its product categories, as the WeChat Pay team builds up the vital transaction infrastructure to facilitate online payments.</p>    <p>例句讲解：build up 是一个短语动词，意思是“建立，发展”。在这个例句中，它表示腾讯计划扩大其与直播电子商务相关的员工人数，并拓宽其产品类别，同时微信支付团队正在建立必要的交易基础设施以促进在线支付。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Launched in 2020, Channels has been growing rapidly and had about 813 million active users as of June 2022. That number was ahead of Douyin’s 680 million users and the 390 million on Kuaishou, according to estimates by Chinese data analytics firm QuestMobile. - 频道于 2020 年推出，发展迅速，截至 2022 年 6 月，活跃用户约为 8.13 亿。根据中国数据分析公司 QuestMobile 的估计，这一数字高于抖音的 6.8 亿用户和快手的 3.9 亿用户。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Channels has been growing rapidly，其中主语是Channels，谓语是has been growing rapidly，宾语是about 813 million active users。Launched in 2020是一个过去分词短语作状语，修饰Channels，表示频道于 2020 年推出。That number was ahead of Douyin’s 680 million users and the 390 million on Kuaishou是一个现在完成时态的句子，其中主语是That number，谓语是was ahead of，宾语是Douyin’s 680 million users and the 390 million on Kuaishou。根据Estimates by Chinese data analytics firm QuestMobile，这一数字高于抖音的 6.8 亿用户和快手的 3.9 亿用户。这个句子的意思是说，频道于 2020 年推出，发展迅速，截至 2022 年 6 月，活跃用户约为 8.13 亿。根据中国数据分析公司 QuestMobile 的估计，这一数字高于抖音的 6.8 亿用户和快手的 3.9 亿用户。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>完成时态 - 表示动作或状态在某个时间点之前已经完成。    <p>原文例句：Tencent Holdings, China’s video gaming and social media giant, saw its ubiquitous super app WeChat achieve significant growth in its live-streaming e-commerce business last year, thanks to the popularity of its TikTok-style short video function.</p>    <p>语法讲解：完成时态是由助动词have/has和过去分词构成的，表示动作或状态在某个时间点之前已经完成。在这个例句中，saw是see的过去式，表示腾讯在去年看到了其无所不在的超级应用微信在其直播电子商务业务中取得显著增长。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时态 - 表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Tencent was expected to hit 100 billion yuan (US$13.9 billion) in e-commerce GMV, a measure of the total value of goods sold online, through WeChat Channels last year, according to a report last month by Chinese media outlet LatePost.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是由助动词have/has和过去分词构成的，表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。在这个例句中，was expected to hit是expect的过去式，表示腾讯预计去年通过微信频道实现电子商务 GMV 1000 亿元人民币（139 亿美元）。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Online orders made through WeChat’s short video and live streaming function, Channels, grew more than 244 per cent in 2023 over the previous year</li>
<li>WeChat Channels has also become a major driver of Tencent’s advertising business, which grew 20 per cent year on year in the third quarter</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/424841e5-a3ac-4b8a-ae91-51168cfa301a_99a90435.jpg" /><figcaption>The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s internet industry, as Tencent Holdings quietly made inroads into the live-streaming e-commerce market. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>, China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> giant, saw its ubiquitous super <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">app</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> achieve significant growth in its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/live-streaming" target="_self" title="">live-streaming</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce business</a> last year, thanks to the popularity of its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a>-style short video function.</p><p>WeChat’s short video and live streaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023, according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/guangzhou-0" target="_self" title="">Guangzhou</a>, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p><p>While the platform’s exact GMV figures were not released, conference attendees were told that the number of orders made through WeChat’s video function – marketed as Channels – grew more than 244 per cent in 2023 over the previous year, according to a report by Chinese online media outlet Thepaper.cn.</p><p>A number of attendees at the conference, which was held as a closed-door event exclusive to industry partners, on Friday confirmed the reported growth rate. Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="2408" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/382a2415-7317-4bb1-8359-257715bbe26b_8190c8e6.jpg" title="Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>WeChat’s high GMV performance last year showed how prescient Tencent founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/abacus/who-what/who/article/3028219/pony-ma-tycoon-behind-chinas-social-media-and-gaming-giant" target="_self" title="">Pony Ma Huateng</a> was in December 2022, when he told an internal town hall meeting that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3204291/tencents-pony-ma-says-cost-cutting-will-continue-2023-and-pins-hope-short-video-major-growth-driver" target="_self" title="">short video was key to the company’s future</a>.</p><p>The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> industry, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244790/tencent-set-hit-e-commerce-sales-milestone-2023-closing-short-video-rivals-bytedance-kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Tencent quietly made inroads</a> into the live-streaming e-commerce market to take on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Kuaishou Technology</a> – the country’s two largest short video platforms.</p><p>Tencent was expected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244790/tencent-set-hit-e-commerce-sales-milestone-2023-closing-short-video-rivals-bytedance-kuaishou" target="_self" title="">hit 100 billion yuan (US$13.9 billion) in e-commerce GMV</a>, a measure of the total value of goods sold online, through WeChat Channels last year, according to a report last month by Chinese media outlet LatePost.</p><p>While the e-commerce turnover on WeChat Channels is small compared with those of Kuaishou and TikTok’s Chinese sibling Douyin, Tencent has bet on swiftly building its online retail business on the back of the country’s vast number of WeChat users, estimated at 1.34 billion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/648b1380-6ea8-4522-b681-e27f1eb67183_1126e908.jpg" title="WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Tencent also plans to expand its live-streaming e-commerce-related headcount and broaden its product categories, as the WeChat Pay team builds the vital transaction infrastructure to facilitate online payments, according to the LatePost report.</p><p>WeChat Channels has already become a major driver of Tencent’s advertising business, which increased 20 per cent year on year in the third quarter, the fastest growth achieved by all of the company’s business segments in that period. During the second quarter, WeChat Channels raked in 3 billion yuan (US$421 million) in advertising revenue.</p><p>Launched in 2020, Channels has been growing rapidly and had about 813 million active users as of June 2022. That number was ahead of Douyin’s 680 million users and the 390 million on Kuaishou, according to estimates by Chinese data analytics firm QuestMobile.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
