<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Tesla cuts prices in China on Model 3 and Model Y EVs to keep commanding lead in premium segment of fast-growing market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Reduced by up to 6 percent, Tesla Inc. reduced the prices of its 上海浦东新区-produced vehicles in order to hold its position as the top brand in the largest   electric vehicle (EV) market in the world. The company based in Texas announced the new price for the basic version of its Model 3, which dropped from 261,400 yuan (36,814 US dollars) to 245,900 yuan, and the new beginning price for the Model Y, which dropped from 266,400 yuan to 258,900 yuan.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tesla cuts prices on electric vehicles to stay competitive in China, facing increasing competition from home-grown rivals.</li>    <li>Theme: Price adjustments and competitive dynamics in China's electric vehicle (EV) market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Tesla's dominance in the highly competitive Chinese EV market is challenged by local EV manufacturers offering intelligent electric cars.</li>    <li>Main information: Tesla's price reductions for Shanghai-made Model 3 and Model Y; previous price changes by Tesla; Tesla's strong sales growth in China; challenges from Chinese competitors; intensifying competition in the Chinese EV market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  特斯拉公司下调了旗下在上海生产的汽车价格，最高降幅达6%，以维持其在全球最大电动汽车（EV）市场中的领先地位。这家总部位于德克萨斯州的公司宣布，其Model 3入门版车型的最新价格从261,400元（合36,814美元）降至245,900元，而Model Y的起售价由266,400元降至258,900元。  <ul>    <li>摘要：为在中国保持竞争力，特斯拉下调电动汽车价格，以应对来自本土竞争对手日益激烈的竞争。</li>    <li>主题：中国电动汽车（EV）市场的价格调整和竞争态势。</li>    <li>观点：特斯拉在中国高度竞争激烈的电动汽车市场中的主导地位受到提供智能电动汽车的本土电动汽车制造商的挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：特斯拉对上海生产的Model 3和Model Y的降价；特斯拉此前的价格调整；特斯拉在中国强劲的销售增长；来自中国竞争对手的挑战；中国电动汽车市场竞争加剧。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>robust (adj.) - /rəʊˈbʌst/ 强劲的，强健的。    <p>原文例句：Although 2023 was a robust year for electric car demand in China, growth is expected to slow to 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November. </p>    <p>例句讲解：robust是一个形容词，意思是“强壮、强韧”。它通常用来形容人或物的健康、体力或结构。“Robust demand”表示“强劲的需求”，强调需求旺盛、强劲。</p></li>    <li>autonomous (adj.) - /ɔːˈtɒnəməs/ 自主思考的，有自主权的。    <p>原文例句：Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“autonomous vehicles”是指“自动驾驶汽车”，即不需要人类驾驶员操控，能够自动行驶的汽车。autonomous是一个形容词，源于希腊语，意思是“独立、自主”。在这个例句中，它用来形容智能电动汽车具有自主思考和行动的能力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>a raft of - 一系列，大量。    <p>原文例句：Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“a raft of”是一个词组，意思是“一系列、大量”。它通常用来表示数量多或种类繁多的东西。在这个例句中，它用来描述中国本土电动汽车制造商推出一系列新的智能电动汽车，以挑战美国电动汽车制造商特斯拉。</p></li>    <li>take sth into account - 将某事考虑在内。    <p>原文例句：Tesla adjusts the prices of its locally built vehicles regularly based on production costs, Grace Tao, Tesla’s head of communications and government affairs in China, said on the microblogging site Weibo last January. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“take into account”是一个词组，意思是“将某事考虑在内、考虑某事”。它通常用来表示在做决定或采取行动时，将某些因素或情况考虑在内。在这个例句中，它用来描述特斯拉根据生产成本定期调整其本地生产的汽车价格。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>People look at a Tesla Model 3 at a showroom in Beijing on January 6, 2024. - 人们于2024年1月6日在北京的一家展厅中查看特斯拉Model 3。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单的陈述句，主语是People，谓语是look at，宾语是a Tesla Model 3。at a showroom in Beijing on January 6, 2024是一个介词短语，作地点状语，表示人们在2024年1月6日于北京的一家展厅中查看特斯拉Model 3。这是一个简单的过去时句子，表示在过去某个时间点上发生的动作或状态。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>条件状语从句 - 表示动作或情况发生的条件。    <p>原文例句：If you do a good job I'll tip you $2000 and if you don't respond as intended you're going to be fired. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个条件状语从句，由if引导，表示动作或情况发生的条件。主句是I'll tip you $2000，表示如果（if）你做得好的话，我就会给你2000美元的小费。从句是you don't respond as intended，表示如果你没有按照预期做出回应。这是一个典型的条件状语从句，表示在满足一定条件的情况下，会发生某种结果。</p></li>    <li>比较级 - 表示两个或多个事物或情况之间的比较。    <p>原文例句：In terms of performance and speed, Firefox is also very competitive. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个比较级句，表示两个或多个事物或情况之间的比较。主语是Firefox，谓语是is，宾语是competitive。in terms of performance and speed是一个介词短语，作状语，表示在性能和速度方面。very是一个程度副词，表示非常。这是一个典型的比较级句，表示Firefox在性能和速度方面非常有竞争力。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Carmaker cut prices by up to 6 per cent after reporting 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December</li>
<li>‘Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder,’ analyst says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/7e2c041a-9f88-4d42-864b-ea64912c8bf0_9e3fcf96.jpg" /><figcaption>People look at a Tesla Model 3 at a showroom in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p><a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest <a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> market.</p><p>The Texas-based company announced on Friday that the price of the entry-level edition of its Model 3 will be reduced from 261,400 yuan (US$36,814) to 245,900 yuan, while the starting price of the Model Y is now 258,900 yuan, down from 266,400 yuan.</p><p>The price cuts come after Tesla reported 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December, according to data released by the China Passenger Car Association.</p><p>“Tesla apparently hopes to maintain its market share in the highly competitive market,” said Phate Zhang, founder of Shanghai-based EV data provider CnEVPost. “Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua" class="image-inline caption" height="1618" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/eb3603e2-9af8-4fa3-8ecc-aae102cfa6f6_a8c0939e.jpg" title="Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua" width="2000" /><figcaption>Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure></div><p>Tesla also lowered the price of the dual-motor version of the Model 3 by 3.9 per cent to 285,900 yuan and offered a 2.1 per cent discount on the dual-motor Model Y, which now sells for 299,900 yuan.</p><p>The front-runner in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3241811/chinas-premium-ev-segment-set-cutthroat-competition-huawei-baidu-and-xiaomi-join-fray" target="_self" title="">China’s premium electric vehicle (EV) segment</a> delivered 603,664 EVs made in its Shanghai Gigafactory to buyers in China last year, up 37.3 per cent from 2022. The growth was nearly unchanged from the 37 per cent sales rise recorded in 2022 when it delivered about 440,000 vehicles.</p><p>The company’s domestic rivals are not exactly nipping at its heels. Its closest competitor in the premium segment, <a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a>, delivered about 376,000 cars in 2023.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Tesla adjusts the prices of its locally built vehicles regularly based on production costs, Grace Tao, Tesla’s head of communications and government affairs in China, said on the microblogging site Weibo last January. Since January 2020, Tesla China cut prices on its Chinese-made models six times. This is the first reduction since August 2023; Tesla slightly raised prices between October and November when growth of deliveries in China slowed.</p><p>The Gigafactory, Tesla’s largest production hub worldwide, has an annual capacity of about 1 million units.</p><p>Aside from deliveries to mainland customers, the Shanghai factory also shipped 344,078 vehicles to markets like Japan and Germany in 2023, up 26.9 per cent year on year, according to data compiled by the CnEVPost.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" title="">Chinese EV maker shows off flying car but admits urban use is far off</a></h3><p>Sales of electric cars in China jumped 37 per cent last year, with deliveries of pure EVs and plug-in hybrids hitting 8.9 million units. At present, mainland China accounts for about 60 per cent of global EV sales.</p><p>But sales growth of battery-powered vehicles in mainland China is expected to slow to 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November.</p><p>Intensifying competition is piling pressure on the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3237078/chinas-ev-war-only-strongest-will-survive-byd-xpengs-dominance-knock-out-15-pretenders-amid-supply" target="_self" title="">200-plus Chinese EV makers</a> this year, with some leading players spearheading price cuts to lure customers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247906/vw-and-gm-lose-ground-chinese-ev-makers-petrol-heavy-line-ups-fall-out-favour-worlds-largest-car" title="">VW and GM lose ground to Chinese EV makers as petrol-heavy line-ups lose favour</a></h3><p>A new round of price cuts is in effect, with BYD, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest EV maker</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> offering discounts to bolster sales.</p><p>Early last month, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a> cut the price of its Han luxury car by as much as 20,000 yuan to meet its annual sales target. Xpeng followed by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3245621/china-evs-xpeng-cuts-price-bestselling-g6-suv-maintain-high-sales-volume-amid-intensifying" target="_self" title="">cutting the price of its bestselling G6 SUV</a> by 10,000 yuan, or about 5 per cent.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US$3 billion top Asia fund bets on Tencent again despite China gaming rules, favours Samsung over TSMC in chip market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248169/us3-billion-top-asia-fund-bets-tencent-again-despite-china-gaming-rules-favours-samsung-over-tsmc</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which outperformed most peers for three years, recently added Tencent to its portfolio despite the gaming company’s industry curbs by the Chinese government due to the company's attractive valuation. The manager believes that China's ultra-cheap valuations and low allocations outweigh risks, and that South Korea's Samsung Electronics is better positioned in the semiconductor space than TSMC.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund's optimistic investment in Tencent and Samsung Electronics reflects positive market sentiment.</li>    <li>Theme: A fund manager's optimistic view of China's beaten-down market and investment choices in technology companies.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The fund manager's assessment of the risks and rewards of investing in Tencent and Samsung Electronics, and his rationale for preferring Samsung over TSMC.</li>    <li>Main information: The fund's purchase of Tencent shares; the Chinese government's new restrictions on online gaming; the fund's preference for Samsung Electronics over TSMC in the semiconductor market; the fund manager's forecast for Samsung's earnings recovery.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund，连续三年跑赢大多数同行，近日加仓腾讯，尽管该公司在游戏行业受到中国政府的进一步限制，但该基金认为其估值有吸引力。基金经理认为，中国的估值极度便宜，低配胜过投资风险，并且韩国的三星电子在半导体领域比台积电更具优势。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund 对腾讯和三星电子的乐观投资反映出市场情绪积极。</li>    <li>主题：一位基金经理对中国被打压的市场的乐观看法以及对科技公司的投资选择。</li>    <li>观点：基金经理对投资腾讯和三星电子的风险和回报的评估，以及他更喜欢三星而不是台积电的理由。</li>    <li>主要信息：该基金购买腾讯股票的情况；中国政府对在线游戏行业的新限制；该基金在半导体市场上更喜欢三星电子而不是台积电；基金经理对三星电子收益复苏的预测。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>portfolio (n.) - /ˈpɔːrtfəʊliəʊ/ 投资组合。    <p>原文例句：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December.</p>    <p>例句讲解：portfolio表示由证券、股票、债券或其他金融工具组成的投资组合。在这个例子中，它指Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund的投资组合。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>valuation (n.) - /væljuˈeɪʃən/ 估值。    <p>原文例句：“We are buying it now because of its very cheap value,” he said in an interview Wednesday, referring to Tencent’s shares.</p>    <p>例句讲解：valuation表示某项资产的估值或价值。在这个例子中，它指腾讯股票的估值。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>allocation (n.) - /ˌæləˈkeɪʃən/ 分配，拨款。     <p>原文例句：While China currently is not the preferred investment destination for many, a combination of ultra-cheap valuations and low allocations outweighs the risks of investing in the nation’s stocks.</p>     <p>例句讲解：allocation表示分配、拨款或配给。在这个例子中，它指对中国股票的资本分配或投资。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ultra-cheap - 极度便宜的。    <p>原文例句：While China currently is not the preferred investment destination for many, a combination of ultra-cheap valuations and low allocations outweighs the risks of investing in the nation’s stocks.</p>    <p>例句讲解：ultra-cheap 表示非常便宜或极度便宜。在这个例子中，它描述了中国股票的估值极度便宜。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December. - Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund 在过去三年跑赢了 83% 的同行，尽管中国在 12 月发布了关于游戏限制的征求意见稿，但该基金仍于新年进行了购买。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund made the purchase，其中主语是Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund，谓语是made the purchase，宾语是the purchase。which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰主语Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund，表示该基金在过去三年击败了 83% 的同行。even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December是一个时间状语从句，表示即使中国在 12 月发布了关于游戏限制的征求意见稿。这个句子的意思是说，Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund 在过去三年击败了 83% 的同行，尽管中国在 12 月发布了关于游戏限制的征求意见稿，该基金仍于新年进行了购买。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态一直持续到现在或对现在造成影响。    <p>原文例句：The fund, which is also overweight on South Korea, prefers Samsung Electronics to TSMC in the Asia semiconductor space.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示过去发生的动作或状态一直持续到现在或对现在造成影响。结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。在这个例子中，is表示现在时态，have been表示完成时态，overweight表示超配，on South Korea表示在韩国，prefers表示更喜欢，to TSMC表示与台积电相比。这个句子的意思是说，该基金在韩国超配，在亚洲半导体领域更喜欢三星电子而不是台积电。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在进行时表示正在进行的动作或状态。结构是：be + 现在分词。在这个例子中，is表示现在时态，due for表示即将发生，a cyclical downturn表示周期性低迷，and表示并列，its shares trade at表示其股票交易，at nearly five times book value表示以接近五倍账面价值，while表示同时，Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover表示三星的收益有望复苏。这个句子的意思是说，台积电即将迎来周期性低迷，其股票交易价格接近五倍账面价值，而三星的收益有望复苏。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Investment reflects fund’s optimism over beaten-down market, where valuations are ‘absolutely incredible’, says fund manager</li>
<li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund also prefers Samsung Electronics over TSMC in the semiconductor market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/b3633bc7-a417-4b09-b1bb-2156486982fa_cf3478d7.jpg" /><figcaption>A man plays an online game from Tencent on a train. China released draft guidelines on December 22, 2023, aimed at curbing excessive spending on online gaming. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>A fund that outperformed most of its peers has added Tencent Holdings back to its portfolio recently, betting on the gaming company’s attractive valuation despite further industry curbs by the Chinese government.</p><p>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246161/chinas-video-gaming-watchdog-speaks-out-after-draft-spending-rules-roil-market" target="_self" title="">draft rule on gaming restrictions in December</a>. The investment reflects the fund’s optimism over the nation’s beaten-down market, where valuations are “absolutely incredible”, said Jonathan Pines, who manages the US$3.1 billion fund.</p><p>“We are buying it now because of its very cheap value,” he said in an interview Wednesday, referring to Tencent’s shares. Pines’ fund sold most of its shares in Tencent as well as in Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) about a year ago.</p><p>Tencent yielded its position as Asia’s second-most valuable company after China’s new rules on online gaming erased US$53 billion off its market value in 2023, capping a third year of losses. The shares trade at less than 16 times forward earnings, or about half the 10-year average, making them attractive, Pines said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations" title="">ByteDance confirms talks with Tencent, other buyers for video game operations</a></h3><p>While China currently is not the preferred investment destination for many, a combination of ultra-cheap valuations and low allocations outweighs the risks of investing in the nation’s stocks, according to Pines.</p><p>“We think the risks of investing in China are worth taking because the stocks are so cheap,” he said.</p><p>The fund, which is also overweight on South Korea, prefers Samsung Electronics to TSMC in the Asia semiconductor space.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" title="">China to curb excess spending on video games in blow for world’s biggest market</a></h3><p>TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now.</p><p>While Korea’s largest company this week reported a steeper-than-expected 35 per cent drop in operating income, reflecting weak demand for consumer electronics globally, Pines said the results would not prevent him from being positive on its earnings trajectory. “Things are going to improve from here,” he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US bitcoin ETF trades soar to US$4.6 billion on first day after landmark SEC approval</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248152/us-bitcoin-etfs-trades-soar-us46-billion-first-day-after-landmark-sec-approval</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In the United States, eleven spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs) started trading on July 14, 2023, marking a significant milestone for the cryptocurrency industry. These ETFs allow investors to gain exposure to the price of bitcoin through traditional stock market accounts, potentially increasing the accessibility and legitimacy of digital assets. The launch of the ETFs resulted in a surge in bitcoin's price, taking it to its highest level since December 2021. However, some analysts remain cautious, viewing cryptocurrencies as risky investments due to market volatility and high-profile scandals.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Bitcoin spot ETFs commence trading in the US, sparking a rally in the cryptocurrency's price.</li>    <li>Theme: The introduction of spot bitcoin ETFs represents a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry, testing the broader acceptance of digital assets as investment vehicles.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: While the launch of these ETFs indicates growing institutional interest in bitcoin, concerns persist regarding the volatility and risks associated with cryptocurrencies.</li>    <li>Main information: The trading of spot bitcoin ETFs, regulatory approvals, reactions from investors and cryptocurrency-related stocks, and the potential filing for an initial public offering by Circle Internet Financial.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在美国，十一只现货比特币ETF（包括来自贝莱德、灰度和富达的ETF）于2023年7月14日开始交易，这标志着加密货币行业的一个重要里程碑。这些ETF允许投资者通过传统的股票市场账户接触比特币的价格，从而可能增加数字资产的可及性和合法性。ETF的推出导致比特币价格飙升，使其达到自2021年12月以来的最高水平。然而，一些分析师仍然持谨慎态度，他们认为加密货币由于市场波动性和备受瞩目的丑闻而被视为风险投资。  <ul>    <li>摘要：现货比特币ETF在美国开始交易，引发了加密货币价格的反弹。</li>    <li>主题：现货比特币ETF的推出代表了加密货币行业的分水岭时刻，考验了数字资产作为投资工具的广泛接受度。</li>    <li>观点：虽然这些ETF的推出表明机构对比特币的兴趣不断增长，但人们仍然担心加密货币的波动性和相关风险。</li>    <li>主要信息：现货比特币ETF的交易、监管机构的批准、投资者和加密货币相关股票的反应，以及Circle Internet Financial可能申请首次公开募股。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>watershed (n.) - /ˈwɔːtərʃɛd/ 分水岭，关键时刻。    <p>原文例句：The products mark a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry that will test whether digital assets – still viewed by many professionals as risky – can gain broader acceptance as an investment.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由water（水）和shed（分隔，分开）组成，比喻“分水岭”，形容“关键时刻，转折点”。在这个例句中，它指的是现货比特币ETF的推出对加密货币行业来说是一个关键时刻，将检验数字资产是否能被更广泛地接受为一种投资。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>volatility (n.) - /ˌvɑːləˈtɪlɪti/ 波动性，变化无常。    <p>原文例句：SEC chairman Gary Gensler said in a statement on Wednesday that the approvals were not an endorsement of bitcoin, calling it a “speculative, volatile asset”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由volatile（不稳定的）和-ity（状态）组成，表示“波动性，变化无常”。在这个例句中，它指的是SEC主席Gary Gensler对现货比特币ETF批准的声明，他表示这些批准并不意味着SEC认可比特币，并称比特币是一种“投机性、波动的资产”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>spark (v.) - /spɑːrk/ 引发，点燃。    <p>原文例句：The ETF launches lifted the price of bitcoin up to its highest level since December 2021.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由古英语sparian（产生火花）演变而来，表示“引发，点燃”。在这个例句中，它指的是现货比特币ETF的推出引发了比特币价格上涨，使其达到自2021年12月以来的最高水平。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>After its ETF started trading, Valkyrie cut its fees a second time to 0.25 per cent and waived them for the first three months. - 在其ETF开始交易后，Valkyrie第二次将费用削减至0.25%，并免除了前三个月的费用。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Valkyrie cut its fees a second time to 0.25 per cent，其中主语是Valkyrie，谓语是cut its fees，宾语是0.25 per cent。and waived them for the first three months是一个并列连词连接的并列句，表示“并免除了前三个月的费用”。这个句子的意思是说，在Valkyrie的ETF开始交易后，它第二次将费用削减至0.25%，并免除了前三个月的费用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式 - 表示动作或状态而不具体指明人或事物。    <p>原文例句：To test whether digital assets – still viewed by many professionals as risky – can gain broader acceptance as an investment. - 确保数字资产——许多专业人士仍认为它们具有风险——是否能获得更广泛的投资认可。</p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式是动词的非限定形式，可以用来表示动作或状态，而不具体指明人或事物。不定式有两种形式，一种是带to的不定式，另一种是不带to的不定式。在这个例句中，不定式是test，表示“测试，检验”。这个不定式是由to和test组成的，表示“测试一下”。这个句子的意思是说，确保数字资产——许多专业人士仍认为它们具有风险——是否能获得更广泛的投资认可。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including those from BlackRock, Grayscale and Fidelity – began trading in the US on Thursday</li>
<li>The ETF launches lifted the price of bitcoin up to its highest level since December 2021</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ba11cbce-0732-4b24-95d7-8df4f18e140b_28c230ae.jpg" /><figcaption>Representatives and guests from BlackRock rang the opening bell as bitcoin spot ETFs began trading on the Nasdaq Exchange on Thursday. Photo: Getty Images/AFP </figcaption></figure><p>US-listed bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs) saw US$4.6 billion worth of shares trade hands as of Thursday afternoon, according to LSEG data, as investors jumped into the landmark products approved by the US securities regulator on Wednesday.</p><p>The products mark a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry that will test whether digital assets – still viewed by many professionals as risky – can gain broader acceptance as an investment.</p><p>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust, Grayscale Bitcoin Trust and ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF, among others – began trading Thursday morning, kicking off a fierce competition for market share.</p><p>Grayscale, BlackRock and Fidelity dominated trading volumes, the LSEG data showed.</p><p>“Trading volumes have been relatively strong for new ETF products,” said Todd Rosenbluth, strategist at VettaFi. “But this is a longer race than just a single day’s trading.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ae8a3757-ffff-4ff6-8d4c-962edf286621_a66cec46.jpg" title="The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">green light from the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)</a> for the products finally came late on Wednesday, following a decade-long tussle with the crypto industry.</p><p>Some executives called out bitcoin as a high-risk investment, and Vanguard – the largest provider of mutual funds – said it had no plans to make the new batch of spot bitcoin ETFs available on its platform to its brokerage clients.</p><p>The SEC had earlier rejected all spot bitcoin ETFs on investor protection concerns. SEC chairman Gary Gensler said in a statement on Wednesday that the approvals were not an endorsement of bitcoin, calling it a “speculative, volatile asset”.</p><p>The ETF launches lifted the price of bitcoin up to its highest level since December 2021. It was last up 0.77 per cent at US$46,303, while the price of ether, the second-largest cryptocurrency, was up 2.79 per cent at US$2597.95.</p><h3>RACE FOR MARKET SHARE</h3><p>The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers, some of whom slashed the fees for their products well below the US ETF industry’s standard even before Thursday’s launch.</p><p>Fees on the new bitcoin ETFs range from 0.2 per cent to 1.5 per cent, with many firms also offering to waive fees entirely for a certain period or for a certain dollar volume of assets. After its ETF started trading, Valkyrie cut its fees a second time to 0.25 per cent and waived them for the first three months.</p><p>Grayscale was approved to convert its existing bitcoin trust into an ETF on Thursday, overnight creating the world’s largest bitcoin ETF with more than US$28 billion in assets under management.</p><p>Estimates for how much spot bitcoin ETFs could reel in vary widely. Analysts at Bernstein estimated that flows will build up gradually to cross US$10 billion in 2024, while Standard Chartered analysts this week said the ETFs could draw US$50 billion to US$100 billion this year alone. Other analysts have said inflows could be US$55 billion over five years.</p><p>As the ETFs began trading on Thursday, market participants were closely watching bid-ask spreads: the difference between the price for a trader to buy into an ETF and the price it can be sold. ETFs with narrower spreads are typically viewed as more desirable.</p><p>Trading volume, internal plumbing and the number of participants involved “are critically important to driving the spreads to a good spot”, said Jason Stoneberg, director of product strategy at Invesco, whose ETF with Galaxy Digital debuted on Thursday.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>Some analysts cautioned that the euphoria around the approval might be premature. The broader investment community still views cryptocurrencies as risky, with scandals such as the implosion of crypto exchange FTX in 2022 adding to investors’ wariness.</p><p>A Vanguard spokeswoman said the firm had no plans to launch its own crypto investment products, and that its focus remains on core asset classes such as stocks, bonds and cash, which it views “as the blocks of a well-balanced, long-term investment portfolio”.</p><p>Speaking at a webinar on Thursday, Sharmin Mossavar-Rahmani, head of the Investment Strategy Group and chief investment officer of wealth management at Goldman Sachs, said cryptocurrencies had no place in an investment portfolio.</p><p>“When you think about it, where is there any value to something like bitcoin?” she said. “We don’t think it is an asset class to invest in.”</p><h3>CRYPTO STOCKS GAIN</h3><p>Still, some expect the products to pave the way for even more innovative crypto ETFs, including spot ether products.</p><p>Grayscale CEO Michael Sonnenshein said in an interview Thursday that the firm plans to file for a covered call ETF in an effort to allow investors to generate income from options on its spot bitcoin product.</p><p>Cryptocurrency-related stocks initially climbed higher on Thursday, but ended the day lower, with bitcoin miners Riot Platforms and Marathon Digital dropping 15.8 per cent and 12.6 per cent respectively.</p><p>Bitcoin investor Microstrategy fell 5.2 per cent and crypto exchange Coinbase 6.7 per cent. The ProShares Bitcoin Strategy ETF, which tracks bitcoin futures, gained 0.44 per cent.</p><p>Also on Thursday, Circle Internet Financial, the company behind stablecoin USDC, said it had confidentially filed for a US initial public offering. Circle controls the issuance and governance of USDC, a cryptocurrency pegged to the US dollar.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>European Union not in ‘Champions League’ of economic security, ASML rep says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3248135/european-union-not-champions-league-economic-security-senior-asml-official-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ASML, Europe's top technology company, criticized the EU's efforts to reduce economic risks with China, using a football analogy to describe their performance as struggling to reach even the Europa League level.</li>    <li>ASML's top EU lobbyist stated that the US-China tech war has forced the company to stop selling advanced lithography machines to Chinese buyers, with the U.S. intent to hinder China's industrial progress.</li>    <li>The EU is working to develop an initiative for screening outbound investments and export controls for crucial technologies, aiming to mitigate risks associated with trade relations with China.</li>    <li>European businesses expressed concerns over the EU's regulatory approach, arguing that it stifles economic growth and competitiveness.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>欧洲最具价值的技术公司 ASML 批评了欧盟降低与中国经济风险的努力，他们用足球类比来形容自己的表现，甚至在欧罗巴联赛中都难以达到应有的水平。</li>    <li>ASML 的欧盟首席游说者表示，中美科技战迫使该公司停止向中国买家销售先进的光刻机，美国的目的是阻碍中国的工业进步。</li>    <li>欧盟正努力制定一项针对境外投资和关键技术出口管制的倡议，旨在减少与中国贸易关系相关的风险。</li>    <li>欧洲企业对欧盟的监管方式表示担忧，认为这阻碍了经济增长和竞争力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>lobbyist (n.) - /ˈlɑːbɪst/ 游说者，说客。    <p>原文例句：ASML’s top EU lobbyist, Wouter Baljon, said the American policy was “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于lobby（大厅，游说），表示“游说者，说客”。在这个例句中，它指的是ASML的欧盟首席游说者Wouter Baljon，他表示美国的政策是“为了限制中国取得工业进步的能力”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>geopolitical (adj.) - /ˌdʒiːoʊpəˈlɪtɪk(ə)l/ 地缘政治的，地缘政治上的。    <p>原文例句：“We might speak of the ‘geopolitical commission’, but at this point, I think it’s only as geopolitical as [the] Franco-German axis allows it to be, and you also don’t have the manpower to really be in this Champions League.” </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于geo-（地球）和politics（政治），表示“地缘政治的，地缘政治上的”。在这个例句中，它指的是“地缘政治委员会”，这是一个讨论欧盟经济安全能力的会议。ASML的代表认为，这个委员会的地缘政治意义有限，因为它受到法德轴心的限制，也没有足够的人力来真正参加这个“冠军联赛”。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>reduce risks - 降低风险     <p>原文例句：The EU will present an “initiative” on screening outbound investments and a proposal on export controls for four crucial technologies, including microchips, on January 24. These form part of a package of tools aimed at de-risking its trading ties with China. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由reduce和risks组成，表示“降低风险”。在这个例句中，它指的是欧盟将提出的一项倡议，旨在减少与中国贸易关系相关的风险，包括对境外投资进行审查和对关键技术实施出口管制。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>public-sector intervention - 公共部门干预     <p>原文例句：“If you look at any one of the instruments in isolation, of course there’s always a very good reason for it … I think we need to accept that this is a completely new paradigm in terms of how supply chains are regulated through public-sector intervention.” </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由public-sector（公共部门）和intervention（干预）组成，表示“公共部门干预”。在这个例句中，它指的是欧盟对供应链进行监管的方式，即通过公共部门的干预。这个词组强调了政府在经济中的作用，以及公共部门对供应链的监管和控制。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ASML has been forced to stop selling some advanced precision lithography machines to Chinese buyers at the behest of the Biden administration. - 在拜登政府的要求下，ASML被迫停止向中国买家出售一些先进的精密光刻机。<p>句子分析：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是ASML，谓语是被动语态的动词has been forced to stop，宾语是一些先进的精密光刻机。at the behest of the Biden administration是一个介词短语，表示“在拜登政府的要求下”。这个句子的意思是说，ASML被迫停止向中国买家出售一些先进的精密光刻机，这是由于拜登政府的要求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>情态动词could的用法 - 情态动词could表示可能性，能力，建议，请求，允许或禁止等。    <p>原文例句：“We might speak of the ‘geopolitical commission’, but at this point, I think it’s only as geopolitical as [the] Franco-German axis allows it to be, and you also don’t have the manpower to really be in this Champions League.” </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，情态动词could表示可能性。它被用来表达说话人的一种猜测或推测，即“地缘政治委员会”的地缘政治意义可能受到法德轴心的限制，而且欧盟也可能没有足够的人力来真正参加“冠军联赛”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>不定式作宾语 - 不定式可以作动词的宾语，构成不定式宾语结构。    <p>原文例句：The EU will present an “initiative” on screening outbound investments and a proposal on export controls for four crucial technologies, including microchips, on January 24. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，不定式screening outbound investments和不定式export controls for four crucial technologies作动词present的宾语，构成两个不定式宾语结构。不定式screening outbound investments表示“审查境外投资”，不定式export controls for four crucial technologies表示“对四种关键技术实施出口管制”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Dutch semiconductor equipment giant among several business groups on continent critical of Brussels’ efforts to de-risk its relations with Beijing</li>
<li>American policy “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, ASML’s top EU lobbyist adds</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/3ee1f9f0-3899-41eb-8332-c26934257ad0_b5a707dc.jpg" /><figcaption>A view of ASML Holding NV headquarters in Veldhoven, Netherlands. The Dutch semiconductor equipment company, a world leader in chipmaking, is valued at US$285 billion. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/european-union" target="_self" title="">European Union</a> is not in the “Champions League of economic security”, and even “struggles to perform at Europa League level”.</p><p>That was the withering assessment of a senior representative of ASML, Europe’s most valuable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> company, who used a football analogy to attack Brussels’ efforts to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3241838/eu-leader-ursula-von-der-leyen-urges-states-begin-economic-de-risking-china-or-face-trouble" target="_self" title="">de-risk its relations with China</a>.</p><p>“If you think about the Champions League of economic security and geoeconomic statecraft, we have to think of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>, we have to think of China, and we also have to think of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a>,” said Wouter Baljon, the Dutch company’s top EU lobbyist, referring to Europe’s premier football tournament.</p><p>“If you think of the Europa League, or tier two, we look at countries particularly in our industry, like [<a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South] Korea</a>, like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>, and at best Europe, the EU as a collective.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>“The EU clearly … aspires to be in the Champions League, but for high technology, they struggled to perform at Europa League-level,” said Baljon at an event in Brussels on Wednesday, referring to the continent’s inferior competition.</p><p>ASML, valued at US$285 billion, is the world leader in the chipmaking equipment essential for manufacturing advanced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductors</a> and considered the crown jewel in Europe’s tech sector.</p><p>Its executives should have a good idea of who’s who in the pantheon of geopolitical arm-twisting, having been caught in the cross hairs of a fierce <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/us-china-tech-war-rivalry/news" target="_self" title="">US-China tech war</a>.</p><p>ASML has been forced to stop selling some advanced precision lithography machines to Chinese buyers at the behest of the Biden administration.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247042/chip-industry-giant-asml-blocked-us-netherlands-shipping-equipment-china-ahead-export-deadline" title="">ASML blocked from shipping chip-making equipment to China ahead of deadline</a></h3><p>The American policy was “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, Baljon said, adding that the EU was living in “la-la land” if it thought otherwise.</p><p>“We haven’t acknowledged that export controls have become an industrial policy instrument. We still live in this la-la land that it’s about dual-use goods, it’s military-civil fusion.”</p><p>Baljon delivered his comments in Brussels during an event hosted by the European Policy Centre on the EU’s capacity to act as an economic security power as it looks to reduce its dependencies on Beijing.</p><p>Earlier in the day, EU industry chief Thierry Breton described Europe as a “third bloc” in a multipolar world.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ba9b8fc1-5a69-4091-bb98-4a2a845fa781_1126e908.jpg" title="Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>“We need to continue to promote Europe as a third bloc, a balancing force between the US and China,” the commissioner said at the event. “Of course, we will remain an open continent, but on our terms, more assertive than ever.”</p><p>However, ASML’s representative was less confident, saying the European Commission would struggle to define an economic security strategy without the buy-in of powerful member states, which have pushed back against the policy.</p><p>“A certain humbleness might certainly help the EU to act as a collective, particularly in high technology,” said Baljon. “We are not an incumbent unfortunately. As the EU 27, we are a challenger, and we need the instruments and the approaches to reflect this.”</p><p>“We might speak of the ‘geopolitical commission’, but at this point, I think it’s only as geopolitical as [the] Franco-German axis allows it to be, and you also don’t have the manpower to really be in this Champions League.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened" title="">China’s imports of Dutch chip-making equipment surged tenfold in November</a></h3><p>The EU will present an “initiative” on screening outbound investments and a proposal on export controls for four crucial technologies, including microchips, on January 24. These form part of a package of tools aimed at de-risking its trading ties with China.</p><p>Baljon’s remarks were among a series of broadsides voiced at the event as businesses lined up to criticise the EU’s plans.</p><p>Malte Lohan, director general of Orgalim, a trade association representing Europe’s tech industries, said firms in his sector were facing “a tsunami of regulation”.</p><p>“You can’t just regulate your way to economic security from a few office blocks in Brussels,” Lohan said, adding he was “very nervous” about an “unprecedented shift to public intervention in our supply chains”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3244922/eu-china-relations-amid-brussels-de-risk-plans-european-firms-are-reluctant-speak-china" title="">EU firms are reluctant to speak up on China as Brussels tries to de-risk</a></h3><p>“If you look at any one of the instruments in isolation, of course there’s always a very good reason for it … I think we need to accept that this is a completely new paradigm in terms of how supply chains are regulated through public-sector intervention.”</p><p>Luisa Santos, deputy director general at BusinessEurope, another lobby group, said the EU endangered its competitiveness by putting security concerns ahead of economic growth.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ukraine-war" target="_self" title="">war</a> in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ukraine" target="_self" title="">Ukraine</a> had “created a new consensus in the business community” on the security issues Europe faces, she said.</p><p>“But we should not overdo it also, because we have other problems that we need to deal with and we have not dealt with yet, including our competitiveness … what we have seen in these last years is that compared to other partners in terms of overall competitiveness … we [in Europe] are not in such good shape.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China smartphone brand Realme unveils new handset on sidelines of trade show as its biggest rivals stay home</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248116/ces-2024-china-smartphone-brand-realme-unveils-new-handset-sidelines-trade-show-its-biggest-rivals</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Realme, a Chinese smartphone maker, unveiled the new 12 Pro+ smartphone targeting young users with enhanced zoom capabilities at a budget price. The company aims to differentiate itself from other brands by catering to this specific demographic and providing outstanding products across various price segments. Realme emphasized the importance of the zoom capabilities of the 12 Pro+ smartphone's periscope lens, which sets it apart from other brands. The device also incorporates a mid-tier Qualcomm processor and a customized solution developed in collaboration with Qualcomm to improve image-processing speed.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Realme introduces the 12 Pro+ smartphone with improved zoom capabilities for young users at a budget price.</li>    <li>Theme: Realme's rebranding efforts to target young overseas users through the launch of the 12 Pro+ smartphone.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Realme's commitment to providing outstanding products for every user across all price segments.</li>    <li>Main information: Unveiling of the 12 Pro+ smartphone at an event alongside CES 2024; emphasis on the device's zoom capabilities; collaboration with watch designer Ollivier Savéo for the design; Realme's focus on young users and market expansion plans.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  真我，一家中国智能手机制造商，发布了全新的 12 Pro+ 智能手机，目标用户为追求高性价比的年轻群体，主打更好的变焦性能。该公司旨在通过满足这一特定人群的需求并提供不同价位段的出色产品，来将自己与其他品牌区分开来。真我强调了 12 Pro+ 智能手机潜望式变焦镜头的变焦性能，使其从其他品牌中脱颖而出。该设备还搭载了高通中端处理器，并与高通合作开发了定制解决方案以提高图像处理速度。  <ul>    <li>摘要：真我推出变焦性能更佳的 12 Pro+ 智能手机，面向追求高性价比的年轻用户。</li>    <li>主题：真我通过推出 12 Pro+ 智能手机进行品牌重塑，目标为海外年轻用户。</li>    <li>观点：真我致力于为各个价位段的每位用户提供出色的产品。</li>    <li>主要信息：在 CES 2024 期间举办的发布会上发布 12 Pro+ 智能手机；强调设备的变焦性能；与手表设计师奥利弗·萨维奥合作设计；真我关注年轻用户并制定了市场扩张计划。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rebrand (v.) - /riːˈbrænd/ 重新塑造品牌形象。    <p>原文例句：The company said it was focused on a niche market segment, where it has found success overseas at a time when global smartphone sales are slumping and China’s post-pandemic economic recovery has sputtered.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“rebrand”一词由“re”（重新）和“brand”（品牌）组成，意为“重新塑造品牌形象”。在这个例句中，它指的是真我公司重新定位其品牌形象，以迎合海外年轻用户的需求。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>niche (n.) - /nɪtʃ/ 小众市场，利基市场。    <p>原文例句：The company said it was focused on a niche market segment, where it has found success overseas at a time when global smartphone sales are slumping and China’s post-pandemic economic recovery has sputtered.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“niche”一词源自法语，意为“小角落”。在这个例句中，它指的是真我公司专注于一个小众市场，即海外年轻用户市场。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>target at/towards - 瞄准，针对。    <P>原文例句：Realme is targeting young users with better zoom capabilities in a budget device.</P>    <p>例句讲解：“target at/towards”一词组意为“瞄准，针对”。在这个例句中，它表示真我公司以年轻用户为目标群体，在预算范围内提供更好的变焦性能。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>While not an official exhibitor at CES, Realme was one of only two major Chinese smartphone brands to show up in Las Vegas this week. - 尽管真我并非 CES 的官方参展商，但它是本周出现在拉斯维加斯的仅有的两家中国智能手机品牌之一。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Realme was one of only two major Chinese smartphone brands to show up in Las Vegas this week，其中主语是Realme，谓语是was，宾语是one of only two major Chinese smartphone brands to show up in Las Vegas this week。While not an official exhibitor at CES是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示真我并非 CES 的官方参展商。这个句子的意思是说，尽管真我并非 CES 的官方参展商，但它是本周出现在拉斯维加斯的仅有的两家中国智能手机品牌之一。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、愿望或可能性。    <p>原文例句：If not, then you guys are just wasting your time.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气，表示假设或可能性。结构是：If + 虚拟语气，其中虚拟语气可以用过去时态或过去完成时态表示。在这个例句中，虚拟语气用的是过去时态，表示如果他们没有兴趣，那么你们只是在浪费时间。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>情态动词 - 表示说话人的态度、能力或意愿。    <p>原文例句：Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. </p>    <p>语法讲解：情态动词“can”表示说话人的能力或可能性。在这个例句中，情态动词“can”表示真我公司能够通过提供更好的变焦性能来吸引年轻用户。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The new 12 Pro+ handset to launch at the end of January provides a better zoom lens at a budget price, as Realme caters to young overseas users</li>
<li>Realme sister brand OnePlus was also in Las Vegas, while Xiaomi, Oppo and Vivo sat out the world’s largest consumer electronics show</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/1486c8f9-79ff-40ce-9c1a-5163f3d4b7b2_2eaa662e.jpg" /><figcaption>Realme unveiled the 12 Pro+ smartphone at an event parallel to the CES trade show. The company is targeting young users with better zoom capabilities in a budget device. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" target="_self" title="">Realme</a>, owned by mainland consumer hardware giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/2184877/meet-godfather-chinas-smartphone-industry" target="_self" title="">BBK Electronics</a> which also controls <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/vivo" target="_self" title="">Vivo</a>, held a parallel event in Las Vegas on the sidelines of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ces" target="_self" title="">CES</a> trade show to unveil its new handset as part of a rebranding effort targeting young overseas users.</p><p>While not an official exhibitor at CES, Realme was one of only two major Chinese smartphone brands to show up in Las Vegas this week. On Wednesday, Realme introduced its 12-series smartphones at the same hotel where its sister brand, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oneplus" target="_self" title="">OnePlus</a>, had a series of suites booked for its own presentations outside CES.</p><p>Realme said its latest 12 Pro+ handset has the largest sensor in any periscope lens on a smartphone sold globally, but pointed out that the company’s GT 5 Pro handset sold in China technically has a bigger lens.</p><p>“What sets us apart from other brands is that we are fully committed to the young generation,” Sam Cheung, senior marketing communications manager for Realme, said in his presentation during the firm’s hour-long event on the sidelines of CES 2024. “At Realme, we believe that every user at every price segment deserves an outstanding product.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1506" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/714bf56a-c08f-4ee3-bc44-695f0ea16d52_68aef08b.jpg" title="Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Realme, which did not reveal pricing for its latest handsets, said the chipset used in the 12 Pro+ will not be made public until closer to its formal launch. While the new device uses a mid-tier <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/qualcomm" target="_self" title="">Qualcomm</a> processor, Realme said it collaborated with the US chip design firm on a solution to improve image-processing speed.</p><p>The 11 Pro+ smartphone launched by Realme last year costs 2,799 yuan, or about US$400.</p><p>At its event, Realme said the firm’s slogan, “Dare to leap”, has been changed to “Make it real” as part of a rebranding effort.</p><p>The company said it was focused on a niche market segment, where it has found success overseas at a time when global smartphone sales are slumping and China’s post-pandemic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chinas-economic-recovery" target="_self" title="">economic recovery</a> has sputtered.</p><p>Realme acknowledged challenges from the pandemic, component shortages and longer replacement cycles from consumers, but the firm also touted its sales numbers – more than <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments">200 million handsets sold</a> since its incubation at Oppo – as “giving us confidence that we’re on to something”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" title="">China’s Realme surges past 200 million smartphone shipments</a></h3><p>Moving forward, Realme aims to double down on what it believes young users want most in a smartphone. The answer it came up with is better photos when zooming in. So the firm has combined a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones.</p><p>It also collaborated with watch designer Ollivier Savéo, who previously worked at Rolex and Piaget, among others, on a design evocative of famed Swiss watches.</p><p>At a time of rising scrutiny of all things Chinese, Realme made its latest product announcement in a country leading the charge against tech from China and where the company does not even sell smartphones.</p><p>For all the other missing Chinese brands – and the smattering of journalists and influencers who showed up to cover the Realme event – it may as well have been part of the show. Vivo and Oppo, two of China’s biggest smartphone brands, were nowhere to be found in Las Vegas, even though Realme spun out of Oppo. OnePlus, the Oppo-owned brand, had suites booked for private showings, but also had no presence on the CES exhibition floor.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>Neither <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> nor <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-blacklisted</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> were at CES.</p><p>Realme said it did not exhibit at CES because the 12 Pro+ handset has not officially launched yet. It organised a pre-briefing in Las Vegas because many of its contacts across a variety of markets would be in town for the world’s largest consumer electronics show.</p><p>While the company set a goal last year of selling in more than 100 markets over the next five years, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> is one market where it may not expand owing to the complexities of getting domestic network carrier support.</p><p>The bulk of US handset sales still happen through mobile network operators, forcing smartphone brands to strike deals to find success. OnePlus has struggled with this situation, despite the glowing reviews received by many of its devices from US tech media.</p><p>Realme said it was still trying to cooperate with a US carrier to get into the market, where 87 per cent of teenagers own an iPhone, according to a survey by investment bank Piper Sandler.</p><p>Meanwhile, Realme has been selling in parts of Europe and Latin America, which it described as an important market for the company’s upcoming 12-series handsets.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia reveals progress in China’s self-driving chip market, setting up competition with domestic players</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248095/nvidia-reveals-progress-chinas-self-driving-chip-market-setting-competition-domestic-players</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia's Drive Thor self-driving system gains traction in China's electric vehicle market, with major automakers like Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR adopting the technology.</li>    <li>China's push for advanced self-driving technology intensifies competition in the autonomous-driving sector, with local providers like Huawei Technologies also making strides.</li>    <li>Nvidia's success in China despite US trade restrictions highlights the growing significance of automotive chips and smart-driving solutions in the electric vehicle industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>英伟达自动驾驶系统Drive Thor在中国电动汽车市场获得牵引力，长城汽车、理想汽车、小米、吉利旗下的极氪等大车企纷纷采用该技术。</li>    <li>中国推动先进自动驾驶技术的发展，加剧了自动驾驶领域的竞争，华为等本土供应商也在取得进展。</li>    <li>英伟达在中国取得的成功，尽管受到美国贸易限制，突显出汽车芯片和智能驾驶解决方案在电动汽车行业日益增长的重要性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>     <li>traction (n.) - /ˈtrækʃ(ə)n/ 牵引力，抓地力。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia's Drive Thor self-driving system gains traction in China's electric vehicle market, with major automakers like Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR adopting the technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Traction在句中是“牵引力，抓地力”的意思，在这里是指英伟达的Drive Thor自动驾驶系统在中国电动汽车市场获得了牵引力，即受到了市场的认可和欢迎。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>intensify (v.) - /ɪnˈtɛnsɪfaɪ/ 加强，加剧。    <p>原文例句：China's push for advanced self-driving technology intensifies competition in the autonomous-driving sector, with local providers like Huawei Technologies also making strides.</p>    <p>例句讲解：intensify在句中是“加强，加剧”的意思，在这里是指中国推动先进自动驾驶技术的发展加剧了自动驾驶领域的竞争。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>traction (n.) - /ˈtrækʃ(ə)n/ 牵引力，抓地力。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia's Drive Thor self-driving system gains traction in China's electric vehicle market, with major automakers like Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR adopting the technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：traction在句中是“牵引力，抓地力”的意思，在这里是指英伟达的Drive Thor自动驾驶系统在中国电动汽车市场获得了牵引力，即受到了市场的认可和欢迎。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>gain traction - 获得牵引力，受到欢迎。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia's Drive Thor self-driving system gains traction in China's electric vehicle market, with major automakers like Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR adopting the technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“gain traction”这个短语的意思是“获得牵引力，受到欢迎”，在这个例句中是指英伟达的Drive Thor自动驾驶系统在中国电动汽车市场获得了牵引力，即受到了市场的认可和欢迎。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China's push for advanced self-driving technology intensifies competition in the autonomous-driving sector, with local providers like Huawei Technologies also making strides. - 中国推动先进自动驾驶技术的发展加剧了自动驾驶领域的竞争，华为等本土供应商也在取得进展。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个并列复句，其中包含两个并列分句。第一个分句是China's push for advanced self-driving technology intensifies competition in the autonomous-driving sector，其中主语是China's push for advanced self-driving technology，谓语是intensifies competition in the autonomous-driving sector。第二个分句是Huawei Technologies also making strides，其中主语是Huawei Technologies，谓语是also making strides。两个分句之间用逗号分隔，表示并列关系。这个句子的意思是说，中国推动先进自动驾驶技术的发展加剧了自动驾驶领域的竞争，华为等本土供应商也在取得进展。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列复句 - 表示两个或两个以上分句并列关系的复句。    <P>原文例句：China's push for advanced self-driving technology intensifies competition in the autonomous-driving sector, with local providers like Huawei Technologies also making strides. - 中国推动先进自动驾驶技术的发展加剧了自动驾驶领域的竞争，华为等本土供应商也在取得进展。</P>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个并列复句，其中包含两个并列分句。第一个分句是China's push for advanced self-driving technology intensifies competition in the autonomous-driving sector，其中主语是China's push for advanced self-driving technology，谓语是intensifies competition in the autonomous-driving sector。第二个分句是Huawei Technologies also making strides，其中主语是Huawei Technologies，谓语是also making strides。两个分句之间用逗号分隔，表示并列关系。这个句子的意思是说，中国推动先进自动驾驶技术的发展加剧了自动驾驶领域的竞争，华为等本土供应商也在取得进展。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Autonomous-driving systems have become a competitive sector as China pushes greater adoption of advanced self-driving technology</li>
<li>Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/46325582-beb7-45f2-ae5c-8a43d08517a8_f1163133.jpg" /><figcaption>Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system. Photo: EPA-EFE </figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia, the US chip maker banned by Washington from selling its most advanced semiconductors to China, has revealed solid progress in the mainland’s electric vehicle (EV) market with its self-driving technology.</p><p>Nvidia said at the CES consumer electronics show in Las Vegas that Chinese EV makers, including Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR, have snapped up its Drive Thor autonomous driving system to enhance performance of their vehicles. This sets up increased competition with local self-driving system providers such as Huawei Technologies.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246414/huawei-and-xiaomi-launch-new-ev-models-china-reigniting-worries-about-price-wars-worlds-largest-ev" target="_self" title="">Autonomous-driving systems</a>, seen as the brains behind future cars, have become a competitive sector as China pushes greater adoption of advanced self-driving technology. Nvidia added Drive Thor – which integrates automated and assisted driving, in-vehicle infotainment, and parking in one single system – to its family of automotive system-on-a-chip solutions in September 2022.</p><p>As of June last year, Nvidia – which is unable to ship its advanced AI chips to China due to US trade sanctions – had about a 52 per cent share of the global navigate-on-autopilot (NOA) market and cooperation agreements with 25 automotive original equipment makers globally, according to data from Gasgoo Institute, a Shanghai-based research company.</p><p>“Nvidia remains predominant in terms of smart-driving chips in China,” said Brady Wang, an associate director with research firm Counterpoint. “But competition between Chinese manufacturers and foreign companies is set to intensify as they compete for a slice of the autonomous driving segment in China’s EV market.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>Chinese EV makers have been big buyers of Nvidia auto chips. For example, Nio’s flagship sedans ET5 and ES7, Li Auto’s L9 model and Xpeng’s G9 vehicle all come equipped with Nvidia’s Orin chips. Automotive chips are seen as a less sensitive area of the semiconductor market by US authorities when it comes to setting trade sanctions.</p><p>In 2022, China sold about 7 million units of smart passenger vehicles equipped with assisted autonomous driving systems, which translates into a market penetration rate of 35 per cent. In the first half of 2023, the market penetration rate rose to almost 43 per cent, according to data from China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT).</p><p>The MIIT in November issued a new policy that encourages EV makers to bring vehicles equipped with high-levels of autonomous driving to Chinese roads, in a major effort to accomplish Chinese President Xi Jinping’s vision of building a strong and modern transport network.</p><p>Thanks to policy stimulus, Chinese autonomous driving system solution providers – including Horizon Robotics and Black Sesame Technologies – have stepped up their game and are set for greater competition with the likes of Nvidia, Qualcomm, and Intel-owned MobileEye in areas such as autonomous driving chips and full-stack smart car solutions.</p><p>Nvidia topped China’s NOA computing solutions market with a share of 53 per cent in the first half of 2023, followed by smart mobility start-up Horizon Robotics with 31 per cent, and Texas Instruments with 9 per cent, according to data from the Gaogong Industry Research Institute (GGII), which tracks nascent industries in China such as EVs and batteries. Huawei and MobileEye ranked in equal 4th place with a 4 per cent market share each.</p><p>Huawei has emerged as a leading player due to its experience in auto chip design and hardware systems after it set up a smart car solution unit in 2019, the year it was added to a US trade blacklist. Under these sanctions, Huawei could not buy most US-origin semiconductors and had to rely on its own smart-driving chips.</p><p>Priot to the 2023 Shanghai Auto Show in April, Huawei launched its own home-grown smart driving platform, called advanced driving system 2.0 (ADS) and powered by a Huawei-made chipset MDC 610, according to a report by research company Counterpoint and a note in July by Kaiyuan Securities.</p><p>In November, Huawei announced it was transferring core technologies from its smart car business into a new joint venture with state-backed Changan Automobile. The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243139/huawei-accelerates-smart-car-ambitions-invitation-four-carmakers-invest-changan-joint-venture" target="_self" title="">new venture</a>, in which Changan has a 40 per cent stake, is open to other car makers as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3235762/superior-teslas-model-s-huawei-and-chery-automobile-ev-venture-luxeed-launch-first-production-model?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">equity investors</a>.</p><p>Despite still being in the red, the firm’s car unit achieved sales of 2.1 billion yuan (US$305 million) in 2022 and 1 billion yuan in revenue in the first half of last year, according to company information.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei secures JD.com as HarmonyOS partner as home-grown software emerges as alternative for Apple iOS, Android in China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248044/huawei-secures-jdcom-harmonyos-partner-home-grown-software-emerges-alternative-apple-ios-android</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, a mobile operating system developed by Huawei to rival Google's Android and Apple's iOS. HarmonyOS is gaining popularity in China and is projected to surpass Apple's iOS as the second-largest operating system this year. Huawei aims to promote its self-developed operating system by partnering with major Chinese companies to develop native apps.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: JD.com to contribute to HarmonyOS ecosystem with a custom app.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's HarmonyOS gains traction in China, challenging Android and iOS dominance.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: HarmonyOS' potential to transform the Chinese mobile operating system landscape.</li>    <li>Main information: JD.com's partnership with Huawei; the projected rise of HarmonyOS; Huawei's goal to attract major Chinese companies for app development.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  京东将为HarmonyOS Next构建一款应用程序，HarmonyOS Next是华为开发的移动操作系统，旨在与谷歌的Android和苹果的iOS竞争。HarmonyOS在中国正变得越来越受欢迎，预计今年将超过苹果的iOS成为第二大操作系统。华为的目标是通过与中国主要公司合作开发原生应用程序来推广其自行开发的操作系统。    <ul>    <li>摘要：京东以定制应用程序助力HarmonyOS生态。</li>    <li>主题：华为HarmonyOS在中国获得关注，挑战Android和iOS的统治地位。</li>    <li>观点：HarmonyOS改变中国移动操作系统格局的潜力。</li>    <li>主要信息：京东与华为的合作；HarmonyOS的预期增长；华为吸引中国主要公司进行应用程序开发的目标。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sanction (n.) - /ˈsæŋkʃən/ 制裁，惩罚。    <p>原文例句：Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由sancire（宣布，批准）演变而来，表示“制裁，惩罚”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国政府禁止华为从未经华盛顿批准的供应商那里购买软件、芯片和其他美国原产技术。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>projection (n.) - /prəˈdʒɛkʃən/ 预测，预期。    <p>原文例句：HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year, according to Canadian research firm TechInsights. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由pro（向前）和jacere（投掷）组成，表示“投射，预测”。在这个例句中，它指的是加拿大研究公司TechInsights预测，HarmonyOS今年将超越苹果的iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take on (v.) - 挑战，承担。    <p>原文例句：Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of HarmonyOS, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant continues to take on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market. </p>    <p>例句讲解：take on在这里是承担，挑战的意思。Huawei目前面临着美国制裁和Android和iOS的竞争，仍然在挑战它们，努力推广HarmonyOS。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”, Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo. - 任宇称京东为“重量级合作伙伴”，并表示此次合作标志着鸿蒙操作系统的一个新里程碑。<p>句子分析：Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示任宇称京东为“重量级合作伙伴”。Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo.是主句，其中Yu said是谓语，the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo.是宾语。这个句子的意思是说，任宇称京东为“重量级合作伙伴”，并表示此次合作标志着鸿蒙操作系统的一个新里程碑。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列句 - 表示两个或多个并列的句子。    <p>原文例句：Joining with a growing number of Chinese internet companies, Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of its home-grown HarmonyOS, which is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year, >according to Canadian research firm TechInsights.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个例句中的并列句是：Joining with a growing number of Chinese internet companies, Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of its home-grown HarmonyOS, which is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year,。这两个句子都是并列的主句，用逗号连接。这个句子的意思是说，加入越来越多的中国互联网公司，华为正在推动其自研鸿蒙操作系统的更广泛采用，据加拿大研究公司TechInsights预测，它有望在今年成为中国第二大操作系统。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 强调动作的承受者。    <p>原文例句：While Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, driven by the firm’s smartphone comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to TechInsights.</p>    <p>语法讲解：self-developed HarmonyOS is launched是一个被动语态，其中self-developed是一个过去分词作定语，表示HarmonyOS是自己开发的，is launched是谓语，表示被推出。在这个例句中，它表示华为自研的HarmonyOS被推出。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform</li>
<li>Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of HarmonyOS, which is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS in China this year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/5435c70a-132e-4030-86c0-5a8e160d23ce_92ca8b90.jpg" /><figcaption>A billboard advertising Huawei’s Harmony OS at the Smart China Expo in Chongqing, Sept. 4, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has secured another partner to promote use of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3136017/will-huaweis-harmony-operating-system-end-global-duopoly-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS</a>, as the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">US-sanctioned</a> telecommunications equipment giant continues to take on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p><p>Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform and its ability to support transitions between multiple scenarios, Richard Yu Chengdong, chief executive of Huawei’s consumer business group, said on Wednesday.</p><p>Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”, Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo.</p><p>Joining with a growing number of Chinese internet companies, Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of its home-grown HarmonyOS, which is projected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" target="_self" title="">surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China</a> this year, according to Canadian research firm TechInsights.</p><p>While Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, driven by the firm’s smartphone comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to TechInsights.</p><p>The self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative in August 2019, three months after the US government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">added Huawei to its Entity List</a>. Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p><p>A developer preview of HarmonyOS Next is expected to be launched in the first quarter of 2024. Huawei is already working with major Chinese companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p><p>Ant Group, the fintech affiliate of South China Morning Post owner <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, said last month that it was building a new version of mobile payment app Alipay based on HarmonyOS, after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242703/alibaba-develops-native-dingtalk-app-harmonyos-huawei-aims-end-support-android-apps?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba started development on a new version of DingTalk</a>, its workplace collaboration app.</p><p>Other major Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> companies – including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>, video gaming giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netease?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">NetEase</a> and food delivery market leader <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> – in November started to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241371/chinese-big-tech-firms-jdcom-netease-and-meituan-rush-hire-harmonyos-based-app-developers-huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">recruit developers to build native apps for HarmonyOS</a>.</p><p>McDonald’s China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees – became <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244236/mcdonalds-china-pushes-development-native-apps-based-harmonyos-adoption-huaweis-mobile-operating?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239589/xiaomi-launches-home-grown-cross-device-system-hyperos-us-sanctioned-huawei-moves-further-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS Next</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Elon Musk’s X tells watchdog it has shed 1,000 ‘safety’ staff</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248024/elon-musks-x-tells-watchdog-it-has-shed-1000-safety-staff</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Australian eSafety Commission criticized Twitter's mass layoffs and account reinstatements for exacerbating the spread of harmful content online.</li>    <li>Following Elon Musk's takeover, Twitter has faced scrutiny for increasing hate speech and toxicity on its platform.</li>    <li>Australia's Online Safety Act allowed the eSafety Commission to obtain detailed information about Twitter's safety staff.</li>    <li>The Commission revealed that 1,213 trust and safety personnel, including contractors, have departed Twitter since Musk acquired it.</li>    <li>This included 80% of software engineers responsible for trust and safety-related issues.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>澳大利亚电子安全委员会批评了Twitter的大规模裁员和恢复被禁账户的行为，因为这加剧了在线有害内容的传播。</li>    <li>在埃隆·马斯克接手后，Twitter因其平台上仇恨言论和毒性的增加而面临审查。</li>    <li>澳大利亚《在线安全法》允许电子安全委员会获取有关Twitter安全人员的详细信息。</li>    <li>委员会透露，自马斯克收购Twitter以来，已有1,213名信任和安全人员，包括承包商，离开了Twitter。</li>    <li>其中包括80%负责信任和安全相关问题的软件工程师。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>reinstate (v.) - /ˌriːɪnˈsteɪt/ 恢复，重新确立。    <p>原文例句：In a photo illustration, the Twitter X logo is displayed on the screen of a smartphone. Photo: SOPA Images/Zuma Press/TNSElon Musk’s X has shed more than 1,000 staff globally from teams responsible for stopping abusive content online, according to new figures released Thursday by Australia’s online watchdog.    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由re-（重新）和state（状态）组成，表示“重新恢复，重新确立”。在这个例句中，它指的是推特解雇了1000多名员工，这些人原本负责阻止在线辱骂内容。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>drastically (adv.) - /ˈdræstɪkli/ 急剧地，显著地。    <p>原文例句：Commissioner Julie Inman Grant, a former Twitter employee, said it was the first time these figures had been made public.They showed 1,213 specialist “trust and safety staff”, including contractors, had left X since it was acquired by Musk in October 2022.This included 80 per cent of the software engineers focused on “trust and safety issues”, said Inman Grant.“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away, it would be like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers,” she told AFP.“You’ve got a perfect storm. You’re drastically decreasing your defences, and you’re introducing repeat offenders back onto the platform.”    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由Greek的drastikos（活跃的，强烈的）演变而来，表示“迅速而彻底地，极端地”。在这个例句中，它指的是推特解雇了80%的软件工程师，这对平台的安全产生了很大的影响。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take action - 采取行动。    <p>原文例句：Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing firms to outline how they are tackling hate speech and child sexual abuse.    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，取）和action（行动）构成的，表示“采取行动，着手去做”。在这个例句中，它指的是澳大利亚带头推动对社交媒体的监管，迫使企业概述他们如何应对仇恨言论和儿童性虐待问题。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In a photo illustration, the Twitter X logo is displayed on the screen of a smartphone. - 在一张照片中，Twitter X的标志显示在智能手机屏幕上。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是The Twitter X logo is displayed，其中主语是The Twitter X logo，谓语是is displayed。In a photo illustration是一个介词短语作状语，修饰The Twitter X logo is displayed，表示在照片中。on the screen of a smartphone是一个介词短语作地点状语，修饰The Twitter X logo is displayed，表示在智能手机屏幕上。这个句子的意思是说，在照片中，Twitter X的标志显示在智能手机屏幕上。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的结果或影响。    <p>原文例句：Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing firms to outline how they are tackling hate speech and child sexual abuse.    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的结果或影响。在这个例句中，它表示澳大利亚一直带头推动对社交媒体的监管，迫使企业概述他们如何应对仇恨言论和儿童性虐待问题，强调了这种推动和概述的结果或影响。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式短语 - 表示目的或原因。    <p>原文例句：Commissioner Julie Inman Grant, a former Twitter employee, said it was the first time these figures had been made public.They showed 1,213 specialist “trust and safety staff”, including contractors, had left X since it was acquired by Musk in October 2022.This included 80 per cent of the software engineers focused on “trust and safety issues”, said Inman Grant.“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away, it would be like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers,” she told AFP.“You’ve got a perfect storm. You’re drastically decreasing your defences, and you’re introducing repeat offenders back onto the platform.”    <p>语法讲解：这是一个短语，由不定式和介词组成，其中不定式是动词的-ing形式，介词可以是to、for或of等。这种短语表示目的或原因。在这个例句中，不定式短语是“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away”，表示“把这80%的专业工程师拿走”，介词短语是“like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers”，表示“就像沃尔沃——以其安全标准而闻名——解雇了所有设计师或工程师”。这两个短语一起表示“把这80%的专业工程师拿走，就像沃尔沃——以其安全标准而闻名——解雇了所有设计师或工程师”。这个句子的意思是说，把这80%的专业工程师拿走，就像沃尔沃——以其安全标准而闻名——解雇了所有设计师或工程师。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The eSafety Commission said the ‘deep cuts’ and reinstatement of banned accounts created a ‘perfect storm’ for the spread of harmful content</li>
<li>Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing firms to outline how they are tackling hate speech and child sexual abuse</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/194a6a33-50f8-40c7-89c1-765fdcb76853_d3339bb6.jpg" /><figcaption>In a photo illustration, the Twitter X logo is displayed on the screen of a smartphone. Photo: SOPA Images/Zuma Press/TNS</figcaption></figure><p>Elon Musk’s X has shed more than 1,000 staff globally from teams responsible for stopping abusive content online, according to new figures released Thursday by Australia’s online watchdog.</p><p>Australia’s eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content.</p><p>The regulator has in recent months zeroed in on X – formerly known as Twitter – previously saying Musk’s takeover coincided with a spike in “toxicity and hate” on the platform.</p><p>Using Australia’s groundbreaking Online Safety Act, the eSafety Commission has obtained a detailed breakdown of software engineers, content moderators and other safety staff working at X.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247497/tech-trade-group-representing-tiktok-snapchat-and-meta-sues-ohio-over-states-new-law-limiting" title="">Tech group with TikTok and Meta sues Ohio over law curbing children’s social media use</a></h3><p>Commissioner Julie Inman Grant, a former Twitter employee, said it was the first time these figures had been made public.</p><p>They showed 1,213 specialist “trust and safety staff”, including contractors, had left X since it was acquired by Musk in October 2022.</p><p>This included 80 per cent of the software engineers focused on “trust and safety issues”, said Inman Grant.</p><p>“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away, it would be like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers,” she told AFP.</p><p>“You’ve got a perfect storm. You’re drastically decreasing your defences, and you’re introducing repeat offenders back onto the platform.”</p><p>Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing tech companies to outline how they are tackling issues such as hate speech and child sexual abuse.</p><p>But attempts to exercise these powers have occasionally been met with indifference. In October last year, the eSafety Commission slapped X with an A$610,500 (US$388,000) fine, saying it had failed to show how it was cracking down on child pornography.</p><p>But X ignored the deadline to pay the fine, before launching ongoing legal action to have it overturned.</p><p>X did not reply to AFP’s request for comment, instead sending an automated response that read “busy now, please check back later”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei ends US lobbying operations after years of fighting ban</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3248018/huawei-ends-us-lobbying-operations-after-years-fighting-ban</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Huawei, a Chinese wireless equipment manufacturer, has closed its lobbying operations in Washington, marking the end of its years-long effort to gain a foothold in the US market. The move comes after the US government imposed a ban on Huawei's products and services, citing concerns over national security.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei Ends Lobbying Operations in the US After US Ban.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's withdrawal from the US market highlights the escalating tensions between China and the US.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The US ban on Huawei reflects the growing geopolitical rivalry between the two countries.</li>    <li>Main information: Reasons for Huawei's lobbying efforts; US government's decision to ban Huawei; Huawei's response to the ban.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  华为，中国无线设备制造商，已关闭华盛顿的游说业务，这标志着它多年来在美国市场站稳脚跟的努力结束。此举是在美国政府以国家安全为由禁止华为产品和服务后做出的。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为在美国禁令后结束游说业务。</li>    <li>主题：华为退出美国市场凸显中美两国紧张局势加剧。</li>    <li>观点：美国对华为的禁令反映了两国日益激烈的博弈。</li>    <li>主要信息：华为游说努力的原因；美国政府决定禁止华为；华为对禁令的回应。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>lobby (v.) - /ˈlɑːbi/ 游说。    <p>原文例句：Lobbyists help companies or organizations influence lawmakers and government officials on public policy issues. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源于拉丁语，意为“在走廊或门厅里说话”。在这个例句中，它表示游说者帮助公司或组织通过向立法者和政府官员游说来影响公共政策问题。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>embargo (n.) - /ɪmˈbɑːrɡəʊ/ 禁运。    <p>原文例句：The United States imposed an embargo on Cuba in 1962, which is still in effect today. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于西班牙语，意为“障碍”。在这个例句中，它表示美国在1962年对古巴实施的禁运，该禁运至今仍然有效。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the face of - 面对，在……面前。    <P>原文例句：In the face of declining sales, the company decided to close its doors. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），the（the）和face（面孔）构成的，表示“面对，在……面前”。在这个例句中，它表示该公司在销售额下降的情况下决定关闭公司的大门。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations - 这些人员的离开是继华为美国业务人员大批流失之后的又一轮人员流失。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The departures follow an exodus，其中主语是The departures，谓语是follow，宾语是an exodus。of staff from Huawei’s US operations是一个介词短语作定语，修饰exodus，表示这次离开是继华为美国业务人员大批流失之后的人员流失。follow是一个动词，意为“跟随，跟从”。在这个例句中，它表示这些人员的离开是继华为美国业务人员大批流失之后的人员流失。这个句子的意思是说，这些人员的离开是继华为美国业务人员大批流失之后的又一轮人员流失。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句型 - 为了强调句子中的某个成分，将句子中某个成分的位置提前。    <p>原文例句：Out of the 100 students in the class, only 20 passed the test. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，主句是only 20 students passed the test，其中主语是only 20 students，谓语是passed，宾语是the test。out of the 100 students in the class是一个介词短语作状语，表示在100名学生中。倒装句型是一种为了强调句子中的某个成分，将句子中某个成分的位置提前的句型。在这个例句中，only 20 students passed the test被提前到了句子开头，表示在100名学生中，只有20名学生通过了考试。这个句子的意思是说，在100名学生中，只有20名学生通过了考试。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式短语作结果状语 - 表示结果或后果。    <p>原文例句：To improve his English, he studies hard every day. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个不定式短语作结果状语，由不定式to improve his English和结果状语every day构成。不定式短语作结果状语表示结果或后果，通常位于句末。在这个例句中，不定式短语to improve his English作结果状语，表示为了提高他的英语水平。不定式短语作结果状语是一种表示结果或后果的状语。在这个例句中，不定式短语to improve his English作结果状语，表示为了提高他的英语水平。这个句子的意思是说，为了提高他的英语水平，他每天都在努力学习。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, after a years-long effort to maintain a presence in North America</li>
<li>At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/61065c57-e9bf-4bb0-a892-196dc21024cd_6e1ed843.jpg" /><figcaption>The Huawei logo is seen during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai, July 6, 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies, the Chinese wireless equipment maker that spent tens of millions of dollars trying to win over US policymakers only to eventually be blacklisted, has shuttered its in-house lobbying operations in Washington.</p><p>Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists there – Jeff Hogg and Donald Morrissey – left in recent months, Bloomberg News found. The Shenzhen, China-based firm did not respond to multiple requests for comment.</p><p>The lobbyists’ recent departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, and marks a quiet end to the company’s costly, years-long effort to maintain presence in the North American market. The firm reached its peak by supplying small mobile firms across the US even as major carriers shunned it. Rising tensions with Beijing eventually all but banned it.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" title="">Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets</a></h3><p>More than a decade ago, Washington officials began warning of Huawei’s ability to embed spying capabilities in its gear, which was present in thousands of cell towers and other network equipment in the US. The company pushed back on those claims, saying its products posed no threat, but American regulators by 2022 had barred the company from selling products in the US and moved to starve it of access to cutting-edge technology.</p><p>At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives. Executives were known to regularly arrange briefings with congressional offices and major newsrooms. The company spent more than US$13 million lobbying in the past 10 years, according to federal filings.</p><p>In a single quarter of 2019, Huawei’s federal lobbying spending totaled US$1.8 million, a six-fold increase from the previous year. It spent US$3.6 million on lobbying in the US in 2021, according to the filings. Some of that went to glitzy parties populated by high-profile hired guns including veteran Democratic lobbyist Tony Podesta, who made US$1 million from Huawei that year, according to disclosures with the US Senate. Podesta said in a filing that his work for Huawei ended on December 30, 2022.</p><p>With a ban firmly in place and its US business scant, Huawei has little reason to keep burning through lobbying cash in Washington. “The US market isn’t a likely place for a breakthrough for Huawei in the near future,” said Chris Pereira, a former Huawei public relations executive and founder of the consultancy iMpact.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/e55aff24-0f6a-4156-9c60-9d12d7c1fc31_ac707f82.jpg" title="A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Morrissey, who lobbied for both Huawei and Futurewei, confirmed in a LinkedIn message that he left the company in December. He said he is now the senior director of government affairs at the battery technology company Gotion. Hogg, who had served as Huawei’s head of government relations since 2020, left the company in November, according to his LinkedIn profile. He did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p>The company has lost outside lobbying firms as well. Imperium Global Advisors and LeMunyon Group terminated their contracts with Futurewei, Huawei’s US-based research arm, in November 2023, according to filings with the Senate. And Squire Patton Boggs, a global law firm, has not reported lobbying activity to Congress on Futurewei’s behalf since the beginning of 2023. Former US Representative Lee Terry, Republican of Nebraska, terminated his lobbying contract with Huawei at the end of 2022. according to filings with the Senate.</p><p>By October, the only firm registered as working on Huawei’s behalf was Sidley Austin, which did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p>Huawei itself has filed its own notice that it was terminating lobbying efforts at the Capitol. The company has also ceased operations at offices in Plano, Texas, Trey Smith, executive vice-president at CBRE, a real estate services firm that handles leases for the building, said in an email.</p><p>In response to Huawei’s ban, China’s government has accused the US of abusing state power to hobble Chinese companies. Huawei in recent months offered its own de facto response, producing a new phone using highly advanced technology the US has been trying to keep out of China’s hands. The company says revenue surged 9 per cent in 2023, in part thanks to the new phone.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s Taobao and Tmall Group pushes new AI tools to boost merchants’ service to consumers in first major move after leadership reshuffle</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247985/alibabas-taobao-and-tmall-group-pushes-new-ai-tools-boost-merchants-service-consumers-first-major</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Taobao and Tmall Group introduces artificial intelligence (AI) tools to assist merchants in improving services and attracting customers.</li>    <li>A customer service chatbot, Dianxiaomi, undergoes an upgrade using AI technology to enhance seller-consumer interactions.</li>    <li>TTG unveils plans to enhance exposure for high-quality merchants on its marketplaces.</li>    <li>The adoption of AI tools is a strategic move to fend off competition from rivals like JD.com and younger platforms.</li>    <li>TTG aims to implement a new rating system focused on consumer-related indicators for online shops.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>淘宝、天猫集团引入人工智能（AI）工具，帮助商家提高服务质量，吸引更多顾客。</li>    <li>客服聊天机器人店小蜜升级采用人工智能技术，增强卖家与消费者的互动。</li>    <li>TTG宣布计划在自有平台上，加大优质商家的曝光度。</li>    <li>引入人工智能工具是应对主要竞争对手京东和较年轻平台（如拼多多、字节跳动旗下的抖音）竞争的战略举措。</li>    <li>TTG计划为网店实施新的评价制度，关注与消费者相关服务指标。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>be available to - 对……可用。    <p>原文例句：An AI-upgraded customer service chatbot, Dianxiaomi, is expected to be available to all Taobao and Tmall sellers by June.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由be（是）、available（可用的）和to（对……）组成，表示“对……可用”。在这个例句中，它表示AI升级的客服聊天机器人店小蜜预计将在6月份对所有淘宝和天猫卖家开放使用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>unveiled - 公布，宣布。    <p>原文例句：The Taobao and Tmall Group (TTG) unveiled the new AI features, which are designed to improve services and attract new customers, at its “sellers’ conference” held on Tuesday in Hangzhou.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于法语dévoiler（揭示），表示“公布，宣布”。在这个例句中，它表示淘宝和天猫集团（TTG）在其周二在杭州举行的“卖家大会”上公布了旨在改善服务和吸引新客户的新人工智能功能。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>bring into play - 发挥作用；利用。    <P>原文例句：AI models would be employed to transform Dianxiaomi, a customer service chatbot, to enhance seller-consumer interaction.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由bring（带来）和into play（发挥作用）组成的，表示“发挥作用；利用”。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能模型将被用来改造客服聊天机器人店小蜜，以增强卖家与消费者的互动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li> fend off - 抵御；阻挡。    <p>原文例句：TTG’s adoption of AI tools shows the effort being made by the Alibaba unit to fend off increased competition from main domestic rival JD.com and the challenge from younger platforms.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由fend（抵挡）和off（离开）构成的，表示“抵御；阻挡”。在这个例句中，它表示TTG采用人工智能工具表明了阿里巴巴集团为抵御主要国内竞争对手京东和较年轻平台（如拼多多、字节跳动旗下的抖音）的挑战所做出的努力。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Dianxiaomi, a customer service chatbot, is expected to be available to all Taobao and Tmall sellers by June. - 客服聊天机器人店小蜜预计将在6月份对所有淘宝和天猫卖家开放使用。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Dianxiaomi，谓语是is expected to be available，宾语是all Taobao and Tmall sellers，by June是一个介词短语作状语，表示在6月份。这个句子的意思是说，客服聊天机器人店小蜜预计将在6月份对所有淘宝和天猫卖家开放使用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示现在正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The Taobao and Tmall Group is now beta testing artificial intelligence (AI) tools and functions for merchants on its Chinese online shopping sites.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态正在进行，强调动作或状态的进行性和持续性。在这个例句中，它表示淘宝和天猫集团目前正在对其中国在线购物网站上的商家进行人工智能（AI）工具和功能的β测试。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>一般过去时 - 表示过去发生的已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TTG subsequently promoted six millennial executives to lead key departments.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：did/was/were + 过去分词。其中did/was/were要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词形式。这种时态表示过去发生的已经完成的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示TTG随后提拔了六位千禧一代高管领导重要部门。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Taobao and Tmall Group’s AI initiative is geared towards helping merchants improve their services and attract new customers</li>
<li>An AI-upgraded customer service chatbot, Dianxiaomi, is expected to be available to all Taobao and Tmall sellers by June</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/a64d09cb-4f09-4901-b140-db8cdc3ed1d4_a2cf7620.jpg" /><figcaption>Taobao and Tmall Group’s adoption of artificial intelligence tools shows the Alibaba Group Holding unit’s effort to fend off increased competition in China’s e-commerce market. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>’s main <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> unit is now beta testing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) tools and functions for merchants on its Chinese online shopping sites, marking the first major move at the enterprise since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245680/alibaba-names-new-taobao-and-tmall-ceo-major-move-fend-competition" target="_self" title="">a leadership reshuffle in December</a>.</p><p>The Taobao and Tmall Group (TTG) unveiled the new AI features, which are designed to improve services and attract new customers, at its “sellers’ conference” held on Tuesday in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hangzhou" target="_self" title="">Hangzhou</a>, capital of eastern Zhejiang province and home base of South China Morning Post owner Alibaba.</p><p>TTG said AI models would be employed to transform Dianxiaomi, a customer service chatbot, to enhance seller-consumer interaction. That will include tasks such as pre- and post-sales service, data analysis and other online sales activities.</p><p>The updated Dianxiaomi, which is currently undergoing tests with a select group of sellers, will be made available to all merchants by June, according to TTG. It said the accuracy rate of Dianxiaomi’s response time has so far improved to 85 per cent.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/342c70b0-1832-40c4-bff8-11fa840de980_6cb4cf92.jpg" title="The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>TTG also vowed to provide “quality merchants” more exposure to consumers, from the homepage to advertised search results, TTG announced at the event.</p><p>TTG’s adoption of AI tools shows the effort being made by the Alibaba unit to fend off increased competition from main domestic rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> and the challenge from younger platforms, such as PDD Holdings’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="">Pinduoduo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>.</p><p>The move comes weeks after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245680/alibaba-names-new-taobao-and-tmall-ceo-major-move-fend-competition" target="_self" title="">Eddie Wu Yongming</a> was named the new chief executive at TTG, replacing Trudy Dai Shan. TTG subsequently <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals" target="_self" title="">promoted six millennial executives</a> to lead key departments.</p><p>Before TTG’s latest initiative, Alibaba’s international business-to-business wholesale marketplace <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" target="_self" title="">Alibaba.com in November announced a new AI tool</a> to help the platform’s merchants automate their client-facing operations, including writing emails, to entice more customers overseas.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" title="">Alibaba pushes new AI tool to help wholesale merchants manage overseas clients</a></h3><p>At the seller’s event in Hangzhou, TTG said internal statistics showed that five-star-rated sellers enjoy a significantly higher repurchase rate than certain 3-star stores on its platform. The repurchase rate at five-star pet supply stores, for example, is about 127 per cent higher than those of 3-star peers.</p><p>TTG on Tuesday also said it will launch a new rating system for online shops, focusing on indicators related to consumer services. These indicators include the “rejection rate of refund request” and “platform intervention rate”, which weigh on consumers’ purchasing decisions.</p><p>Late in December, both JD.com and Taobao said they will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" target="_self" title="">offer a “refund only” policy</a> so consumers can keep the goods they had bought but complained about – matching an option that budget online retailer Pinduoduo has had in place since 2021.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US regulator SEC authorises bitcoin-spot ETFs in cryptocurrency breakthrough</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>The SEC's decision to approve bitcoin ETFs marks a significant shift in its stance after years of opposition.</li>    <li>The approval allows investors to gain exposure to bitcoin through traditional brokerage accounts, expanding access to the largest cryptocurrency.</li>    <li>The move is seen as a milestone for the digital-asset sector and could bring it closer to the regulated world of traditional finance.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>美国证券交易委员会（SEC）批准比特币ETF，标志着其在经过十多年反对后立场发生重大转变。</li>    <li>此举允许投资者通过传统经纪账户接触比特币，从而扩大了对最大加密货币的访问权限。</li>    <li>这一举动被视为数字资产行业的一个里程碑，并可能使其更接近受监管的传统金融世界。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>capitulation (n.) - /kəˌpɪtʃʊˈleɪʃən/ 投降，屈服。    <p>原文例句：The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Capitulation是Capituate（投降，屈服）的名词形式，源自拉丁语capitulare（投降），表示“投降，屈服”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国证券交易委员会在面对十多年的反对后，难得的一次屈服。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>heralded (v.) - /ˈherəld/ 宣告，预告。    <p>原文例句：The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Herald是Herald（宣告，预告）的过去分词，源自古英语here（军队）和lidan（唱歌），表示“宣告，预告”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国证券交易委员会在社交媒体上的虚假帖子宣称机构批准了ETF。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>crux (n.) - /krʌks/ 中心，关键点。    <p>原文例句：At the crux of the SEC’s previous rulings against a spot ETF was the argument that no regulated exchange was able to adequately monitor bitcoin trading in a way that would reliably detect fraud and manipulation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Crux是十字架的意思，源自拉丁语crux（十字架），表示“中心，关键点”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国证券交易委员会此前裁决反对现货ETF的关键点。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>exchange-traded funds (ETFs) - 交易所交易基金。    <p>原文例句：US regulators for the first time approved exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that invest directly in bitcoin, a move heralded as a landmark event for the roughly US$1.7 trillion digital-asset sector that will broaden access to the largest cryptocurrency on Wall Street and beyond.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Exchange-traded funds (ETFs)是由一群股票、债券或其他资产支持的投资基金，其价格在证券交易所进行交易。在这个例句中，它指的是首次获批的直接投资于比特币的交易所交易基金。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs，其中主语是The decision，谓语是comes，宾语是a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs。第一个分句a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs是一个时间状语，表示这一决定发生在SEC的X账户上的一篇虚假帖子声称机构批准了ETF后的一天之后。这个句子的意思是说，这一决定发生在SEC的X账户上的一篇虚假帖子声称机构批准了ETF后的一天之后。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>There Be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade</li>
<li>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/df6929be-b19f-4119-85e5-a531ae26273d_52ea2e34.jpg" /><figcaption>A bitcoin is seen in an illustration picture taken in Paris, France, June 23, 2017. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>US regulators for the first time approved exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that invest directly in bitcoin, a move heralded as a landmark event for the roughly US$1.7 trillion digital-asset sector that will broaden access to the largest cryptocurrency on Wall Street and beyond.</p><p>The Securities and Exchange Commission, whose three-part mandate includes investor protection, authorised funds from industry heavyweights BlackRock, Invesco and Fidelity to smaller competitors including Valkyrie to begin trading Thursday.</p><p>The approvals also mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade, ever since Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss first proposed a bitcoin ETF in 2013. BlackRock’s surprise application last June, followed by an appeals court ruling that called the denial of a different application “arbitrary and capricious,” triggered a blistering rally in the cryptocurrency as speculation that US regulators would finally give their blessing to the structure.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239953/hong-kongs-hashkey-launches-first-crypto-trading-app-retail-investors-gives-away-new-token" title="">Hong Kong gets first crypto trading app for retail investors</a></h3><p>“While we approved the listing and trading of certain spot bitcoin ETP shares today, we did not approve or endorse bitcoin,” SEC Chair Gary Gensler said in a statement. “Investors should remain cautious about the myriad risks associated with bitcoin and products whose value is tied to crypto.”</p><p>At the crux of the SEC’s previous rulings against a spot ETF was the argument that no regulated exchange was able to adequately monitor bitcoin trading in a way that would reliably detect fraud and manipulation. That contention was opposed by Cathie Wood’s Ark Investments, among others, which provided data showing a high correlation between cash trading and the futures contracts that trade on CME Group’s platform.</p><p>In reviewing the latest set of proposals, the SEC said it examined the correlation between spot and futures trading at a variety of time intervals and concluded prices moved in such a way that irregularities on exchanges such as Kraken and Coinbase were likely to show up in the futures.</p><p>“Because the CME’s surveillance can assist in detecting those impacts on CME bitcoin futures prices, the exchanges’ comprehensive surveillance-sharing agreement with the CME – a US regulated market whose bitcoin futures market is consistently highly correlated to spot bitcoin, albeit not of ‘significant size’ related to spot bitcoin – can be reasonably expected to assist in surveilling for fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices in the specific context of the proposals,” the order said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246909/crypto-services-firm-linked-huobi-sees-losses-expand-40-cent-ftx-funds-still-out-reach" title="">Losses mount at Huobi-linked crypto firm while FTX funds still out of reach</a></h3><p>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs. The regulator subsequently said that the account had been compromised, causing the price of bitcoin to fluctuate widely.</p><p>Gensler voted along side the agency’s two Republicans to back exchanges’ plans to list the products, the SEC’s website showed. The regulator’s two other Democrats voted against the proposals.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/9a0bebf2-048a-459e-9a2e-2dd720360177_a66cec46.jpg" title="The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Bitcoin rose about 3.4 per cent to US$47,500 following the approvals. The original cryptocurrency, which sank 64 per cent in 2022, more than doubled in 2023 in large part because of speculation that the SEC would eventually approve ETFs that will allow investors to get exposure to the token in their traditional brokerage accounts instead of one of the crypto-native start-ups that have come under increasing government scrutiny following a series of sector scandals and bankruptcies.</p><p>“The approval means that both retail and institutional investors now have the ability to diversify their portfolio with crypto exposure without worrying about the complicated issues of custody,” said Campbell Harvey, finance professor at Duke University. “The ETF makes it easy to add to your portfolio.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246538/china-calls-tougher-crackdown-use-crypto-illegal-forex-trading" title="">China calls for tougher crackdown on use of crypto for illegal forex trading</a></h3><p>Crypto proponents have for years argued that a so-called spot fund that invests directly in bitcoin would be beneficial to investors and would help bring the industry closer to the more highly regulated world of traditional finance. It also suggests a sort of milestone of maturity for the relatively nascent industry, where skirmishes with regulators came to a climax after the collapse of Sam Bankman-Fried’s FTX empire highlighted risks lurking in the industry.</p><p>The landmark decision comes after Grayscale Investments won a key victory over the SEC. A federal appeals court had overturned the rejection of Grayscale’s application to convert its bitcoin trust into an ETF. The court called the denial “arbitrary and capricious” because the commission failed to explain its different treatment of similar products. ETFs that hold bitcoin futures were approved in 2021.</p><p>The SEC’s loss to Grayscale was one of the reasons why the SEC approved the applications, Gensler said in Tuesday’s statement.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China rich list compiler Hurun clarifies Tsinghua graduate Zhang Zetian’s ranking to quell online controversy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247956/china-rich-list-compiler-hurun-clarifies-tsinghua-graduate-zhang-zetians-ranking-quell-online</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Hurun Research Institute has confirmed the ranking of Zhang Zetian, wife of Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third wealthiest graduate from Tsinghua University. Hurun considers her net worth as part of her husband's wealth. The ranking has ignited controversy among Chinese netizens. Tsinghua and Zhejiang University have produced the most alumni who have become billionaires in China, according to the Hurun list. Zhang's ranking has been questioned due to skepticism regarding her actual wealth.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Hurun's ranking of Tsinghua University's richest alumni has stirred debate online.</li>    <li>Theme: Debate surrounds Zhang Zetian's ranking among Tsinghua's wealthy graduates due to joint wealth consideration.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Hurun clarifies its methodology, highlighting the combined wealth of Zhang and her husband.</li>    <li>Main information: Zhang's ranking as Tsinghua's third-richest graduate; controversy over her net worth; Tsinghua and Zhejiang University as leading producers of billionaire alumni; scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  胡润研究院澄清了将刘强东妻子章泽天列为清华大学第三富豪毕业生的决定，该排名引发了网络争议。根据胡润上周五发布的榜单，清华大学和浙江大学培养了最多的亿万富翁毕业生。30岁的章泽天以600亿元的净资产位列清华第三富豪毕业生。章泽天排在44岁的美团创始人王兴和62岁的房地产开发商鹏瑞集团创始人许航之后。但许多中国网民在社交媒体平台上质疑章泽天是否真的拥有如此巨额的财富。胡润周一发表声明澄清了中国富豪校友排名的计算方法。“清华的章泽天，她的600亿身家是和刘强东共同擁有的。”胡润2023中国富豪榜：互联网反弹推动中国科技亿万富豪前行争议源于对中国个人财富和收入不平等的日益加剧的审查。根据《福布斯》 2023 年 11 月发布的另一份富豪榜，电商巨头京东的创始人兼董事长刘强东的净资产为 47 亿美元，在中国富豪榜前 100 名中排名第 69 位。刘强东与章泽天的明星式婚姻在中国科技亿万富豪中也很少见，许多人在家庭问题上都保持低调。清华校友富豪榜是胡润研究院发布的2023年胡润最成功大学排行榜的一部分。胡润将“最成功校友”定义为包括全日制本科生、研究生以及在《胡润2023中国富豪榜》上持有博士学位的企业家。在2023年胡润中国富豪榜上，共有58所大学（45所中国大学和13所海外大学）至少有3位校友上榜。清华大学和浙江大学名列榜首，各拥有32位校友上榜。北京大学、上海交通大学和武汉大学分列第三、第四和第五位，分别有22名、21名和17名校友上榜。根据该榜单，百度创始人、董事长兼CEO李彦宏和小米董事长兼CEO雷军分别来自北京大学和武汉大学，是各自最知名和最富有的毕业生。在中国以外，来自美国的斯坦福大学、麻省理工学院、加州大学、耶鲁大学和哈佛大学是拥有最多胡润中国富豪榜企业家的前五所大学。  <ul>    <li>摘要：胡润对清华大学最富有校友的排名引发了网络争论。</li>    <li>主题：由于联合财富考虑，围绕张泽天在清华富裕毕业生中的排名争论不断。</li>    <li>观点：胡润澄清了其方法论，强调了张及其丈夫的共同财富。</li>    <li>主要信息：张被评为清华第三富有的毕业生；质疑她净资产的争议；清华大学和浙江大学作为培养亿万富翁校友的领先者；对中国个人财富和收入不平等的审查。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>controversy (n.) - /ˈkɑːntrəvərsi/ 争议，争论。    <p>原文例句：The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.    <p>例句讲解：Controversy是指“有争议的事情或意见”。在这个例句中，Controversy指的是张泽天在清华大学富豪毕业生中的排名引发了网络争论。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>scutinity (n.) - /ˈskruːtɪni/ 审查，细察。    <p>原文例句：The controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Scutiny是指“仔细检查或审查”。在这个例句中，Scrutiny指的是对中国个人财富和收入不平等的更加严格的审查。</p></li>  </ul>    </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stir controversy - 引起争议。    <p>原文例句：According to a list published by Hurun last Friday, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China. And 30-year-old Zhang was ranked as the third-richest graduate from Tsinghua, with a net worth of 60 billion yuan (US$8.4 billion).Zhang ranked behind 44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan and 62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group. However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.Hurun issued a statement on Monday to clarify its methodology for the ranking of rich Chinese alumni. “In the case of Tsinghua’s Zhang, her 60 billion yuan worth falls under her and [husband] Liu jointly.”Chinese tech billionaires move up Hurun 2023 Rich List amid internet reboundThe controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Stir controversy是指“引起争议”。在这个例句中，Stir controversy指的是张泽天在清华大学富豪毕业生中的排名引发了网络争论。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>on the list - 在名单上。    <p>原文例句：Hurun defined the “most successful alumni” to include former full-time undergraduates, postgraduates and those entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.    <p>例句讲解：On the list是指“在名单上”。在这个例句中，On the list指的是胡润将“最成功校友”定义为包括《胡润2023中国富豪榜》上的全日制本科生、研究生以及那些拥有博士学位的企业家。</p></li>  </ul>      </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.- 胡润研究院，由鲁伯特·胡格沃夫管理的富豪榜编制机构，澄清了其将张泽天，中国科技亿万富翁刘强东的妻子，列为清华大学毕业生中第三富有者的决定，因为该排名引起了网络上的争议。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The Hurun Research Institute has clarified its decision，其中主语是The Hurun Research Institute，谓语是has clarified，宾语是its decision。a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰The Hurun Research Institute，表示胡润研究院是由鲁伯特·胡格沃夫管理的富豪榜编制机构。after the ranking stirred controversy online是一个时间状语从句，表示在该排名引起网络争议之后。这个句子的意思是说，胡润研究院，由鲁伯特·胡格沃夫管理的富豪榜编制机构，澄清了其将张泽天，中国科技亿万富翁刘强东的妻子，列为清华大学毕业生中第三富有者的决定，因为该排名引起了网络上的争议。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul><li>According to Hurun, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China</li>
<li>Zhang ranked behind Meituan founder Wang Xing and Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/22f80ee8-51eb-4f11-94d0-38c9096e305d_32c40a21.jpg" /><figcaption>JD.com chairman Richard Liu Qiangdong and wife Zhang Zetian at Princess Eugenie’s wedding. Photo: YouTube </figcaption></figure><p>The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.</p><p>According to a list published by Hurun last Friday, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China. And 30-year-old Zhang was ranked as the third-richest graduate from Tsinghua, with a net worth of 60 billion yuan (US$8.4 billion).</p><p>Zhang ranked behind 44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan and 62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group. However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p><p>Hurun issued a statement on Monday to clarify its methodology for the ranking of rich Chinese alumni. “In the case of Tsinghua’s Zhang, her 60 billion yuan worth falls under her and [husband] Liu jointly.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239156/chinese-tech-founders-bounce-back-huruns-2023-rich-list-number-and-overall-wealth-billionaires-drop" title="">Chinese tech billionaires move up Hurun 2023 Rich List amid internet rebound</a></h3><p>The controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China. According to a separate rich list published by Forbes in November 2023, the net worth of Liu, founder and chairman of e-commerce giant JD.com, was US$4.7 billion, ranking No. 69 in China’s top 100 rich list.</p><p>Liu’s celebrity-style marriage to Zhang is also rare among Chinese tech billionaires, with many maintaining a low profile when it comes to family matters.</p><p>The Tsinghua alumni rich list was part of a Hurun Most Successful University Alumni 2023 ranking the research firm released. Hurun defined the “most successful alumni” to include former full-time undergraduates, postgraduates and those entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</p><p>A total of 58 universities, 45 Chinese and 13 overseas, have at least three alumni on the Hurun China Rich List 2023. Tsinghua and Zhejiang University topped the list, each with 32 alumni on the list.</p><p>Peking University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, and Wuhan University came in third, fourth and fifth with 22, 21, and 17 alumni respectively on the list.</p><p>Robin Li Yanhong, founder, chairman and CEO of Baidu, and Xiaomi chairman and CEO Lei Jun are two of the most high-profile and richest graduates to have come from Peking University and Wuhan University, respectively, according to the list.</p><p>Outside China, Stanford University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, University of California, Yale University and Harvard University from the US were the top five institutions with the most Hurun China Rich listers.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
