<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Huawei sets up new smart car unit as it accelerates automotive ambitions in wake of earlier deal with Changan</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248785/huawei-sets-new-smart-car-unit-it-accelerates-automotive-ambitions-wake-earlier-deal-changan</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese tech giant Huawei has established a new smart car company named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, showcasing its ambition to expand into the automobile industry. This move follows Huawei's memorandum of cooperation with state-owned carmaker Changan Automobile to initiate a smart car joint venture (JV).    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei sets up new smart car company, Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, to enter the automotive industry.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's strategic shift towards smart car manufacturing, leveraging its technological expertise and collaboration with Changan Automobile.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Huawei's commitment to innovation, industry collaboration, and its potential to revolutionize the smart car sector.</li>    <li>Main information: Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology's establishment, its focus on smart car equipment and AI, the planned transfer of Huawei's smart car system business, and potential partnerships with other carmakers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国科技巨头华为成立了新的智能汽车公司----深圳银旺智能科技有限公司，展示了其进军汽车行业的雄心。此举是继华为与国有汽车制造商长安汽车签署合作备忘录，启动智能汽车合资企业(JV)之后。    <ul>    <li>摘要：华为成立新的智能汽车公司深圳银旺智能科技有限公司，进入汽车行业。</li>    <li>主题：华为战略转向智能汽车制造，利用其技术专长与长安汽车合作。</li>    <li>观点：华为致力于创新、行业合作，以及其颠覆智能汽车领域的潜力。</li>    <li>主要信息：深圳银旺智能科技有限公司的成立、其对智能汽车设备和人工智能的关注、华为智能汽车系统业务的计划转移，以及与其他汽车制造商的潜在合作。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>state-owned (adj.) - 国有，公有的。    <p>原文例句：The new company, named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, was set up on Tuesday with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan (US$140.3 million) and is wholly owned by Huawei, according to records on business registry information platform Tianyancha.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由state（国家）和owned（所有，拥有的）构成的，表示“国有，公有的”。在这个例句中，它指的是深圳银旺智能科技有限公司是由华为全资拥有的一家国有企业。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>autonomous (adj.) - 自主的，独立的。    <p>原文例句：The new venture was set up by Huawei’s car unit to serve the industry better with its smart car solutions, according to a person familiar with the situation who declined to be named. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Greek，由auto-（自我）和nomos（法律）组成，意为“self-governing（自治）”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为汽车部门成立的新合资企业是自主的，独立的，以便更好地为行业服务。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>start a new (v.) - 开始新的，创立新的。    <P>原文例句：Under the partnership, Huawei said it plans to transfer its smart-car system business to a new unit with investments from Changan Automobile and “integrate the core technologies and resources of [Huawei’s] smart car solutions into the new company”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由start（开始）和new（新的）构成的，表示“开始新的，创立新的”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为计划将其智能汽车系统业务转移到一个新的部门，并“将华为智能汽车解决方案的核心技术和资源整合到新公司中”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The new company, named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, was set up on Tuesday with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan (US$140.3 million) and is wholly owned by Huawei, according to records on business registry information platform Tianyancha.- 新公司名为深圳银旺智能科技有限公司，周二成立，注册资本10亿元人民币（合1.403亿美元），华为全资所有，据工商登记信息平台天眼查记录。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The new company was set up on Tuesday，其中主语是The new company，谓语是was set up，宾语是on Tuesday。named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰The new company，表示新公司名为深圳银旺智能科技有限公司。with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan (US$140.3 million)是一个介词短语作状语，表示新公司的注册资本为10亿元人民币（合1.403亿美元）。and is wholly owned by Huawei是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示新公司全资由华为所有。这个句子的意思是说，新公司名为深圳银旺智能科技有限公司，周二成立，注册资本10亿元人民币（合1.403亿美元），华为全资所有，据工商登记信息平台天眼查记录。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 表示动作、状态或原因。    <p>原文例句：The new company, named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, was set up on Tuesday with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan (US$140.3 million) and is wholly owned by Huawei, according to records on business registry information platform Tianyancha.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在分词短语是由现在分词和其修饰语构成的，在句中作状语，表示动作、状态或原因。在这个例句中，现在分词短语是named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology，表示新公司名为深圳银旺智能科技有限公司，作状语，修饰谓语was set up，表示新公司成立时的名称。现在分词短语with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan (US$140.3 million)表示新公司的注册资本为10亿元人民币（合1.403亿美元），作状语，修饰谓语was set up，表示新公司成立时的注册资本。现在分词短语and is wholly owned by Huawei表示新公司全资由华为所有，作状语，修饰谓语was set up，表示新公司成立时的所有权。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>主从复合句 - 表示包含主句和从句的句子。    <p>原文例句：The new company was set up on Tuesday with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan (US$140.3 million) and is wholly owned by Huawei, according to records on business registry information platform Tianyancha.</p>    <p>语法讲解：主从复合句是由主句和从句组成的句子，主句表达主要意思，从句表达补充或修饰主句的意思。在这个例句中，主句是The new company was set up on Tuesday with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan (US$140.3 million) and is wholly owned by Huawei，表示新公司周二成立，注册资本10亿元人民币（合1.403亿美元），华为全资所有。从句是according to records on business registry information platform Tianyancha，表示据工商登记信息平台天眼查记录，作状语，修饰谓语was set up，表示新公司成立时的依据。这个句子的意思是说，新公司周二成立，注册资本10亿元人民币（合1.403亿美元），华为全资所有，据工商登记信息平台天眼查记录。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The new company, named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, has a registered capital of 1 billion yuan</li>
<li>Development comes after Huawei signed a memorandum of cooperation in November with Changan Automobile</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/e37393ee-ae53-42e1-b91e-e3573624b3f0_f7eb1e73.jpg" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies has set up a new smart car company. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has set up a new smart car company as the US-sanctioned telecoms equipment giant steps up its ambitions in the automobile industry, following its earlier announcement of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242954/us-sanctioned-huawei-forms-smart-vehicle-joint-venture-state-owned-changan-automobile-amid-effort" target="_self" title="">a joint venture (JV) with Chinese state-owned carmaker Changan Automobile</a>.</p><p>The new company, named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, was set up on Tuesday with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan (US$140.3 million) and is wholly owned by Huawei, according to records on business registry information platform Tianyancha.</p><p>The records show that the new firm’s business covers smart car equipment manufacturing, artificial intelligence (AI) system integration services, and AI software development, among other areas.</p><p>The development comes after Huawei signed a memorandum of cooperation in November with Changan Automobile, a major state-owned carmaker based in Chongqing, southwestern Sichuan province, to start a new smart car JV.</p><p>Under the partnership, Huawei said it plans to transfer its smart-car system business to a new unit with investments from Changan Automobile and “integrate the core technologies and resources of [Huawei’s] smart car solutions into the new company”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" title="">Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights</a></h3><p>The new venture was set up by Huawei’s car unit to serve the industry better with its smart car solutions, according to a person familiar with the situation who declined to be named. Huawei declined to comment on the relationship between the new entity and its JV with Changan.</p><p>While Huawei currently holds 100 per cent of the new firm, it is open to more industry partners joining to become a technology platform with diversified equity, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Securities Times.</p><p>In November, Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group and chairman of its Intelligent Automotive Solution business unit, called on Chinese carmakers Seres Group, Chery Automobile, JAC Motors and BAIC Motor to take an equity stake in the Huawei-Changan JV.</p><p>All four of these companies – generally considered smaller carmakers in the country – currently partner with Huawei to develop and sell new brands under the so-called Huawei Select model, through which the smartphone giant collaborates closely with companies on everything from product design to sales. These brands include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3238274/huaweis-ev-brand-aito-hits-sales-jackpot-new-suv-will-compensate-buyers-delivery-delays-sizzling?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Aito with Seres</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3235762/superior-teslas-model-s-huawei-and-chery-automobile-ev-venture-luxeed-launch-first-production-model?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Luxeed with Chery</a>.</p><p>At Changan’s global partnership conference on Tuesday, the automaker’s chairman Zhu Huarong revealed that Huawei had promised not to produce cars under their JV deal, which was sealed within three months of initiating discussions, according to a live-streamed video of the event.</p><p>Zhu also said that the two companies are in the process of discussing the details of their partnership and its establishment, which is tentatively named “Newcool” in English.</p><p>The Huawei-Changan JV will also be open to more firms, Zhu said, adding that it will focus on seven main businesses including intelligent automotive systems, smart cockpits and a digital platform.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s IC output grew 6.9% in 2023, defying weaker customer demand, tighter US sanctions</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248776/chinas-ic-output-grew-69-2023-defying-weaker-customer-demand-tighter-us-sanctions</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In 2023, China's total production of integrated circuits (ICs) increased by 6.9% compared to the previous year, reaching 351.4 billion units. However, the industry faced challenges due to weaker demand, especially from smartphone and personal computer makers, as well as tighter US-led sanctions. China's largest foundry, SMIC, saw its capacity utilization rate drop significantly, and its total shipments of wafers declined by 24% year-on-year in the first nine months of 2023. The overall semiconductor foundry capacity utilization rates remained under downward pressure due to the prevailing economic turbulence. Separately, China's exports of ICs decreased in both volume and value, while imports also declined.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's IC industry saw a slight increase in production but faced challenges due to weaker demand and sanctions.</li>    <li>Theme: China's semiconductor industry navigates challenges amid shifting market dynamics and geopolitical tensions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of weaker demand, particularly from key sectors, and US-led sanctions on China's IC industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Production and shipment figures for ICs, capacity utilization rates, export and import data, and industry outlook.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023年，中国集成电路（IC）总产量与去年相比增长了6.9%，达到3514亿片。然而，由于需求疲软，尤其是智能手机和个人电脑制造商的需求疲软，以及美国主导的制裁日趋严格，该行业面临挑战。中国最大的晶圆代工厂中芯国际的产能利用率大幅下降，2023年前九个月的晶圆总出货量同比下降24%。由于普遍存在的经济动荡，整体半导体代工厂的产能利用率仍面临下行压力。此外，中国集成电路出口量和出口额均有所下降，进口量和进口额也有所下降。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国集成电路产业产量小幅增长，但面临需求疲软和制裁的挑战。</li>    <li>主题：中国半导体产业在市场动态变化和地缘政治紧张局势中应对挑战。</li>    <li>观点：需求疲软，特别是主要行业的疲软，以及美国主导的制裁对中国集成电路产业的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：集成电路产量和出货量数据，产能利用率，进出口数据和行业前景。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>wafer (n.) - /ˈweɪfər/ 晶圆，硅片。    <p>原文例句：SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语单词“wafer”，意思是“薄圆饼、薄片”，用来指硅片，即半导体材料的薄片，用作制造集成电路。在这个例句中，它指的是中芯国际从2023年1月到9月期间晶圆的总出货量下降了24%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>capacity utilization (n.) - /kəˈpæsəti juːtɪlaɪˈzeɪʃən/ 产能利用率    <p>原文例句：China chip design expert warns of losses due to industry overcrowding.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词组由capacity（容量），utilization（利用）和rate（比率）组成，表示“产能利用率”，即实际产量与理论产能的比率。在这个例句中，它指的是中国芯片设计专家警告由于行业产能过剩而导致的损失。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>on year - 与去年相比。    <P>原文例句：In 2023, China’s total production of integrated circuits (ICs) increased by 6.9 per cent from a year earlier. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由on（在……上）和year（年份）组成的，表示“与去年相比”。在这个例句中，它表示2023年中国集成电路（IC）的总产量比前一年增长了6.9%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year, reflecting weaker demand from its main customers in sectors spanning from smartphones to carmakers. - 中芯国际从2023年1月到9月期间晶圆的总出货量下降了24%，反映了从智能手机到汽车制造商等主要客户的需求疲软。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是SMIC’s total shipments of wafers declined by 24 per cent year on year，其中主语是SMIC’s total shipments of wafers，谓语是declined，宾语是24 per cent year on year。reflecting weaker demand from its main customers in sectors spanning from smartphones to carmakers是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示SMIC的晶圆总出货量下降的原因或方式，即反映了从智能手机到汽车制造商等主要客户的需求疲软。这个句子的意思是说，中芯国际从2023年1月到9月期间晶圆的总出货量下降了24%，反映了从智能手机到汽车制造商等主要客户的需求疲软。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 强调句首的状语或宾语，将它们提前到主语之前。    <p>原文例句：A semiconductor wafer foundry in Western Science City in southwest China’s Chongqing Municipality, Aug. 24, 2023. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，将状语A semiconductor wafer foundry in Western Science City in southwest China’s Chongqing Municipality提前到主语Photo之前，以强调这个状语。这个句子的意思是说，这是2023年8月24日在中国西南重庆市的西方科学城的一个半导体晶圆代工厂。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式 - 表示动词的非限定形式，可以作主语、宾语、表语、状语或同位语。    <p>原文例句：The country produced 351.4 billion ICs last year, compared with 324.2 billion in 2022. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，不定式to reach the total IC number作状语，表示“为了达到集成电路的总数”。不定式可以由动词原形或加to的不定式构成，不定式具有动词和名词的双重特性，可以作主语、宾语、表语、状语或同位语。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The country produced 351.4 billion ICs last year, compared with 324.2 billion in 2022, according to data published by China’s National Bureau of Statistics</li>
<li>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year, reflecting weaker demand from its main customers</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/ce7b587c-5f38-411c-9843-cac4990a5c01_4b7791c6.jpg" /><figcaption>A semiconductor wafer foundry in Western Science City in southwest China’s Chongqing Municipality, Aug. 24, 2023. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China’s total output of integrated circuits (ICs) in 2023 increased 6.9 per cent from a year earlier despite sluggish demand at one of its largest wafer foundries in the second half.</p><p>The country produced 351.4 billion ICs last year, compared with 324.2 billion in 2022, according to data published on Wednesday by China’s National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).</p><p>The NBS data counted a variety of chips to reach the total IC number, including logic, memory, analogue and special chips, plus sensors and chip modules.</p><p>In 2023, China’s semiconductor manufacturing industry was marred by factors such as weaker economic post-pandemic recovery, sluggish demand from smartphone and personal-computer makers, and tighter US-led sanctions that restricted its access to advanced technologies.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3241136/china-chip-design-expert-warns-losses-due-industry-overcrowding-says-more-cautious-path-self" title="">China chip design expert warns of losses due to industry overcrowding</a></h3><p>China’s top foundry <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240965/chinese-chip-maker-smics-sales-fall-third-straight-quarter-despite-boost-huaweis-5g-smartphone" target="_self" title="">Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC),</a> which derived 84 per cent of its total revenue from the domestic market in the third quarter, saw its capacity utilisation rate fall to an average of 74 per cent in the first three quarters of last year, compared with 96 per cent in the same period the year before.</p><p>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year, reflecting weaker demand from its main customers in sectors spanning from smartphones to carmakers.</p><p>The company will report its fourth-quarter and full-year results on February 7.</p><p>The market softness was also felt by China’s second-largest foundry Hua Hong Semiconductor, which saw revenue in the first nine months of last year drop 0.79 per year on year, while third-quarter capacity utilisation sank to 86.8 per cent from a capacity overload situation in the second quarter, according to data from the company.</p><p>Industry analysts have predicted the sluggish demand to continue in the current quarter, with signs of recovery only becoming visible in the second quarter.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/ebdd4d9b-53c5-45d6-928a-bbc3ebc20246_d7e8111e.jpg" title="SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>Overall semiconductor foundry capacity utilisation rates are still under downward pressure amid the prevailing economic turbulence this quarter, Taiwan-based IC research company TrendForce said in a recent note.</p><p>TrendForce predicted that foundry inventory levels will improve in the second quarter, returning to a healthier equilibrium despite the continuing murky outlook for end-customer orders.</p><p>Separately, China exported a total of 267.8 billion ICs worth US$135.9 billion in 2023, down 1.8 per cent by volume and 10.1 per cent lower in value from 2022.</p><p>Meanwhile, China imported 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion, down 10.8 per cent by volume and 15.4 per cent in value from 2022, official data showed.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s internet giants must step up opening their ‘walled gardens’, state media says, ahead of Tencent flagship game’s return to Douyin</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248762/chinas-internet-giants-must-step-opening-their-walled-gardens-state-media-says-ahead-tencent</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Securities Times urged China's internet giants to be more open and collaborative to jointly tackle market challenges and promote industry growth. The Securities Times article called for breaking down digital barriers and enabling collaboration across internet ecosystems, with examples such as Tencent's Honour of Kings returning to Douyin and the partnership between ByteDance and Tencent. Increased cooperation in video content distribution, gaming operations, and e-commerce platforms was highlighted, showing a trend of collaboration among rival internet companies in China.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Encouraging open collaboration among internet companies in China.</li>    <li>Theme: Breaking down digital barriers and enabling cross-platform collaboration in China's internet industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The need for internet giants to embrace open-mindedness and inclusivity, leading to mutually beneficial cooperation and industry expansion.</li>    <li>Main information: Collaboration examples involving Tencent, Douyin, ByteDance, Alibaba, and JD.com, showcasing a shift towards collaboration in the Chinese internet sector.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  证券时报发文称，中国互联网巨头需更加开放，积极协作，共同应对市场挑战，促进行业增长。 文章呼吁打破数码壁垒，推动互联网生态系统间的合作，以腾讯《王者荣耀》回归抖音、字节跳动与腾讯合作等为例，强调了视频内容分发、游戏业务、电商平台等方面的合作，呈现中国互联网企业间协同合作的趋势。  <ul>    <li>摘要：鼓励中国互联网企业间开放协作。</li>    <li>主题：打破数码壁垒，推动中国互联网行业跨平台协作。</li>    <li>观点：互联网巨头需要开放心态，包容合作，实现互利共赢，推动行业扩张。</li>    <li>主要信息：涉及腾讯、抖音、字节跳动、阿里巴巴、京东等企业的合作案例，显现中国互联网行业走向协作的趋势。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ecosystem (n.) - /ˈekəʊˌsɪstəm/ 生态系统。    <p>原文例句：The call to break more digital barriers in China’s internet industry comes days before Tencent’s Honour of Kings returns to Douyin’s platform, embracing the vast ecosystem of ByteDance, which has more than 600 million daily active users.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“生态系统”一词源于希腊语oikos（房子、住所）和σύστημα（系统），意为“一个生物体与其周围环境之间的相互作用及其生存条件的总和”。在该例句中，它指的是字节跳动拥有超过6亿日活跃用户的庞大生态系统，腾讯《王者荣耀》回归抖音平台即意味着融入这个生态系统。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>collaboration (n.) - /kəˌlæbəˈreɪʃən/ 合作，协作。    <p>原文例句：China’s major internet companies ‘need to be more open-minded’ about enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms, according to the Securities Times article.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“协作”一词源于拉丁语collaborare（共同劳动），意为“共同努力以实现共同目标”。在该例句中，它指的是中国主要互联网公司需要在使他们的生态系统跨平台协作方面更具开放意识。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>face market pressures together - 共同面对市场压力。    <p>原文例句：“Internet companies need to leverage each other to face the market pressures together,” the Securities Times article said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“共同面对市场压力”是一个动词词组，意为“利用各自的优势和资源共同应对市场挑战”。在该例句中，它指的是互联网公司需要利用彼此的优势和资源共同应对市场挑战。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>be more open-minded - 更加开放。    <p>原文例句：“In the future, internet companies need to be more open-minded and inclusive to promote truly win-win cooperation in the industry,” the Securities Times article said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“更加开放”是一个形容词词组，意为“具有更强的包容性和接受性”。在该例句中，它指的是互联网公司需要具有更强的包容性和接受性，以促进行业内的真正互利合作。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>At present, collaborations among these companies “are far from deep”, said an article published on Tuesday by Shenzhen-based Securities Times, a financial newspaper owned by the Chinese Communist Party mouthpiece People’s Daily. - 目前，这些公司之间的合作“还远远不够深入”，深圳证券时报周二发表的一篇文章说道，该报是一家由中国共产党喉舌人民日报所有 的财经报纸。    <p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是collaborations among these companies “are far from deep”，其中主语是collaborations among these companies，谓语是are far from deep。said an article published on Tuesday by Shenzhen-based Securities Times, a financial newspaper owned by the Chinese Communist Party mouthpiece People’s Daily是一个定语从句，修饰主句中的collaborations，表示这些合作还远远不够深入，该文章由深圳证券时报于周二发表，深圳证券时报是一家由中国共产党喉舌人民日报所有的财经报纸。这个句子的意思是说，目前，这些公司之间的合作还远远不够深入，该文章由深圳证券时报于周二发表，深圳证券时报是一家由中国共产党喉舌人民日报所有的财经报纸。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式作目的语 - 表示动作或状态的目的或结果。    <p>原文例句：The call to break more digital barriers in China’s internet industry comes days before Tencent’s Honour of Kings returns to Douyin’s platform.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个动词不定式作目的语的例子，结构是：动词不定式+to+动词原形。动词不定式作目的语表示动作或状态的目的或结果，在该例句中，to break more digital barriers in China’s internet industry表示打破中国互联网行业中更多的数字壁垒，是return to Douyin’s platform的目的或结果。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Collaborations among these Big Tech firms ‘are far from deep’, according to an article by Securities Times</li>
<li>The call to break more digital barriers in China’s internet industry comes days before Tencent’s Honour of Kings returns to Douyin’s platform</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/e3c9aa50-df1e-4b22-8f21-d4b06c403b4e_0bbdcb09.jpg" /><figcaption>China’s major internet companies ‘need to be more open-minded’ about enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms, according to the Securities Times article. Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants must accelerate efforts to open up their “walled gardens”, enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms as a means “to face market pressures together” and assure the industry’s further expansion, according to state-owned media.</p><p>At present, collaborations among these companies “are far from deep”, said an article published on Tuesday by Shenzhen-based Securities Times, a financial newspaper owned by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chinas-communist-party" target="_self" title="">Chinese Communist Party</a> mouthpiece People’s Daily.</p><p>The call to break more digital barriers in China’s internet industry comes days before <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honour-kings" target="_self" title="">Honour of Kings</a>, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3116088/honour-kings-became-worlds-most-popular-game-it-was-desperate?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">world’s most popular mobile game</a>, officially returns to the popular live-streaming platform of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3101626/douyin-chinas-tiktok-grows-daily-active-users-600-million-home" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>, which has more than 600 million daily active users, from January 21.</p><p>“In the future, internet companies need to be more open-minded and inclusive to promote truly win-win cooperation in the industry,” the Securities Times article said.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Increased collaboration between China’s major internet companies are expected to not only benefit consumers, but help further expand the industry, according to state media. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/4358c69f-a073-4444-8f19-753e8dd060b9_53933fe2.jpg" title="Increased collaboration between China’s major internet companies are expected to not only benefit consumers, but help further expand the industry, according to state media. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Increased collaboration between China’s major internet companies are expected to not only benefit consumers, but help further expand the industry, according to state media. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>The collaboration between ByteDance and Tencent comes amid the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> industry’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248249/chinas-video-gaming-market-ended-2023-battered-and-bruised-can-world-beating-titles-and-innovation?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">regulatory uncertainties and a weaker macro environment in China</a>.</p><p>While China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248694/china-gdp-beijings-long-do-list-boost-economy-2024" target="_self" title="">gross domestic product rose by 5.2 per cent</a> year on year in 2023, the world’s second-largest economy still faced mounting concerns this year including waning investor confidence, a protracted property market slump and a weak private sector.</p><p>“Internet companies need to leverage each other to face the market pressures together,” the Securities Times article said.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a> owner ByteDance earlier this month confirmed that it was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">in talks with multiple potential buyers</a>, including Tencent, to sell its video gaming operations.</p><p>Last April, Tencent and Douyin <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3216333/tencent-and-douyin-end-years-copyright-disputes-signing-cooperation-agreement-content-distribution" target="_self" title="">agreed to a partnership in video content distribution</a> after years of contentious copyright disputes.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>Under that deal, Tencent authorised Douyin to distribute its video content and clarify copyright rules for users to produce modifications and adaptations. As a result, users of ByteDance-owned platforms Douyin, Xigua Video and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/abacus/culture/article/3074051/why-chinas-favorite-news-app-lets-users-order-food" target="_self" title="">Jinri Toutiao</a> will be able to produce derivative works based on Tencent-owned videos.</p><p>There have been other cases of collaboration between rival internet platform operators over the years,</p><p>In November, Alibaba Group Holding’s grocery chain <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/e-commerce/article/3103476/alibabas-freshippo-opens-first-membership-only-store-shanghai" target="_self" title="">Freshippo</a> opened a store on rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3155846/chinas-internet-walled-gardens-may-be-cracking-users-face-long" title="">Beijing wants to smash online walls but Big Tech treads carefully</a></h3><p>Tencent’s super app <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> and Alibaba’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247985/alibabas-taobao-and-tmall-group-pushes-new-ai-tools-boost-merchants-service-consumers-first-major" target="_self" title="">Taobao and Tmall Group</a> in September announced an expanded collaboration, which enabled users who click on advertisements on WeChat to be <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235835/alibaba-tencent-break-more-digital-barriers-between-wechat-and-taobao-tmall-economic-uncertainty" target="_self" title="">directed to shops and live-streaming campaigns on Taobao and Tmall</a>.</p><p>In November 2021, Tencent opened WeChat to third-party online links including those of Douyin and Taobao.</p><p>In September that same year, Alibaba started allowing consumers to use Tencent’s WeChat Pay as a payment option on a number of its platforms including food delivery platform <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3227745/alibabas-eleme-food-delivery-platform-extends-welfare-coverage-3-million-couriers-collective" target="_self" title="">Ele.me</a>, video-streaming platform <a href="https://www.scmp.com/abacus/who-what/what/article/3028268/how-youku-went-being-chinas-youtube-chinas-hulu" target="_self" title="">Youku</a>, online ticketing platform Damai and cross-border e-commerce platform Kaola.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s hi-tech manufacturing faces ‘extraordinary pressures’ as 2023 output stalls</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248773/chinas-hi-tech-manufacturing-faces-extraordinary-pressures-2023-output-stalls</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In 2023, the growth rate of China's hi-tech manufacturing industry hit a record low of 2.7% due to economic slowdown and US containment efforts.</li>    <li>Beijing aims to drive economic growth through innovation and technology, seeking to replace the real estate sector and address demographic challenges.</li>    <li>Despite increased investment, the hi-tech sector is facing headwinds like global recession risks, US-China tensions, and weak consumer demand.</li>    <li>US sanctions pose risks to Chinese tech companies seeking public listings, affecting market valuations.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>2023年，中国高技术制造业增长率创下2.7%的记录新低，因经济放缓和美国遏制措施。</li>    <li>北京旨在通过创新和技术推动经济增长，寻求取代房地产行业并应对人口挑战。</li>    <li>尽管投资增加，高科技行业正面临全球衰退风险、中美紧张局势和消费者需求疲软等不利因素的影响。</li>    <li>美国制裁对寻求公开上市的中国科技公司构成风险，影响市场估值。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>faltering (adj.) - /ˈfɔːltərɪŋ/ 摇摆不定的，犹豫不决的。    <p>原文例句：Output from China’s hi-tech manufacturing sector grew at the slowest pace on record last year amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States, with the decline weighing on Beijing’s march towards superpower status.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词来源于Old French，表示“摇摆不定的，犹豫不决的”。在这个例句中，它描述了中国高科技制造业产值增长创下历史最低水平的原因之一，即经济疲软。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>containment (n.) - /kənˈteɪnmənt/ 遏制，围堵。    <p>原文例句：Output from China’s hi-tech manufacturing sector grew at the slowest pace on record last year amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States, with the decline weighing on Beijing’s march towards superpower status.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词由contain（包含，容纳）和-ment（行为，过程）组成，表示“遏制，围堵”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国对中国日益增强的经济和技术实力采取的遏制措施，这也是中国高科技制造业产值增长创下历史最低水平的原因之一。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>decoupling (n.) - /diːˈkʌplɪŋ/ 脱钩，分离。    <p>原文例句：“The hi-tech recovery will require China to return to higher economic growth and counteract US decoupling.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词由de-（分开）和couple（连接，耦合）组成，表示“脱钩，分离”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国试图与中国在经济、技术等领域脱钩，这给中国的高科技产业带来了挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>going public - 上市。    <p>原文例句：“Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public, the potential sanctions would affect their market valuations”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由go（去）和public（公共的）组成，表示“上市”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国科技制造商在证券交易所上市。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Beijing has pinned its hopes on innovation and technology to power the world’s second-largest economy as it seeks to find new growth engines. - 北京将希望寄托在创新和技术上，以推动世界第二大经济体发展，因为它寻求寻找新的增长引擎。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Beijing has pinned its hopes on innovation and technology to power the world’s second-largest economy，其中主语是Beijing，谓语是has pinned its hopes on innovation and technology to power the world’s second-largest economy，宾语是new growth engines。as it seeks to find new growth engines是一个状语从句，修饰主句，表示北京寻求寻找新的增长引擎。这个句子的意思是说，北京将希望寄托在创新和技术上，以推动世界第二大经济体发展，因为它寻求寻找新的增长引擎。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语作定语 - 修饰名词或代词。    <p>原文例句：Output from China’s hi-tech manufacturing sector grew at the slowest pace on record last year amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States.</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语作定语是用来修饰名词或代词的一种短语，它由一个分词及其修饰语组成。在这个例句中，amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States是一个分词短语作定语，修饰名词sector，表示在经济疲软和美国不断升级的遏制措施中。这个短语的意思是说，在经济疲软和美国不断升级的遏制措施中，中国高科技制造业产值增长创下历史最低水平。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023, but this marked the lowest level of growth since records began in 2018</li>
<li>Beijing has pinned its hopes on innovation and technology to power the world’s second-largest economy as it seeks to find new growth engines</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/bb42c49a-576e-447b-9e8e-c4b1bce62af6_f90326de.jpg" /><figcaption>Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Output from China’s hi-tech manufacturing sector grew at the slowest pace on record last year amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States, with the decline weighing on Beijing’s march towards superpower status.</p><p>Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023, falling behind an increase of 5 per cent from the overall manufacturing industry, marking the lowest level of growth since the National Bureau of Statistics started to release the figures in 2018.</p><p>The hi-tech manufacturing industry had seen its growth soar to a record high of 18.2 per cent in 2021 before easing to 7.4 per cent in 2022, having stood at 7.1 per cent in 2020 amid coronavirus-induced disruptions to the global supply chain.</p><p>Beijing has pinned its hopes on innovation and technology to power the world’s second-largest economy as it seeks to find new growth engines to replace the real estate sector, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248695/chinas-population-falls-208-million-14097-billion-2023-births-tumble-adding-demographic-concerns" target="_self" title="">address its demographic challenges</a> and move up the advanced industrial chain.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>Investment in hi-tech manufacturing grew by 9.9 per cent last year, beating the 6.5 per cent increase seen in the overall manufacturing industry, but the financing still registered the slowest pace since records began in 2015.</p><p>Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, said the sector is heading into a cooling period after years of rapid expansion.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248694/china-gdp-beijings-long-do-list-boost-economy-2024" target="_self" title="">“The latest economic data</a> indicate that the whole economic recovery is weak, and market confidence in many sectors is shaky, including tech,” he said.</p><p>“The hi-tech recovery will require China to return to higher economic growth and counteract US decoupling.</p><p>“It also demands the country’s ability to adapt to deglobalisation, but maintain a strong global exporter role.”</p><blockquote>Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public, the potential sanctions would affect their market valuationsChen Zhiwu</blockquote><p>In December, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246040/china-targets-industries-future-2024-humanoid-robots-and-biomedicines-drive-high-quality-economic" target="_self" title="">said it would increase funding</a> to nurture the transformation of traditional manufacturers into hi-tech producers.</p><p>It said China’s hi-tech manufacturing industry was currently facing challenges from insufficient innovation and increasing external pressure.</p><p>Chen Zhiwu, a chair professor of finance at the University of Hong Kong, said headwinds such as risks of a global recession and US-China tensions would continue to exert “extraordinary pressures” on China’s hi-tech push.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies" title="">‘More, better’: premier urges China to focus on application of core technologies</a></h3><p>“The US tech war has largely thwarted Chinese tech companies’ [initial public offering] opportunities. Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public, the potential sanctions would affect their market valuations,” said Chen.</p><p>He added China’s weak economic momentum is also weighing on the market’s overall willingness to invest, with hi-tech manufacturing just one element.</p><p>“The rapid development of hi-tech industries over the past 20 years has provided China with a massive boost to its economic boom, this was partly due to the impact of a stable external environment on investor confidence,” Chen said.</p><p>“Many hi-tech companies I’ve surveyed recently said that market demand for tech products is relatively low, and with uncertain market sentiment, consumers are tightening their wallets so much that companies have to cut back on production.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Saudi Arabia is eyeing a ‘sizeable’ investment to kick off kingdom’s foray into semiconductors</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248768/saudi-arabia-eying-sizeable-investment-kick-kingdoms-foray-semiconductors</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Saudi Arabia, with the goal of diversifying its economy, plans to make substantial investments in the semiconductor and space industries this year. The Public Investment Fund (PIF) intends to announce a major player within the semiconductor industry to lead Saudi efforts and establish a national space company for investments and acquisitions. Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman's strategy aims to reduce reliance on oil sales and transform the Saudi economy by 2025.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Saudi Arabia's economic diversification strategy involves significant investments in the semiconductor and space industries.</li>    <li>Theme: Saudi Arabia's transition away from oil dependence and towards a diversified economy.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The role of PIF in transforming the Saudi economy; Saudi Arabia's ambition to become a regional and global leader in the space industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Planned investments in the semiconductor industry; the goal of establishing regional and global leadership in the space sector; steps taken to attract investments from both the US and China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  沙特阿拉伯为实现经济多元化，计划今年在半导体和太空产业领域进行大量投资。公共投资基金（PIF）打算宣布半导体行业内的主要参与者以领导沙特努力，并为投资和收购建立一家国家太空公司。王储穆罕默德·本·萨勒曼的战略旨在减少对石油销售的依赖，到 2025 年转型沙特经济。  <ul>    <li>摘要：沙特阿拉伯的经济多元化战略涉及对半导体和太空产业的巨额投资。</li>    <li>主题：沙特阿拉伯从依赖石油转向多元化经济的转变。</li>    <li>观点：PIF 在转型沙特经济中的作用；沙特阿拉伯在太空产业中成为区域和全球领导者的雄心。</li>    <li>主要信息：对半导体行业的计划性投资；在太空领域建立区域和全球领导地位的目标；采取措施吸引美国和中国的投资。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sovereign wealth fund (n.) - /ˈsɑːvərən ˌwelθ fʌnd/ 主权财富基金。    <p>原文例句：Saudi Arabia’s sovereign wealth fund is planning to make big investments in both the semiconductor and space industries this year as the kingdom accelerates efforts to diversify its economy away from oil. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由sovereign（主权的）和wealth fund（财富基金）组成，表示“一国政府投资管理的基金”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>chipmaker (n.) - /ˈtʃɪpˌmeɪkər/ 芯片制造商。    <p>原文例句：US EV maker Lucid Group is already assembling cars from the site, and is set to be joined by Hyundai Motor and Ceer, a brand created by the PIF.     </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由chip（芯片）和maker（制造商）组成，表示“生产微处理器的公司”</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>from the ground up - 从头开始，从基础开始。    <P>原文例句：One of its key initiatives has been to develop an auto manufacturing hub on the west coast of the kingdom.     </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由from（从），the（the），ground（地面）和up（向上）组成，表示“从头开始，从基础开始”。在这个例句中，它表示沙特阿拉伯的一个主要举措是从头开始在该国的西海岸开发一个汽车制造中心。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>downstream industries - 下游产业。    <P>原文例句：The plan involves developing downstream industries that is expected to also include making semiconductors and batteries.     </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由downstream（下游）和industries（产业）组成，表示“在下游的部门或产业”。在这个例句中，它表示该计划涉及发展下游产业，预计还包括生产半导体和电池。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“The new space economy is definitely the next trillion-dollar opportunity,” Al-Swaha said. - 艾尔·斯瓦哈说：“新的太空经济绝对是下一个万亿美元机遇。”    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Al-Swaha，谓语是said，宾语是“The new space economy is definitely the next trillion-dollar opportunity”。said是一个过去式动词，表示艾尔·斯瓦哈曾经说过某些话。The new space economy is definitely the next trillion-dollar opportunity是一个名词性从句，充当宾语，表示新的太空经济绝对是下一个万亿美元机遇。这个句子的意思是说，艾尔·斯瓦哈说，“新的太空经济绝对是下一个万亿美元机遇”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态一直持续到现在。    <p>原文例句：The kingdom launched its space programme in 2018 and sent astronauts into space last year, as part of a wider plan to invest in the industry.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是一种时态，表示过去发生的动作或状态一直持续到现在。它的结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。在这个例句中，现在完成时态的动词是have launched，表示沙特阿拉伯从2018年开始就发射了它的空间计划，一直持续到现在。现在完成时态的动词是has sent，表示沙特阿拉伯去年把宇航员送入太空，一直持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去式 - 表示过去发生的事件或动作。    <p>原文例句：The kingdom launched its space programme in 2018 and sent astronauts into space last year, as part of a wider plan to invest in the industry.</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去式是一种时态，表示过去发生的事件或动作。它的结构是：did + 动词原形/过去式。在这个例句中，过去式的动词是launched，表示沙特阿拉伯在2018年发射了它的空间计划。过去式的动词是sent，表示沙特阿拉伯去年把宇航员送入太空。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Public Investment Fund is looking at making a “sizeable investment” this year into the semiconductor industry, the Saudi communications minister said</li>
<li>PIF plans to make an announcement on a particular champion within the space to lead the Saudi efforts, the minister said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/3343fdd8-ac9c-4f06-8626-ba93903d1af0_6ec679cb.jpg" /><figcaption>Riyadh, capital of Saudi Arabia. Photo: Natalie Wong</figcaption></figure><p>Saudi Arabia’s sovereign wealth fund is planning to make big investments in both the semiconductor and space industries this year as the kingdom accelerates efforts to diversify its economy away from oil.</p><p>The Public Investment Fund is looking at making a “sizeable investment” this year into the semiconductor industry, Saudi Minister of Communications and Information Technology Abdullah Al-Swaha said in an interview at the World Economic Forum in Davos. “They plan to make an announcement on a particular champion within the space to lead the Saudi efforts,” he said, declining to give further details.</p><p>Alswaha, who is chairman of the kingdom’s Space Agency as well, said the fund will also look to create a national space company to invest and acquire assets in that sector. The space industry is “ripe right now” for M&amp;A, he said.</p><p>The fund, known as PIF, has emerged as one of the key parts of Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman’s plan to shake up the Saudi economy and wean it off a reliance on oil sales. It has rapidly built up assets of around US$700 billion after a spending spree on everything from electric carmakers to backing upstart golf tournaments, and plans to control US$1 trillion by 2025.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3226303/saudi-arabia-deepen-ties-hong-kong-using-city-bridge-mainland-chinas-world-class-digital-prowess" title="">Saudi Arabia to use Hong Kong as bridge to China’s tech prowess</a></h3><p>One of its key initiatives has been to develop an auto manufacturing hub on the west coast of the kingdom. US EV maker Lucid Group is already assembling cars from the site, and is set to be joined by Hyundai Motor and Ceer, a brand created by the PIF. The plan involves developing downstream industries that is expected to also include making semiconductors and batteries.</p><p>The kingdom launched its space programme in 2018 and sent astronauts into space last year, as part of a wider plan to invest in the industry.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>“The new space economy is definitely the next trillion-dollar opportunity,” Al-Swaha said. “The kingdom is very bullish on not only becoming a regional leader in this space but also a global leader. The ambition by 2030 is to definitely establish regional leadership and then move on by 2040 to global leadership.”</p><p>A key part of Saudi Arabia’s space investments will be in communications, Alswaha said. “2.6 billion people in 2024 are still not connected and the only way to connect the unconnected is from the skies.”</p><p>Alswaha said that Saudi Arabia expects to be able to continue to attract investment from both US and Chinese technologies companies, even as tensions between the world’s two largest economies escalate. The kingdom “has demonstrated our partnership with both east and west on protecting their intellectual property and patents and any potential technology leakage,” Alswaha said.</p><p>Saudi Arabia is “pro-investment, pro-partnership and open market,” he said. “Anybody that complies with our regulatory, security requirements, serves our national interest, we will work with.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei chases enterprise clients in South Korea as consumers hold onto Samsung, Apple smartphones</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248755/huawei-chases-enterprise-clients-south-korea-consumers-hold-samsung-apple-smartphones</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Huawei's goal of retaking the global smartphone market may not materialize in South Korea, where Apple and Samsung continue to reign as the leading competitors. The company's plan to establish a cloud business branch there encounters difficulties due to lingering US sanctions, a saturated 5G smartphone market, and a lack of local partners. Huawei's effort to expand its smartphone presence in Korea since 2014 hasn't succeeded due to limited operator support.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei's struggles in South Korea's smartphone market despite global comeback plans.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's attempt to regain market share in South Korea's smartphone sector faces challenges.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The article highlights the obstacles Huawei faces in its quest for South Korean smartphone market share.</li>    <li>Main information: US sanctions, 5G smartphone market saturation, lack of local partners, and Samsung's dominance are key factors hindering Huawei's progress.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  华为计划重新夺回全球智能手机市场，但在韩国，苹果和三星仍主导市场，成为主要竞争对手，华为的目标可能无法实现。由于美国制裁的持续影响、5G 智能手机市场的饱和和缺乏本地合作伙伴，该公司在当地建立云业务部门的计划遇到了困难。华为自 2014 年以来一直在努力扩大其在韩国的智能手机业务，但由于运营商的支持有限，尚未成功。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为在韩国智能手机市场的困境，尽管有全球卷土重来的计划。</li>    <li>主题：华为在韩国智能手机市场重获市场份额的尝试面临挑战。</li>    <li>观点：文章重点介绍了华为在争取韩国智能手机市场份额时面临的障碍。</li>    <li>主要信息：美国制裁、5G 智能手机市场饱和、缺乏本地合作伙伴以及三星的优势是阻碍华为进步的关键因素。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>secure (v.) - /sɪˈkjʊər/ 确保，保证。    <p>原文例句：Huawei is struggling to expand its market share or secure trust from local partners amid the US-China tech rivalry, analysts said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于拉丁语securus，由se-（没有）和cura（关心）组成，意为“没有担心，无忧无虑”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为正在努力扩大其市场份额或确保本地合作伙伴的信任。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>project (n.) - /ˈprɑːdʒɛkt/ 项目，工程。    <p>原文例句：Huawei has tried to launch both premium and affordable smartphones in Korea since 2014, but it has been unable to gain ground “largely due to local operators’ preference for Samsung,” said Woody Oh, service director at TechInsights. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于拉丁语projectum，由pro-（向前）和iacere（投掷）组成，意为“向前投掷，抛掷”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为自 2014 年以来一直试图在韩国推出高端和价格适中的智能手机。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>comeback (n.) - /ˈkʌmˌbæk/ 回归，复出。    <p>原文例句：Chinese telecommunications equipment giant Huawei Technologies is poised to make a comeback in the global smartphone market this year, but in South Korea, the company must contend with the lingering impact of US sanctions and intense competition with international and local rivals, according to industry watchers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由come（来）和back（回去）组成，表示“回来，复出”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为准备在今年的全球智能手机市场中卷土重来。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei, which briefly surpassed Samsung to lead global smartphone shipments in early 2020, has dropped out of the global top five since 2021. - 华为在 2020 年初曾短暂超过三星成为全球智能手机发货量第一，但自 2021 年以来已跌出全球前五名。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huawei has dropped out of the global top five since 2021，其中主语是Huawei，谓语是has dropped out，宾语是the global top five。which briefly surpassed Samsung to lead global smartphone shipments in early 2020是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰Huawei，表示华为在 2020 年初曾短暂超过三星成为全球智能手机发货量第一。这个句子的意思是说，华为在 2020 年初曾短暂超过三星成为全球智能手机发货量第一，但自 2021 年以来已跌出全球前五名。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Huawei had tried to launch both premium and affordable smartphones in Korea since 2014, but it has been unable to gain ground “largely due to local operators’ preference for Samsung,” said Woody Oh, service director at TechInsights. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间点之前已经完成，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示华为自 2014 年以来一直试图在韩国推出高端和价格适中的智能手机，但由于当地运营商更青睐三星，因此未能取得进展。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Huawei is unlikely to gain ground in the South Korean smartphone market, which is dominated by Samsung and Apple, analysts say</li>
<li>The Chinese firm’s new cloud division in the country is eyeing business from the local tech and entertainment industries</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/d6d72751-e72c-48a7-a6f8-b7bfee2bdd85_b0324fe1.jpg" /><figcaption>Huawei is trying to expand its cloud business in South Korea. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>Chinese telecommunications equipment giant Huawei Technologies is poised to make a comeback in the global smartphone market this year, but in South Korea, the company must contend with the lingering impact of US sanctions and intense competition with international and local rivals, according to industry watchers.</p><p>Huawei is forecast to move into the spotlight in the smartphone industry in 2024, with projected double-digit growth in global shipments, according to a report published last week by research firm TechInsights, which described the Chinese company as a potential “big surprise”.</p><p>But in Korea – home to smartphone and semiconductor titan Samsung Electronics – Huawei is struggling to expand its market share or secure trust from local partners amid the US-China tech rivalry, analysts said.</p><p>The Shenzhen-based company, which has been offering various products and services to Korean customers for two decades, has been effectively absent from the country’s smartphone market in the past few years due to its “inability to source 5G chipsets”, said Abhilash Kumar, an analyst at TechInsights.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/425f24ee-d4dd-4d9c-94ca-0de11642cc70_34f54c2a.jpg" title="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“South Korea’s smartphone market is 5G-heavy, with a 5G penetration of more than 95 per cent for 2023, so it made little sense for consumers to buy Huawei’s 4G-powered phones,” he said.</p><p>Since 2019, Washington has barred the Chinese company, on national security grounds, from accessing US technologies including Google’s most popular apps, which are commonly pre-installed in Android phones sold by rivals like Samsung. That has dealt a heavy blow to Huawei’s overseas sales.</p><p>Huawei, which briefly surpassed Samsung to lead global smartphone shipments in early 2020, has dropped out of the global top five since 2021. Last year, the world’s five biggest smartphone vendors were Apple, Samsung, Xiaomi, Transsion and Vivo, according to a report published on Monday by research firm IDC.</p><p>In Korea, Huawei had a market share of just 0.1 per cent as of December, far lagging Samsung’s 68.7 per cent and Apple’s 26.5 per cent, numbers from online database Statcounter showed.</p><p>Huawei made a splash in its home market China last August with the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233636/huaweis-mate-60-pro-will-help-it-take-lost-ground-china-can-it-help-smartphone-giant-regain-global" target="_self" title="">surprise launch of the Mate 60 Pro</a> handset equipped with an advanced, domestically-developed 5G chip. The company is reportedly aiming to bring its handsets back to some overseas markets, including in Europe.</p><p>Still, “it looks unlikely” that the firm would return to the Korean smartphone market, Kumar said.</p><p>“Now that Huawei might have managed to source 5G chipsets locally,” he said. “It’s still difficult for it because [South Korea] is Samsung- and Apple-heavy and doesn’t have much acceptance for Chinese vendors.”</p><p>Huawei has tried to launch both premium and affordable smartphones in Korea since 2014, but it has been unable to gain ground “largely due to local operators’ preference for Samsung,” said Woody Oh, service director at TechInsights. “To be successful in the Korean market, [manufacturers] must seek operators’ support.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Customers at an Apple store in Hanam, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/b995137c-2916-4199-9a6d-622ad91aadb4_a66cec46.jpg" title="Customers at an Apple store in Hanam, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Customers at an Apple store in Hanam, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Amid difficulties in the consumer market, Huawei is pinning its hopes on enterprise services, according to Wang Balian, CEO of Huawei Korea.</p><p>The Huawei-supported 5G network used by Korean carriers ranked first in global tests last year, Wang said at a year-end event in Seoul last month. The company’s enterprise products include data centre networks, campus networks and storage services.</p><p>Wang said the company was also expanding its foothold in the cloud computing market, having established a cloud division in Korea last year in hope of serving the information technology and cultural entertainment industries.</p><p>The executive highlighted Huawei’s commitment to the Korean market despite running into controversies last year, when SK Hynix – the second-largest memory chip maker in Korea – announced it was investigating how its products ended up in the Mate 60 Pro.</p><p>Hynix said at the time that it “no longer does business with Huawei since the introduction of the US restrictions against the company”.</p><p>One of Huawei’s key business partners in Korea is LG Electronics. Wang called LG Uplus, South Korea’s third-largest mobile carrier and the country’s sole mobile network operator using Huawei’s 5G base stations, has been touted as one of the Chinese firm’s “important global clients”.</p><p>Looking to 2024, Wang said Huawei Korea, which has more than 230 employees, planned to help the country achieve its digitisation and carbon neutrality goals, while continuing to support the cultivation of 1,000 next-generation information technology professionals.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Should we let AI take over mundane work? Not so fast</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3248614/should-we-let-ai-take-over-mundane-work-not-so-fast</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In the age of generative AI (like ChatGPT), companies and schools must carefully consider how to deploy AI to enhance productivity without hindering learning and skill development. Generative AI can outperform humans in tasks such as answering patient questions or generating content. However, it has limitations, such as producing incorrect results due to insufficient training or biases. Outsourcing tasks to AI can lead to a decline in human productivity, as seen in a study on Python maintainers after the introduction of a bug bounty program. This occurred because the maintainers had less motivation to perform tasks that were no longer rewarded and lost opportunities for inter-task learning. This suggests that using generative AI may come at the cost of sacrificing essential learning and skill development in the long term.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Generative AI and its impact on learning versus work output.</li>    <li>Theme: The importance of balancing productivity gains from generative AI with the potential loss of learning and skill development, especially in educational settings.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The authors advocate for a careful approach to generative AI in organizations and schools, prioritizing learning over work outcomes and considering the interrelated nature of tasks to mitigate the risk of diminishing human capabilities.</li>    <li>Main information: Research findings on the negative impact of outsourcing bug reporting to a crowdsourcing program on Python maintainers' productivity; suggestions for managing generative AI use in organizations and schools to prevent erosion of human capabilities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在生成式人工智能（如ChatGPT）时代，公司和学校必须慎重考虑如何部署人工智能以提高生产力，而不妨碍学习和技能发展。生成式人工智能在诸如回答患者问题或生成内容等任务方面优于人类。然而，它也有局限性，例如由于培训不足或偏见而产生不正确的结果。将任务外包给人工智能可能会导致人类生产力下降，正如在引入赏金计划后对Python维护者的研究中所见。这是因为维护人员对不再获得奖励的任务的积极性降低，且失去了进行跨任务学习的机会。这表明，从长期来看，使用生成式人工智能可能会以牺牲基本学习和技能发展为代价。  <ul>    <li>摘要：生成式人工智能及其对学习与工作产出的影响。</li>    <li>主题：平衡生成式人工智能带来的生产力提升与潜在的学习和技能发展损失，尤其是在教育环境中，这一重要性。</li>    <li>观点：作者提倡在组织和学校中谨慎使用生成式人工智能，优先考虑学习而非工作成果，并考虑任务的相互关联性，以降低损害人类能力的风险。</li>    <li>主要信息：关于将错误报告外包给众包程序对Python维护人员生产力的负面影响的研究结果；关于在组织和学校中管理生成式人工智能的使用以防止人类能力丧失的建议。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>intertwined (adj.) - /ˌɪntəˈtwaɪnd/ 交织在一起，盘绕在一起。    <p>原文例句：We might wish to discourage AI’s use for deeply intertwined tasks.    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由inter-（相互）和twined（缠绕）构成的，表示“交织在一起，盘绕在一起”。在这个例句中，它指的是AI不应该被用于深度交织的任务，即相互关联的任务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>detriment (n.) - /ˈdɛtrɪm(ə)nt/ 损害，危害。    <p>原文例句：The short-term gain in productivity could be offset by the long-term loss in capability.    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁文，由de-（消除）和tritus（磨损）组成，表示“损害，危害”。在这个例句中，它指的是短期的生产力提高可能会被长期能力的丧失所抵消。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：We might wish to discourage AI’s use for deeply intertwined tasks. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示我们可能希望阻止AI用于深度交织的任务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>This inter-task learning side-effect is illuminating. It suggests that learning and other capabilities may be sacrificed when we enjoy the power and convenience of generative AI. - 这种跨任务学习的副作用令人警醒。这表明，当我们享受生成式人工智能的力量和便利时，可能会牺牲学习和其他能力。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是It suggests that learning and other capabilities may be sacrificed，其中主语是It，谓语是suggests，宾语是that learning and other capabilities may be sacrificed。This inter-task learning side-effect is illuminating是一个主语从句，修饰主句，表示这种跨任务学习的副作用令人警醒。when we enjoy the power and convenience of generative AI是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示当我们享受生成式人工智能的力量和便利时。这个句子的意思是说，当我们享受生成式人工智能的力量和便利时，可能会牺牲学习和其他能力，这种跨任务学习的副作用令人警醒。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：Generative AI tools may be better deployed for tasks that have little relation to other tasks. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子采用了被动语态，将宾语Generative AI tools置于句首，并使用助动词may be和过去分词deployed来表示动作或状态是由Generative AI tools承受的。这种语态通常用于强调动作或状态的承受者，或当动作或状态的执行者不重要或未知时。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>非限制性定语从句 - 表示对先行词的进一步解释或说明，从句与先行词之间用逗号隔开。    <p>原文例句：The short-term gain in productivity could be offset by the long-term loss in capability, which is key to our contribution to future tasks.    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中的定语从句which is key to our contribution to future tasks是用来解释或说明先行词the long-term loss in capability的，所以它是非限制性定语从句。非限制性定语从句与先行词之间用逗号隔开，并且从句中通常包含重要的信息，如果去掉从句，句子的意思就会发生改变。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>It may seem that outsourcing tasks to generative AI like ChatGPT could increase productivity</li>
<li>However, it might actually limit the supplementary learning that occurs when people do certain tasks, so AI must be deployed with care</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/5a7e78e1-6d56-4263-b127-4cf22193c5c2_b285be82.jpg" /><figcaption>After the public gained access to OpenAI’s chatbot, which can create human-like written responses to simple user prompts, in November 2022, it shifted how people think about artificial intelligence. Photo: TNS</figcaption></figure><p>Generative artificial intelligence, especially OpenAI’s implementation of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243449/chatgpt-one-year-how-openais-chatbot-brought-generative-artificial-intelligence-public-consciousness" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT,</a> has opened up new possibilities for the creation of intelligent content. In fact, AI-generated content is so good that it reads almost as if it was written by a human being.</p><p>For example, a study by researchers from US universities published in May found that when answering random patient questions from a social media platform, ChatGPT outperformed physicians in terms of both quality of information and empathy. And OpenAI has a said GPT4, the state-of-the-art model underlying ChatGPT Plus, could score in the top 10 per cent in the SAT reading exam for college admissions, the GRE verbal test for graduate school admissions and the uniform bar exam for lawyers.</p><p>This tool is expected to be deployed in companies and other organisations to enhance worker productivity. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3227884/chatgpt-helps-hong-kong-students-critical-thinking-teachers-stay-ahead-human-touch" target="_self" title="">Schools and teachers</a> are also keen to embrace it. Many universities now <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3233269/hong-kong-universities-relent-rise-chatgpt-ai-tools-teaching-and-assignments-keep-eye-out-plagiarism" target="_self" title="">allow students</a> to use generative AI in course work and assignments. Some local institutions offer free access to ChatGPT, encouraging students to use it in school.</p><p>However, generative AI has its limitations. Because the content it produces is generated from a complex large-language model instead of logically developed and based on facts, AI sometimes “hallucinates”, that is, produces incorrect or misleading results, due to insufficient training data, bias and incorrect assumptions. In June, two lawyers in the US <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223490/us-lawyer-sorry-after-chatgpt-creates-fake-cases" target="_self" title="">were sanctioned</a> for using ChatGPT to produce a legal brief with fictitious case citations. They claimed they weren’t aware ChatGPT could make up cases.</p><p>This case raises an important question: how does generative AI affect human capability when people no longer need to develop logical arguments and verify facts when creating content?</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Using generative AI to produce work is akin to outsourcing it to other people. Thus, we can infer its impact on human capability by referencing outsourcing.</p><p>We conducted research on how contributions to the well-known programming language, Python, changed after the introduction of a crowdsourcing program called Internet Bug Bounty (IBB), which rewards people for finding security vulnerabilities in open source software – but excludes the official system maintainers, who have been reporting and fixing bugs, and making enhancements, from the reward.</p><p>The IBB program should have made the Python maintainers’ job easier, giving them more time to perform other tasks and hence increasing their productivity in those tasks.</p><p>Interestingly, we found the opposite. The official Python maintainers not only discovered fewer bugs after the IBB program, they also made fewer enhancements to Python. This means their overall productivity fell after bug reporting was outsourced.</p><p>We looked at many reasons for the drop in productivity, including a loss of motivation due to not being rewarded in the IBB program. We concluded that it was mainly due to a lack of inter-task learning. There was a bigger drop in productivity among Python maintainers who reported more bugs before the IBB program than those who reported fewer. The drop was also bigger when the bug reporting and enhancement tasks were more closely related.</p><p>We surveyed a number of Python maintainers, most of whom said that finding vulnerabilities helped them learn and gain ideas for how to enhance the program. This implies that when performing a task, we not only contribute to the outcome, we learn at the same time.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Internet Bug Bounty program, which rewards people for identifying security vulnerabilities in open source software, should have helped increase the productivity of those whose job it is to find and fix bugs, but that has not necessarily happened. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1021" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/d1810c19-5739-4f42-8dda-8bdb3366e566_50b374a4.jpg" title="The Internet Bug Bounty program, which rewards people for identifying security vulnerabilities in open source software, should have helped increase the productivity of those whose job it is to find and fix bugs, but that has not necessarily happened. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Internet Bug Bounty program, which rewards people for identifying security vulnerabilities in open source software, should have helped increase the productivity of those whose job it is to find and fix bugs, but that has not necessarily happened. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>This inter-task learning side-effect is illuminating. It suggests that learning and other capabilities may be sacrificed when we enjoy the power and convenience of generative AI. The short-term gain in productivity could be offset by the long-term loss in capability. Worse, this capability may be key to our contribution to future tasks, including, possibly, intelligent knowledge work.</p><p>So how should generative AI use be managed in an organisation? First, distinguish between objectives – are we seeking work output or learning and training? In most places, work output may be the priority, so it would be reasonable to actively deploy generative AI tools. Even so, we must be aware this may slow employees’ learning of how to perform tasks.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3247902/how-ai-development-fostered-digital-sweatshop-and-why-it-matters-technologys-future" title="">How AI development has fostered a digital ‘sweatshop’ in poor countries</a></h3><p>Second, start classifying tasks by nature, in terms of whether they are interrelated. Generative AI tools may be better deployed for tasks that have little relation to other tasks, for example, pure automation jobs. We might wish to discourage AI’s use for deeply intertwined tasks.</p><p>Third, more training should be provided once generative AI is deployed. People are intrinsically lazy. If we let them use generative AI without supplementing it with learning opportunities, their ability may deteriorate over time.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>At school, the priority should be learning rather than work output. We must seek to prevent the unrestrained use of generative AI in homework or assignments. If students don’t do homework themselves but outsource it entirely to AI, they may soon lose the ability to reason, innovate and produce more advanced knowledge.</p><p>We must revisit the common question, “Why waste time doing mundane work when AI can do it for us?” This is a dangerous sentiment because we do work not only to produce an outcome, but to learn as well. Such learning builds the foundation for future knowledge production.</p><p>We should not get carried away by generative AI, thinking that only work outcomes matter. The learning itself is equally important, if not more so.</p><p><strong>Kai-Lung Hui is Elman Family Professor of Business and senior associate dean at Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Business School</strong></p><p><strong>Jiali Zhou is an assistant professor at the American University in Washington DC</strong></p><p><strong>The views expressed here are the authors’ own</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Davos 2024: OpenAI CEO Altman, Time owner Benioff disagree on AI’s use of copyrighted content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248702/davos-2024-openai-ceo-altman-time-owner-benioff-disagree-ais-use-copyrighted-content</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Salesforce首席执行官兼时代杂志所有者马克·贝尼奥夫表示，人工智能公司应该标准化对内容创作者的付款，以公平对待他们。OpenAI首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼说，训练数据通常不像其所有者认为的那样有价值。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: AI companies should standardize payments to treat content creators fairly.</li>    <li>Theme: The issue of AI companies using copyrighted data without fair compensation for content creators.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Marc Benioff's criticism of AI companies for exploiting content creators; OpenAI's CEO Sam Altman's response and his view on the value of training data.</li>    <li>Main information: Benioff's accusation of data theft by AI companies; ongoing negotiations between publications and ChatGPT maker OpenAI for licensing; OpenAI's partnerships for specific uses of news content; Benioff's concerns about social media's risks to the democratic process.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Salesforce首席执行官兼时代杂志所有者马克·贝尼奥夫表示，人工智能公司窃取知识产权来构建他们的技术。包括时代与纽约时报在内的媒体的内容出现在人工智能公司的结果中，他说。生成人工智能服务（如 ChatGPT）的大型语言模型的制造商因为使用受版权保护的材料而受到越来越多的审查。贝尼奥夫的时代杂志是目前正在与 ChatGPT 制造商 OpenAI 谈判以授权其新闻作品的出版物之一，彭博社首次报道。其他公司包括华纳兄弟探索公司的 CNN 和福克斯。纽约时报于去年 11 月起诉 OpenAI 及其合作伙伴微软，理由是未经许可使用该出版物的文章。萨姆·阿尔特曼于周一在达沃斯举行的OpenAI首席执行官说，“没有人真正确切地知道”这些数据的一个公平价格是多少，但人工智能公司应该标准化付款以公平对待内容创作者。Benioff 的 Salesforce 将其人工智能驱动的软件功能推销为包括“信任层”，以防止滥用客户数据。OpenAI 否认未经许可使用受保护的材料。首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼周二早些时候接受彭博社采访时表示，训练数据通常不如其所有者认为的那么有价值。“我们不想训练纽约时报的数据，”阿尔特曼说，并补充说，研究更侧重于从少量高质量数据中学习。他说，应该有可能避免任何新闻内容的限制。OpenAI 一直在就新闻内容的特定用途达成合作伙伴关系，并且还有更多内容即将推出，阿尔特曼说。“我认为会有很棒的新方法来消费和货币化新闻。”7 月，OpenAI 与美联社签署协议，以访问部分新闻社的档案。OpenAI 还于 12 月与 Axel Springer 达成了一项为期三年的协议，以未披露的金额使用这家德国媒体公司的作品。当被问及人工智能是否会在许多国家的大选年中给民主进程带来风险时，贝尼奥夫表示，他最大的担忧仍然是社交媒体。“监管机构没有履行他们的职责，”他补充道。  <ul>    <li>摘要：人工智能公司应标准化支付以公平对待内容创作者。</li>    <li>主题：人工智能公司使用受版权保护的数据而不对内容创作者进行公平补偿的问题。</li>    <li>观点：马克·贝尼奥夫批评人工智能公司利用内容创作者；OpenAI 首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼的回应以及他对比遍历数据价值的看法。</li>    <li>主要信息：贝尼奥夫指责人工智能公司窃取数据；出版物与 ChatGPT 制造商 OpenAI 之间正在进行的许可谈判；OpenAI 用于特定新闻内容用途的合作伙伴关系；贝尼奥夫担心社交媒体对民主进程的风险。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ripped off (phr. v.) - 窃取，剽窃。    <p>原文例句：Marc Benioff, the Salesforce chief executive who also owns Time magazine, said artificial intelligence (AI) companies ripped off intellectual property to build their technology.    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指窃取或剽窃他人的创意、作品或财产。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能公司窃取知识产权来构建他们的技术。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>scrutiny (n.) - 仔细检查，审查。    <p>原文例句：There is increasing scrutiny on the makers of large language models that power generative AI services, such as ChatGPT, over their use of copyrighted materials.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是指仔细检查或审查某事或某人。在这个例句中，它表示人们对生成人工智能服务的制造商，如 ChatGPT，使用受版权保护的材料进行越来越多的审查。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>monetise (v.) - 货币化，使货币化。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI CEO Sam Altman says training data often is not as valuable as its owners think it is.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是指将某物转化为货币或使其具有货币价值。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼表示，训练数据通常不如其所有者认为的那么有价值。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fair price - 合理的价格。    <P>原文例句：“Nobody really exactly knows” what a fair price for this data is, Benioff added, but AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly.    </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指对某物或服务来说合理或适当的价格。在这个例句中，它表示贝尼奥夫补充说，“没有人真正确切地知道”这些数据的一个公平价格是多少，但人工智能公司应该标准化付款以公平对待内容创作者。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>pay for - 付费购买。    <P>原文例句：If you get fired then I will get fired.     </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由pay（支付）和for（为了）构成的，表示“为了某物而支付”。在这个例句中，它表示如果你被解雇，那么我也会被解雇。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Marc Benioff, the Salesforce chief executive who also owns Time magazine, said artificial intelligence (AI) companies ripped off intellectual property to build their technology. - Salesforce 首席执行官兼时代杂志所有者马克·贝尼奥夫表示，人工智能 (AI) 公司窃取知识产权来构建他们的技术。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Marc Benioff said，其中主语是Marc Benioff，谓语是said，宾语是AI companies ripped off intellectual property to build their technology。who also owns Time magazine是一个定语从句，修饰主语Marc Benioff，表示马克·贝尼奥夫也是时代杂志的所有者。这个句子的意思是说，Salesforce 首席执行官兼时代杂志所有者马克·贝尼奥夫表示，人工智能 (AI) 公司窃取知识产权来构建他们的技术。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>一般现在时 - 表示现在正在发生或存在的状态或动作。    <p>原文例句：Salesforce markets its AI-powered software features as including a “trust layer” to prevent the misuse of customer data.</p>    <p>语法讲解：一般现在时态表示现在正在发生或存在的状态或动作，其结构是：主语 + be + 现在分词。be动词要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。在这个例句中，be动词是markets，表示Salesforce正在销售其人工智能驱动的软件功能。现在分词是including，表示包括一个“信任层”。这个句子的意思是说，Salesforce 将其人工智能驱动的软件功能推销为包括一个“信任层”，以防止滥用客户数据。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：When asked whether AI presented risks to the democratic process in an election year for many countries, Benioff said his biggest concern is still social media.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或已经完成的动作或状态，其结构是：主语 + have/has + 过去分词。have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去  <ul><li>AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly, says Salesforce CEO and Time owner Marc Benioff</li>
<li>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman says training data often is not as valuable as its owners think it is</li>
</ul><p>Marc Benioff, the Salesforce chief executive who also owns Time magazine, said artificial intelligence (AI) companies ripped off intellectual property to build their technology.</p><p>“All the training data has been stolen,” Benioff said on Tuesday in an interview at Bloomberg House at the World Economic Forum in Davos. Content from media outlets including Time and The New York Times surfaces in results from AI companies, he said.</p><p>There is increasing scrutiny on the makers of large language models that power generative AI services, such as ChatGPT, over their use of copyrighted materials. Benioff’s Time is among publications currently negotiating with ChatGPT maker OpenAI to license their news work, as first reported by Bloomberg.</p><p>Other companies include Warner Bros Discovery’s CNN and Fox. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3246432/new-york-times-sues-chatgpt-maker-openai-microsoft-copyright-infringement-unlawful-use-stories-train" target="_self" title="">The New York Times sued OpenAI</a> and its partner Microsoft in November for using the publication’s articles without permission.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/256a3cae-17dc-4815-bfb6-2b8f632dd1af_a66cec46.jpg" title="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Nobody really exactly knows” what a fair price for this data is, Benioff added, but AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly. Benioff’s Salesforce markets its AI-powered software features as including a “trust layer” to prevent the misuse of customer data.</p><p>OpenAI has disputed that it used protected material without permission. CEO Sam Altman, in an interview earlier on Tuesday with Bloomberg, said training data often is not as valuable as its owners think it is.</p><p>“We do not want to train on The New York Times data,” Altman said, adding that research is more focused on learning from small amounts of high-quality data. It should be possible to avoid any news content that is off limits, he said.</p><p>OpenAI has been striking partnerships for specific uses of news content and more are coming, Altman said. “I think there’s going to be great new ways to consume and monetise news.”</p><p>In July, OpenAI signed an agreement with the Associated Press to access some of the news agency’s archives. OpenAI also reached <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content" target="_self" title="">a three-year deal in December with Axel Springer</a> to use the German media company’s work for an undisclosed sum.</p><p>When asked whether AI presented risks to the democratic process in an election year for many countries, Benioff said his biggest concern is still social media. “Regulators have not done their job,” he added.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Davos 2024: Microsoft CEO ‘comfortable’ with OpenAI non-profit board structure despite Altman ousting</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248699/davos-2024-microsoft-ceo-comfortable-openai-non-profit-board-structure-despite-altman-ousting</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Satya Nadella, CEO of Microsoft, expressed that he has no concerns regarding OpenAI's governance structure. This statement came following the temporary dismissal of OpenAI's CEO, Sam Altman, and subsequent reinstatement. The non-profit board of OpenAI aims to ensure the development of powerful artificial intelligence (AI) that benefits humanity. Meanwhile, Microsoft's partnership with OpenAI is currently under scrutiny by competition authorities in Europe, Britain, and the United States.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella's stance on OpenAI's governance structure and the ongoing scrutiny of their partnership.</li>    <li>Theme: Satya Nadella's perspective on the governance structure of OpenAI and Microsoft's role in its development.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The potential impact of the Microsoft-OpenAI partnership on competition and the scrutiny it faces.</li>    <li>Main information: Nadella's comfort with OpenAI's governance structure; OpenAI's reinstatement of CEO Sam Altman; ongoing scrutiny of the Microsoft-OpenAI partnership by competition authorities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  微软首席执行官萨提亚·纳德拉表示，他对 OpenAI 的治理结构没有任何问题。这一表态是在 OpenAI 首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼被暂时免职并随后复职之后做出的。OpenAI 的非营利董事会旨在确保发展有利于人类的强大人工智能 (AI)。与此同时，微软与 OpenAI 的合作关系目前正受到欧洲、英国和美国竞争当局的审查。  <ul>    <li>摘要：微软首席执行官萨提亚·纳德拉对 OpenAI 治理结构的立场以及对其合作关系的持续审查。</li>    <li>主题：萨提亚·纳德拉对 OpenAI 治理结构的看法以及微软在其中发挥的作用。</li>    <li>观点：微软与 OpenAI 合作关系对竞争的潜在影响及其面临的审查。</li>    <li>主要信息：纳德拉对 OpenAI 治理结构的满意度；OpenAI 恢复萨姆·阿尔特曼为首席执行官；竞争当局对微软与 OpenAI 合作关系的持续审查。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>governance (n.) - /ˈgʌvənəns/ 治理，管理。    <p>原文例句：The surprise November dismissal of OpenAI’s CEO Sam Altman over an alleged communication breakdown triggered a crisis at the start-up behind ChatGPT, in which employees threatened to resign en masse and go work for Microsoft, which is backing OpenAI with billions of dollars.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由govern（统治，管理）和-ance（状态，行为）组成，表示“管理，治理”。在这个例句中，它指的是OpenAI的治理结构，即该公司如何管理和运营。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>ultimately (adv.) - /ˈʌltɪmətli/ 最终，最后。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI’s board, charged with protecting the start-up non-profit’s mission to develop powerful artificial intelligence that benefits humanity, ultimately restored Altman days later and now is in the process of filling out its membership.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由ultimus（最后一个）和-ly（方式，程度）组成，表示“最后，最终”。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI的董事会最终恢复了阿尔特曼的职务，并正在补充其成员。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>scrutiny (n.) - /ˈskruːtɪni/ 审查，仔细检查。    <p>原文例句：Competition authorities in Europe, Britain and reportedly the United States have started looking closely at the Microsoft-OpenAI relationship.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由scrutor（检查者）和-y（状态，行为）组成，表示“审查，仔细检查”。在这个例句中，它指的是竞争当局对微软与 OpenAI 关系的审查。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>have no issue with - 对……没有问题。    <p>原文例句：“I’m comfortable. I have no issues with any structure,” Nadella said at a Bloomberg News event on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum’s annual meeting in Davos.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由have（有），no（没有），issue（问题）和with（与）组成的，表示“对……没有问题”。在这个例句中，它表示纳德拉对OpenAI的治理结构没有问题。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>go look at - 去看看。    <p>原文例句：Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg“We’ll go look at it from all angles,” he said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由go（去），look at（看看）组成的，表示“去看看”。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI的首席执行官阿尔特曼说他们会从各个角度去看看OpenAI的治理结构。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Competition authorities in Europe, Britain and reportedly the United States have started looking closely at the Microsoft-OpenAI relationship. - 据报道，欧洲、英国和美国的竞争当局已开始密切关注微软与 OpenAI 的关系。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Competition authorities have started looking closely at the Microsoft-OpenAI relationship，其中主语是Competition authorities，谓语是have started looking closely，宾语是the Microsoft-OpenAI relationship。in Europe, Britain and reportedly the United States是一个地点状语，表示欧洲、英国和美国这些地方。据报道，是一个状语，表示这句话的内容是据报道的。这个句子的意思是说，据报道，欧洲、英国和美国的竞争当局已开始密切关注微软与 OpenAI 的关系。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft’s investments in computing power and years-old bet on OpenAI before its ChatGPT fame, Nadella said, were a “highly risky bet” and “not all conventional wisdom”.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是英语中的一种时态，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。结构是：have/has + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词。在这个例句中，它表示微软在计算能力方面的投资以及在ChatGPT流行之前对OpenAI的多年押注，纳德拉说，这是一个“高风险的赌注”，而且“并非所有人都认同的常规智慧”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Satya Nadella, speaking on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum’s meeting in Davos, says he has ‘no issues with any structure’ at OpenAI</li>
<li>The fact that Microsoft does not fully own OpenAI distinguished their deal in a pro-competitive way, according to Nadella</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/82fe2885-0760-4ede-8a50-6e322e78b818_940b6a88.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella at the World Economic Forum annual meeting in Davos, Switzerland on Tuesday. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella on Tuesday said he had no issue with partner OpenAI’s governance structure, two months after the start-up’s non-profit board temporarily ousted its chief executive without regard to investors’ interests.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3241992/chatgpt-maker-open-ai-pushes-out-co-founder-and-ceo-sam-altman-says-he-wasnt-consistently-candid" target="_self" title="">surprise November dismissal</a> of OpenAI’s CEO Sam Altman over an alleged communication breakdown triggered a crisis at the start-up behind ChatGPT, in which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242258/nearly-all-openai-staff-threaten-go-microsoft-unless-board-quits-investors-try-bring-back-altman" target="_self" title="">employees threatened to resign en masse</a> and go work for Microsoft, which is backing OpenAI with billions of dollars.</p><p>“I’m comfortable. I have no issues with any structure,” Nadella said at a Bloomberg News event on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum’s annual meeting in Davos.</p><p>OpenAI’s board, charged with protecting the start-up non-profit’s mission to develop powerful artificial intelligence that benefits humanity, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242394/microsoft-pushes-changes-openai-after-board-start-sought-merger-rival-anthropic" target="_self" title="">ultimately restored Altman</a> days later and now is in the process of filling out its membership.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1309" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/0651d6dd-f234-47b6-97b5-741fcb1f1268_28052076.jpg" title="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“I expect us to make a lot of progress on that in the coming months,” OpenAI CEO Altman said at a later Bloomberg event in Davos. “And then after that, the new board will take a look at the governance structure.”</p><p>“We’ll go look at it from all angles,” he said.</p><p>Microsoft has now secured a non-voting observer position on the OpenAI board.</p><p>Competition authorities in Europe, Britain and reportedly the United States have started looking closely at the Microsoft-OpenAI relationship. Their agreement guarantees the Windows maker large chunks of the start-up’s profits depending on certain conditions, a person briefed on the terms has said.</p><p>According to Nadella, the fact that Microsoft does not fully own OpenAI distinguished their deal in a pro-competitive way.</p><p>“Partnerships is one avenue of, in fact, having competition,” he said.</p><p>Microsoft’s investments in computing power and years-old bet on OpenAI before its ChatGPT fame, Nadella said, were a “highly risky bet” and “not all conventional wisdom”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with widening iPhone discounts, but rival Huawei stays above the fray</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  JD.com offers higher discounts on iPhone 15 than Apple in China’s intensifying price war. Apple became the top global smartphone vendor in 2023, dethroning Samsung. Chinese smartphone vendors like Xiaomi and Honor provide discounts on their Android models. Huawei’s Mate 60 Pro 5G faces supply shortage but remains popular despite US sanctions. Worsening demand for smartphones led to a 30% decline in iPhone sales and a 3% decrease in Apple’s market share in mainland China.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Price competition in China's smartphone market, Apple's rise as a global leader, and Huawei's comeback amid US sanctions</li>    <li>Theme: Market dynamics and challenges in the smartphone industry in China and globally</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Apple's aggressive pricing strategy in China, the diversification of Android brands, and Huawei's resilience despite restrictions</li>    <li>Main Information: iPhone discounts by JD.com and Apple, declining iPhone sales in China, Huawei's return to the premium segment, and challenges faced by Huawei</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  京东在中国的iPhone 15降价幅度高于苹果公司，引发了激烈的价格战。苹果公司成为2023年全球第一大智能手机厂商，取代了三星。小米、 荣耀等中国手机厂商对旗下安卓机型进行降价。华为Mate 60 Pro 5G手机因供应短缺，但尽管受到美国制裁，仍然很受欢迎。智能手机需求恶化导致iPhone在中国的销量下降了30%，苹果的市场份额下降了3%。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国智能手机市场的价格竞争、苹果成为全球领导者以及华为在美国制裁中复出</li>    <li>主题：中国和全球智能手机行业市场动态和挑战</li>    <li>观点：苹果在中国市场激进的定价策略、安卓品牌的差异化以及华为在面临制裁情况下表现出的韧性</li>    <li>主要信息：京东和苹果的iPhone降价、在中国下降的iPhone销量、华为重返高端市场以及华为面临的挑战</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tout (v.) - /taʊt/ 大力宣扬，宣传。    <p>原文例句：Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com on Monday touted deeper discounts of as much as 800 yuan (US$112.24) off on the latest iPhone 15 model in a post on WeChat.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源于中古英语“touten”，意为“吹嘘，夸耀”。在这个例句中，它是“大力宣扬，宣传”的意思，说明京东在微信上大力宣扬iPhone 15最高降价800元。</p></li>  </ul><ul>    <li>shipment (n.) - /ˈʃɪpmənt/ 货物装运，货运。    <p>原文例句：Apple topped global smartphone shipments in 2023 to unseat long-standing market leader Samsung, according to research firm IDC.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源于中古英语“shipment”，意为“装载，装船”。在这个例句中，它是“货物装运，货运”的意思，说明苹果公司在2023年全球智能手机出货量方面超过了长期占据市场领导地位的三星。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>mark down (v.) - /mɑːk daʊn/ 以较低的价格出售，打折出售。    <p>原文例句：The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由两个词构成：“mark”表示“标记，做记号”，“down”表示“向下，降低”。在这个例句中，它是“以较低的价格出售，打折出售”的意思，说明各大中国智能手机厂商都在网上和线下零售活动中对旗下的安卓手机进行降价。</p></li>  </ul><ul>    <li>fierce (adj.) - /fɪərs/ 激烈的，猛烈的。    <p>原文例句：A price war in mainland China, the world’s largest smartphone market, has intensified amid widening discounts offered for iPhones by online marketplaces.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源于拉丁语“ferox”，意为“野蛮的，残忍的”。在这个例句中，它是“激烈的，猛烈的”的意思，说明在中国大陆这个全球最大的智能手机市场，随着网络市场上iPhone的折扣力度加大，价格战变得更加激烈。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unseat (v.) - /ˌʌnˈsiːt/ 使失去座位，使下台。    <p>原文例句：Apple topped global smartphone shipments in 2023 to unseat long-standing market leader Samsung, according to research firm IDC.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源于拉丁语“unseat”，意为“赶出，驱逐”。在这个例句中，它是“使失去座位，使下台”的意思，说明苹果公司在2023年全球智能手机出货量方面超过了长期占市场领导地位的三星。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>make a comeback (v.) - /meɪk ə ˈkʌmbæk/ 东山再起，复出。    <p>原文例句：“Huawei is back and making inroads quickly within China.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由两个动词“make”和“comeback”构成，“make”表示“使，造成”，“comeback”表示“复出，卷土重来”。在这个例句中，它是“东山再起，复出”的意思，说明华为在中国市场复出并迅速发展。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns.</li>    <p>句子分析：这个复合句由两个并列分句组成，第一个分句是“The latest iPhone markdowns have come”，第二个分句是“major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns”。第一个分句的主语是“The latest iPhone markdowns”，谓语是“have come”，宾语是“as major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns”。第二个分句的主语是“major Chinese smartphone vendors”，谓语是“knocked down”，宾语是“prices on their various Android handsets”。“both online and offline retail campaigns”是介词短语，作地点状语，修饰“knocked down”。这个句子的意思是：各大中国智能手机厂商都在网上和线下零售活动中对旗下的安卓手机进行降价，导致最新款iPhone的降价活动也随之而来。</p> </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由分词和其宾语、补语或状语构成的短语，在句中作定语、状语或表语。    <p>原文例句：Apple topped global smartphone shipments in 2023 to dethrone long-standing market leader Samsung.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中包含了一个分词短语“to dethrone long-standing market leader Samsung”，其中“to dethrone”是动词原形，“long-standing market leader Samsung”是宾语。这个分词短语作目的状语，表示苹果公司在2023年全球智能手机出货量方面超过三星的目的是为了取代三星长期以来的市场领导地位。</p></li>  </ul><ul>    <li>并列分句 - 由两个或两个以上结构相同或相似的分句并列组合而成的句子。    <p>原文例句：The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子由两个并列分句组成，第一个分句是“The latest iPhone markdowns have come”，第二个分句是“major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns”。这两个分句在结构上相同，都有主语、谓语和宾语。它们之间用“as”连接，表示因果关系  <ul><li>Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com on Monday touted discounts of as much as US$112 off on the iPhone 15, higher than Apple’s own local price markdown</li>
<li>Apple topped global smartphone shipments in 2023 to unseat long-standing market leader Samsung, according to research firm IDC</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/66dac82e-619d-4ada-b6cc-c633141a8133_2a932251.jpg" /><figcaption>The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>A price war in mainland China, the world’s largest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> market, has intensified amid widening discounts offered for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhones</a> by online marketplaces, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> unseated rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> in annual industry shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023.</p><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> on Monday touted deeper discounts of as much as 800 yuan (US$112.24) off on the latest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3235981/apple-iphone-15-review-faster-cheaper-new-standard-models-are-big-jump-over-their-predecessors" target="_self" title="">iPhone 15</a> model in a post on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a>, which was on the same day <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248529/apples-china-price-cuts-iphones-macbooks-cancel-out-pressure-rivals-chasing-premium-segment-say" target="_self" title="">Apple offered to cut prices by up to 500 yuan</a> on a range of models, including the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3148864/apples-iphone-13-may-not-have-many-new-features-its-lower-price-tag" target="_self" title="">iPhone 13</a> and its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235532/apples-iphone-15-draws-long-lines-china-despite-competition-huawei" target="_self" title="">new handsets that debuted last September</a>.</p><p>The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honor" target="_self" title="">Honor</a>, knocked down prices on their various Android models in both online and offline retail campaigns. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, which last year <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china" target="_self" title="">made a comeback in the 5G smartphone market</a>, did not pursue a similar strategy.</p><p>Apple’s atypical discount drive on the mainland shows the US tech giant’s focus to gain ground in the world’s second-biggest economy amid sluggish global iPhone sales, which has seen the company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">hit by two ratings downgrades</a> in the first week of this year.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/49690f1b-f395-4601-bae1-959ea30c7d93_ca1ba25a.jpg" title="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Apple faced more challenges in China compared to the rest of the world,” said Will Wong, senior research manager for client devices at IDC Asia-Pacific. “It not only faced competition from Huawei, but also a change in consumers’ sentiment that is now more cautious in spending.”</p><p>In the first week of the year, iPhone sales on the mainland were already down 30 per cent year on year, according to a Jefferies research note published on January 7. The brokerage indicated that there was “a big rise in discounts” for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3209228/apple-cuts-iphone-14-prices-china-us125-making-rare-sales-push-following-quarterly-revenue-drop" target="_self" title="">iPhone 14</a> and 14 Plus models, while the newer iPhone 15 and 15 Plus models saw “a moderate rise” in discounts.</p><p>The iPhone’s total sales volume last year on the mainland was down 3 per cent from 2022, which translated to a 0.4 per cent decline in Apple’s market share, according to Jefferies.</p><p>Worries about smartphone demand have pushed Apple’s shares down this month, enabling <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft</a> to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248395/microsoft-overtakes-apple-worlds-most-valuable-company-us289-trillion-market-capitalisation" target="_self" title="">become the world’s most valuable company</a> after ending the January 12 trading session in the US higher than the iPhone maker.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248395/microsoft-overtakes-apple-worlds-most-valuable-company-us289-trillion-market-capitalisation" title="">Microsoft overtakes Apple as world’s most valuable company at US$2.89 trillion</a></h3><p>Still, Apple received some good news on Monday when research firm IDC reported that the Cupertino, California-based company topped global smartphone shipments last year to dethrone long-standing market leader Samsung.</p><p>Apple’s global smartphone shipments last year reached 234.6 million units that gave the company a record market share of 20.1 per cent, up 3.7 per cent from 226.3 million in 2022, according to IDC. Apple was also the sole smartphone vendor in the top-four rankings – including Samsung, Xiaomi and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> – to record unit shipment growth in 2023.</p><p>On the intense global smartphone competition, the “overall Android space is diversifying within itself”, said Ryan Reith, group vice-president at IDC’s Worldwide Mobility and Consumer Device Trackers unit. “Huawei is back and making inroads quickly within China.”</p><p>Shenzhen-based Huawei’s return to the premium segment of the smartphone market was paved by its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china" target="_self" title="">launch last August of the Mate 60 Pro 5G handset</a>, powered by an advanced home-grown processor that defied US tech restrictions. The company’s new 5G smartphone and its advanced chip was hailed as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">symbolic of China’s victory in defying tough US sanctions</a>, fanning strong patriotic fervour that translated into robust domestic sales.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain" title="">Huawei’s Mate 60 Pro is a blow to US sanctions but battles remain, analysts say</a></h3><p>Huawei, however, faces a supply shortage for the Mate 60 Pro because of production constraints. The popular 5G model is still subject to a reservation purchase scheme without immediate availability on the company’s official website.</p><p>As Apple and its Chinese rivals turn to price promotions amid the weak macroeconomic environment on the mainland, Huawei will need to rely on the strength of its brand name to weather these headwinds, according to IDC’s Wong.</p><p>“The production constraints seem like a hurdle to Huawei, but it may also be a marketing tactic [to create greater demand],” Wong said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
