<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Nokia set to exit telecommunications joint venture with Huawei amid US-China tensions</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249181/nokia-set-exit-telecommunications-joint-venture-huawei-amid-us-china-tensions</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nokia sells its majority stake in TD Tech, a joint venture with Huawei, to a consortium led by Chinese government entities.</li>    <li>TD Tech, once a Nokia-majority-owned company, has been effectively controlled by Huawei since 2021, primarily selling rebranded Huawei phones.</li>    <li>The deal follows Nokia's failed attempt last year to sell its shares to another Chinese company, which Huawei opposed.</li>    <li>The new buyers include Chengdu High-Tech Investment Group, Chengdu Gaoxin Jicui Technology Co, and venture capital firm Huagai.</li>    <li>The sale is subject to regulatory approval and public feedback, with the Chinese government seeking input until January 28.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>诺基亚将所持有的TD Tech多数股权出售给由中国政府实体牵头的财团。</li>    <li>TD Tech曾是诺基亚控股公司，自2021年以来一直由华为实际控制，主要销售重新贴牌的华为手机。</li>    <li>这笔交易是在诺基亚去年试图将其股份出售给另一家中国公司但遭华为反对后进行的。</li>    <li>新的买家包括成都高新技术投资集团、成都高新技术投资集团和风投公司华盖资本。</li>    <li>这笔交易需要监管部门批准并征求公众意见，中国政府寻求在1月28日前收集意见。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stake (n.) - /steɪk/ 股份，股权。    <p>原文例句：Nokia sells its majority stake in TD Tech, a joint venture with Huawei, to a consortium led by Chinese government entities.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Stake在这里表示“股份，股权”。诺基亚出售其在TD Tech的多数股权，意味着它将失去TD Tech的大部分控制权。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>consortium (n.) - /kənˈsɔːrʃɪəm/ 财团，联合企业。    <p>原文例句：Nokia sells its majority stake in TD Tech, a joint venture with Huawei, to a consortium led by Chinese government entities.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Consortium在这里表示“财团，联合企业”。诺基亚将TD Tech的多数股权出售给由中国政府实体牵头的财团，意味着它将与该财团合作运营TD Tech。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>joint venture - 合资企业。    <P>原文例句：Nokia sells its majority stake in TD Tech, a joint venture with Huawei, to a consortium led by Chinese government entities.</P>    <p>例句讲解：“Joint venture”在这里表示“合资企业”。TD Tech是诺基亚与华为共同创办的合资企业，双方共同持股并共同经营。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The document did not reveal how much equity each of the new participants will hold. - 文件没有披露新参与者各自将持有多少权益。<p>句子分析：这是一个否定句，主句是The document did not reveal，其中主语是The document，谓语是did not reveal，宾语是how much equity each of the new participants will hold。this of the new participants是一个介词短语，作定语，修饰equity，表示每个新参与者的权益。will hold是一个将来时态的动词，表示新参与者将持有多少权益。这个句子的意思是说，文件没有披露新参与者各自将持有多少权益。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设或不真实的情况。    <p>原文例句：While Nokia had been the majority owner of the joint venture, Huawei has been the de facto controller, according to industry observers.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气的句子，表示假设或不真实的情况。While Nokia had been the majority owner of the joint venture这个分句表示假设诺基亚是合资企业的多数所有者，Huawei has been the de facto controller这个分句表示华为一直是事实上的控制者。这两个分句之间用逗号隔开，表示这是一种虚拟语气。虚拟语气通常用于表示假设、愿望、建议或不真实的情况。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>并列句 - 表示两个或多个句子之间存在并列关系。    <p>原文例句：TD Tech, founded in 2005, had been a joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens until 2007, when Siemens sold half of its stake to Nokia. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个并列句，表示TD Tech, founded in 2005, had been a joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens和when Siemens sold half of its stake to Nokia这两个句子之间存在并列关系。这两个句子之间用逗号隔开，表示这是一种并列句。并列句通常用于表示两个或多个句子之间存在并列关系，这些句子可以是主句与主句，也可以是主句与从句。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Finnish company will sell its majority stake in TD Tech to a group that includes state-owned entities, pending final government approval</li>
<li>Huawei has long been considered the de facto controller of TD Tech, which has been selling rebranded phones from the Chinese giant since 2021</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/96782c3a-8a2e-4d29-8e59-79d66ccfe5a6_def6fa44.jpg" /><figcaption>The Nokia headquarters in Espoo, Finland. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Finnish telecoms equipment giant Nokia has found new buyers for its majority stake in a Beijing-based joint venture with Huawei Technologies, after a proposed deal fell through last year following strong protest by the Chinese partner.</p><p>Under the latest agreement, wireless technology firm TD Tech will be jointly controlled by Huawei and a group of entities that include the government-owned Chengdu High-Tech Investment Group and Chengdu Gaoxin Jicui Technology Co, as well as venture capital firm Huagai, according to a disclosure published on Friday by the State Administration for Market Regulation (SAMR).</p><p>The document did not reveal how much equity each of the new participants will hold. Before the sale, Nokia owned 51 per cent of TD Tech, while Huawei held 49 per cent.</p><p>Regulators said they had no antitrust concerns on the deal and would solicit public feedback until January 28. Huawei and TD Tech together control no more than 10 per cent of China’s smartphone market, according to the SAMR, which did not specify the time frame for that data.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/36a09b3c-7803-48e6-a443-6a2cec7d849d_34f54c2a.jpg" title="An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Huawei had a 14 per cent share in the Chinese smartphone market in the third quarter last year, putting it in fifth place behind its spin-off Honor and rivals Oppo, Vivo and Apple, data from market intelligence firm Counterpoint Research showed.</p><p>TD Tech, founded in 2005, had been a joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens until 2007, when Siemens sold half of its stake to Nokia. In 2013, Siemens divested all its shares, making Nokia the major shareholder.</p><p>Known for its wireless communications equipment, including 4G and 5G networking gear, TD Tech has a presence in more than 100 countries serving 8 million industry customers, according to its website.</p><p>While Nokia had been the majority owner of the joint venture, Huawei has been the de facto controller, according to industry observers.</p><p>“The management are former Huawei employees, with product solutions based on Huawei products but fine-tuned for the industry market,” Yang Guang, an analyst covering the telecoms sector at research firm Omdia, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3216677/huawei-opposition-nokia-sale-joint-venture-threatens-finnish-firms-exit-us-china-tensions-weigh-deal" target="_self" title="">said last year</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3216677/huawei-opposition-nokia-sale-joint-venture-threatens-finnish-firms-exit-us-china-tensions-weigh-deal" title="">Huawei opposition to Nokia sale of joint venture threatens Finnish firm’s exit</a></h3><p>When Nokia last year tried to sell its majority stake to Shanghai-listed ink maker New East New Materials, Huawei threatened to stop licensing technology to TD Tech. That deal ultimately collapsed.</p><p>Huawei likely did not want to lose control of TD Tech, which could help the Chinese tech giant circumvent some US sanctions and help it address certain market segments more efficiently, Yang said at the time.</p><p>TD Tech in 2021 started selling what amounted to rebranded Huawei phones under its own brand. They included the M40 5G, which used a 7-nanometre chip from Taiwan-based MediaTek instead of Huawei’s own Kirin processors.</p><p>Sanctions imposed by Washington currently bar companies from selling to Huawei advanced chips made with US-origin technology, which includes MediaTek processors made by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a>, the world’s largest contract chip maker.</p><p>Despite the US restrictions, Huawei last year launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233636/huaweis-mate-60-pro-will-help-it-take-lost-ground-china-can-it-help-smartphone-giant-regain-global" target="_self" title="">its Mate 60 Pro</a>, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G processor.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China convenes Huawei, Tencent, Baidu to draft metaverse standards in bid to become global technology leader</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3249180/china-convenes-huawei-tencent-baidu-draft-metaverse-standards-bid-become-global-technology-leader</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In response to the rapid development of the metaverse sector, China has assembled a working group consisting of 60 experts from the private sector, government agencies, and academic institutions. The group aims to establish and promote metaverse industry standards, addressing ethical and security challenges within the sector. It will focus on building and maintaining a system of metaverse standards, promoting these standards, and training talent. The group will also encourage Chinese companies and institutions to actively participate in international standard-setting activities.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China forms a working group to establish metaverse industry standards, aiming to promote the healthy and orderly development of the sector.</li>    <li>Theme: Standardization of the metaverse industry in China, involving various stakeholders to address challenges and set common guidelines.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The necessity of establishing metaverse standards to guide the ethical and secure development of the industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Composition of the working group; tasks and responsibilities of the group; emphasis on both domestic and international standard-setting activities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  为了应对元宇宙行业快速发展的现状，中国组建了一个由60名专家组成的工作组，成员囊括了来自私营部门、政府机构和学术机构的各界人士。该工作组旨在建立并推广元宇宙行业的标准，以应对行业内面临的伦理和安全挑战。工作组将致力于建立和维护元宇宙行业标准体系、推广这些标准以及培养相关领域人才。同时，工作组还将鼓励中国企业和机构积极参与国际标准制定活动。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国组建工作组，建立元宇宙行业标准，以促进行业健康有序发展。</li>    <li>主题：中国元宇宙行业标准化，涉及各界利益相关者，以应对挑战并制定共同准则。</li>    <li>观点：建立元宇宙标准的必要性，以指导行业的伦理和安全发展。</li>    <li>主要信息：工作组组成；工作组的任务和职责；对国内和国际标准制定活动均予以重视。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>metaverse (n.) - /ˈmetəvɜːrs/ 元宇宙。    <p>原文例句：The working group is tasked with building, maintaining and promoting metaverse industry standards, China’s technology regulator says.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“metaverse”一词由“meta”（超越）和“universe”（宇宙）合成，意为“超越宇宙”。它是指一个虚拟的、三维的数字世界，用户可以在其中进行互动和交流。这个词最早出现在科幻小说中，现在已被广泛用于科技领域，特别是虚拟现实（VR）和增强现实（AR）领域。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>standard (n.) - /ˈstændərd/ 标准，规范。     <p>原文例句：The group is tasked with building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“standard”一词源自古法语“estandart”，意为“旗帜、标语”。它指的是一种被公认的、可遵循的规则或准则。在科学、技术、工程和制造等领域，标准尤为重要，它可以确保产品和服务的质量、安全性和兼容性。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>set up - 建立。    <p>原文例句：Shanghai has planned to set up both government-backed and private funds dedicated to metaverse development.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“set up”是一个动词短语，意为“建立、创立”。它通常用于表示创建一个新的组织、机构或项目。在这个例句中，“set up”表示“建立”，指上海计划建立政府支持的和私人资助的元宇宙发展基金。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>be tasked with - 被赋予任务。    <p>原文例句：The group is tasked with building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“be tasked with”是一个被动语态结构，意为“被赋予任务、被委托”。它通常用于表示某人或某组织被赋予一项特定的任务或职责。在这个例句中，“be tasked with”表示“被赋予任务”，指该工作组被赋予了建立和维护元宇宙行业标准体系的任务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China has formed a working group to establish metaverse standards. - 中国组建了一个工作组，以建立元宇宙标准。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是China，谓语是has formed，宾语是a working group to establish metaverse standards。介词短语to establish metaverse standards作目的状语，表示工作组的目的是建立元宇宙标准。这个句子的意思是说，中国组建了一个工作组，以建立元宇宙标准。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The group is tasked with building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards. - 该工作组的任务是建立和维护一个元宇宙行业标准体系。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The group is tasked with building and maintaining，其中主语是The group，谓语是is tasked with，宾语是building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards。现在分词短语building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards作目的状语，表示工作组的任务是建立和维护一个元宇宙行业标准体系。这个句子的意思是说，该工作组的任务是建立和维护一个元宇宙行业标准体系。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作的承受者。    <p>原文例句：The group is tasked with building, maintaining and promoting metaverse industry standards.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是一种语态，表示动作的承受者。结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的第三种形式。被动语态可以使句子更加正式和客观。在这个例句中，be用的是is，表示现在时态，过去分词是tasked，表示被赋予任务。这个句子的意思是说，该工作组被赋予了建立、维护和推广元宇宙行业标准的任务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The MIIT in September proposed to form a working group to “guide the healthy and orderly development of the metaverse industry through standard regulation”.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。现在完成时表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，have用的是has，表示现在完成时，过去分词是proposed，表示提议。这个句子的意思是说，工业和信息化部在9月份提议组建一个工作组，通过标准化监管来指导元宇宙产业的健康有序发展。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The working group consists of 60 experts, including those from the private sector as well as government officials and academic researchers</li>
<li>The group is tasked with building, maintaining and promoting metaverse industry standards, China’s technology regulator says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/56f4a36f-d5d5-434d-8326-ac2adaa5400e_7b70980f.jpg" /><figcaption>China has formed a working group to establish metaverse standards. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) has assembled 60 experts, including some from the country’s largest technology firms, to form a new working group to establish standards for the metaverse sector.</p><p>Representatives from telecoms equipment giant Huawei Technologies, video gaming titans Tencent Holdings and NetEase, web search and artificial intelligence champion Baidu, financial technology firm Ant Group and computer maker Lenovo Group are among those on the list published by the MIIT on Friday.</p><p>Ant is an affiliate of Alibaba Group Holding, owner of the Post.</p><p>Other members include MIIT officials and researchers from Peking University, Fudan University and other renowned institutions in the country.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>The MIIT in September proposed to form a working group to “guide the healthy and orderly development of the metaverse industry through standard regulation”, cautioning that the sector was facing ethical and security challenges.</p><p>The group would be tasked with “building and maintaining a system of metaverse industry standards”, “promoting the standards” and “training talent”, the regulator said in its proposal.</p><p>Besides focusing on domestic standards, the group would also “encourage local companies and institutions to deeply engage in international standard-setting activities”.</p><p>The metaverse, a loosely-defined term that refers to a virtual three-dimensional world, has become a trending topic in the past few years.</p><p>US social media giant Facebook changed its name to Meta Platforms in 2021. CEO and founder Mark Zuckerberg explained during the rebranding announcement that he sought to embrace “the next chapter for the internet”.</p><p>In 2022, Meta, Microsoft and others founded the Metaverse Standards Forum, which also comprises Huawei, Tencent and some other Chinese tech giants.</p><p>Beijing is hoping to become a leader in the emerging field. Five authorities, including the MIIT, released a joint plan last year to nurture at least <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3233933/china-wants-metaverse-firms-global-influence-and-plans-five-industrial-clusters-2025" target="_self" title="">three metaverse companies “with global influence”</a> by 2025.</p><p>Several local governments have made it a priority to develop the metaverse sector.</p><p>Beijing’s eastern Tongzhou district, considered a “sub-centre” of the capital city, has vowed to incorporate more than 100 metaverse-related firms by the end of the year.</p><p>Shanghai has planned to set up both government-backed and private funds dedicated to metaverse development. The first one, established in late 2022, raised an initial sum of 1 billion yuan (US$140 million).</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TuSimple will continue its drive to Asia-Pacific in wake of autonomous truck firm’s decision to delist from Nasdaq</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3249140/tusimple-will-continue-its-drive-asia-pacific-wake-autonomous-truck-firms-decision-delist-nasdaq</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  图森未来(TuSimple)正在将业务重点转向亚太地区，包括中国、日本和澳大利亚，那里的监管支持和强大的供应链可以帮助该公司实现商业目标。同时，图森未来计划从纳斯达克退市。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 图森未来将重点转向亚太地区寻求更好的商业机会，并计划从纳斯达克退市。</li>    <li>Theme: 企业融资的限制和自驾卡车行业面临的挑战。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 自驾卡车行业的问题和机遇。</li>    <li>Main information: 图森未来将重点转向亚太地区的原因、图森未来的发展计划、自驾卡车行业面临的挑战和图森未来面临的调查和法律纠纷。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  图森未来正在将业务重点转向亚太地区，包括中国、日本和澳大利亚，那里的监管支持和强大的供应链可以帮助该公司实现商业目标。同时，图森未来计划从纳斯达克退市。  <ul>    <li>摘要：图森未来将重点转向亚太地区寻求更好的商业机会，并计划从纳斯达克退市。</li>    <li>主题：企业融资的限制和自驾卡车行业面临的挑战。</li>    <li>观点：自驾卡车行业的问题和机遇。</li>    <li>主要信息：图森未来将重点转向亚太地区的原因、图森未来的发展计划、自驾卡车行业面临的挑战和图森未来面临的调查和法律纠纷。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>integrate (v.) - /ˈɪntɪɡreɪt/ 整合，融合。    <p>原文例句：For autonomous trucks, we have to integrate the advanced software capabilities – the virtual driver – with reliable and scalable hardware that includes the truck itself, Tier-1 components coupled with the right use case. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由in-（进入，向内）和tegrare（连接，组合）组成，意为“使结合在一起，使融合”。在这个例句中，它指的是将自动驾驶卡车的先进软件功能、可靠的硬件以及合适的用例进行整合。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>volatile (adj.) - /ˈvɑːlət̬aɪl/ 不稳定的，易变的。    <p>原文例句： TuSimple cited changes in the capital markets for “pre-commercialised companies” and significantly increased stock price volatility as part of its rationale for delisting. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，意为“多变的，不稳定的”。在这个例句中，它指的是“预商业化公司”的资本市场的变化和股票价格的大幅波动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>navigate (v.) - /ˈnævɪɡeɪt/ 航行，驾驭。    <p>原文例句：It also said being a private firm would help the company better navigate its transformation. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，意为“驾驶，航行”。在这个例句中，它指的是作为一家私人公司将有助于该公司更好地驾驭转型。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>on the road - 正在进行中，在旅途中。    <P>原文例句：The company’s shares closed at US$0.49 on Thursday, trading around 98 per cent lower than its debut price of US$40.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由on（在……上）和road（路）构成的，表示“在路上，正在进行中”。在这个例句中，它表示该公司股票的收盘价为0.49美元，比其40美元的首次公开募股价格低了约98%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The US Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) kicked off an investigation of TuSimple with the FBI and the Securities and Exchange Commission in 2022. - 美国外国投资委员会（CFIUS）于 2022 年与联邦调查局和证券交易委员会一起对图森未来展开调查。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是CFIUS kicked off an investigation of TuSimple，其中主语是CFIUS，谓语是kicked off，宾语是an investigation of TuSimple。with the FBI and the Securities and Exchange Commission是一个介词短语作伴随状语，表示调查是由FBI和证券交易委员会一起进行的。in 2022是一个时间状语，表示调查发生在2022年。这个句子的意思是说，美国外国投资委员会（CFIUS）于2022年与联邦调查局和证券交易委员会一起对图森未来展开调查。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TuSimple has focused on Level 4 autonomy. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示图森未来一直专注于四级自动驾驶。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC, including China, Japan and Australia, where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help</li>
<li>TuSimple this week announced a plan to voluntarily delist from Nasdaq, with its last trading day expected to be around February 7</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/9379da4f-2af9-460b-b031-733718defcaa_f6769707.jpg" /><figcaption>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC. Photo: Handout </figcaption></figure><p>Autonomous truck company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217769/tusimple-working-resolving-us-issues-after-management-turmoil-and-pushing-ahead-autonomous-driving?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">TuSimple Holdings</a> will continue to pivot to the Asia-Pacific (APAC) region for better commercial opportunities and in line with its plan to delist from the Nasdaq exchange, said chief executive officer Lu Cheng.</p><p>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC, including China, Japan and Australia, where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help the firm’s commercial goals, Lu said in a Friday interview, as the self-driving industry continues to push for profitability.</p><p>“For autonomous trucks, we have to integrate the advanced software capabilities – the virtual driver – with reliable and scalable hardware that includes the truck itself, Tier-1 components coupled with the right use case,” Lu said. “That’s one of the benefits of focusing our business more on APAC because of the maturity of the hardware supply chain.”</p><p>The company started test runs of Level 4 autonomous trucks in Japan last year, and conducted full autonomous runs – without a human in the truck – on public roads in Shanghai. Level 4 is considered to be fully autonomous driving, although a human driver can still request control, and the car still has a cockpit.</p><p>San Diego, California-based TuSimple, which carried out an initial public offering (IPO) in 2021, announced its plan to voluntarily delist from Nasdaq on Wednesday, with its last trading day on the exchange expected to be around February 7.</p><p>The company cited changes in the capital markets for “pre-commercialised companies” and significantly increased stock price volatility as part of its rationale for delisting. It also said being a private firm would help the company better navigate its transformation.</p><p>The company’s shares closed at US$0.49 on Thursday, trading around 98 per cent lower than its debut price of US$40.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244089/autonomous-trucking-company-tusimple-cease-us-operations-amid-new-round-lay-offs-focus-asia-pacific" title="">Autonomous trucking firm TuSimple to exit US amid new lay-offs, focus on Asia</a></h3><p>Lu said the company could explore another IPO down the road “when the company makes more progress and the market conditions make sense”, but it has no timeline or location in mind at the present time.</p><p>TuSimple said last month that it was cutting 75 per cent of its workforce and winding down its operations in the US. The retreat comes amid further consolidation in the autonomous driving industry, with several leading players announcing lay-offs and downsizing in the past year.</p><p>Last July, Alphabet unit Waymo announced that it would slow down work in the self-driving truck field under its Via subsidiary. Last May, Embark Technology – an early proponent of self-driving truck software development in the US – delisted from the Nasdaq and went private via a merger, after running out of capital to pursue commercial production.</p><p>The lack of a clear path to profitability and real commercialisation is a challenge for the industry, which includes technology, hardware supply chain, and regulatory issues, Lu said. “Being able to move from demos and pilots to actually providing a real service that is profitable is the biggest challenge,” he added.</p><p>TuSimple reported a US$248.6 million loss from operations in the first nine months of 2023, narrowing from a US$341.7 million loss in the same period in the previous year.</p><p>TuSimple, once considered a star in the global autonomous driving sector and a leader in US self-driving truck development, has focused on Level 4 autonomy. It was also the first company to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/2169885/driverless-tech-start-aims-replace-15-million-truckers-us-china?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">deploy autonomous trucks on pilot tests</a> between the cities of Tucson and Phoenix in Arizona and Las Vegas, Nevada in 2018.</p><p>The company has been grappling with a US government investigation, corporate disputes and lay-offs since 2022.</p><p>The US Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS), an inter-agency panel that reviews the national security implications of foreign investments in the US, kicked off an investigation of TuSimple with the FBI and the Securities and Exchange Commission in 2022.</p><p>The inquiry revolves around whether TuSimple co-founder and then-chief executive Hou Xiaodi <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217769/tusimple-working-resolving-us-issues-after-management-turmoil-and-pushing-ahead-autonomous-driving?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">made illegal funding or technology transfers to Hydron</a>, a Chinese autonomous truck start-up established by another TuSimple co-founder Chen Mo in 2021.</p><p>How was fired by the company’s board in October 2022 after an internal investigation, with it citing a “loss in trust and confidence” in connection with the alleged sharing of confidential information with Hydron.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong eyes ‘more flexible’ path in regulating spot cryptocurrency ETFs as US races ahead with approvals</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249086/hong-kong-eyes-more-flexible-path-regulating-spot-crypto-etfs-us-races-ahead-approvals</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  香港计划对现货加密货币ETF的规定与美国的主要区别在于，香港将允许现金和实物认购。香港证监会和金融管理局授权现货加密货币ETF的计划，让业界对香港成为加密货币中心的预期持乐观态度。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 香港证监会和金管局联合授权现货加密货币ETF，引发业界对香港成为加密货币中心的预期乐观。</li>    <li>Theme: 香港推出更灵活的加密货币交易所交易基金（ETF）制度，以期成为加密货币中心。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 香港和美国在现货加密货币ETF的监管方式上存在差异，香港允许现金和实物认购，而美国仅允许现金认购。</li>    <li>Main information: 香港的现货加密货币ETF允许现金和实物认购；香港的加密货币监管框架与美国的差异；香港证监会和金管局的联合计划引发业界乐观；香港面临来自美国的竞争。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  A key difference between the proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs in Hong Kong and the US is that the city will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions. The plan by the SFC and Hong Kong Monetary Authority to authorise spot cryptocurrency ETFs has given the industry optimism about the city’s prospects of becoming a cryptocurrency hub. Stacks of cryptocurrency coin representations are set against the backdrop of the Hong Kong flag. Photo: Shutterstock Images Hong Kong is set to develop a more flexible regime for cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs), even though the US leads in both approval speed and market size, experts said. A key difference between Hong Kong’s proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs and products approved in the US is that Hong Kong will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions. Under such rules, participating dealers can directly use bitcoin to subscribe to or redeem the ETF’s shares, whereas in the US, such subscriptions and redemptions are only allowed with cash. The different approach reflects a divergence of virtual asset regulatory frameworks, where the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) “appears reluctant to allow licensed dealers to touch bitcoin” when subscribing for and redeeming ETF shares because spot bitcoin trades are unregulated in the US, according to Andrew Fei, a partner at King & Wood Mallesons in Hong Kong. Hong Kong securities watchdog puts virtual asset trading platforms on fraud alert Regulators in Hong Kong last month said that they will allow retail access to spot virtual asset ETFs, and are willing to accept applications from funds hoping to offer such products to the public. After nine spot bitcoin ETFs in the US, offered by fund giants including BlackRock and Fidelity, attracted nearly US$2 billion in their first three days of trading, virtual asset industry participants in Hong Kong have urged the Hong Kong government to speed up the approval of the city’s own offerings. “I hope that Hong Kong, amid the rapid development and intense competition in the virtual asset sector, can seize a spot globally as quickly as possible,” Legislative Council member Johnny Ng Kit-chong wrote in a post on X, formerly Twitter, last week. “[Hong Kong should] strive to be the first to implement relevant policies and products particularly in Asia.” Hong Kong regulators propose licensing for sale of stablecoins to public In a statement last week, SEC chair Gary Gensler said that despite its approval of spot bitcoin ETFs, the regulator “did not approve or endorse bitcoin”, which is “primarily a speculative, volatile asset that’s also used for illicit activity including ransomware, money laundering, sanction evasion, and terrorist financing”. “In the US, the spot bitcoin market is largely unregulated and the SEC remains somewhat sceptical about spot bitcoin transactions,” Fei said. However, because spot virtual asset transactions on licensed virtual asset trading platforms are regulated in Hong Kong, the city’s Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) “appears to be more comfortable with virtual asset ETFs”, he added. The SFC and the Hong Kong Monetary Authority’s joint plan to authorise spot cryptocurrency ETFs has given the industry optimism about the city’s prospects of becoming a cryptocurrency hub. “Hong Kong’s regulatory environment, known for adaptability, positions it well in navigating the evolving world of digital assets,” said Dmitry Lapidus, senior liquid analyst at US venture capital firm CoinFund. The Nasdaq board in Times Square, New York, shows video of the opening bell as Bitcoin Spot ETF’s are launched on the Nasdaq Exchange on January 11. Photo: Getty Images via AFP “Hong Kong is one of the few major jurisdictions in the world that has a clear vision on regulating virtual assets now, and I truly believe this move will continue to serve Hong Kong as a global financial hub in the coming days,” said Kennix Chan, executive director at Victory Securities Company Limited. But the city will face strong competition from jurisdictions like the US, experts noted. The American cryptocurrency market is poised to be much larger for US and world investors, especially when the ones offering the spot cryptocurrency ETFs are finance heavyweights such as Blackrock, Fidelity, Franklin, and Invesco, said Jack Poon, professor of practice for fintech and entrepreneurship at the Hong Kong Polytechnic University. “They have a huge existing customer base and a brand that retail investors feel comfortable with,” Poon said, adding that they are also offering low fees that issuers in Hong Kong may not be able to absorb in the long term.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Hong Kong plans to allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions for spot cryptocurrency ETFs, offering a more flexible regime than the US.</li>    <li>Theme: The Hong Kong government aims to establish the city as a cryptocurrency hub by introducing a more flexible regulatory framework for cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs).</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Experts believe that Hong Kong's proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs have the potential to attract investors and position the city as a leading center for digital asset trading.</li>    <li>Main information: The key difference between Hong Kong's and the US's approach to spot cryptocurrency ETFs lies in the allowed subscription methods. Hong Kong permits both cash and in-kind subscriptions, while the US only allows cash.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>requisite (adj.) - /ˈrɛkwɪzɪt/ 必需的，必要的。<p>原文例句：The necessary hardware and software are in place only if it is requisite that the signal quality be preserved. </p><p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Late Latin，意思是“必须的，必要的，需要的”。在这个例句中，它表示如果要保持信号质量，那么必须具备必要的硬件和软件。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>backlog (n.) - /ˈbæklɑːɡ/ 积压的工作，未完成的工作。<p>原文例句：For a typical engineering change notice, the backlog was 48 days. </p><p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于back（后面）和log（记录），意思是“积压的工作，未完成的工作”。在这个例句中，它表示对于一个典型的工程变更通知，积压的工作是48天。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>facilitate (v.) - /fəˈsɪlɪteɪt/ 促进，便利。<p>原文例句：The major goal of the report is to facilitate a greater understanding of the effects of the information revolution. </p><p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Late Latin，意思是“使容易，使方便”。在这个例句中，它表示该报告的主要目的是促进对信息革命影响的更深入理解。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>integration (n.) - /ɪntɪˈɡreɪʃən/ 融合，整合。<p>原文例句：This paper describes a methodology for the integration of computational fluid dynamics into structural analysis. </p><p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，意思是“融合，结合，整合”。在这个例句中，它表示本文描述了一种将计算流体动力学整合到结构分析中的方法。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in common - 共同的，一般的。    <P>原文例句：This has much in common with the well-known Kalman-Bucy filter. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在里面），common（共同）组成，表示“共同的，一般的”。在这个例句中，它表示这与众所周知的卡尔曼-巴茜滤波器有很多共同之处。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions, whereas in the US, such subscriptions and redemptions are only allowed with cash. - 香港将允许现金和实物认购，而美国仅允许现金认购。<p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，由两个并列分句组成。第一个分句是Hong Kong will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions，主语是Hong Kong，谓语是will allow，宾语是both cash and in-kind subscriptions。  <ul><li>A key difference between Hong Kong’s proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs and the US is that the city will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions</li>
<li>The SFC and Hong Kong Monetary Authority’s plan to authorise spot cryptocurrency ETFs has given the industry optimism about the city’s prospects of becoming a cryptocurrency hub</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/cfc5c501-3421-4cf4-a330-cfc6070fee33_e8f94cca.jpg" /><figcaption>Stacks of cryptocurrency coin representations are set against the backdrop of the Hong Kong flag. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure><p>Hong Kong is set to develop a more flexible regime for cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs), even though the US leads in both approval speed and market size, experts said.</p><p>A key difference between Hong Kong’s proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs and products approved in the US is that Hong Kong will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions. Under such rules, participating dealers can directly use bitcoin to subscribe to or redeem the ETF’s shares, whereas in the US, such subscriptions and redemptions are only allowed with cash.</p><p>The different approach reflects a divergence of virtual asset regulatory frameworks, where the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) “appears reluctant to allow licensed dealers to touch bitcoin” when subscribing for and redeeming ETF shares because spot bitcoin trades are unregulated in the US, according to Andrew Fei, a partner at King &amp; Wood Mallesons in Hong Kong.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3248972/hong-kong-securities-watchdog-puts-virtual-asset-trading-platforms-aramex-and-difx-alert-list" title="">Hong Kong securities watchdog puts virtual asset trading platforms on fraud alert</a></h3><p>Regulators in Hong Kong last month said that they will allow retail access to spot virtual asset ETFs, and are willing to accept applications from funds hoping to offer such products to the public.</p><p>After nine spot bitcoin ETFs in the US, offered by fund giants including BlackRock and Fidelity, attracted nearly US$2 billion in their first three days of trading, virtual asset industry participants in Hong Kong have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248282/hong-kong-needs-speed-approval-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-after-us-launch-industry" target="_self" title="">urged the Hong Kong government to speed up</a> the approval of the city’s own offerings.</p><p>“I hope that Hong Kong, amid the rapid development and intense competition in the virtual asset sector, can seize a spot globally as quickly as possible,” Legislative Council member Johnny Ng Kit-chong wrote in a post on X, formerly Twitter, last week. “[Hong Kong should] strive to be the first to implement relevant policies and products particularly in Asia.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246415/hong-kong-regulators-propose-tougher-rules-sale-stablecoins-retail-investors" title="">Hong Kong regulators propose licensing for sale of stablecoins to public</a></h3><p>In a statement last week, SEC chair Gary Gensler said that despite its approval of spot bitcoin ETFs, the regulator “did not approve or endorse bitcoin”, which is “primarily a speculative, volatile asset that’s also used for illicit activity including ransomware, money laundering, sanction evasion, and terrorist financing”.</p><p>“In the US, the spot bitcoin market is largely unregulated and the SEC remains somewhat sceptical about spot bitcoin transactions,” Fei said.</p><p>However, because spot virtual asset transactions on licensed virtual asset trading platforms are regulated in Hong Kong, the city’s Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) “appears to be more comfortable with virtual asset ETFs”, he added.</p><p>The SFC and the Hong Kong Monetary Authority’s joint plan to authorise spot cryptocurrency ETFs has given the industry <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual?module=hard_link&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">optimism</a> about the city’s prospects of becoming a cryptocurrency hub.</p><p>“Hong Kong’s regulatory environment, known for adaptability, positions it well in navigating the evolving world of digital assets,” said Dmitry Lapidus, senior liquid analyst at US venture capital firm CoinFund.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Nasdaq board in Times Square, New York, shows video of the opening bell as Bitcoin Spot ETF’s are launched on the Nasdaq Exchange on January 11. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1335" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/a280c4ae-0893-40b7-9b49-19d29cae20e5_a57dc0a9.jpg" title="The Nasdaq board in Times Square, New York, shows video of the opening bell as Bitcoin Spot ETF’s are launched on the Nasdaq Exchange on January 11. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Nasdaq board in Times Square, New York, shows video of the opening bell as Bitcoin Spot ETF’s are launched on the Nasdaq Exchange on January 11. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Hong Kong is one of the few major jurisdictions in the world that has a clear vision on regulating virtual assets now, and I truly believe this move will continue to serve Hong Kong as a global financial hub in the coming days,” said Kennix Chan, executive director at Victory Securities Company Limited.</p><p>But the city will face strong competition from jurisdictions like the US, experts noted.</p><p>The American cryptocurrency market is poised to be much larger for US and world investors, especially when the ones offering the spot cryptocurrency ETFs are finance heavyweights such as Blackrock, Fidelity, Franklin, and Invesco, said Jack Poon, professor of practice for fintech and entrepreneurship at the Hong Kong Polytechnic University.</p><p>“They have a huge existing customer base and a brand that retail investors feel comfortable with,” Poon said, adding that they are also offering low fees that issuers in Hong Kong may not be able to absorb in the long term.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
