<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Davos 2024: OpenAI CEO Altman, Time Owner Benioff disagree on AI’s use of copyrighted content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248702/davos-2024-openai-ceo-altman-time-owner-benioff-disagree-ais-use-copyrighted-content</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Salesforce CEO Marc Benioff and OpenAI CEO Sam Altman discussed the issue of AI companies' use of copyrighted materials in training their models. Benioff criticized AI companies for "stealing" training data, while Altman argued that training data is often not as valuable as its owners believe. Both agreed that AI companies should standardize payments to content creators to ensure fair treatment.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: AI companies' use of copyrighted materials and the need for fair compensation to content creators.</li>    <li>Theme: The debate over the value of training data and the responsibility of AI companies to compensate content creators.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Benioff's criticism of AI companies for misusing copyrighted data and his call for standardized payments; Altman's defense of AI companies and his belief that training data is often overvalued.</li>    <li>Main information: The use of copyrighted content in AI training; OpenAI's licensing negotiations with media outlets; the lawsuit filed by The New York Times against OpenAI and Microsoft; Altman's argument that training data is not always valuable; OpenAI's partnership with the Associated Press and Axel Springer.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Salesforce首席执行官马克·贝尼奥夫和OpenAI首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼讨论了人工智能公司在训练其模型时使用版权材料的问题。贝尼奥夫批评人工智能公司“窃取”训练数据，而阿尔特曼则认为训练数据通常不如其所有者认为的那么有价值。双方都同意人工智能公司应标准化向内容创建者支付的费用，以确保公平对待。  <ul>    <li>摘要：人工智能公司使用版权材料以及向内容创建者支付公平报酬的必要性。</li>    <li>主题：关于训练数据价值的争论以及人工智能公司补偿内容创建者的责任。</li>    <li>观点：贝尼奥夫批评人工智能公司滥用版权数据并呼吁标准化支付；阿尔特曼对人工智能公司的辩护以及他认为训练数据常常被高估的观点。</li>    <li>主要信息：版权内容在人工智能训练中的使用；OpenAI与媒体机构的许可谈判；《纽约时报》对OpenAI和微软提起的诉讼；阿尔特曼认为训练数据并不总是具有价值的观点；OpenAI与美联社和阿克塞尔·施普林格的合作关系。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ripped off (v.) - /rɪp ɒf/ 窃取，剽窃。    <p>原文例句：Marc Benioff, the Salesforce chief executive officer who also owns Time magazine, said artificial intelligence (AI) companies ripped off intellectual property to build their technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语是由rip（撕，扯）和off（掉，离）组成的，表示“窃取，剽窃”。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能（AI）公司窃取了知识产权来构建他们的技术。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>standardise (v.) - /ˈstændəˌraɪz/ 标准化，使标准化。    <p>原文例句：Nobody really exactly knows what a fair price for this data is, Benioff added, but AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于standard（标准），表示“标准化，使标准化”。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能（AI）公司应该标准化向内容创建者支付的费用，以确保公平对待。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>misuse (v.) - /mɪsˈjuːz/ 滥用，误用。    <p>原文例句：Benioff’s Salesforce markets its AI-powered software features as including a “trust layer” to prevent the misuse of customer data.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于mis（错误地，坏地）和use（使用），表示“滥用，误用”。在这个例句中，它表示Salesforce将其人工智能（AI）驱动的软件功能宣传为包含一个“信任层”，以防止客户数据被滥用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>intellectual property - 知识产权。    <p>原文例句：Marc Benioff, the Salesforce chief executive officer who also owns Time magazine, said artificial intelligence (AI) companies ripped off intellectual property to build their technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由intellectual（知性的，理智的）和property（财产，权利）组成，表示“知识产权”。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能（AI）公司窃取了知识产权来构建他们的技术。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fair price - 公平的价格。    <p>原文例句：Nobody really exactly knows what a fair price for this data is, Benioff added, but AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由fair（公平的，公正的）和price（价格）组成的，表示“公平的价格”。在这个例句中，它表示没有人确切地知道这些数据公平的价格是多少。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>trust layer - 信任层。    <p>原文例句：Benioff’s Salesforce markets its AI-powered software features as including a “trust layer” to prevent the misuse of customer data.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由trust（信任，信赖）和layer（层）组成的，表示“信任层”。在这个例句中，它表示Salesforce将其人工智能（AI）驱动的软件功能宣传为包含一个“信任层”，以防止客户数据被滥用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“All the training data has been stolen,” Benioff said Tuesday in an interview at Bloomberg House at the World Economic Forum in Davos. - 贝尼奥夫周二在达沃斯世界经济论坛彭博社大厦的采访中说：“所有训练数据都被窃取了”。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Benioff，谓语是said，宾语是All the training data has been stolen。Tuesday是一个时间状语，表示周二。in an interview at Bloomberg House at the World Economic Forum in Davos是一个地点状语，表示在达沃斯世界经济论坛彭博社大厦的采访中。这个句子的意思是说，贝尼奥夫周二在达沃斯世界经济论坛彭博社大厦的采访中说：“所有训练数据都被窃取了”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>OpenAI has disputed that it used protected material without permission. - OpenAI 否认在未经允许的情况下使用了受保护的材料。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是OpenAI has disputed，其中主语是OpenAI，谓语是has disputed。that it used protected material without permission是一个宾语从句，其中主语是it，谓语是used，宾语是protected material。without permission是一个介词短语，作状语，表示在未经允许的情况下。这个句子的意思是说，OpenAI 否认在未经允许的情况下使用了受保护的材料。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句 - 表示强调句型。    <p>原文例句：“All the training data has been stolen,” Benioff said Tuesday in an interview at Bloomberg House at the World Economic Forum in Davos. - 贝尼奥夫周二在达沃斯世界经济论坛彭博社大厦的采访中说：“所有训练数据都被窃取了”。</p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句是英语中常用的一种句型，可以加强语气，突出强调句子的某个成分。强调句的结构通常是：It is/was + 被强调成分 + that + 其他。在这个例句中，被强调成分是All the training data has been stolen，it是形式主语，that引导一个句子作真正的主语。这个句子的意思是说，所有训练数据都被窃取了。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>不定式 - 表示动词的不定形式。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI has disputed that it used protected material without permission. - OpenAI 否认在未经允许的情况下使用了受保护的材料。</p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式是没有时态和人称变化的动词形式，由to加动词原形构成。不定式有作主语、宾  <ul><li>AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly, says Salesforce CEO and Time owner Marc Benioff</li>
<li>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman says training data often is not as valuable as its owners think it is</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/205a42a4-b828-49fe-9b5b-64ae3191358d_a0e69d62.jpg" /><figcaption>Marc Benioff, CEO of Salesforce.com, at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Marc Benioff, the Salesforce chief executive officer who also owns Time magazine, said artificial intelligence (AI) companies ripped off intellectual property to build their technology.</p><p>“All the training data has been stolen,” Benioff said Tuesday in an interview at Bloomberg House at the World Economic Forum in Davos. Content from media outlets including Time and The New York Times surfaces in results from AI companies, he said.</p><p>There is increasing scrutiny on the makers of large language models that power generative AI tools such as ChatGPT over their use of copyrighted materials. Benioff’s Time is among publications currently negotiating with ChatGPT maker OpenAI to license their news work, as first reported by Bloomberg.</p><p>Other companies include Warner Bros Discovery’s CNN and Fox. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3246432/new-york-times-sues-chatgpt-maker-openai-microsoft-copyright-infringement-unlawful-use-stories-train" target="_self" title="">The New York Times sued OpenAI</a> and its partner Microsoft in November for using the publication’s articles without permission.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/256a3cae-17dc-4815-bfb6-2b8f632dd1af_a66cec46.jpg" title="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Nobody really exactly knows” what a fair price for this data is, Benioff added, but AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly. Benioff’s Salesforce markets its AI-powered software features as including a “trust layer” to prevent the misuse of customer data.</p><p>OpenAI has disputed that it used protected material without permission. CEO Sam Altman, in an interview earlier Tuesday with Bloomberg, said training data often is not as valuable as its owners think it is.</p><p>“We do not want to train on The New York Times data,” Altman said, adding that research is more focused on learning from small amounts of high-quality data. It should be possible to avoid any news content that is off limits, he said.</p><p>OpenAI has been striking partnerships for specific uses of news content and more are coming, Altman said. “I think there’s going to be great new ways to consume and monetise news.”</p><p>In July, OpenAI signed an agreement with the Associated Press to access some of the news agency’s archives. OpenAI also reached <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content" target="_self" title="">a three-year deal in December with Axel Springer</a> to use the German media company’s work for an undisclosed sum.</p><p>When asked whether AI presented risks to the democratic process in an election year for many countries, Benioff said his biggest concern is still social media. “Regulators have not done their job,” he added.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Davos 2024: Microsoft CEO ‘comfortable’ with OpenAI non-profit board structure despite Altman ousting</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248699/davos-2024-microsoft-ceo-comfortable-openai-non-profit-board-structure-despite-altman-ousting</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella expresses his support for OpenAI's governance structure, despite a recent CEO dismissal and concerns over its non-profit mission.</li>    <li>Theme: Nadella emphasizes the value of partnerships in promoting competition, highlighting Microsoft's investment in OpenAI as a non-traditional approach.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Nadella believes that Microsoft's partial ownership of OpenAI enhances competition, as it aligns with the company's pro-competitive strategy.</li>    <li>Main information: Nadella's comments at the World Economic Forum; OpenAI's CEO dismissal and reinstatement; ongoing efforts to finalize the board structure; Microsoft's observer position on the board; scrutiny from competition authorities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>摘要：微软首席执行官萨提亚·纳德拉表达了对OpenAI治理结构的支持，尽管近期首席执行官被免职以及对其非营利使命的担忧。</li>    <li>主题：纳德拉强调了伙伴关系在促进竞争中的价值，强调微软对OpenAI的投资是一种非传统的做法。</li>    <li>观点：纳德拉认为，微软对OpenAI的部分所有权增强了竞争，因为它符合公司亲竞争的战略。</li>    <li>主要信息：纳德拉在世界经济论坛上的评论；OpenAI首席执行官的解雇和复职；最终确定董事会结构的正在进行的努力；微软在董事会中的观察员席位；来自竞争当局的审查。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>governance (n.) - /ˈgʌvənəns/ 管理，治理。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella on Tuesday said he had no issue with partner OpenAI’s governance structure, two months after the start-up’s non-profit board temporarily ousted its chief executive without regard to investors’ interests.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语 gubernare（掌舵），表示“当权者对所管理范围内的人和事所实施的管理”。在这个例句中，它指的是OpenAI的治理结构，即其领导层和决策机制。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>non-profit (adj.) - /ˌnɑːnˈprɑːfɪt/ 非盈利的。    <p>原文例句：The surprise November dismissal of OpenAI’s CEO Sam Altman over an alleged communication breakdown triggered a crisis at the start-up behind ChatGPT, in which employees threatened to resign en masse and go work for Microsoft, which is backing OpenAI with billions of dollars.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词指的是不以盈利为目的的组织或机构。在这个例句中，OpenAI是一个非营利性组织，其成立宗旨是开发对人类有益的强大人工智能，而并非以盈利为目的。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>without regard to - 不顾。    <P>原文例句：Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella on Tuesday said he had no issue with partner OpenAI’s governance structure, two months after the start-up’s non-profit board temporarily ousted its chief executive without regard to investors’ interests.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由without（没有），regard（重视）和to（对……）构成的，表示“不顾，不考虑”。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI的非营利性董事会暂时罢免了首席执行官，而没有考虑到投资者的利益。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The fact that Microsoft does not fully own OpenAI distinguished their deal in a pro-competitive way, according to Nadella. - 纳德拉表示，微软不完全拥有OpenAI这一事实以一种有利于竞争的方式使其交易脱颖而出。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是The fact that Microsoft does not fully own OpenAI，谓语是distinguished，宾语是their deal。in a pro-competitive way是一个状语，表示微软不完全拥有OpenAI这一事实使得两家公司的交易以一种有利于竞争的方式脱颖而出。according to Nadella是一个介词短语作状语，表示根据纳德拉的说法，这一事实使得两家公司的交易以一种有利于竞争的方式脱颖而出。这个句子的意思是说，纳德拉表示，微软不完全拥有OpenAI这一事实以一种有利于竞争的方式使其交易脱颖而出。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI’s board, charged with protecting the start-up non-profit’s mission to develop powerful artificial intelligence that benefits humanity, ultimately restored Altman days later and now is in the process of filling out its membership.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：had + been + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI的董事会在保护OpenAI的使命方面做出了努力，包括恢复Altman的首席执行官职位，并正在为董事会增加成员。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft has secured a non-voting observer position on the OpenAI board.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示正在进行的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示微软已经获得了OpenAI董事会的一个无投票权的观察员席位。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Satya Nadella, speaking on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum’s meeting in Davos, says he has ‘no issues with any structure’ at OpenAI</li>
<li>The fact that Microsoft does not fully own OpenAI distinguished their deal in a pro-competitive way, according to Nadella</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/82fe2885-0760-4ede-8a50-6e322e78b818_940b6a88.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella at the World Economic Forum annual meeting in Davos, Switzerland on Tuesday. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella on Tuesday said he had no issue with partner OpenAI’s governance structure, two months after the start-up’s non-profit board temporarily ousted its chief executive without regard to investors’ interests.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3241992/chatgpt-maker-open-ai-pushes-out-co-founder-and-ceo-sam-altman-says-he-wasnt-consistently-candid" target="_self" title="">surprise November dismissal</a> of OpenAI’s CEO Sam Altman over an alleged communication breakdown triggered a crisis at the start-up behind ChatGPT, in which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242258/nearly-all-openai-staff-threaten-go-microsoft-unless-board-quits-investors-try-bring-back-altman" target="_self" title="">employees threatened to resign en masse</a> and go work for Microsoft, which is backing OpenAI with billions of dollars.</p><p>“I’m comfortable. I have no issues with any structure,” Nadella said at a Bloomberg News event on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum’s annual meeting in Davos.</p><p>OpenAI’s board, charged with protecting the start-up non-profit’s mission to develop powerful artificial intelligence that benefits humanity, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242394/microsoft-pushes-changes-openai-after-board-start-sought-merger-rival-anthropic" target="_self" title="">ultimately restored Altman</a> days later and now is in the process of filling out its membership.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1309" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/0651d6dd-f234-47b6-97b5-741fcb1f1268_28052076.jpg" title="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“I expect us to make a lot of progress on that in the coming months,” OpenAI CEO Altman said at a later Bloomberg event in Davos. “And then after that, the new board will take a look at the governance structure.”</p><p>“We’ll go look at it from all angles,” he said.</p><p>Microsoft has now secured a non-voting observer position on the OpenAI board.</p><p>Competition authorities in Europe, Britain and reportedly the United States have started looking closely at the Microsoft-OpenAI relationship. Their agreement guarantees the Windows maker large chunks of the start-up’s profits depending on certain conditions, a person briefed on the terms has said.</p><p>According to Nadella, the fact that Microsoft does not fully own OpenAI distinguished their deal in a pro-competitive way.</p><p>“Partnerships is one avenue of, in fact, having competition,” he said.</p><p>Microsoft’s investments in computing power and years-old bet on OpenAI before its ChatGPT fame, Nadella said, were a “highly risky bet” and “not all conventional wisdom”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with widening iPhone discounts, but rival Huawei stays above the fray</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary:</h2>  Apple's iPhone sales in China face fierce competition from local brands and weak consumer sentiment. Despite price discounts, iPhone sales in China fell by 30% in the first week of 2023. However, Apple surpassed Samsung to become the world's top smartphone vendor in 2023.  Huawei's return to the premium smartphone market challenges Apple, but the company faces supply shortages for its Mate 60 Pro model.  Amidst the price war, Huawei's brand strength will be crucial in weathering the challenges posed by Apple and other Chinese rivals.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Price wars intensify in China's smartphone market as Apple and Chinese brands compete for market share.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's iPhone sales in China decline amid competition and weak consumer sentiment, Huawei's return to the premium segment adds pressure.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of brand strength and marketing strategies in driving smartphone sales in China, the impact of macroeconomic factors on consumer spending.</li>    <li>Main information: iPhone discounts in China, Huawei's Mate 60 Pro launch and supply constraints, Apple's global smartphone shipment growth, rivalry among top smartphone brands.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果iPhone在中国市场面临来自本土品牌的激烈竞争和消费者购买意愿低迷的挑战，即使降价，2023年第一周中国大陆的iPhone销售额仍同比下滑30%。不过，苹果在2023年依旧力压三星成为全球第一大智能手机供应商。华为重返高端手机市场对苹果形成挑战，但Mate 60 Pro机型供应不足。在价格战中，华为的品牌力量对于应对苹果和其他中国竞争对手的挑战至关重要。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国智能手机市场价格战加剧，苹果与中国品牌争夺市场份额。</li>    <li>主题：苹果iPhone在中国市场销量下滑，竞争激烈且消费者购买意愿低迷，华为重返高端手机市场增加压力。</li>    <li>观点：品牌实力和营销策略对推动中国智能手机销量的意义，宏观经济因素对消费者支出的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：iPhone在中国降价、华为Mate 60 Pro发布和供应不足、苹果全球智能手机出货量增长、顶级智能手机品牌的竞争。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>markdown (n.) - 降价商品。    <p>原文例句：The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns.  </p>    <p>例句讲解：markdown一词由mark（标记）和down（向下）组成，表示“降低价格”，“降价商品”。在这个例句中，它指的是iPhone的降价促销活动，即各大中国智能手机厂商在线上和线下零售活动中降低其各种安卓手机的价格。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Android (n.) - 机器人；安卓系统，一种手机操作系统。    <p>原文例句：The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns.  </p>    <p>例句讲解：Android一词来源于古希腊语，原意为“像男人一样”，后来发展为“机器人”。同时，也被谷歌公司用来给自己的手机系统命名，在国内也称为安卓系统，是一种基于Linux的自由及开放源代码的操作系统。在这个例句中，它指的是安卓手机，即各大中国智能手机厂商的各种安卓手机。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>on the mainland - 在大陆（中国）。    <P>原文例句：Apple unseated rival Samsung Electronics in annual industry shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这是一个介词词组，表示“在中国大陆”，用于指代中国大陆地区。在这个例句中，它表示Apple在2023年全球年出货量上首次超越竞争对手三星电子，成为全球第一大智能手机供应商。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company’s new 5G smartphone and its advanced chip was hailed as symbolic of China’s victory in defying tough US sanctions, fanning strong patriotic fervour that translated into robust domestic sales. - 该公司的这款新的5G智能手机和先进芯片被誉为是中国战胜严峻美国制裁的象征，激发了强烈的民族热情，转化为强劲的国内销售。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company’s new 5G smartphone and its advanced chip was hailed as symbolic of China’s victory in defying tough US sanctions，其中主语是The company’s new 5G smartphone and its advanced chip，谓语是was hailed，宾语是symbolic of China’s victory in defying tough US sanctions。fanning strong patriotic fervour that translated into robust domestic sales是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰The company’s new 5G smartphone and its advanced chip，表示该公司的这款新的5G智能手机和先进芯片被誉为是中国战胜严峻美国制裁的象征，激发了强烈的民族热情，转化为强劲的国内销售。这个句子的意思是说，该公司的这款新的5G智能手机和先进芯片被誉为是中国战胜严峻美国制裁的象征，激发了强烈的民族热情，转化为强劲的国内销售。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作定语 - 用于修饰名词或代词，使其意义更加具体和详细。    <p>原文例句：Apple unseated rival Samsung Electronics in annual industry shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见句型，表示某人或某物在某时间或某段时间内所做的事情或所处状态。结构是：主语 + 谓语 + 时间状语。其中主语是某人或某物，谓语是动词，时间状语表示某时间或某段时间。在这个例句中，主语是Apple，谓语是unseated，时间状语是in annual industry shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023，表示Apple在2023年全球年出货量上首次超越竞争对手三星电子，成为全球第一大智能手机供应商。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作定语 - 用于修饰名词或代词，使其意义更加具体和详细。    <p>原文例句：The company’s new 5G smartphone and its advanced chip was hailed as symbolic of China’s victory in defying tough US sanctions, fanning strong patriotic fervour that translated into robust domestic sales. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个复杂句，表示某人或某物在过去某个时间或某段时间内所做的事情或所处状态。结构是：主语 + 谓语 + 时间状语 + 过去分词短语。其中主语是某人或某物，谓语是动词，时间状语表示过去某个时间或某段时间，过去分词短语是动词的过去分词形式，表示某人或某物在过去某个时间或某段时间内所做的事情或所处状态。在这个例句中，主语是The company’s new 5G smartphone and its advanced chip，谓语是was hailed，时间状语是in annual industry shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023，过去分词短语是fanning strong patriotic fervour that translated into robust domestic sales，表示该公司的这款新的5G智能手机和先进芯片被誉为是中国战胜严峻美国制裁的象征，激发了强烈的民族热情，转化为强劲的国内销售。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com on Monday touted discounts of as much as US$112 off on the iPhone 15, higher than Apple’s own local price markdown</li>
<li>Apple topped global smartphone shipments in 2023 to unseat long-standing market leader Samsung, according to research firm IDC</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/66dac82e-619d-4ada-b6cc-c633141a8133_2a932251.jpg" /><figcaption>The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>A price war in mainland China, the world’s largest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> market, has intensified amid widening discounts offered for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhones</a> by online marketplaces, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> unseated rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> in annual industry shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023.</p><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> on Monday touted deeper discounts of as much as 800 yuan (US$112.24) off on the latest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3235981/apple-iphone-15-review-faster-cheaper-new-standard-models-are-big-jump-over-their-predecessors" target="_self" title="">iPhone 15</a> model in a post on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a>, which was on the same day <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248529/apples-china-price-cuts-iphones-macbooks-cancel-out-pressure-rivals-chasing-premium-segment-say" target="_self" title="">Apple offered to cut prices by up to 500 yuan</a> on a range of models, including the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3148864/apples-iphone-13-may-not-have-many-new-features-its-lower-price-tag" target="_self" title="">iPhone 13</a> and its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235532/apples-iphone-15-draws-long-lines-china-despite-competition-huawei" target="_self" title="">new handsets that debuted last September</a>.</p><p>The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honor" target="_self" title="">Honor</a>, knocked down prices on their various Android models in both online and offline retail campaigns. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, which last year <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china" target="_self" title="">made a comeback in the 5G smartphone market</a>, did not pursue a similar strategy.</p><p>Apple’s atypical discount drive on the mainland shows the US tech giant’s focus to gain ground in the world’s second-biggest economy amid sluggish global iPhone sales, which has seen the company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">hit by two ratings downgrades</a> in the first week of this year.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/49690f1b-f395-4601-bae1-959ea30c7d93_ca1ba25a.jpg" title="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Apple faced more challenges in China compared to the rest of the world,” said Will Wong, senior research manager for client devices at IDC Asia-Pacific. “It not only faced competition from Huawei, but also a change in consumers’ sentiment that is now more cautious in spending.”</p><p>In the first week of the year, iPhone sales on the mainland were already down 30 per cent year on year, according to a Jefferies research note published on January 7. The brokerage indicated that there was “a big rise in discounts” for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3209228/apple-cuts-iphone-14-prices-china-us125-making-rare-sales-push-following-quarterly-revenue-drop" target="_self" title="">iPhone 14</a> and 14 Plus models, while the newer iPhone 15 and 15 Plus models saw “a moderate rise” in discounts.</p><p>The iPhone’s total sales volume last year on the mainland was down 3 per cent from 2022, which translated to a 0.4 per cent decline in Apple’s market share, according to Jefferies.</p><p>Worries about smartphone demand have pushed Apple’s shares down this month, enabling <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft</a> to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248395/microsoft-overtakes-apple-worlds-most-valuable-company-us289-trillion-market-capitalisation" target="_self" title="">become the world’s most valuable company</a> after ending the January 12 trading session in the US higher than the iPhone maker.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248395/microsoft-overtakes-apple-worlds-most-valuable-company-us289-trillion-market-capitalisation" title="">Microsoft overtakes Apple as world’s most valuable company at US$2.89 trillion</a></h3><p>Still, Apple received some good news on Monday when research firm IDC reported that the Cupertino, California-based company topped global smartphone shipments last year to dethrone long-standing market leader Samsung.</p><p>Apple’s global smartphone shipments last year reached 234.6 million units that gave the company a record market share of 20.1 per cent, up 3.7 per cent from 226.3 million in 2022, according to IDC. Apple was also the sole smartphone vendor in the top-four rankings – including Samsung, Xiaomi and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> – to record unit shipment growth in 2023.</p><p>On the intense global smartphone competition, the “overall Android space is diversifying within itself”, said Ryan Reith, group vice-president at IDC’s Worldwide Mobility and Consumer Device Trackers unit. “Huawei is back and making inroads quickly within China.”</p><p>Shenzhen-based Huawei’s return to the premium segment of the smartphone market was paved by its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china" target="_self" title="">launch last August of the Mate 60 Pro 5G handset</a>, powered by an advanced home-grown processor that defied US tech restrictions. The company’s new 5G smartphone and its advanced chip was hailed as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">symbolic of China’s victory in defying tough US sanctions</a>, fanning strong patriotic fervour that translated into robust domestic sales.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain" title="">Huawei’s Mate 60 Pro is a blow to US sanctions but battles remain, analysts say</a></h3><p>Huawei, however, faces a supply shortage for the Mate 60 Pro because of production constraints. The popular 5G model is still subject to a reservation purchase scheme without immediate availability on the company’s official website.</p><p>As Apple and its Chinese rivals turn to price promotions amid the weak macroeconomic environment on the mainland, Huawei will need to rely on the strength of its brand name to weather these headwinds, according to IDC’s Wong.</p><p>“The production constraints seem like a hurdle to Huawei, but it may also be a marketing tactic [to create greater demand],” Wong said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>HashKey claims ‘unicorn status’ after raising US$100 million for one of Hong Kong’s two licensed cryptocurrency exchanges</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248601/hashkey-claims-unicorn-status-after-raising-us100-million-one-hong-kongs-two-licensed-cryptocurrency</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong-based HashKey Group, a cryptocurrency exchange, has raised US$100 million in a Series A funding round, valuing the company at over US$1 billion, making it a unicorn company.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>总部位于香港的加密货币交易所HashKey Group在A轮融资中筹集了1亿美元资金，使公司的估值超过10亿美元，成为一家独角兽公司。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unicorn company (n.) - 独角兽公司，指估值超过10亿美元的初创公司。    <p>原文例句：HashKey Group, the company behind one of Hong Kong’s two cryptocurrency exchanges approved to serve retail investors, said it raised nearly US$100 million in a funding round that valued it at more than US$1 billion, making it a so-called unicorn company.</p>    <p>例句讲解：unicorn是“独角兽”的意思，company是“公司”的意思，unicorn company就是“独角兽公司”。这个词语用来形容估值超过10亿美元的初创公司，因为独角兽是一种稀有的生物，所以用它来形容估值超过10亿美元的初创公司，寓意其稀缺性和价值。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Series A round (n.) - A轮融资，指初创公司在获得种子轮融资后进行的下一轮融资。    <p>原文例句：Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, HashKey Group said</p>    <p>例句讲解：Series A round是“A轮融资”的意思，是初创公司在获得种子轮融资后进行的下一轮融资。Series是“系列”的意思，A是字母表的第一个字母，所以Series A round就是“A轮融资”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>virtual asset (n.) - 虚拟资产，指数字形式存在的资产，如加密货币、数字货币等。    <P>原文例句：What does Hong Kong mean by virtual assets?</P>    <p>例句讲解：virtual是“虚拟的”意思，asset是“资产”的意思，virtual asset就是“虚拟资产”。这个词语指的是数字形式存在的资产，如加密货币、数字货币等。香港证监会将虚拟资产定义为“任何以电子形式表示的价值，可以交易、转移或存储，并且不是法定货币”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>HashKey Group, the company behind one of Hong Kong’s two cryptocurrency exchanges approved to serve retail investors, said it raised nearly US$100 million in a funding round that valued it at more than US$1 billion, making it a so-called unicorn company. - HashKey Group是香港获准为散户投资者提供服务的两家加密货币交易所之一，该公司表示，在估值超过10亿美元的融资中筹集了近1亿美元资金，成为了一家独角兽公司。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是HashKey Group raised nearly US$100 million in a funding round，其中主语是HashKey Group，谓语是raised，宾语是nearly US$100 million in a funding round。that valued it at more than US$1 billion是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰funding round，表示这一融资将公司的估值提高到了10亿美元以上。making it a so-called unicorn company是一个现在分词短语作结果状语，表示这一融资使HashKey Group成为了一家独角兽公司。这个句子的意思是说，HashKey Group是香港获准为散户投资者提供服务的两家加密货币交易所之一，该公司表示，在估值超过10亿美元的融资中筹集了近1亿美元资金，成为了一家独角兽公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句 - 强调句主要用于强调句子中的某个成分，强调句有两种形式：<br>(1) It is/was + 被强调成分 + that/who + 其他成分。<br>(2) 被强调成分 + it is/was (that/who) + 其他成分。    <p>原文例句：It is worth noting that the exchange has only been operating for a little over a year, yet it has already attracted a significant number of users and a substantial amount of trading volume.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子是一个强调句，强调的是the exchange这个成分。句子结构是：It is + 被强调成分 + that/who + 其他成分。It is是强调句的标志，worth noting是现在分词短语作表语，表示值得注意的是，that the exchange has only been operating for a little over a year, yet it has already attracted a significant number of users and a substantial amount of trading volume是对the exchange的强调。这个句子的意思是说，值得注意的是，该交易所仅仅运营了一年多一点，但它已经吸引了大量的用户和大量的交易量。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：HashKey Group, established in Hong Kong in 2018, was approved by the Securities and Futures Commission last August to serve retail investors under the city’s new regime for centralised cryptocurrency exchanges.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中的was approved表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，即HashKey Group从2018年成立以来一直被批准为零售投资者提供服务。was approved的结构是：be + 过去分词，其中be是助动词，过去分词是approve的过去分词形式。这个句子的意思是说，HashKey Group是2018年在香港成立的，去年8月被证券及期货事务监察委员会批准为零售投资者提供服务，即该集团从2018年成立以来一直被批准为零售投资者提供服务。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, HashKey Group said</li>
<li>OKX Ventures is one of the lead investors in HashKey’s funding round, Bloomberg reported</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/3db425dc-5d1c-4046-8dd8-4e916a7cbc11_056fab3a.jpg" /><figcaption>A view of HashKey Group’s booth during the 2021 Hong Kong FinTech Week at the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre on 3 November 2021. Photo: Shutterstock.</figcaption></figure><p>HashKey Group, the company behind one of Hong Kong’s two cryptocurrency exchanges approved to serve retail investors, said it raised nearly US$100 million in a funding round that valued it at more than US$1 billion, making it a so-called unicorn company.</p><p>Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, the Hong Kong-based company <a href="https://group.hashkey.com/en/newsroom/HashKey-Group-Series-A-Financing-Round" target="_self" title="">said in a statement</a> on Tuesday, without disclosing any names.</p><p>OKX Ventures, the investment arm of OKX, one of the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchanges and an applicant for Hong Kong’s virtual asset exchange license, is one of the lead investors in HashKey’s funding round, Bloomberg reported. HashKey and OKX both declined to comment.</p><p>HashKey operates the licensed HashKey Exchange, the HashKey Capital venture capital and asset management arm and other blockchain technology services. It will use the funding to “solidify” its web3 ecosystem, diversify its licensed product offerings in Hong Kong and develop its business globally, it said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246047/chinas-crypto-craving-back-door-binance-traders-look-more-important-exchanges-future-wake-us" title="">China’s back-door cryptocurrency traders look more important than ever to Binance’s future</a></h3><p>HashKey Group, established in Hong Kong in 2018, was approved by the Securities and Futures Commission <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3229913/hashkey-and-osl-receive-hong-kongs-first-approvals-operate-crypto-exchanges-retail-investors" target="_self" title="">last August</a> to serve retail investors under the city’s new regime for centralised cryptocurrency exchanges.</p><p>The exchange attracted 15,500 registered users at the end of 2023, with daily trading volume exceeding US$630 million in December, HashKey said last month. Nearly 40 per cent of the value traded on its platform came from professional investors, it said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3201697/what-are-virtual-assets-hong-kong-and-what-do-citys-new-rules-mean-crypto-trading" title="">What does Hong Kong mean by virtual assets?</a></h3><p>HashKey Exchange handled US$15.3 million in trading volume over 24 hours through Tuesday, according to the market tracker CoinGecko. That is a trickle compared with the US$13.6 billion transacted over the same period on Binance, the world’s largest exchange for cryptocurrencies.</p><p>HashKey is one of a range of cryptocurrency firms banking on Hong Kong’s push to embrace the virtual asset industry, even as public perception of the sector has plunged following scandals involving companies including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ftx" target="_self" title="">FTX</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jpex-cryptocurrency-scandal" target="_self" title="">JPEX</a>.</p><p>Twelve companies have so far submitted their applications for Hong Kong’s licence for virtual asset trading platforms.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3237817/hong-kongs-crypto-hub-dream-mired-high-costs-other-barriers-one-year-jpex-one-stumbling-block" title="">High costs cloud Hong Kong’s crypto hub dream</a></h3><p>Venture capital funding in the cryptocurrency industry plunged last year following a series of collapses in 2022. In the three months ending September 2023, cryptocurrency firms around the world raised US$1.8 billion across 309 deals, representing a 69.6 per cent decline in deal value and 55.9 per cent drop in deal numbers from the same period a year ago, according to data by PitchBook.</p><p>The market recently bounced back on the back of enthusiasm brought by the US’ approval of the first spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs), which allow investors to gain exposure to virtual assets without directly buying any cryptocurrency tokens.</p><p>Hong Kong last month also said that it will move to open up retail access to cryptocurrency spot ETFs, after previously only allowing retail participation in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3203539/crypto-futures-etfs-debut-hong-kong-lukewarm-interest-after-market-turmoil-ftx-collapse?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">cryptocurrency futures ETFs</a>, which hold cryptocurrency futures contracts, instead of direct investments in cryptocurrency tokens at their spot prices.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech war: Chinese chip-tool giant Naura forecasts surge in 2023 sales on strong local demand amid US export controls</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3248610/tech-war-chinese-chip-tool-giant-naura-forecasts-surge-2023-sales-strong-local-demand-amid-us-export</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  China's Advanced Semiconductor Equipment giant Naura Technology expects a revenue surge by half and net profit growth by 57% to 80% in 2023, buoyed by technology breakthroughs and increased market share. The company's innovations in etching, deposition, cleaning, and furnace equipment for semiconductor manufacturing have bolstered its dominance.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Naura Technology anticipates remarkable growth in revenue and net profit through technological advancements, catering to the domestic semiconductor market.</li>    <li>Theme: Amid an exodus of foreign semiconductor manufacturers from China, domestic players like Naura seize the opportunity to capture a larger market share by offering competitive alternatives.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Naura's technological breakthroughs and market expansion reflect the growing strength of China's semiconductor industry, driven by government initiatives for self-sufficiency.</li>    <li>Main information: Naura's projected revenue range, projected net profit range, new equipment orders, major clients, and competitive landscape in the domestic semiconductor market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国先进的半导体设备巨头纳芯科技预计，2023年收入将增长一半，净利润将增长57%至80%，这得益于其技术突破和增加的市场份额。该公司在半导体制造所需的蚀刻、沉积、清洗和炉子设备方面的创新，巩固了其主导地位。  <ul>    <li>摘要：纳芯科技通过技术进步，迎合国内半导体市场的需求，预计收入和净利润将显著增长。</li>    <li>主题：随着外国半导体制造商纷纷撤出中国，纳芯科技等国内企业抓住机遇，提供有竞争力的替代品，抢占更大的市场份额。</li>    <li>观点：纳芯科技的技术突破和市场扩张反映了中国半导体产业的日益强大，这得益于政府的自主化倡议。</li>    <li>主要信息：纳芯科技预计的收入范围、预计的净利润范围、新设备订单、主要客户以及国内半导体市场的竞争格局。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>surge (v.) - /sɜːdʒ/ 激增，急剧增加。    <p>原文例句：Naura Technology Group expects its 2023 revenue to jump by around half from a year earlier, as leaps in its technology helped it gain a larger market share in the country.</p>    <p>例句讲解：surge在这里作名词，意为“激增，急剧增加”。在这个例子中，它指的是纳芯科技预计其2023年的收入将比去年增加一半左右。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>forecast (v./n.) - /ˈfɔːrˌkæst/ 预测，预报。    <p>原文例句：Naura said in a regulatory filing on Monday evening that its revenue last year is projected to grow between 42 per cent and 57 per cent to 20.9 billion yuan and 23.1 billion yuan (US$2.93 billion and US$3.24 billion).</p>    <p>例句讲解：forecast在这里作动词，意为“预测，预报”。在这个例子中，forecast可以理解为“预计”。Naura预计其去年的收入将在42%至57%之间增长，达到209亿至231亿元人民币之间（29.3亿至32.4亿美元）。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>niche (n.) - /niːʃ/ 利基，专门市场。    <p>原文例句：Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment China, Naura’s main rival, has said it expects 2023 revenue to rise more than 30 per cent on the back of strong demand from mainland fabs.</p>    <p>例句讲解：niche在这里作名词，意为“利基，专门市场”。在这个例子中，niche可以理解为“市场空白”、“市场机会”。纳芯科技的主要竞争对手先进微电子设备有限公司表示，预计2023年的收入将增长30%以上，这得益于来自中国大陆晶圆厂的强劲需求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>jump by - 增长，增加。    <p>原文例句：Naura Technology Group expects its 2023 revenue to jump by around half from a year earlier, as leaps in its technology helped it gain a larger market share in the country.</p>    <p>例句讲解：jump by在这里可以理解为“增长”、“增加”。纳芯科技预计其2023年的收入将比去年增加一半左右。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>take the lead in - 带头，引领。    <p>原文例句：Naura Technology Group expects its 2023 revenue to jump by around half from a year earlier, as leaps in its technology helped it gain a larger market share in the country.</p>    <p>例句讲解：take the lead in在这里可以理解为“带头”、“引领”。纳芯科技预计其2023年的收入将比去年增加一半左右，这得益于其技术上的飞跃，使其在国内市场获得了更大的份额。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 在……方面。    <p>原文例句：Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment China, Naura’s main rival, has said it expects 2023 revenue to rise more than 30 per cent on the back of strong demand from mainland fabs.</p>    <p>例句讲解：in terms of在这里可以理解为“在……方面”。纳芯科技的主要竞争对手先进微电子设备有限公司表示，预计2023年的收入将增长30%以上，这得益于来自中国大陆晶圆厂的强劲需求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Naura Technology Group expects last year’s sales to grow by roughly half. - 纳芯科技集团预计去年的销售额将增长约一半。    <p>句子分析：This sentence is in the simple future tense and expresses the company's expectation for its sales growth in the previous year. "Naura Technology Group" is the subject, "expects" is the verb, "last year’s sales" is the object, and "to grow by roughly half" is the infinitive phrase expressing the expected growth.</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The company said in a regulatory filing on Monday evening that its revenue last year is projected to grow between 42 per cent and 57 per cent to 20.9 billion yuan and 23.1 billion yuan. - 该公司在周一晚间的监管文件中表示，预计去年收入将增长42%至57%，达到209亿至231亿元人民币。    <p>句子分析：This sentence is in the past tense and reports the company's statement about its projected revenue growth. "The company" is the subject, "said" is the verb, "in a regulatory filing on Monday evening" is a prepositional phrase indicating when and where the statement was made, "that its revenue last year is projected to grow between 42 per cent and 57 per cent to 20.9 billion yuan and 23.1 billion yuan" is the object clause expressing the projected growth.</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>介词短语 - 由介词和介词宾语组成的短语，用来修饰动词、形容词或其他副词。    <p>原文例句：Naura Technology Group said in a regulatory filing on Monday evening that its revenue last year is projected to grow between 42 per cent and 57 per cent to 20.9 billion yuan and 23.1 billion yuan. - 该公司在周一晚间的监管文件中表示，预计去年收入将增长42%至57%，达到209亿至231亿元人民币。</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中，“in a regulatory filing on Monday evening”是一个介词短语，修饰动词“said”。表示“在周一晚间的监管文件中”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语 - 由过去分词和修饰语组成的短语，用来修饰名词或代词。    <p>原文例句：The company said in a regulatory filing on Monday evening that its revenue last year is projected to grow between 4  <ul><li>Naura Technology expects a jump in both its revenue and net profit in 2023, as technology breakthroughs drive local demand</li>
<li>With foreign semiconductor equipment manufacturers pulling out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/dc40cd20-632e-4e89-9957-bc5f891f0b1e_628de1bf.jpg" /><figcaption>Naura Technology Group expects last year’s sales to grow by roughly half. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>State-backed Chinese semiconductor equipment giant Naura Technology Group expects its 2023 revenue to jump by around half from a year earlier, as leaps in its technology helped it gain a larger market share in the country.</p><p>The company said in a regulatory filing on Monday evening that its revenue last year is projected to grow between 42 per cent and 57 per cent to 20.9 billion yuan and 23.1 billion yuan (US$2.93 billion and US$3.24 billion).</p><p>“[Naura] has made technology breakthroughs and achieved volume production of more than a dozen of semiconductor equipment including etching, deposition and cleaning, and furnace, which help the company to cover more semiconductor manufacturing processes, leading to higher market shares,” Naura said.</p><p>Net profits are expected to increase between 57 per cent and 80 per cent to between 3.3 billion yuan and 3.8 billion yuan.</p><p>The company said it received over 30 billion yuan worth of new equipment orders in 2023, over 70 per cent of them related to semiconductor-related tools. It did not disclose similar figures in its revenue forecasts for 2022 or 2021.</p><p>Beijing-based Naura counts China’s largest foundries as major clients, such as Yangtze Memory Technologies Corp (YMTC).</p><p>Amid a government-supported semiconductor self-sufficiency drive, YMTC has been in talks with domestic tool suppliers, including what was said to be a major company based in the Chinese capital, to produce replacements for crucial parts widely found in its equipment made by US firm Lam Research, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3235074/tech-war-chinas-top-memory-chip-maker-ymtc-forges-closer-ties-domestic-supplier-replace-us-parts" target="_self" title="">sources told the Post last year</a>.</p><p>Lam Research has suspended equipment supply and services to clients in mainland China after Washington tightened US export controls in October 2022.</p><p>With foreign players pulling their staff and operations out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives. The surging demand has helped lift sales of Chinese equipment manufacturers, although most of their products – especially those in advanced nodes below 10 nanometres – are thought to lag in quality.</p><p>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment China, Naura’s main rival, has said it expects 2023 revenue to rise more than 30 per cent on the back of strong demand from mainland fabs.</p><p>Shares of Shenzhen-listed Naura rose around 3 per cent to nearly 239 yuan in the morning trading session on Tuesday.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Microsoft launches consumer version of Copilot for US$20 a month with access to ChatGPT technology through Office</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248564/microsoft-launches-consumer-version-copilot-us20-month-access-chatgpt-technology-through-office</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Microsoft is making its Copilot artificial intelligence tool available to consumers and smaller companies. The consumer version, called Copilot Pro, costs US$20 per month and offers access to OpenAI's latest ChatGPT technology and image-creation features. Consumers with a cloud subscription to Office can use Copilot to help answer questions, summarize data, and create content in Word, Outlook, Excel, and PowerPoint. Microsoft is also getting rid of the 300-subscription minimum for its enterprise service.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Microsoft's Copilot Pro brings AI assistance to Office for consumers and small businesses.</li>    <li>Theme: Microsoft's efforts to expand the reach of its Copilot artificial intelligence tool.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The growing demand for AI assistance in productivity tools and the importance of making it accessible to a wider range of users.</li>    <li>Main information: Copilot Pro's features, pricing, and availability; Microsoft's plans to roll out a builder tool for creating custom Copilots; differences in privacy rules between the consumer and business versions.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  微软正向消费者和小公司开放其Copilot 人工智能工具。这个叫做Copilot Pro的消费者版本每个月需要付费20 美元，可以运用OpenAI 最新的人工智能语言模型ChatGPT 技术和图像生成功能。可以通过云订阅Office 的用户可以使用Copilot 来帮助回答问题、总结数据并在Word、Outlook、Excel和PowerPoint中创建内容。微软还取消了其企业服务的300订阅最低限额。  <ul>    <li>摘要：微软的Copilot Pro为消费者和小公司带来适用于Office的人工智能助理。</li>    <li>主题：微软努力扩大其Copilot人工智能工具的影响范围。</li>    <li>观点：生产工具中对人工智能助理的需求日益增长，以及让更广泛的用户可以使用的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：Copilot Pro的功能、定价和可用性；微软计划推出一个用于创建定制Copilot的构建器工具；消费者版和商业版在隐私规则上的差异。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>expand (v.) - /ɪkˈspænd/ 扩展，扩大。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft is expanding its artificial intelligence assistant to consumers and making the corporate version available to smaller companies as it tries to increase the number of paying customers for the new services. </p>    <p>例句讲解：expand表示“扩大，扩展”，它源自拉丁语，由ex-（出，离开）和pandere（张开，展开）组成。在这个例句中，它描述了微软正在将其人工智能助理扩展到消费者，并将企业版本提供给更小的公司，以增加新服务的付费客户数量。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>accessible (adj.) - /əkˈsɛsəbəl/ 可以访问的，易于获取的。    <p>原文例句：The Redmond, Washington-based software giant said in a statement that consumers with a cloud subscription to Office will be able to use Copilot to help answer questions, summarize data and create content in Word, Outlook, Excel and PowerPoint.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“accessible”在句中作后置定语，修饰data。accessible的意思是“接近的，容易接近的”，引申为“可理解的，容易读懂的”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>a portion of - 一部分，一部分。    <P>原文例句：Microsoft said it will retain a portion of prompts and responses from the consumer model to retrain models and improve the product. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由a（一个），portion（部分），of（属于）构成的，表示“一部分”。在这个例句中，它表示微软会保留一部分来自消费者模型的提示和回复，以便对模型进行再训练并改进产品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Consumers with a cloud subscription to Office will be able to use Copilot to help answer questions, summarise data and create content in Word, Outlook, Excel and PowerPoint. - 消费者可以通过云订阅Office来使用Copilot以帮助回答问题，总结数据，以及在Word、Outlook、Excel和PowerPoint中创建内容。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是Consumers will be able to use Copilot，其中主语是Consumers，谓语是will be able to use Copilot。with a cloud subscription to Office是一个介词短语作定语，修饰Consumers，表示这些消费者是通过云订阅Office的。to help answer questions, summarise data and create content in Word, Outlook, Excel and PowerPoint是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示Copilot可以帮助消费者回答问题、总结数据，以及在Word、Outlook、Excel和PowerPoint中创建内容。这个句子的意思是说，消费者可以通过云订阅Office来使用Copilot以帮助回答问题，总结数据，以及在Word、Outlook、Excel和PowerPoint中创建内容。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人对某件事的假设、愿望、建议等。    <p>原文例句：Spataro said that Microsoft plans to roll out a builder tool, similar to what OpenAI unveiled last year, that will let individuals create their own Copilots for a specific topic, a service that is already available to enterprises. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个使用虚拟语气”will let”的例子，表示微软计划推出一个类似于OpenAI去年推出的构建器工具，允许个人为特定主题创建自己的Copilot，这项服务目前已经对企业开放。虚拟语气通常用于表达说话人对某件事的假设、愿望、建议、许可或命令等。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>复合句 - 由两个或多个独立分句组成的句子。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft has been testing the Office-based copilot, now called Copilot for Microsoft 365, since March. The company began selling it widely in November, as long as companies purchased at least 300 subscriptions. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个复合句，由两个独立分句组成：Microsoft has been testing the Office-based copilot, now called Copilot for Microsoft 365, since March. 和The company began selling it widely in November, as long as companies purchased at least 300 subscriptions.。这两个分句之间用逗号隔开，并且它们都有自己的主语和谓语。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Consumers of Office will be able to use Copilot Pro to help answer questions and create content in Word, Outlook, Excel and PowerPoint</li>
<li>Companies previously had to buy at least 300 subscriptions to use Copilot, a requirement Microsoft is getting rid of</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/60d99f9f-7754-4b8a-9cd6-70a210df5cd6_c9e26244.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft has debuted a consumer version of its Copilot artificial intelligence tool. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure><p>Microsoft is opening up its artificial intelligence assistant to consumers and making the corporate version available to smaller companies as it tries to increase the number of paying customers for the new services.</p><p>Microsoft is selling a US$20-a-month consumer version of Copilot, with access to OpenAI’s latest ChatGPT technology and image-creation features, the Redmond, Washington-based software giant said in a statement.</p><p>Consumers with a cloud subscription to Office will be able to use Copilot to help answer questions, summarise data and create content in Word, Outlook, Excel and PowerPoint.</p><p>The company, which has been selling a similar product to large businesses for a monthly fee of US$30 per user, will get rid of the 300-subscription minimum for its enterprise service.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>As Microsoft has revamped nearly all of its products around artificial intelligence tools based on technology from OpenAI, its Office products remain one of the best ways to get customers to pay extra for AI assistance.</p><p>Executives have said demand is unusually high, with Azure chief Scott Guthrie likening it to the queues outside shops to purchase Windows 95 software nearly three decades ago.</p><p>Microsoft has been testing the Office-based copilot, now called Copilot for Microsoft 365, since March. The company began selling it widely in November, as long as companies purchased at least 300 subscriptions. That left out small businesses and those that wanted to begin with a smaller trial, said Jared Spataro, a Microsoft vice-president, in an interview.</p><p>“We have just never seen demand in the commercial space for a product like we are seeing for Copilot from Microsoft 365,’’ he said. “We have had pressure I have never seen from small and medium businesses saying ‘why will you not let us buy this? Let us try it’.”</p><p>Microsoft announced the new services ahead of the World Economic Forum in Davos, which will be attended by chief executive officer Satya Nadella.</p><p>Microsoft’s consumer service, called Copilot Pro, offers similar features to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3235800/openai-updates-chatgpt-ability-hear-and-speak-see-images-it-still-cannot-sing" target="_self" title="">OpenAI’s ChatGPT Plus</a> at the same price, though the integration with Office differentiates their product, Spataro said.</p><p>The company plans to roll out a builder tool, similar to what OpenAI unveiled last year, that will let individuals create their own Copilots for a specific topic, a service that is already available to enterprises.</p><p>Microsoft’s privacy rules for the consumer version also differ from the business one. Unlike data from corporate customers, Microsoft said it will retain a portion of prompts and responses from the consumer model to retrain models and improve the product.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>AirPods maker Goertek to open Vietnam factory as part of Apple’s supply chain diversification</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248542/airpods-maker-goertek-open-vietnam-factory-part-apples-supply-chain-diversification</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Goertek, an Apple supplier, plans to establish a wholly-owned subsidiary in Vietnam to manufacture consumer electronics products, driven by business expansion and long-term operation goals. The Vietnamese entity aims to enhance the company's overall competitiveness and cater to client demand, aligning with Goertek's future development strategy. This move is part of Apple's broader initiative to diversify its production outside China and mitigate reliance on a single country.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Goertek's subsidiary in Vietnam targets consumer electronics manufacturing.</li>    <li>Theme: Goertek's investment strategy aligns with Apple's diversification efforts.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of Vietnam as a manufacturing hub for Apple.</li>    <li>Main information: Goertek's investment in Vietnam; alignment with company's future plans; Apple's diversification strategy; impact of COVID-19 restrictions on Apple's supply chain.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  歌尔股份，苹果供应商，计划在越南建立全资子公司，生产消费类电子产品，以满足其业务扩展和长期运营的目标。越南实体旨在提高公司的整体竞争力并满足客户需求，与歌尔股份未来的发展战略相一致。此举是苹果更广泛的将生产多元化到中国以外并减少对单一国家依赖的举措的一部分。  <ul>    <li>摘要：歌尔股份在越南设立的子公司瞄准消费电子制造。</li>    <li>主题：歌尔股份的投资战略与苹果的多元化努力相一致。</li>    <li>观点：越南作为苹果制造业中心的意义。</li>    <li>主要信息：歌尔股份在越南的投资；与公司未来规划的契合；苹果的多元化策略；新冠肺炎限制措施对苹果供应链的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>subsidiary (n.) - /səbˈsɪdɪeri/ 子公司，分支机构。    <p>原文例句：Goertek said on Monday it would invest up to US$280 million to establish a wholly-owned subsidiary in Vietnam to meet demands for “business expansion and long-term operation” in the Southeast Asian nation, according to a corporate filing.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“subsidiary”是由sub-（在……之下）和sidere（坐下）组成的，表示“在……之下坐下”，引申为“子公司，分支机构”。在这个例句中，它是指歌尔股份在越南设立的全资子公司。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>diversify (v.) - /dɪˈvɜːsɪfaɪ/ 多样化，使多样化。    <p>原文例句：Since then, Apple has encouraged its contract manufacturing partners to diversify into other countries, including Vietnam, to reduce its reliance on China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“diversify”是由di-（分开）和versus（转向）组成的，表示“使变化，使多样化”。在这个例句中，它是指苹果鼓励其代工合作伙伴将业务多元化到包括越南在内的其他国家，以减少对中国的依赖。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Apple supplier BOE signs US$9 billion deal to build display plant in China</p>    <p>例句讲解：“in terms of”是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它是指苹果供应商京东方在中国的建厂项目。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company has been tapped by Apple to become one of the major mainland suppliers of its mixed-reality Vision Pro headset, which is set to launch in early February. - 该公司已被苹果选中，成为其混合现实Vision Pro头盔的主要大陆供应商之一，该头盔将于2月初发布。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company has been tapped by Apple to become one of the major mainland suppliers of its mixed-reality Vision Pro headset，其中主语是The company，谓语是has been tapped，宾语是one of the major mainland suppliers of its mixed-reality Vision Pro headset。which is set to launch in early February是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰headse，表示该头盔将于2月初发布。这个句子的意思是说，该公司已被苹果选中，成为其混合现实Vision Pro头盔的主要大陆供应商之一，该头盔将于2月初发布。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>一般过去时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Goertek said on Monday it would invest up to US$280 million to establish a wholly-owned subsidiary in Vietnam to meet demands for “business expansion and long-term operation” in the Southeast Asian nation, according to a corporate filing.</p>    <p>语法讲解：一般过去时是英语时态的一种，表示过去发生的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的完成性。结构是：主语 + 过去式动词（或助动词did + 动词原形）。在这个例句中，said是过去式动词，表示歌尔股份在星期一宣布将投资高达2.8亿美元在越南建立一家全资子公司，以满足东南亚国家“业务扩张和长期经营”的需求。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Goertek was tapped by Apple as one of the major mainland suppliers of its mixed-reality Vision Pro headset, which is set to launch in early February</li>
<li>The Vietnamese subsidiary is expected to be located in the Bac Ninh province, which has attracted investment from a raft of South Korean firms</li>
</ul><p>Apple supplier Goertek said on Monday it would invest up to US$280 million to establish a wholly-owned subsidiary in Vietnam to meet demands for “business expansion and long-term operation” in the Southeast Asian nation, according to a corporate filing.</p><p>Goertek’s Vietnamese entity, which will manufacture consumer electronics products, from AirPods and smartwatches to virtual reality and augmented reality gear, is a project that will meet both the Chinese assembler’s future development plan and client demand, it said in the filing to the Shenzhen Stock Exchange.</p><p>“[The project] is advantageous to make better use of local resources in Vietnam to enhance the company’s overall competitiveness,” Goertek said.</p><p>The company has been tapped by Apple to become one of the major mainland suppliers of its mixed-reality Vision Pro headset, which is set to launch in early February.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248092/apple-supplier-boe-one-worlds-top-display-makers-forges-us9-billion-deal-build-next-generation-plant" title="">Apple supplier BOE signs US$9 billion deal to build display plant in China</a></h3><p>The Vietnamese subsidiary, which will be set up through its Hong Kong entity Goertek (Hong Kong) Co, is expected to be located in northern Bac Ninh province, which has attracted investment from a raft of South Korean firms including consumer electronics and semiconductor giant Samsung Electronics.</p><p>South Korean firms have emerged as major investors in that province, setting up factories for electronics, smartphones, semiconductors and precision mechanical manufacturing equipment, according to the Vietnam Chamber of Commerce and Industry.</p><p>Goertek’s latest move comes as Apple is starting to shift more of its production outside China, a move that came after Beijing’s stringent Covid-19 restrictions during the pandemic disrupted the US firm's manufacturing supply chain, impacting its global sales in the lead up to the Christmas shopping season in 2022.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248044/huawei-secures-jdcom-harmonyos-partner-home-grown-software-emerges-alternative-apple-ios-android" title="">JD.com supports Huawei’s HarmonyOS as alternative for Apple iOS, Android in China</a></h3><p>Since then, Apple has encouraged its contract manufacturing partners to diversify into other countries, including Vietnam, to reduce its reliance on China.</p><p>Apple suppliers, including Taiwanese electronics contract manufacturer Foxconn Technology Group, have invested up to US$16 billion to reduce their dependence on China, by relocating facilities to India, Vietnam, Mexico as well as the US, according to a report by AppleInsider, citing research by investment bank TD Cowen.</p><p>Foxconn, formally known as Hon Hai Precision Industry and the world's biggest maker of iPhones, late last year announced a plan to invest US$1.6 billion in India to expand its presence in the South Asian nation.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
