<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Huawei ends US lobbying operations after years of fighting ban</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3248018/huawei-ends-us-lobbying-operations-after-years-fighting-ban</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei has ended its in-house lobbying operations in the United States, after years of trying to win over US policymakers.</li>    <li>The company's last two registered lobbyists have left in recent months, and it is no longer responding to requests for comment.</li>    <li>The shutdown of Huawei's lobbying operations marks the end of the company's costly efforts to maintain a presence in the US market.</li>    <li>Huawei has been banned from selling products in the US since 2022, and it has lost market share to Apple and other competitors.</li>    <li>The company is facing increasing pressure from the US government, which is concerned about its close ties to the Chinese government and its potential for espionage.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>多年来一直试图拉拢美国政策制定者的华为公司，已结束其在美国的内部游说活动。</li>    <li>该公司最近几个月其最后两名登记的游说者已经离职，并且不再回应任何评论请求。</li>    <li>华为关闭其游说活动标志着该公司为维持其在美国市场的业务所做出的代价高昂的努力的结束。</li>    <li>自 2022 年以来，华为就被禁止在美国销售产品，并且已经失去了对苹果和其他竞争对手的市场份额。</li>    <li>该公司正面临着美国政府的越来越大的压力，美国政府担心其与中国政府的密切关系及其潜在的间谍活动。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>payroll (n.) - /ˈpeɪrəʊl/ 薪资，工资单。</li>    <p>原文例句：At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由pay（工资）和roll（清单）组成，表示“薪资，工资单”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为在鼎盛时期雇佣了九家游说公司和一支庞大的公关代表队伍。</p>    <li>shun (v.) - /ʃʌn/ 躲避，回避。</li>    <p>原文例句：The firm reached its peak by supplying small mobile firms across the US even as major carriers shunned it.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语，表示“躲避，回避”。在这个例句中，它描述了华为通过向美国的小型移动公司提供设备而达到其顶峰，尽管主要运营商避开了它。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>shutter down - /ˈʃʌtər ˈdaʊn/ 关闭，停业。</li>    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies, the Chinese wireless equipment maker that spent tens of millions of dollars trying to win over US policymakers only to eventually be blacklisted, has shuttered its in-house lobbying operations in Washington.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由shutter（遮光板，快门）和down（向下）组成，表示“关闭，停业”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为关闭了其在华盛顿的内部游说部门。</p>    <li>even as - /ˈiːvən æz/ 即使，尽管。</li>    <p>原文例句：The firm reached its peak by supplying small mobile firms across the US even as major carriers shunned it.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由even（即使）和as（像……一样）组成，表示“即使，尽管”。在这个例句中，它描述了华为即使受到主要运营商的避开，也通过向美国的小型移动公司提供设备而达到其顶峰。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists there – Jeff Hogg and Donald Morrissey – left in recent months, Bloomberg News found.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Bloomberg News found，其中主语是Bloomberg News，谓语是found，宾语是Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists there – Jeff Hogg and Donald Morrissey – left in recent months。这个句子告诉我们，彭博新闻社发现，华为最后两位在当地的注册游说者——杰夫·霍格和唐纳德·莫里西——于最近几个月离职。</p>    <li>The company has lost outside lobbying firms as well. Imperium Global Advisors and LeMunyon Group terminated their contracts with Futurewei, Huawei’s US-based research arm, in November 2023, according to filings with the Senate.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company has lost outside lobbying firms as well，其中主语是The company，谓语是has lost，宾语是outside lobbying firms。这个句子告诉我们，该公司也失去了外部游说公司。 Imperium Global Advisors 和 LeMunyon Group 于 2023 年 11 月终止了与华为美国研究部门 Futurewei 的合同。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词作定语 - 用于修饰先行词，表示先行词的状态或特征。</li>    <p>原文例句：The departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, after a years-long effort to maintain a presence in North America.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个过去分词短语作定语，修饰先行词The departures，表示这些离职行为发生在华为多年努力维持在北美市场的业务之后，即这些离职行为是华为多年努力维持在北美市场的业务的结果。在句中起到定语的作用，表示这些离职行为的背景或原因。</p>    <li>被动语态 - 强调动作的承受者或接受者。</li>    <p>原文例句：Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists there – Jeff Hogg and Donald Morrissey – left in recent months, Bloomberg News found.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子采用了被动语态，其中谓语left用了过去分词形式，强调动作的承受者或接受者，即华为的最后两位注册游说者于最近几个月离职。使用被动语态的好处是它可以突出动作的承受者或接受者，而不是动作的执行者，从而使句子更具客观性和正式性。</p>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, after a years-long effort to maintain a presence in North America</li>
<li>At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/61065c57-e9bf-4bb0-a892-196dc21024cd_6e1ed843.jpg" /><figcaption>The Huawei logo is seen during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai, July 6, 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies, the Chinese wireless equipment maker that spent tens of millions of dollars trying to win over US policymakers only to eventually be blacklisted, has shuttered its in-house lobbying operations in Washington.</p><p>Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists there – Jeff Hogg and Donald Morrissey – left in recent months, Bloomberg News found. The Shenzhen, China-based firm did not respond to multiple requests for comment.</p><p>The lobbyists’ recent departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, and marks a quiet end to the company’s costly, years-long effort to maintain presence in the North American market. The firm reached its peak by supplying small mobile firms across the US even as major carriers shunned it. Rising tensions with Beijing eventually all but banned it.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" title="">Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets</a></h3><p>More than a decade ago, Washington officials began warning of Huawei’s ability to embed spying capabilities in its gear, which was present in thousands of cell towers and other network equipment in the US. The company pushed back on those claims, saying its products posed no threat, but American regulators by 2022 had barred the company from selling products in the US and moved to starve it of access to cutting-edge technology.</p><p>At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives. Executives were known to regularly arrange briefings with congressional offices and major newsrooms. The company spent more than US$13 million lobbying in the past 10 years, according to federal filings.</p><p>In a single quarter of 2019, Huawei’s federal lobbying spending totaled US$1.8 million, a six-fold increase from the previous year. It spent US$3.6 million on lobbying in the US in 2021, according to the filings. Some of that went to glitzy parties populated by high-profile hired guns including veteran Democratic lobbyist Tony Podesta, who made US$1 million from Huawei that year, according to disclosures with the US Senate. Podesta said in a filing that his work for Huawei ended on December 30, 2022.</p><p>With a ban firmly in place and its US business scant, Huawei has little reason to keep burning through lobbying cash in Washington. “The US market isn’t a likely place for a breakthrough for Huawei in the near future,” said Chris Pereira, a former Huawei public relations executive and founder of the consultancy iMpact.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/e55aff24-0f6a-4156-9c60-9d12d7c1fc31_ac707f82.jpg" title="A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Morrissey, who lobbied for both Huawei and Futurewei, confirmed in a LinkedIn message that he left the company in December. He said he is now the senior director of government affairs at the battery technology company Gotion. Hogg, who had served as Huawei’s head of government relations since 2020, left the company in November, according to his LinkedIn profile. He did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p>The company has lost outside lobbying firms as well. Imperium Global Advisors and LeMunyon Group terminated their contracts with Futurewei, Huawei’s US-based research arm, in November 2023, according to filings with the Senate. And Squire Patton Boggs, a global law firm, has not reported lobbying activity to Congress on Futurewei’s behalf since the beginning of 2023. Former US Representative Lee Terry, Republican of Nebraska, terminated his lobbying contract with Huawei at the end of 2022. according to filings with the Senate.</p><p>By October, the only firm registered as working on Huawei’s behalf was Sidley Austin, which did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p>Huawei itself has filed its own notice that it was terminating lobbying efforts at the Capitol. The company has also ceased operations at offices in Plano, Texas, Trey Smith, executive vice-president at CBRE, a real estate services firm that handles leases for the building, said in an email.</p><p>In response to Huawei’s ban, China’s government has accused the US of abusing state power to hobble Chinese companies. Huawei in recent months offered its own de facto response, producing a new phone using highly advanced technology the US has been trying to keep out of China’s hands. The company says revenue surged 9 per cent in 2023, in part thanks to the new phone.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s Taobao and Tmall Group pushes new AI tools to boost merchants’ service to consumers in first major move after leadership reshuffle</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247985/alibabas-taobao-and-tmall-group-pushes-new-ai-tools-boost-merchants-service-consumers-first-major</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Alibaba's Taobao and Tmall Group are utilizing AI tools to enhance merchant services and attract customers amid rising competition in China's e-commerce market. The AI-upgraded chatbot Dianxiaomi is being tested and will be available to all sellers by June, focusing on improving seller-consumer interaction and efficiency. TTG aims to provide more exposure to quality merchants and fend off competition from rivals like JD.com and emerging platforms.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Alibaba deploys AI to boost e-commerce services and competitive edge.</li>    <li>Theme: Enhancing customer experience and attracting new customers through AI-driven features.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Alibaba's strategic response to intensifying competition in China's e-commerce market.</li>    <li>Main information: Introduction of the AI-upgraded Dianxiaomi chatbot; increased exposure for quality merchants; revamped rating system for online shops.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  阿里巴巴旗下的淘宝天猫集团正通过采用人工智能工具来提升商家服务并吸引顾客，以应对日益激烈的中国电子商务市场竞争。人工智能升级的客服聊天机器人店小蜜正在测试中，并将于6月份向所有卖家开放，重点是改善卖家与消费者的互动和提高效率。TTG旨在为优质商家提供更多曝光，并抵御来自京东等竞争对手以及拼多多和抖音等新兴平台的挑战。  <ul>    <li>摘要：阿里巴巴部署人工智能以提升电子商务服务和竞争优势。</li>    <li>主题：通过人工智能驱动的功能增强客户体验并吸引新客户。</li>    <li>观点：阿里巴巴对中国电子商务市场竞争日益激烈的局势做出的战略回应。</li>    <li>主要信息：引入人工智能升级的店小蜜聊天机器人；增加对优质商家的曝光；为网店提供改进后的评级系统。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>initiative (n.) - /ɪˈnɪʃətɪv/ 首倡，主动。    <p>原文例句：The Taobao and Tmall Group’s AI initiative is geared towards helping merchants improve their services and attract new customers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语initium（开始），表示“开始，首倡，主动”。在这个例句中，它指的是淘宝天猫集团的人工智能倡议，旨在帮助商家改善服务并吸引新客户。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>repurchase (v.) - /ˌriːˈpɜːtʃeɪs/ 回购，再次购买。    <p>原文例句：The repurchase rate at five-star pet supply stores, for example, is about 127 per cent higher than those of 3-star peers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于re-（再）和purchase（购买），表示“再次购买，回购”。在这个例句中，它指的是五星级宠物用品商店的回购率，比三星级同行高出约127%。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fend off - 抵御，击退。    <p>原文例句：The Taobao and Tmall Group’s adoption of artificial intelligence tools shows the Alibaba Group Holding unit’s effort to fend off increased competition in China’s e-commerce market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由fend（抵御，击退）和off（远离，离开）构成的，表示“抵御，击退”。在这个例句中，它指的是淘宝天猫集团采用人工智能工具，表明阿里巴巴集团控股单元努力抵御中国电子商务市场日益激烈的竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in place - 已就位，已实施。    <p>原文例句：matching an option that budget online retailer Pinduoduo has had in place since 2021.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在，里面）和place（地方，位置）构成的，表示“已就位，已实施”。在这个例句中，它指的是匹配拼多多自2021年以来一直实施的“仅退款”政策选项。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The repurchase rate at five-star pet supply stores, for example, is about 127 per cent higher than those of 3-star peers. - 例如，五星级宠物用品商店的回购率比三星级同行高出约127%。<p>句子分析：这是一个比较句，句式是A is + 形容词/副词 + than B。其中A是The repurchase rate at five-star pet supply stores，B是those of 3-star peers。形容词higher表示“更高级的，更高的”。than表示“比……高”。这个句子的意思是说，五星级宠物用品商店的回购率比三星级同行高出约127%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由分词和其修饰语组成的短语。    <p>原文例句：The Taobao and Tmall Group’s adoption of artificial intelligence tools shows the Alibaba Group Holding unit’s effort to fend off increased competition in China’s e-commerce market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个分词短语，由分词adoption和其修饰语The Taobao and Tmall Group’s组成的。分词短语可以用来修饰名词或代词，在这个例句中，它用来修饰名词effort，表示The Taobao and Tmall Group采用人工智能工具这一动作。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用在从句中表示说话人对某事的看法或态度，而不是事实。    <p>原文例句：TTG said AI models would be employed to transform Dianxiaomi, a customer service chatbot, to enhance seller-consumer interaction.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气，would be employed表示“将会被采用”。虚拟语气通常用在从句中，表示说话人对某事的看法或态度，而不是事实。在这个例句中，it表示TTG说人工智能模型将会被采用来转换店小蜜，以增强卖家与消费者的互动。这并不是一个事实，而是一个看法或态度。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Taobao and Tmall Group’s AI initiative is geared towards helping merchants improve their services and attract new customers</li>
<li>An AI-upgraded customer service chatbot, Dianxiaomi, is expected to be available to all Taobao and Tmall sellers by June</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/a64d09cb-4f09-4901-b140-db8cdc3ed1d4_a2cf7620.jpg" /><figcaption>Taobao and Tmall Group’s adoption of artificial intelligence tools shows the Alibaba Group Holding unit’s effort to fend off increased competition in China’s e-commerce market. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>’s main <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> unit is now beta testing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) tools and functions for merchants on its Chinese online shopping sites, marking the first major move at the enterprise since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245680/alibaba-names-new-taobao-and-tmall-ceo-major-move-fend-competition" target="_self" title="">a leadership reshuffle in December</a>.</p><p>The Taobao and Tmall Group (TTG) unveiled the new AI features, which are designed to improve services and attract new customers, at its “sellers’ conference” held on Tuesday in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hangzhou" target="_self" title="">Hangzhou</a>, capital of eastern Zhejiang province and home base of South China Morning Post owner Alibaba.</p><p>TTG said AI models would be employed to transform Dianxiaomi, a customer service chatbot, to enhance seller-consumer interaction. That will include tasks such as pre- and post-sales service, data analysis and other online sales activities.</p><p>The updated Dianxiaomi, which is currently undergoing tests with a select group of sellers, will be made available to all merchants by June, according to TTG. It said the accuracy rate of Dianxiaomi’s response time has so far improved to 85 per cent.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/342c70b0-1832-40c4-bff8-11fa840de980_6cb4cf92.jpg" title="The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>TTG also vowed to provide “quality merchants” more exposure to consumers, from the homepage to advertised search results, TTG announced at the event.</p><p>TTG’s adoption of AI tools shows the effort being made by the Alibaba unit to fend off increased competition from main domestic rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> and the challenge from younger platforms, such as PDD Holdings’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="">Pinduoduo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>.</p><p>The move comes weeks after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245680/alibaba-names-new-taobao-and-tmall-ceo-major-move-fend-competition" target="_self" title="">Eddie Wu Yongming</a> was named the new chief executive at TTG, replacing Trudy Dai Shan. TTG subsequently <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals" target="_self" title="">promoted six millennial executives</a> to lead key departments.</p><p>Before TTG’s latest initiative, Alibaba’s international business-to-business wholesale marketplace <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" target="_self" title="">Alibaba.com in November announced a new AI tool</a> to help the platform’s merchants automate their client-facing operations, including writing emails, to entice more customers overseas.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" title="">Alibaba pushes new AI tool to help wholesale merchants manage overseas clients</a></h3><p>At the seller’s event in Hangzhou, TTG said internal statistics showed that five-star-rated sellers enjoy a significantly higher repurchase rate than certain 3-star stores on its platform. The repurchase rate at five-star pet supply stores, for example, is about 127 per cent higher than those of 3-star peers.</p><p>TTG on Tuesday also said it will launch a new rating system for online shops, focusing on indicators related to consumer services. These indicators include the “rejection rate of refund request” and “platform intervention rate”, which weigh on consumers’ purchasing decisions.</p><p>Late in December, both JD.com and Taobao said they will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" target="_self" title="">offer a “refund only” policy</a> so consumers can keep the goods they had bought but complained about – matching an option that budget online retailer Pinduoduo has had in place since 2021.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US regulator SEC authorises bitcoin-spot ETFs in cryptocurrency breakthrough</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>英语摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>美国证券交易委员会首次批准了直接投资比特币的交易所交易基金 (ETF)，此举被视为数字资产行业的一件具有里程碑意义的事件，将扩大对华尔街及其他地区最大加密货币的投资渠道。</li>    <li>此前，美国证券交易委员会曾在过去十多年里反对此类ETF，然而此次的批准标志着该机构的罕见让步。</li>    <li>美国证券交易委员会主席Gary Gensler表示，虽然批准了某些现货比特币ETP股份的上市和交易，但并未批准或认可比特币，投资者应警惕比特币以及价值与加密货币挂钩的产品所伴随的各种风险。</li>    <li>美国证券交易委员会此次批准基于多种时间间隔内现货和期货交易的相关性审查结果，认为价格变动方式表明，Kraken和Coinbase等交易所的异常情况很可能在期货市场显现。</li>    <li>在批准消息发布后，比特币价格上涨约 3.4%，至 47,500 美元。</li>    <li>加密货币支持者多年来一直认为，直接投资比特币的现货基金将有利于投资者，并有助于推动行业更加接近受高度监管的传统金融界。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>美国证券交易委员会首次批准了直接投资比特币的交易所交易基金（ETF），这是数字资产行业的一个里程碑事件，将扩大华尔街及其他地区对最大加密货币的投资渠道。</li>    <li>此前，美国证券交易委员会在十多年来一直反对此类ETF，此次的批准标志着该机构的罕见让步。</li>    <li>美国证券交易委员会主席加里·詹斯勒表示，虽然批准了某些现货比特币ETF股份的上市和交易，但并未批准或认可比特币，投资者应警惕比特币以及价值与加密货币挂钩的产品所伴随的各种风险。</li>    <li>美国证券交易委员会此次批准基于多种时间间隔内现货和期货交易的相关性审查结果，认为价格变动方式表明，Kraken和Coinbase等交易所的异常情况很可能在期货市场显现。</li>    <li>在批准消息发布后，比特币价格上涨约3.4%，至47,500美元。</li>    <li>加密货币支持者多年来一直认为，直接投资比特币的现货基金将有利于投资者，并有助于推动行业更加接近受高度监管的传统金融界。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>heralded (v.) - /ˈher.əld/ 宣布；预告。    <p>原文例句：The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“heralded”在这个例句中用作动词，意思是“宣布；预告”。它表示美国证券交易委员会在批准ETF的前一天，其X账户上出现了一篇虚假帖子，声称该机构已经批准了ETF。</p></li>    <li>correlation (n.) - /ˌkɒr.ɪˈleɪ.ʃən/ 相关性；关联。    <p>原文例句：In reviewing the latest set of proposals, the SEC said it examined the correlation between spot and futures trading at a variety of time intervals and concluded prices moved in such a way that irregularities on exchanges such as Kraken and Coinbase were likely to show up in the futures.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“correlation”在这个例句中用作名词，意思是“相关性；关联”。它表示美国证券交易委员会在审查最新一批提案时，研究了现货和期货交易在不同时间间隔内的相关性，并得出结论认为，价格的变动方式表明Kraken和Coinbase等交易所的异常情况很可能在期货市场中显现。</p></li>    <li>scrutiny (n.) - /ˈskruː.tɪ.ni/ 审查；检验。    <p>原文例句：“The approval means that both retail and institutional investors now have the ability to diversify their portfolio with crypto exposure without worrying about the complicated issues of custody,” said Campbell Harvey, finance professor at Duke University. “The ETF makes it easy to add to your portfolio.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：“scrutiny”在这个例句中用作名词，意思是“审查；检验”。它表示杜克大学金融学教授坎贝尔·哈维认为，ETF的批准意味着散户和机构投资者现在都可以通过加密货币敞口来分散投资组合，而无需担心复杂的托管问题。ETF使投资者可以轻松地将加密货币添加到投资组合中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>more than - 超过；不止。    <p>原文例句：The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade</p>    <p>例句讲解：“more than”在这个例句中用作词组，意思是“超过；不止”。它表示美国证券交易委员会批准ETF标志着该机构在持续了十多年的反对声中罕见地让步。</p></li>    <li>relative to - 相对而言；与……相比。    <p>原文例句：“Because the CME’s surveillance can assist in detecting those impacts on CME bitcoin futures prices, the exchanges’ comprehensive surveillance-sharing agreement with the CME – a US regulated market whose bitcoin futures market is consistently highly correlated to spot bitcoin, albeit not of ‘significant size’ relative to spot bitcoin – can be reasonably expected to assist in surveilling for fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices in the specific context of the proposals,” the order said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“relative to”在这个例句中用作词组，意思是“相对而言；与……相比”。它表示由于芝加哥商业交易所的监管可以帮助检测芝加哥商业交易所比特币期货价格受到的影响，因此可以合理地预期交易所与芝加哥商业交易所的全面监视共享协议——一个与现货比特币高度相关的美国受监管市场，尽管相对于现货比特币而言并不具有“显着的规模”——有助于监视提案的具体背景下的欺诈和操纵行为和做法。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs. - 这项决定是在美国证券交易委员会的X账户上出现一篇虚假帖子声称该机构已经批准ETF的第二天做出的。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The decision comes，其中主语是The decision，谓语是comes，宾语是the day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs。after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs是一个介词短语作定语，修饰The decision，表示这项决定是在美国证券交易委员会的X账户上出现一篇虚假帖子声称该机构已经批准ETF的第二天做出的。这个句子的意思是说，这项决定是在美国证券交易委员会的X账户上出现一篇虚假帖子声称该机构已经批准ETF的第二天做出的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：ETF that hold bitcoin future were approved in 2021.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时的例子，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。现在完成时表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it has been used表示从过去的2021年开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，即比特币期货ETF已经被批准。</p></li>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去的某个时间点之前已经发生或完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Crypto proponents have for years argued that a so-called spot fund that invests directly in bitcoin would be beneficial to investors and would help bring the industry closer to the more highly regulated world of traditional finance. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去完成时的例子，表示在过去的某个时间点之前已经发生或完成的动作或状态。结构是：had + been + 过去分词。过去完成时表示动作或状态在过去的某个时间点之前已经发生或完成，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，had been argued表示在过去的几年里一直持续到过去的某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态，即加密货币的支持  <ul><li>The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade</li>
<li>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/df6929be-b19f-4119-85e5-a531ae26273d_52ea2e34.jpg" /><figcaption>A bitcoin is seen in an illustration picture taken in Paris, France, June 23, 2017. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>US regulators for the first time approved exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that invest directly in bitcoin, a move heralded as a landmark event for the roughly US$1.7 trillion digital-asset sector that will broaden access to the largest cryptocurrency on Wall Street and beyond.</p><p>The Securities and Exchange Commission, whose three-part mandate includes investor protection, authorised funds from industry heavyweights BlackRock, Invesco and Fidelity to smaller competitors including Valkyrie to begin trading Thursday.</p><p>The approvals also mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade, ever since Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss first proposed a bitcoin ETF in 2013. BlackRock’s surprise application last June, followed by an appeals court ruling that called the denial of a different application “arbitrary and capricious,” triggered a blistering rally in the cryptocurrency as speculation that US regulators would finally give their blessing to the structure.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239953/hong-kongs-hashkey-launches-first-crypto-trading-app-retail-investors-gives-away-new-token" title="">Hong Kong gets first crypto trading app for retail investors</a></h3><p>“While we approved the listing and trading of certain spot bitcoin ETP shares today, we did not approve or endorse bitcoin,” SEC Chair Gary Gensler said in a statement. “Investors should remain cautious about the myriad risks associated with bitcoin and products whose value is tied to crypto.”</p><p>At the crux of the SEC’s previous rulings against a spot ETF was the argument that no regulated exchange was able to adequately monitor bitcoin trading in a way that would reliably detect fraud and manipulation. That contention was opposed by Cathie Wood’s Ark Investments, among others, which provided data showing a high correlation between cash trading and the futures contracts that trade on CME Group’s platform.</p><p>In reviewing the latest set of proposals, the SEC said it examined the correlation between spot and futures trading at a variety of time intervals and concluded prices moved in such a way that irregularities on exchanges such as Kraken and Coinbase were likely to show up in the futures.</p><p>“Because the CME’s surveillance can assist in detecting those impacts on CME bitcoin futures prices, the exchanges’ comprehensive surveillance-sharing agreement with the CME – a US regulated market whose bitcoin futures market is consistently highly correlated to spot bitcoin, albeit not of ‘significant size’ related to spot bitcoin – can be reasonably expected to assist in surveilling for fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices in the specific context of the proposals,” the order said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246909/crypto-services-firm-linked-huobi-sees-losses-expand-40-cent-ftx-funds-still-out-reach" title="">Losses mount at Huobi-linked crypto firm while FTX funds still out of reach</a></h3><p>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs. The regulator subsequently said that the account had been compromised, causing the price of bitcoin to fluctuate widely.</p><p>Gensler voted along side the agency’s two Republicans to back exchanges’ plans to list the products, the SEC’s website showed. The regulator’s two other Democrats voted against the proposals.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/9a0bebf2-048a-459e-9a2e-2dd720360177_a66cec46.jpg" title="The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Bitcoin rose about 3.4 per cent to US$47,500 following the approvals. The original cryptocurrency, which sank 64 per cent in 2022, more than doubled in 2023 in large part because of speculation that the SEC would eventually approve ETFs that will allow investors to get exposure to the token in their traditional brokerage accounts instead of one of the crypto-native start-ups that have come under increasing government scrutiny following a series of sector scandals and bankruptcies.</p><p>“The approval means that both retail and institutional investors now have the ability to diversify their portfolio with crypto exposure without worrying about the complicated issues of custody,” said Campbell Harvey, finance professor at Duke University. “The ETF makes it easy to add to your portfolio.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246538/china-calls-tougher-crackdown-use-crypto-illegal-forex-trading" title="">China calls for tougher crackdown on use of crypto for illegal forex trading</a></h3><p>Crypto proponents have for years argued that a so-called spot fund that invests directly in bitcoin would be beneficial to investors and would help bring the industry closer to the more highly regulated world of traditional finance. It also suggests a sort of milestone of maturity for the relatively nascent industry, where skirmishes with regulators came to a climax after the collapse of Sam Bankman-Fried’s FTX empire highlighted risks lurking in the industry.</p><p>The landmark decision comes after Grayscale Investments won a key victory over the SEC. A federal appeals court had overturned the rejection of Grayscale’s application to convert its bitcoin trust into an ETF. The court called the denial “arbitrary and capricious” because the commission failed to explain its different treatment of similar products. ETFs that hold bitcoin futures were approved in 2021.</p><p>The SEC’s loss to Grayscale was one of the reasons why the SEC approved the applications, Gensler said in Tuesday’s statement.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China rich list compiler Hurun clarifies Tsinghua graduate Zhang Zetian’s ranking to quell online controversy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247956/china-rich-list-compiler-hurun-clarifies-tsinghua-graduate-zhang-zetians-ranking-quell-online</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Hurun Research Institute clarified that Zhang Zetian, wife of tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, is the third-richest graduate of Tsinghua University, with a net worth of 8.4 billion US dollars, despite controversy over her ranking. Hurun's ranking of Tsinghua and Zhejiang University as the top producers of billionaire graduates in China generated discussion on social media, with some questioning Zhang's claimed wealth. Hurun explained that Zhang's wealth is jointly held with her husband, revealing a methodology that includes former students, postgraduates, and doctoral degree holders on the Hurun China Rich List 2023. Other Chinese billionaires like Baidu's Robin Li and Xiaomi's Lei Jun are also alumni of prestigious universities. The list showcased institutions like Stanford, MIT, and Harvard as top universities with many graduates on the Hurun China Rich List.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Controversy surrounds Zhang Zetian's ranking as the third-richest graduate of Tsinghua University, prompting Hurun's clarification.</li>    <li>Theme: Hurun's ranking highlights China's top universities producing billionaire graduates, including Tsinghua and Zhejiang University, as well as Zhang Zetian's prominent position.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The discussion highlights the scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China, challenging the authenticity of Zhang's massive wealth claims.</li>    <li>Main information: Hurun's methodology, including former students and entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees; Zhang's joint wealth with her husband; other notable graduates from prestigious universities; international institutions with graduates on the Hurun China Rich List.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  胡润研究院澄清，尽管张泽天作为中国科技亿万富翁刘强东的妻子，排名一度引起争议，但她的财富确实达到84亿美元，排在清华大学第三位最富有毕业生。胡润将清华大学和浙江大学列为培养亿万富翁毕业生最多的大学，在社交媒体上引发热议，一些人质疑张泽天所声称的财富。胡润解释说，张泽天的财富是她和丈夫共同拥有的，并揭示了一种方法，包括2023胡润中国富豪榜上的前学生、研究生和博士学位获得者。百度李彦宏和小米雷军等其他中国富豪也是名牌大学的校友。该榜单展示了斯坦福大学、麻省理工学院和哈佛大学等国际院校，其众多毕业生入选胡润中国富豪榜。  <ul>    <li>摘要：围绕张泽天作为清华大学第三富裕毕业生的排名引发争议，促使胡润做出澄清。</li>    <li>主题：胡润的排名突显了中国产生亿万富翁毕业生的顶级大学，包括清华和浙江大学，以及张泽天突出的地位。</li>    <li>观点：这次讨论突出了中国对个人财富和收入不平等的审查，挑战了张泽天声称的巨额财富的真实性。</li>    <li>主要信息：胡润的方法，包括前学生和拥有博士学位的企业家；张泽天和她丈夫的共同财富；其他名牌大学的杰出毕业生；胡润中国富豪榜上拥有毕业生的国际机构。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>claim (v.) - /kleɪm/ 声称，主张。    <p>原文例句：However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自古法语clamer（呼喊），意思是“大声说，宣称，主张”。在这个例句中，它指的是许多中国网民在社交媒体平台上质疑张是否真的拥有如此巨额的财富。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>controversy (n.) - /ˈkɑːntrəvərsi/ 争议，争论。    <p>原文例句：According to a separate rich list published by Forbes in November 2023, the net worth of Liu, founder and chairman of e-commerce giant JD.com, was US$4.7 billion, ranking No. 69 in China’s top 100 rich list.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词起源于拉丁语controversia，意为“争论，争议”。在这个例句中，它指的是根据福布斯于2023年11月发布的另一份富豪榜，刘强东作为电子商务巨头京东的创始人兼董事长，其净资产为47亿美元，位列中国百强富豪榜第69位。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>net worth - 净资产。    <p>原文例句：And 30-year-old Zhang was ranked as the third-richest graduate from Tsinghua, with a net worth of 60 billion yuan (US$8.4 billion).</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由net（净）和worth（价值）组成，表示“资产总值减去负债后的剩余价值”。在这个例句中，它指的是30岁的张被评为清华大学第三富有的毕业生，净资产为600亿元人民币（折合84亿美元）。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>social media platforms - 社交媒体平台。    <p>原文例句：However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由social（社会的），media（媒体）和platforms（平台）组成，表示“社交媒体平台”。在这个例句中，它指的是许多中国网民在社交媒体平台上质疑张是否真的拥有如此巨额的财富。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Zhang ranked behind 44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan and 62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group. - 张泽天在富豪榜上排名落后于44岁的王兴，他是外卖巨头美团的创始人，以及62岁的徐航，他是房地产开发商世茂集团的创始人。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Zhang，谓语是ranked behind，宾语是44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan and 62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group。44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan and 62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group是一个长长的主语，其中包括两个并列的成分，即44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan和62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group。这个句子的意思是说，张泽天在富豪榜上排名落后于44岁的王兴，他是外卖巨头美团的创始人，以及62岁的徐航，他是房地产开发商世茂集团的创始人。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>疑问词+动词 - 疑问句。    <p>原文例句：However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个疑问句，疑问词是whether，动词是owns。疑问句的结构是：疑问词+动词+主语+其他。在这个例句中，疑问词是whether，动词是owns，主语是Zhang。这个句子的意思是说，然而，许多中国网民在社交媒体平台上质疑张是否真的拥有如此巨额的财富。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>非限定性相对从句 - 提供额外信息。    <p>原文例句：According to a separate rich list published by Forbes in November 2023, the net worth of Liu, founder and chairman of e-commerce giant JD.com, was US$4.7 billion, ranking No. 69 in China’s top 100 rich list.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个非限定性相对从句，它提供了关于刘强东的信息。非限定性相对从句的结构是：关系代词/副词+先行词+逗号+句子。在这个例句中，关系代词是who，先行词是Liu，句子是founder and chairman of e-commerce giant JD.com。这个句子的意思是说，根据福布斯于2023年11月  <ul><li>According to Hurun, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China</li>
<li>Zhang ranked behind Meituan founder Wang Xing and Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/22f80ee8-51eb-4f11-94d0-38c9096e305d_32c40a21.jpg" /><figcaption>JD.com chairman Richard Liu Qiangdong and wife Zhang Zetian at Princess Eugenie’s wedding. Photo: YouTube </figcaption></figure><p>The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.</p><p>According to a list published by Hurun last Friday, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China. And 30-year-old Zhang was ranked as the third-richest graduate from Tsinghua, with a net worth of 60 billion yuan (US$8.4 billion).</p><p>Zhang ranked behind 44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan and 62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group. However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p><p>Hurun issued a statement on Monday to clarify its methodology for the ranking of rich Chinese alumni. “In the case of Tsinghua’s Zhang, her 60 billion yuan worth falls under her and [husband] Liu jointly.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239156/chinese-tech-founders-bounce-back-huruns-2023-rich-list-number-and-overall-wealth-billionaires-drop" title="">Chinese tech billionaires move up Hurun 2023 Rich List amid internet rebound</a></h3><p>The controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China. According to a separate rich list published by Forbes in November 2023, the net worth of Liu, founder and chairman of e-commerce giant JD.com, was US$4.7 billion, ranking No. 69 in China’s top 100 rich list.</p><p>Liu’s celebrity-style marriage to Zhang is also rare among Chinese tech billionaires, with many maintaining a low profile when it comes to family matters.</p><p>The Tsinghua alumni rich list was part of a Hurun Most Successful University Alumni 2023 ranking the research firm released. Hurun defined the “most successful alumni” to include former full-time undergraduates, postgraduates and those entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</p><p>A total of 58 universities, 45 Chinese and 13 overseas, have at least three alumni on the Hurun China Rich List 2023. Tsinghua and Zhejiang University topped the list, each with 32 alumni on the list.</p><p>Peking University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, and Wuhan University came in third, fourth and fifth with 22, 21, and 17 alumni respectively on the list.</p><p>Robin Li Yanhong, founder, chairman and CEO of Baidu, and Xiaomi chairman and CEO Lei Jun are two of the most high-profile and richest graduates to have come from Peking University and Wuhan University, respectively, according to the list.</p><p>Outside China, Stanford University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, University of California, Yale University and Harvard University from the US were the top five institutions with the most Hurun China Rich listers.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China augmented reality start-up Rokid gets US$70 million in new funding round led by Hefei government</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247968/china-augmented-reality-start-rokid-gets-us70-million-new-funding-round-led-hefei-government</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Rokid, a Chinese augmented reality firm, secured 500 million yuan in its new funding round. The Hefei municipal government led the investment, resulting in Rokid establishing its headquarters, innovation hub, and R&D center in Hefei's New Station Hi-Tech Zone. This investment aligns with Hefei's focus on developing industries such as micro-displays and metaverse. Rokid aims to use the funding for cutting-edge research and development, ecosystem expansion, and delivering enhanced products. The goal is to create a global impact and empower developers. The partnership between Rokid and Hefei aims to drive innovation in metaverse applications and technologies.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Rokid's funding success signifies government support for tech startups.</li>    <li>Theme: Rokid, a Chinese AR firm, receives 500 million yuan in funding, leading to the establishment of its facilities in Hefei.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The partnership showcases the growing importance of XR technologies, and the government's role in fostering innovation in these areas.</li>    <li>Main information: Funding amount, location of headquarters, development focus, and company goals.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  中国增强现实（AR）技术公司Rokid在最新一轮融资中成功筹集了5亿元，由合肥市政府作为牵头投资方。根据协议，Rokid将把工业元宇宙总部、生态系统中心和研发中心设在合肥的新站高新区，以期融入合肥新兴的包括微显示器、元宇宙等领域的生态系统。为了保障资金的使用，地方政府通常要求这些初创公司在当地进行投资。根据与合肥达成的协议，Rokid将在合肥新站高新区建立工业元宇宙总部、生态系统中心和研发中心，以期利用合肥的新兴生态系统，包括微显示器、元宇宙等领域。“我们很荣幸能通过创新为科学/技术的进步做出贡献”，Rokid创始人兼首席执行官朱铭说，并补充称该公司将专注于尖端研发和用户体验优化。“展望未来，我们将持续关注技术里程碑的实现，努力丰富我们的生态系统，以赋能开发者，并交付能造福全球消费者和企业的优质产品”，朱铭说。中国希望到2025年能有5家具有“全球影响力”的元宇宙公司。合肥新兴产业创业投资控制有限公司董事长洪藩补充说，此次合作符合Rokid和合肥致力于推进元宇宙应用和技术创新的努力。“Rokid和合肥的合作建立在共同愿景之上，致力于培育扩展现实（XR）/元宇宙产业发展”，洪藩说。XR是一个涵盖AR、虚拟现实和混合现实技术的总称，旨在结合或镜像物理和数字世界，允许消费者配备XR设备在两者之间穿梭交互。Rokid创立于2014年，为各种消费、旅游和工业用途制造AR设备，其客户包括国家电网公司和家电巨头美的。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Rokid融资成功标志着政府对科技初创企业的支持。</li>    <li>主题：Rokid，一家中国AR公司，获得5亿元融资，将在合肥建立其主要设施。</li>    <li>观点：该合作展示了XR技术日益增长的重要性，以及政府在促进这些领域创新中的作用。</li>    <li>主要信息：融资金额、总部位置、发展重点和公司目标。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>hub (n.) - /hʌb/ 中心，枢纽。    <p>原文例句：Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and R&D centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone</p>    <p>例句讲解：在这个例句中，hub指的是Rokid将在合肥新站高新区建立的生态系统中心，即一个可以让不同的参与者相互连接和协作的平台或环境。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>foster (v.) - /ˈfɒstə/ 培养，促进。    <p>原文例句：“The cooperation between Rokid and Hefei builds on a shared vision to cultivate extended reality [XR]/metaverse industry development, ” Hong said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：在这个例句中，foster指的是洪藩所说的Rokid和合肥之间在培育XR/元宇宙产业发展方面的共同愿景。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make local investments - 在当地进行投资。    <P>原文例句：As a quid pro quo for funding, local governments generally require these start-ups to make local investments. </P>    <p>例句讲解：在这个例句中，make local investments指的是作为对资助的回报，地方政府通常要求这些初创公司在当地进行投资。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>cutting-edge research and development - 尖端研发。    <P>原文例句：Rokid said in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor. </P>    <p>例句讲解：在这个例句中，cutting-edge research and development指的是Rokid在声明中提到的尖端研发，即该公司将在研发方面投入大量资源，以保持技术领先地位。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Rokid said in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor - Rokid在周三的一份声明中说，它已在最新一轮融资中筹集了5亿元（折合7000万美元），由安徽省省会合肥市的市政府领投。</li>    <p>句子分析：这个句子是一个复杂句，主句是Rokid said it has raised 500 million yuan，其中主语是Rokid，谓语是has raised，宾语是500 million yuan。in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示Rokid在周三的一份声明中说它已筹集了5亿元。with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor是一个介词短语，作伴随状语，表示由安徽省省会合肥市的市政府领投。这个句子的意思是说，Rokid在周三的一份声明中说，它已在最新一轮融资中筹集了5亿元（折合7000万美元），由安徽省省会合肥市的市政府领投。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>As part of the deal, Rokid signed an investment and cooperation agreement with Hefei to advance the local metaverse industry - 作为交易的一部分，Rokid与合肥签署了一项投资和合作协议，以推进当地的元宇宙产业。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Rokid signed an investment and cooperation agreement with Hefei，其中主语是Rokid，谓语是signed，宾语是an investment and cooperation agreement。As part of the deal是一个让步状语从句，修饰主句，表示作为交易的一部分。to advance the local metaverse industry是一个目的状语从句，修饰主句，表示为了推进当地的元宇宙产业。这个句子的意思是说，作为交易的一部分，Rokid与合肥签署了一项投资和合作协议，以推进当地的元宇宙产业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>定语从句 - 修饰名词或代词。</li>    <p>原文例句：Rokid said in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个定语从句，修饰名词Rokid，表示Rokid在周三的一份声明中说它已在最新一轮融资中筹集了5亿元（折合7000万美元）。这个定语从句是由that引导的，that在从句中作关系代词，指代Rokid。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 作定语、状语或表语。</li>    <p>原文例句：Rokid said  <ul><li>Rokid said it has raised 500 million yuan in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei as a lead investor</li>
<li>Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and R&amp;D centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/f677fbfd-346b-4b28-a3ab-89b2e076e79f_2f7ce20d.jpg" /><figcaption>Rokid Glass, augmented reality glasses, at the Rokid booth during CES 2018, Las Vegas. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese augmented reality (AR) technology firm Rokid has raised nearly half a billion yuan in its latest round of funding led by a local Chinese government, in a fresh indication of the backing from authorities for tech start-ups.</p><p>Rokid said in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor. As part of the deal, Rokid signed an investment and cooperation agreement with Hefei to advance the local metaverse industry.</p><p>Chinese authorities have increasingly stepped up as private equity investors in projects in line with local development strategies. As a quid pro quo for funding, local governments generally require these start-ups to make local investments.</p><p>Under the Hefei deal, Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and research and development (R&amp;D) centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone, tapping into the Chinese city’s emerging ecosystem including micro-displays, the metaverse and other areas.</p><p>“We are honoured to contribute to advancements in science/technology … through our innovations,” said Misa Zhu, founder and CEO of Rokid, adding that the company will focus on cutting-edge R&amp;D and user experience optimisation.</p><p>“Looking ahead, we will maintain a focus on achieving technological milestones and enriching our ecosystem to empower developers and deliver superior products that benefit consumers and enterprises globally”, Zhu said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3233933/china-wants-metaverse-firms-global-influence-and-plans-five-industrial-clusters-2025" title="">China wants up to 5 metaverse companies with ‘global influence’ by 2025</a></h3><p>Hong Fan, chairman of Hefei New Venture Investment Control, an investment vehicle under the Hefei government, added that the cooperation aligns with Rokid and the city’s efforts to drive innovation on metaverse applications and technologies.</p><p>“The cooperation between Rokid and Hefei builds on a shared vision to cultivate extended reality [XR]/metaverse industry development, ” Hong said.</p><p>XR is an overarching term that includes AR, virtual reality, and mixed reality technologies that seek to combine or mirror the physical and digital worlds to allow consumers, equipped with XR equipment, to traverse between and interact with them.</p><p>Founded in 2014, Rokid has made AR equipment for a variety of consumer, travel, and industrial uses, counting companies such as the State Grid Corporation of China and home appliance giant Midea among its clients.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Can Beethoven, Bach and Mozart help iPhone sales in China? Apple to launch classical music app on mainland amid sluggish demand for its flagship produ...</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247961/can-beethoven-bach-and-mozart-help-iphone-sales-china-apple-launch-classical-music-app-mainland-amid</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Apple Music Classical app to debut in mainland China on January 24, expanding the company's digital services in the country. The app will also be available in five other East Asian markets, including Hong Kong, Macau, Taiwan, Japan, and South Korea. Apple's major digital services business in China is expected to be bolstered by the app's launch, with the country generating the largest App Store-related revenue for the company. Despite weak consumption and competition from Chinese smartphone rivals, Apple remains optimistic about the Chinese market.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple Music Classical app to launch in mainland China and other East Asian markets, targeting the company's largest market for digital services revenue.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's expansion of its digital services in China and the potential impact on iPhone sales in the country.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of Apple's digital services in China, challenges from weak consumption and competition, and Apple's continued optimism about the market.</li>    <li>Main information: Launch date, targeted markets, potential impact on Apple's digital services business, and market share figures for Apple and rivals.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  Apple Music Classical 应用将于 1 月 24 日在中国大陆推出，扩展该公司在该国的数字服务业务。该应用还将在其他五个东亚市场推出，包括香港、澳门、台湾、日本和韩国。Apple 在中国的数字服务业务可能会因该应用的推出而得到提振，中国是其在 App Store 相关收入方面最大的市场。尽管消费疲软并且面临中国智能手机竞争对手的竞争，但 Apple 仍然对中国市场持乐观态度。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Apple Music Classical 应用将在中国大陆和其他东亚市场推出，针对该公司数字服务收入最大的市场。</li>    <li>主题：Apple 在中国扩展其数字服务及其对该国 iPhone 销售的潜在影响。</li>    <li>观点：Apple 在中国数字服务的重要性、来自消费疲软和竞争的挑战以及 Apple 对该市场的持续乐观态度。</li>    <li>主要信息：发布日期、目标市场、对 Apple 数字服务业务的潜在影响以及 Apple 和竞争对手的市场份额数据。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ecosystem (n.) - 生态系统。    <p>原文例句：China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of the total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由eco-（生态，经济）和system（系统）组成，表示“生态系统”。在这个例句中，它指的是Apple 的 App Store 生态系统。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>brokerage (n.) - 经纪公司。    <p>原文例句：The brokerage indicated that there was “a big rise in discounts” for the iPhone 14 and 14 Plus models, while the newer iPhone 15 and 15 Plus models saw “a moderate rise” in discounts. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由broke（破产）和-age（状态或过程）组成，表示“经纪公司”。在这个例句中，它指的是一家经纪公司。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>momentum (n.) - 动量。    <p>原文例句：Chinese smartphone vendors, with Huawei Technologies, Xiaomi and Honor leading the pack, had “much stronger” momentum during the period, with sales delivering “flattish growth” year on year, </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由mover（移动）和-mentum（动作）组成，表示“动量”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国智能手机供应商的势头。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s major digital services business in China, which remains the company’s largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示Apple在中国的数字服务业务是其最大的市场，从App Store相关收入的角度来看。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>lift sales - 提升销量。    <p>原文例句：Whether the classical music app’s local release would somehow help lift iPhone sales on the mainland remains to be seen, as consumption remains weak across the country and Apple faces stiff competition from major Chinese smartphone rivals. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由lift（提升，抬起）和sales（销售）组成，表示“提升销量”。在这个例句中，它表示Apple Music Classical 应用的本地发布是否会以某种方式帮助提升iPhone 的销量还有待观察。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple is expected to see “even higher revenue pressure” on the mainland in 2024, according to Jefferies. - 据杰富瑞称，预计 Apple 在 2024 年将面临“更高的收入压力”。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Apple is expected to see，其中主语是Apple，谓语是is expected to see，宾语是“even higher revenue pressure”。according to Jefferies是一个介词短语，表示“根据杰富瑞”，“even higher revenue pressure”是一个由even（甚至），higher（更高的），revenue（收入）和pressure（压力）组成的词组，表示“更高的收入压力”。这个句子的意思是说，据杰富瑞称，预计 Apple 在 2024 年将面临“更高的收入压力”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话者对某件事的主观态度或看法。    <p>原文例句：Whether the classical music app’s local release would somehow help lift iPhone sales on the mainland remains to be seen, as consumption remains weak across the country and Apple faces stiff competition from major Chinese smartphone rivals. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气的句子，表示说话者对Apple Music Classical 应用的本地发布是否会帮助提升iPhone 销量持有怀疑态度。would somehow help lift iPhone sales on the mainland是一个虚拟语气从句，其中would help lift iPhone sales on the mainland是一个虚拟语气动词，表示说话者对帮助提升iPhone 销量持有怀疑态度。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>过去分词 - 表示一个动作或状态在过去某个时间发生或开始，并一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s major digital services business in China, which remains the company’s largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去分词短语，作定语，修饰Apple’s major digital services business。remains是一个过去分词，表示Apple在中国的数字服务业务一直持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Apple Music Classical app, which was launched in most markets globally in March last year, will make its mainland debut on January 24</li>
<li>On the same date, the app will also be available in five other East Asian markets that include Hong Kong, Macau, Taiwan, Japan and South Korea</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/5bfc68e8-e24d-446d-84dd-b98d8c4fe639_56cadcbe.jpg" /><figcaption>The Apple Music Classical app’s launch in China is likely to bolster the firm’s major digital services business in the country, which is its largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> will soon make its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/classical-music" target="_self" title="">classical music</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">app</a> available in mainland China, expanding the US tech giant’s digital services offering in the world’s largest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> market where sales of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> are seeing a deepening decline.</p><p>The Apple Music Classical app, which was launched in most markets globally in March last year, will make its mainland debut on January 24, according to the company’s online China App Store. The app – touted by Apple as the world’s largest classical music catalogue, with more than five million tracks – can now be pre-ordered by iPhone users in the country.</p><p>On the same date, the stand-alone app will also be available in five other East Asian markets that include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/macau-0" target="_self" title="">Macau</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a>, according to a post on Tuesday by Apple on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/twitter-x" target="_self" title="">X, formerly Twitter</a>.</p><p>The app’s launch is likely to bolster Apple’s major digital services business in China, which remains the company’s largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse" class="image-inline caption" height="1330" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/8163ba04-0fe9-402a-937d-975263f7c4ad_f67d3284.jpg" title="China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse" width="2000" /><figcaption>China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse</figcaption></figure></div><p>China accounted for US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of the total US$1.1 trillion in billings and sales facilitated by the App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published on Apple’s website in May last year.</p><p>By comparison, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> generated US$273 billion, or almost 25 per cent, of the App Store ecosystem’s overall billings and sales in 2022. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/europe" target="_self" title="">Europe</a> accounted for US$119 billion, or 11 per cent, of that year’s total.</p><p>Whether the classical music app’s local release would somehow help lift iPhone sales on the mainland remains to be seen, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247712/chinas-retail-sales-weaken-year-falling-home-prices-jobs-outlook-feed-consumer-insecurity-ubs" target="_self" title="">consumption remains weak</a> across the country and Apple faces stiff competition from major Chinese smartphone rivals.</p><p>In the first week of the year, iPhone sales on the mainland were down 30 per cent year on year, according to a Jefferies research note published on Sunday. The brokerage indicated that there was “a big rise in discounts” for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3192215/apples-iphone-14-sees-surging-pre-orders-china-enthusiastic-consumers" target="_self" title="">iPhone 14</a> and 14 Plus models, while the newer <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3235981/apple-iphone-15-review-faster-cheaper-new-standard-models-are-big-jump-over-their-predecessors" target="_self" title="">iPhone 15</a> and 15 Plus models saw “a moderate rise” in discounts.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics" title="">Apple supplier Foxconn sees sales decline in first quarter of 2024 amid weak demand</a></h3><p>Chinese smartphone vendors, with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honor" target="_self" title="">Honor</a> leading the pack, had “much stronger” momentum during the period, with sales delivering “flattish growth” year on year, Jefferies analysts led by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/enterprises/article/2113581/chinas-chance-lead-global-innovation-may-lie-5g-mobile-technology" target="_self" title="">Edison Lee</a> wrote in the note.</p><p>The iPhone’s total sales volume last year on the mainland was down 3 per cent from 2022, which translated to a 0.4 per cent decline in Apple’s market share, according to Jefferies. It estimated that rival Huawei saw its mainland market share in the December quarter gain 2 per cent from the previous quarter, and 6 per cent year on year.</p><p>Apple is expected to see “even higher revenue pressure” on the mainland in 2024, according to Jefferies.</p><p>Still, Apple has continued to reassure investors even though iPhone sales have been slowing. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240278/apples-ceo-cook-sees-china-bright-spot-after-record-iphone-sales-country-despite-overall-revenue" target="_self" title="">In the firm’s earnings call in November</a>, Apple chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tim-cook" target="_self" title="">Tim Cook</a> said: “Over the long term, I view China as an incredibly important market, and I’m very optimistic about it.”</p><p>Cook made two visits to the mainland last year, meeting senior government officials, Chinese developers and Apple’s contract manufacturing partners.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Foxconn pushes into electric vehicle production near its biggest iPhone plant amid slow smartphone sales</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247941/foxconn-pushes-electric-vehicle-production-near-its-biggest-iphone-plant-amid-slow-smartphone-sales</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Foxconn expands into electric vehicles with new venture in Zhengzhou, focusing on car components, motors, and sales in response to declining smartphone sales.  <ul>    <li>New firm, Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co, established with 500 million yuan capital.</li>    <li>Ventures aims to sharpen Foxconn's focus on electric vehicle industry.</li>    <li>Foxconn's move into automobiles comes amid weakening demand for consumer electronics.</li>    <li>Company reported preliminary revenue of US$198.9 billion in 2023, down 7% from 2022.</li>    <li>Plans to build new factories for smartphones and electronics goods in other cities in Henan.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  富士康在郑州成立新合资公司，专注于汽车零部件、电机和汽车销售，以应对智能手机销售下滑的局面。  <ul>    <li>富士康新能源汽车产业发展（河南）有限公司成立了，注册资本为5亿元人民币。</li>    <li>合资公司的目标是增强富士康在电动汽车行业的影响力。</li>    <li>富士康向汽车业的转型是在消费电子产品需求疲软的大背景下进行的。</li>    <li>该公司2023年初步收入为1989亿美元，比2022年下降7%。</li>    <li>计划在河南其他城市建设新的智能手机和电子产品工厂。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>accelerate (v.) - /əkˈsɛlərˌeɪt/ 加快，加速。    <p>原文例句：Foxconn confirmed the report, adding that the Henan subsidiary was disclosed in December 2023 to the Taiwan Stock Exchange.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由ad-（向，朝）和celer（迅速）组成，意为“加速，加快，推进”。在这个例句中，它表示富士康证实了这一报道，并补充说，河南子公司已于2023年12月向台湾证券交易所披露。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>strategy (n.) - /ˈstrætədʒi/ 战略，策略。    <p>原文例句：Jun Seki, its chief strategy officer for electric vehicles, said the company was in touch with about 14 potential customers and saw India and Japan as promising countries for EV development.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Greek，由stratos（军队）和agein（带领）组成，意为“将军的艺术或科学”。在这个例句中，它指的是富士康负责电动汽车战略的首席战略官，表明该公司正与约14个潜在客户接洽，并认为印度和日本是电动汽车发展的有前景的国家。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>play a role in - 在……中发挥作用。    <p>原文例句：The company’s move into the automobile industry is expected to play a role in addressing the decline in smartphone sales.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由play（扮演，发挥）和a role in（在……中扮演角色）组成的，表示“在某事中发挥作用”。在这个例句中，它表示该公司进入汽车行业有望在解决智能手机销售下滑问题上发挥作用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>under investigation - 正在接受调查。    <p>原文例句：The company, which was put under a tax and land use investigation in October by mainland authorities, employs 200,000 workers in its Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由under（在……之下）和investigation（调查）组成的，表示“正在接受调查”。在这个例句中，它指的是该公司因税收和土地使用问题在10月份被大陆当局调查，该公司在郑州制造中心雇佣了200,000名工人。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>mass produce - 大量生产。    <p>原文例句：In October, Foxconn announced a new electric cargo van called Model N and announced plans to mass produce its compact SUV Model B.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由mass（大量）和produce（生产）组成的，表示“大量生产”。在这个例句中，它表示富士康在10月份宣布推出名为Model N的新款电动货车，并宣布计划批量生产其紧凑型SUV Model B。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The move comes as Foxconn grapples with declining smartphone sales, which fell 7 per cent in 2023 year on year. - 随着富士康应对智能手机销售下滑（2023年同比下降7%）的情况，该公司做出了这一举动。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The move comes，其中主语是The move，谓语是comes。as Foxconn grapples with declining smartphone sales, which fell 7 per cent in 2023 year on year是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示富士康应对智能手机销售下滑的情况。这个句子的意思是说，随着富士康应对智能手机销售下滑（2023年同比下降7%）的情况，该公司做出了这一举动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The company plans to start building new factories for smartphones and electronics goods in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of major construction projects in 2024 released last week by the provincial Development and Reform Commission. - 根据上周省发展改革委公布的2024年重大建设项目清单，该公司计划在河南周口、开封、济源等地建设新的智能手机和电子产品工厂。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company plans，其中主语是The company，谓语是plans。to start building new factories for smartphones and electronics goods in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of major construction projects in 2024 released last week by the provincial Development and Reform Commission是一个不定式短语作目的语，修饰主句，表示该公司计划在河南周口、开封、济源等地建设新的智能手机和电子产品工厂。这个句子的意思是说，根据上周省发展改革委公布的2024年重大建设项目清单，该公司计划在河南周口、开封、济源等地建设新的智能手机和电子产品工厂。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company, which was put under a tax and land use investigation in October by mainland authorities, employs 200,000 workers in its Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：had + been + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词形式。这种时态表示在过去某个时间之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示该公司早在10月份就被大陆当局对税收和土地使用问题进行调查，该公司在郑州制造中心雇佣了200,000名工人。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>强调句 - 用There be结构强调某一部分，通常会将想要强调的成分提前，再用there be结构跟上。    <p>原文例句：There is a new road to the villa.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句，结构是：There + be + 被强调的部分 + 其他。在这个例句中，There is a new road to the villa.强调了有一个新的道路通往别墅，强调了道路的新。There be结构常与形容词、副词等修饰成分一起使用，以强调句子中的某个成分。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Apple supplier has set up a new venture in Zhengzhou to sharpen its focus on the electric vehicle industry</li>
<li>The new project will involve car component manufacturing and development, motor production and car sales</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/aad49844-fb12-4001-aa76-72cbfe6b99d4_f04766b4.jpg" /><figcaption>A Foxconn building in Taipei. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foxconn" target="_self" title="">Foxconn Technology Group</a> has set up a new car venture in Zhengzhou city, capital of central China’s Henan province and home to the world’s largest iPhone factory, as the Apple supplier steps up its efforts in the new energy vehicle (NEV) sector amid declining smartphone sales.</p><p>The new firm, named Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co, was established on January 4 with a registered capital of 500 million yuan (US$70 million), according to public records in the National Enterprise Credit Information Publicity System.</p><p>Its business covers car component manufacturing and development, motor production and NEV sales, among other areas.</p><p>Foxconn, known formally as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hon-hai-precision-industry" target="_self" title="">Hon Hai Precision Industry</a>, said the new venture belongs to Foxconn Innovation Industry Development Group Co and aims to sharpen the company’s focus on the electric vehicle industry, according to a report by the Securities Times on Tuesday.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Foxconn confirmed the report, adding that the Henan subsidiary was disclosed in December 2023 to the Taiwan Stock Exchange.</p><p>The world’s largest contract electronics manufacturer is accelerating its move into the automobile industry amid weakening demand for smartphones and consumer gadgets.</p><p>The Taiwanese giant last week reported US$198.9 billion in preliminary revenue for 2023, down 7 per cent from 2022. It blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, while <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics" target="_self" title="">expecting continuing decline in the first quarter of this year</a>.</p><p>In October, Foxconn <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238352/apple-supplier-foxconn-build-ai-factories-using-nvidias-chips-and-software-range-applications" target="_self" title="">announced a new electric cargo van called Model N</a> and announced plans to mass produce its compact SUV Model B. Jun Seki, its chief strategy officer for electric vehicles, said the company was in touch with about 14 potential customers and saw India and Japan as promising countries for EV development.</p><p>To help push the company towards its new direction, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3218313/apple-supplier-foxconn-sets-global-business-base-iphone-city-show-commitment-china" target="_self" title="">Foxconn opened a new global business base in Zhengzhou</a> last April and reaffirmed its commitment to the Chinese market, even as the firm and other Apple suppliers move to diversify their supply chain.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/853102cf-b84f-499d-9b72-8c24ea357fde_a66cec46.jpg" title="A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Foxconn plans to start building new factories for smartphones and electronics goods in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of major construction projects in 2024 released last week by the provincial Development and Reform Commission.</p><p>The company, which was put under <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239113/china-says-investigation-apple-supplier-foxconns-operations-mainland-normal-law-enforcement" target="_self" title="">a tax and land use investigation</a> in October by mainland authorities, employs 200,000 workers in its Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p><p>In 2022, that facility was rocked by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3200747/violence-erupts-foxconn-zhengzhou-plant-workers-protest-over-benefits-and-covid-19-controls-worlds?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">violent workers’ protests</a> and an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3197909/coronavirus-iphone-factory-exodus-shows-how-chinas-covid-narrative-still-strikes-fear-public?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">exodus of tens of thousands of employees</a> that Apple CEO Tim Cook later <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3208974/apples-tim-cook-blames-supply-disruption-chinas-pandemic-controls-revenue-drop" target="_self" title="">blamed for a decline in the US company’s quarterly revenue</a>.</p><p>Separately, Foxconn plans to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">invest at least US$2.6 billion in a plant</a> it is building in India to make Apple products, according to a report by Bloomberg last month.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China EV maker Xpeng accepts pre-orders for flying car but notes urban use is far off</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese electric vehicle maker Xpeng debuted its flying car at CES 2024, aiming to deliver the first batch by the fourth quarter of 2025.</li>    <li>The company's subsidiary AeroHT presented two types of flying cars: the Land Aircraft Carrier and the sportier eVTOL car.</li>    <li>Xpeng president Brian Gu said the company is in talks with regulators in China to allow use of the vehicle, but international expansion will take time.</li>    <li>Xpeng is targeting a consumer market for its flying cars, rather than enterprise use like its competitor EHang.</li>    <li>Gu acknowledged the challenges of current geopolitical tensions, but said the company's focus is currently on the China market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国电动汽车制造商小鹏汽车在2024年美国消费电子展上首次亮相其飞行汽车，并计划在2025年第四季度交付首批产品。</li>    <li>该公司旗下子公司AeroHT展示了两款飞行汽车：陆地飞机运输车和更具运动感的eVTOL汽车。</li>    <li>小鹏汽车总裁顾宏地说，该公司正在与中国监管机构谈判，以允许该车辆的使用，但国际扩张“需要时间”。</li>    <li>小鹏汽车将飞行汽车的目标市场定位为消费者，而不是像竞争对手亿航一样针对企业使用。</li>    <li>顾宏地承认了当前地缘政治紧张局势带来的挑战，但表示该公司目前专注于中国市场。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>debut (v.) - /ˈdeɪbjuː/ 首次亮相，首次公开演出。    <p>原文例句：Seven years after EHang debuted its first passenger drone, Chinese electric vehicle maker Xpeng entered the market with its own “flying car”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：debut源自法语，意思是“开始”，在这个例句中，它表示“首次亮相，首次公开演出”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>modular (adj.) - /ˈmɑːdjʊlə/ 模块化的，可组装的。    <p>原文例句：Its modular Land Aircraft Carrier will start taking pre-orders in the fourth quarter this year, with deliveries to start a year later. </p>    <p>例句讲解：modular源自拉丁语“modulus”，意思是“度量”，在这个例句中，它表示“模块化的，可组装的”。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>propeller (n.) - /prəˈpɛlə/ 螺旋桨。    <p>原文例句：There is no information on pricing or availability for the AeroHT, which has propellers that pop out of the back. </p>    <p>例句讲解：propeller源自拉丁语“propellere”，意思是“推进”，在这个例句中，它表示“螺旋桨”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>first batch - 第一批，第一批次。    <p>原文例句：Xpeng president Brian Gu said the company is in talks with regulators in China to allow use of the vehicle, but international expansion ‘takes time’. </p>    <p>例句讲解：first batch源自古英语“fyrst”，意思是“第一”，在这个例句中，它表示“第一批，第一批次”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>EHang made a splash when it debuted the EHang 184 at CES in 2016. - 亿航在2016年的国际消费类电子产品展览会上首次亮相EHang 184时引起了轰动。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是EHang made a splash，其中主语是EHang，谓语是made a splash，宾语是when it debuted the EHang 184 at CES in 2016。when it debuted the EHang 184 at CES in 2016是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示亿航在2016年的国际消费类电子产品展览会上首次亮相EHang 184时。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 用于比较两个事物或人的差异。    <p>原文例句：Xpeng president Brian Gu said the company is in talks with regulators in China to allow use of the vehicle, but international expansion ‘takes time’. </p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是形容词或副词的一种形式，用于比较两个事物或人的差异。比较级通常在形容词或副词后加-er，或者在形容词或副词前加more。在这个例句中，takes time是比较级的形式，表示“花费时间”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是一种时态，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。现在完成时态的结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。在这个例句中，has been making是现在完成时态，表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直持续到现在都在印度生产iPhone和其他产品。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The company’s subsidiary AeroHT presented two types of flying cars at CES, including a sportier eVTOL that made its international debut</li>
<li>Xpeng president Brian Gu said the company is in talks with regulators in China to allow use of the vehicle, but international expansion ‘takes time’</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/407dea1a-dbe1-45b0-ac41-d295e42b8239_80ccf63e.jpg" /><figcaption>Brian Gu Hongdi, vice-chairman and president of Xpeng, discusses the company’s new flying car at CES on January 9, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Seven years after EHang debuted its first passenger drone, Chinese electric vehicle maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng">Xpeng</a> entered the market with its own “flying car”, with the goal of delivering the first batch by the fourth quarter of 2025, whether regulations are ready or not.</p><p>The company’s subsidiary AeroHT presented two types of flying cars at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Tuesday. Its modular Land Aircraft Carrier will start taking pre-orders in the fourth quarter this year, with deliveries to start a year later. The sportier AeroHT eVTOL (electric vertical take-off and landing) car made its international debut at the show, having previously conducted flying tests in China.</p><p>There is no information on pricing or availability for the AeroHT, which has propellers that pop out of the back. It has been demoed for flying in China, but it did not take flight at CES. Brian Gu Hongdi, vice-chairman and president of Xpeng, suggested it could launch before regulations are in place for city use, but that people could eventually buy one and fly it in areas where the use of aircraft is not regulated.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247808/ces-2024-china-tv-makers-hisense-and-tcl-promote-ai-live-sports-us-show" title="">Hisense and TCL push AI in TVs, chase industry trends like smart cars</a></h3><p>“The design of our vehicles is not targeted for urban transportation … [which] requires an extensive regulatory approval process,” Gu said. “That’s why we’re targeting a consumer market, for people to first enjoy the experience of flying and then obviously with the regulatory framework in place, we gradually can move towards urban transportation.”</p><p>While Gu said it was too early to say what pricing might be, he expects it to be “similar to buying a luxury performance car”.</p><p>Similar products have been in the works for years. EHang made a splash when it debuted the EHang 184 at CES in 2016. In the years since, it has <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/innovation/article/3024726/nerves-waiver-screaming-lift-joy-two-minute-test-ride-passenger" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/innovation/article/3024726/nerves-waiver-screaming-lift-joy-two-minute-test-ride-passenger">invited journalists to take rides</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/3030521/chinese-drone-maker-ehang-said-file-ipo-nasdaq" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/3030521/chinese-drone-maker-ehang-said-file-ipo-nasdaq">went public on the Nasdaq</a>.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="AeroHT’s modular Land Aircraft Carrier comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/22700ac5-f38a-4718-b5a7-2df12b039468_00d05c81.jpg" title="AeroHT’s modular Land Aircraft Carrier comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>AeroHT’s modular Land Aircraft Carrier comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Xpeng distanced itself from the EHang comparison, saying its products are different and target different buyers. The EV company, which made its debut at CES two years after EHang with its first car, noted that EHang’s products are just aerial vehicles without the ability to be driven on roads. EHang is also targeting enterprise use, while Xpeng is targeting a wider consumer base.</p><p>“We are targeting the consumer market, which is very different,” Gu said. “I don’t see another company that’s doing that right now.”</p><p>While Xpeng has also highlighted how the Land Aircraft Carrier could be used for public services like emergency rescue, the new eVTOL car is a more stylish option that can conceal its rotors. This will presumably make it more appealing for people to buy, whenever it becomes available, even if they cannot fly it to work every morning.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3247413/ai-will-be-spotlight-consumer-electronics-show-2024-glasses-blind-shoes-make-you-walk-faster-and" title="">AI to dominate CES 2024, with glasses for blind, shoes to walk faster</a></h3><p>Gu said the company is already in talks with regulators in China but international expansion “takes time”.</p><p>Xpeng’s ambitions could face some challenges with current geopolitical tensions, though. Chinese drone tech has been caught in the cross hairs before. Washington put DJI, the world’s largest consumer drone maker, on its Entity List that bars US companies from doing business with it without express approval.</p><p>When asked whether this could present some hurdles, Gu said, “I’m not even thinking about that right now … This business is purely focused on the China market right now.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TSMC halts revenue drop, beats expectations on brisk demand for AI chips from Nvidia, Advanced Micro Devices</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247936/tsmc-halts-revenue-drop-beats-expectations-brisk-demand-ai-chips-nvidia-advanced-micro-devices</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  TSMC, a world-renowned chip manufacturer, managed to surpass analysts' predictions for its fourth-quarter revenue, thanks to increased demand for AI-related chips amidst a downturn in the smartphone and laptop market. However, the company's overall yearly revenue experienced a decline, indicating a challenging business environment.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: TSMC's Q4 revenue exceeded expectations, driven by AI chip demand, but yearly revenue declined.</li>    <li>Theme: TSMC's financial performance amidst changing market dynamics.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: AI as a growth driver in the semiconductor industry; challenges faced by the consumer electronics industry.</li>    <li>Main information: TSMC's Q4 revenue details; comparison with previous periods; capital expenditure adjustments; outlook for 2024; AI server farm upgrades; impact of US chip curbs on Apple.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  世界级芯片制造商台积电在智能手机和笔记本电脑芯片销售低迷的情况下，凭借人工智能相关芯片需求的增长，其第四季度收入超出了分析师的预期。然而，该公司全年整体收入有所下降，这表明商业环境充满挑战。  <ul>    <li>摘要：台积电第四季度收入超出预期，受人工智能芯片需求推动，但全年收入下降。</li>    <li>主题：台积电在不断变化的市场格局下的财务表现。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能是半导体行业增长的驱动力；消费电子行业面临的挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：台积电第四季度收入细节；与前几期的比较；资本支出的调整；对 2024 年的前景；人工智能服务器场的升级；美国芯片限制对苹果的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>beat (v.) - /biːt/ 打败，胜过；达到或超过。    <p>原文例句：Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), the world's largest contract chip maker, saw its fourth-quarter revenue beat estimates of a decline, as demand from artificial intelligence (AI) players helped offset sluggish smartphone and laptop chip sales.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词有“打败，胜过；达到或超过”的意思。在这个例句中，beat的意思是“超过”，即台积电第四季度收入超过了预期的下降。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>resurgence (n.) - /rɪˈsɜːdʒəns/ 复苏，重新出现。    <p>原文例句：Still, the latest report from the Semiconductor Industry Association showed the first growth in chip sales in over a year came in November, suggesting momentum is gathering for a resurgence in 2024.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词有“复苏，重新出现”的意思。在这个例句中，resurgence的意思是“复苏”，即半导体芯片销售额在经历了一年多的下降后，在 2023 年 11 月出现了首次增长，这表明半导体行业正在复苏。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>keep...away from - 让……远离。    <p>原文例句：The US company has also been hit by an expanded ban by Chinese agencies and state-owned companies ordering staff to keep iPhones and other foreign devices away from work premises.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由keep（保持，留住）和away from（远离）组成的，表示“让……远离”。在这个例句中，keep...away from的意思是“让……远离”，即美国公司也受到了中国机构和国有企业扩大禁令的影响，这些机构和企业要求员工将 iPhone 和其他外国设备远离工作场所。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TSMC’s US$20.2 billion quarter still fell short of delivering growth. - 台积电 202亿美元的季度收入仍未实现增长。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是TSMC’s，谓语是fell short of delivering growth，宾语是US$20.2 billion quarter。still是副词，表示“仍然，依然”。fell short of delivering growth是一个动词短语，表示“未实现增长”。在这个例句中，TSMC’s US$20.2 billion quarter是台积电 202亿美元的季度收入，still fell short of delivering growth表示台积电 202亿美元的季度收入仍未实现增长。这个句子的意思是说，台积电 202亿美元的季度收入仍未实现增长。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>yet - 表示否定，否定意义为“尚未，还没有”。    <p>原文例句：China to persist with AI development in 2024 despite US chip curbs: UBS</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个词是汉语中“然而”的对应词，它可以表示肯定或否定。当表示否定时，它的否定意义为“尚未，还没有”。在这个例句中，yet表示否定，其否定意义为“尚未，还没有”。这意味着中国在2024年仍将坚持人工智能的发展，尽管美国限制了芯片出口。</p></li>   <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人对某件事的假设、愿望或建议。    <p>原文例句：Apple, arguably TSMC’s most important customer, has faced headwinds with its latest iPhone generation in China, the world’s biggest smartphone market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种语态，它表示说话人对某件事的假设、愿望或建议。在虚拟语气中，动词通常采用过去时或过去完成时的形式。在这个例句中，虚拟语气体现在动词faced上，它表示苹果公司可能面临着挑战。faced headwinds with its latest iPhone generation in China, the world’s biggest smartphone market的意思是，苹果公司可能面临着在其最新一代 iPhone 在中国这个全球最大的智能手机市场上销售的挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Hsinchu-based company reported a NT$625.5 billion quarter, matching earnings from the same period a year earlier</li>
<li>While it outdid analyst expectations and its own guidance, TSMC’s US$20.2 billion quarter still fell short of delivering growth</li>
</ul><p>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), the world's largest contract chip maker, saw its fourth-quarter revenue beat estimates of a decline, as demand from artificial intelligence (AI) players helped offset sluggish smartphone and laptop chip sales.</p><p>Hsinchu-based TSMC, the main chip supplier to Apple and Nvidia, reported December sales of NT$176.3 billion (US$5.7 billion), completing a NT$625.5 billion quarter.</p><p>That matched earnings from the same period a year earlier, which was among TSMC’s highest quarterly results. The average analyst estimate for sales over the last three months was NT$616.2 billion.</p><p>Over the course of 2023, TSMC moderated its capital expenditure plans as the consumer electronics industry grappled with a glut of unsold inventory. The chip maker signalled the trough in demand had been reached in the summer and recovery would begin to take hold in the months leading up to 2024.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Overall revenue declined 4.5 per cent last year, to NT$2.16 trillion.</p><p>While it outdid analyst expectations and its own guidance, TSMC’s US$20.2 billion quarter still fell short of delivering growth. December sales were down 8.4 per cent on the same month a year earlier, offering a mixed outlook for the year ahead.</p><p>Top management including chief executive CC Wei have said they expect overall business to grow this year, and the company has seen its high-performance computing business boosted by demand for AI chips from Nvidia and Advanced Micro Devices.</p><p>Earlier in the week, fellow chip maker Samsung Electronics posted <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" target="_self" title="">its sixth successive quarter of declining operating profit</a>, as it weathered the impact of muted consumer demand in its smartphone and memory businesses.</p><p>Still, the latest report from the Semiconductor Industry Association showed the first growth in chip sales in over a year came in November, suggesting momentum is gathering for a resurgence in 2024.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247835/china-persist-ai-development-efforts-2024-despite-setbacks-rigid-us-semiconductor-restrictions-ubs" title="">China to persist with AI development in 2024 despite US chip curbs: UBS</a></h3><p>Upgrades to AI server farms and on-device AI applications are likely to drive an information technology replacement cycle, according to HSBC analysts Ricky Seo and Hankil Chang.</p><p>“For US cloud service providers, we expect capex to grow significantly, about 65 per cent in 2024e. Additionally, AI server purchases will likely total 57 per cent of their investments in 2024e, up from 8 per cent in 2022,” they wrote in a research note on Wednesday.</p><p>Apple, arguably TSMC’s most important customer, has faced headwinds with its latest iPhone generation in China, the world’s biggest smartphone market. Several analysts have downgraded Apple this year on expectations of soft demand, and this week Jefferies said the iPhone sales slump in China is likely to deepen.</p><p>The US company has also been hit by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3233603/china-orders-government-workers-stop-using-iphones-amid-heightened-tensions-us" target="_self" title="">an expanded ban by Chinese agencies and state-owned companies</a> ordering staff to keep iPhones and other foreign devices away from work premises.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Amazon’s Twitch to cut 500 employees, or 35% of staff, as soon as January 10 as business remains unprofitable</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247877/amazons-twitch-cut-500-employees-or-35-staff-soon-january-10-business-remains-unprofitable</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Amazon-owned live streaming service Twitch is set to lay off 35% of its employees, or around 500 people. This follows the departure of several top executives in recent months. Twitch has been facing concerns over losses and the high cost of running its large-scale website. The company has also been increasing its focus on advertising in recent years, but remains unprofitable.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Twitch to cut 35% of its workforce amid concerns over losses and high costs.</li>    <li>Theme: The financial and operational challenges faced by Twitch, leading to job cuts and restructuring.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of executive departures, increasing costs, and the need for profitability on Twitch's operations.</li>    <li>Main information: Scale of job cuts, reasons for the layoffs, Twitch's focus on advertising, challenges faced by the new CEO, and previous rounds of job reductions at Amazon.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  亚马逊旗下的直播流媒体服务Twitch将裁员35%，约500人。此前，该公司在最近几个月内有多位高管离职。Twitch一直面临着亏损和运营其大型网站的高成本等担忧。近年来，该公司一直在加大对广告的关注，但仍然处于亏损状态。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Twitch因亏损和高成本担忧裁员35%。</li>    <li>主题：Twitch面临的财务和运营挑战，导致裁员和重组。</li>    <li>观点：高管离职、成本上升以及盈利需求对Twitch运营的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：裁员规模、裁员原因、Twitch对广告的关注、新任首席执行官面临的挑战以及亚马逊之前进行的裁员。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.njuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：Twitch also lost its chief revenue officer, who worked on Twitch from within Amazon’s ads unit.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词指的是从销售商品或服务中获得的收入或利润。在这个例句中，chief revenue officer是指Twitch负责收入和利润的首席执行官。</p></li>    <li>unprofitable (adj.) - /ˌʌnˈprɑːf.ɪt.ə.bəl/ 不盈利的，亏损的。    <p>原文例句：Nine years after Amazon’s acquisition of the company, the business remains unprofitable, according to the people, who asked not to be identified discussing private information.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由un-（不）和profitable（盈利的）组成，表示“不盈利的，亏损的”。在这个例句中，它指的是Twitch在被亚马逊收购九年后，仍然处于亏损的状态。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stream live video content - 直播视频内容    <p>原文例句：Running a large-scale website supporting 1.8 billion hours of live video content a month is enormously expensive, company executives have said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：stream live video content是一个动词词组，意为“直播视频内容”。在这个例句中，it refers to the operation of Twitch's website, which involves supporting a large amount of live video content streamed by its users.</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In the final months of 2023, several top executives announced their departures, including Twitch’s chief product officer, chief customer officer and chief content officer. - 在2023年末的几个月里，几名高管宣布离职，包括Twitch的首席产品官、首席客户官和首席内容官。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是several top executives announced their departures，其中主语是several top executives，谓语是announced their departures。In the final months of 2023是一个时间状语，表示在2023年末的几个月里。including Twitch’s chief product officer, chief customer officer and chief content officer是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示包括Twitch的首席产品官、首席客户官和首席内容官。这个句子的意思是说，在2023年末的几个月里，几名高管宣布离职，包括Twitch的首席产品官、首席客户官和首席内容官。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物造成的。    <p>原文例句：Twitch has increased its focus on advertising in recent years.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，Twitch is increased its focus on advertising，其中Twitch是句子主语，increased是谓语，focus on advertising是被动语态的宾语。这个句子的意思是说，Twitch近年来增加了对广告的关注。这种语态的使用可以使句子更加客观和正式。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The cuts come after Twitch’s chief product officer, chief customer officer and chief content officer left in the final months of 2023</li>
<li>Running a large-scale website supporting 1.8 billion hours of live video content a month is enormously expensive, company executives have said</li>
</ul><p>Amazon.com’s live-streaming site Twitch is poised to cut 35 per cent of its staff, or about 500 workers, according to people familiar with the plans, the latest in a series of job reductions there.</p><p>The cuts, which could be announced as soon as Wednesday, come amid concerns over losses at Twitch and after several top executives left the company in the span of a few months. A Twitch representative declined to comment.</p><p>Running a large-scale website supporting 1.8 billion hours of live video content a month is enormously expensive, despite Twitch’s reliance on Amazon’s infrastructure, company executives have said.</p><p>In December, Twitch chief executive Dan Clancy said the company would cease operations in South Korea, where the costs are “prohibitively expensive”, according to a blog post he wrote.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Twitch has increased its focus on advertising in recent years. Nine years after Amazon’s acquisition of the company, the business remains unprofitable, according to the people, who asked not to be identified discussing private information.</p><p>In the final months of 2023, several top executives announced their departures, including Twitch’s chief product officer, chief customer officer and chief content officer. Twitch also lost its chief revenue officer, who worked on Twitch from within Amazon’s ads unit.</p><p>“It’s always bittersweet when talented leaders move on to pursue new opportunities,’’ a Twitch spokesman said at the time. “We are incredibly grateful for their contributions to Twitch and our community, and wish them all the best.”</p><p>The former employees all declined to comment.</p><p>Since he took the position in March 2023, Clancy has been on a cross-country charm offensive to mend relations with the video gaming celebrities who make a living streaming on Twitch.</p><p>Many of them chafed at Twitch’s original approach to ads, which the company reworked after criticism. Streamers have praised Clancy’s desire to listen to their concerns after years of complaints that the service was out of touch with its users.</p><p>The new chief has struggled to stem losses, however. Twitch undertook two rounds of lay-offs last year, cutting over 400 positions, part of wider job reductions at Amazon.</p><p>The online retail giant initiated its biggest-ever corporate job cuts in 2022, which it expanded to 27,000 positions across the company. It continued in October with a new round of cuts to its music division, which encompasses the company’s audio streaming platform and digital storefront for songs.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US SEC says its X account was compromised to falsely say bitcoin ETFs approved</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247873/us-sec-says-its-x-account-was-compromised-falsely-say-bitcoin-etfs-approved</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The SEC’s official Twitter account got hacked and a fake post about bitcoin ETF approval was sent out, causing a surge in Bitcoin price.    </li>    <li>The SEC is investigating the hack and has clarified that no decision on bitcoin ETFs has been made.    </li>    <li>The incident highlights the frequency of cyberattacks and the lack of sympathy from SEC to companies experiencing cybersecurity incidents.    </li>    <li>The SEC is expected to make a decision on bitcoin ETF applications soon, with technical requirements to be fulfilled before trading can commence.    </li>    <li>Previous SEC chairs have refused to approve bitcoin ETFs, but speculation has been growing that the agency may acquiesce to the demand for the product.    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>美国证券交易委员会（SEC）的官方推特账户遭到黑客攻击，发布了一条关于比特币ETF获得批准的虚假帖子，导致比特币价格飙升。    </li>    <li>SEC正在调查此次黑客攻击事件，并澄清尚未就比特币ETF做出任何决定。    </li>    <li>这一事件凸显了网络攻击的频繁发生，以及美国证券交易委员会对遭遇网络安全事件的公司的同情心不足。    </li>    <li>预计美国证券交易委员会将很快对比特币ETF申请做出决定，交易开始前需要满足技术要求。    </li>    <li>美国证券交易委员会前主席曾拒绝批准比特币ETF，但有传言称该机构可能会屈服于对该产品的需求。    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>bitcoin (n.) - 比特币    <p>原文例句：A highly anticipated decision by the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) on whether to approve a spot-bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF) quickly morphed into a major cybersecurity incident on Tuesday.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这是一个合成词，由bit（位）和coin（硬币）组成，比特指数字货币的最小单位，coin指代硬币，合起来表示“比特币”。在这个例句中，它指的是一种加密货币，即比特币。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>hack (v.) - 黑客攻击    <p>原文例句：The SEC’s official Twitter account got hacked and a fake post about bitcoin ETF approval was sent out, causing a surge in Bitcoin price.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这是一个动词，指“黑客攻击”。它源自hacker（黑客），词源可以追溯到“砍断木头”的意思。在这个例句中，它指的是美国证券交易委员会（SEC）的官方推特账户遭到黑客攻击。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>ETF (n.) - 交易所交易基金    <p>原文例句：A highly anticipated decision by the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) on whether to approve a spot-bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF) quickly morphed into a major cybersecurity incident on Tuesday.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这是一个合成词，由exchange-traded fund（交易所交易基金）缩写而成。它指的是一种可在证券交易所公开交易的股票基金，通常跟踪某个特定指数或一篮子股票。在这个例句中，它指的是一种名为spot-bitcoin的交易所交易基金。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take action - 采取行动    <p>原文例句：The SEC said that it would work with law enforcement to investigate the incident, the unauthorised access had been terminated, and that the post was not made by the SEC or its staff.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这是一个动词词组，指“采取行动”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国证券交易委员会（SEC）表示将与执法部门合作调查此次事件，未经授权的访问已被终止，该帖子并非由SEC及其工作人员发布。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>spot-backed bitcoin ETF - 实物支持的比特币ETF    <p>原文例句：The SEC has until January 10 to take action on at least one of those applications, and crypto insiders have speculated the regulator will use that date to announce a slew of decisions at once.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这是一个合成词组，由spot-backed（实物支持的）和bitcoin ETF（比特币ETF）组成。它指的是一种以实物比特币作为支撑的交易所交易基金（ETF）。在这个例句中，它指的是美国证券交易委员会（SEC）将于1月10日前对至少一项相关申请采取行动，加密货币业内人士猜测监管机构将利用这一日期同时宣布一系列决定。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>SEC chairman Gary Gensler at a congress hearing in September. Photo: Reuters    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是SEC chairman Gary Gensler，谓语是at a congress hearing in September。Photo: Reuters是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰SEC chairman Gary Gensler，表示这是在9月份的一次国会听证会上拍摄的照片。这个句子的意思是说，这是美国证券交易委员会（SEC）主席加里·金斯勒9月份在国会听证会上的照片，照片来自路透社。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词作定语 - 用于修饰名词或代词，表示某种状态或关系。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：过去分词作定语是指用过去分词（过去式+ed或不规则变化）来修饰名词或代词，表示某种状态或关系。在这个例句中，过去分词making修饰名词company，表示该公司一直都在生产iPhone和其他产品。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>不定式作宾语 - 在句中充当宾语，表示某种动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The SEC said that it would work with law enforcement to investigate the incident.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式作宾语是指在句中充当宾语，表示某种动作或状态。不定式由to加上动词原形构成。在这个例句中，不定式to investigate the incident作宾语，表示调查这一事件。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>US authorities are investigating how the @SECGov’s account was compromised by ‘an unknown party’</li>
<li>The regulator has clarified that no decision on spot bitcoin ETFs had been made</li>
</ul><p>A highly anticipated decision by the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) on whether to approve a spot-bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF) quickly morphed into a major cybersecurity incident on Tuesday.</p><p>The SEC’s X account was compromised and a fake post claiming that the agency had greenlit plans for the products fuelled a brief surge in the price of the world’s biggest cryptocurrency. It also has sparked an investigation by US authorities into how a social media account at Wall Street’s main regulator was compromised.</p><p>“It really shows the breadth and frequency of cyberattacks,” said Kurt Gottschall, a partner at law firm Haynes Boone and former SEC regional director. “The irony here is that the SEC has not shown much sympathy to public companies and asset managers that have experienced cybersecurity incidents.”</p><p>The breach gave fodder to crypto faithful who have long viewed the commission’s chairman, Gary Gensler, as an enemy due to his zeal to rein in the industry.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="SEC chairman Gary Gensler at a congress hearing in September. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/74063e72-ef97-4ab1-9293-377cc070fd84_57e2bc2f.jpg" title="SEC chairman Gary Gensler at a congress hearing in September. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>SEC chairman Gary Gensler at a congress hearing in September. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>The irony of a cybersecurity incident befalling a regulator that has repeatedly warned of crypto’s online vulnerabilities was not lost on critics who have spent years waiting for the SEC to approve a bitcoin ETF. Traders have been speculating for weeks that the agency could approve several of the products as soon as Wednesday.</p><p>In statements late on Tuesday, the regulator said that it would work with law enforcement to investigate the incident, the unauthorised access had been terminated, and that the post was not made by the SEC or its staff. In a separate statement, Gensler clarified that no decision on ETFs had been made.</p><p>The SEC said that there was unapproved activity on the @SECGov X account “by an unknown party for a brief period of time shortly after 4pm ET” on Tuesday. After the fake post was removed, Joe Benarroch, head of business operations at X, said in a statement that the “account is secure and we are investigating the root cause”.</p><p>About a dozen companies have applied to list ETFs backed by bitcoin in the US. The SEC has until January 10 to take action on at least one of those applications, and crypto insiders have speculated the regulator will use that date to announce a slew of decisions at once.</p><p>There are two technical requirements that must be fulfilled before a spot-backed bitcoin ETF can start trading. First, the SEC must sign off on so-called 19b-4 filings by the exchanges that would list the ETFs. Second, the regulator must approve the relevant S-1 forms, which are the registration applications from the would-be issuers – a list that includes BlackRock and Fidelity.</p><p>The SEC is planning to vote on the exchanges’ filings, the 19b-4s, this week, Bloomberg News has reported. The regulator may or may not take action on the issuers’ applications, the S-1s, around the same time. If the SEC grants both sets of required approvals, the ETFs could start trading as soon as the next business day.</p><p>The SEC under Gensler and his Trump-era predecessor, Jay Clayton, has previously refused to allow such a product to launch, citing concerns about investor protection and the potential for market manipulation. However, speculation has been mounting since August, when the SEC lost a key legal fight against crypto asset manager Grayscale Investments, that the regulator will have to acquiesce to the growing clamour for the product.</p><p>Hype about an approval has been rampant on social media. Bitcoin surged as much as 10 per cent on October 16 when a crypto news site incorrectly posted on X that BlackRock had been approved to list a spot ETF. About US$85 million of mostly bearish trading positions were liquidated during the surge, which quickly reversed.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
