<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Nvidia rolls out new chips, claims leadership of AI PC race</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247752/nvidia-rolls-out-new-chips-claims-leadership-ai-pc-race</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia announces new graphics chips for personal computers, targeting gamers, designers, and other users looking to leverage AI capabilities on their local machines.</li>    <li>The company claims these AI-powered PCs offer enhanced security and responsiveness compared to cloud-based AI services.</li>    <li>Nvidia's competitors, Intel and AMD, have also emphasized the potential of AI PCs, asserting their advantages in terms of security and performance.</li>    <li>The new chips, part of the GeForce RTX 40 series, include the RTX 4080 SUPER, 4070 Ti SUPER, and 4070 Super, priced at $999, $799, and $599, respectively.</li>    <li>Nvidia showcased improved performance for Stable Diffusion XL image generation software, demonstrating a 1.7 times speed boost compared to the previous generation.</li>    <li>The company also mentioned compatibility with ray tracing technology for enhanced gaming visuals and highlighted optimizations with various AI models and software.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>英伟达发布针对个人电脑的新款显卡芯片，目标是希望在其本地机器上利用人工智能功能的游戏玩家、设计师和其他用户。</li>    <li>该公司声称，这些人工智能驱动的个人电脑与基于云的人工智能服务相比，提供了增强的安全性与响应能力。</li>    <li>英伟达的竞争对手英特尔和超微半导体公司也强调了人工智能个人电脑的潜力，并断言它们在安全性和性能方面的优势。</li>    <li>这些新芯片属于 GeForce RTX 40 系列的一部分，包括 RTX 4080 SUPER、4070 Ti SUPER 和 4070 Super，其价格分别为 999 美元、799 美元和 599 美元。</li>    <li>英伟达展示了 Stable Diffusion XL 图像生成软件的性能提升，与上一代技术相比，速度提高了 1.7 倍。</li>    <li>该公司还提到了对光线追踪技术的兼容性，以增强游戏视觉效果，并强调了针对各种人工智能模型和软件的优化。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>leverage (v.) - /ˈlɛvərɪdʒ/ 利用，杠杆。    <p>原文例句：The company claims these AI-powered PCs offer enhanced security and responsiveness compared to cloud-based AI services.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语lever（举起），表示“利用杠杆原理举起或移动重物”，引申为“利用，杠杆”。在这个例句中，它指的是利用人工智能功能来增强个人电脑的安全性和响应能力。</p></li>    <li>showcase (v.) - /ˈʃəʊkeɪs/ 展示，陈列。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia showcased improved performance for Stable Diffusion XL image generation software, demonstrating a 1.7 times speed boost compared to the previous generation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于show（展示）和case（盒子），表示“将物品放在盒子里展示”。在这个例句中，它指的是英伟达展示了Stable Diffusion XL图像生成软件的性能提升。</p></li>    <li>compatibility (n.) - /kəmˌpætəˈbɪləti/ 兼容性，相容性。    <p>原文例句：The company also mentioned compatibility with ray tracing technology for enhanced gaming visuals.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由com-（一起）和patibilis（忍受，相容）组成，表示“能够一起工作或存在”。在这个例句中，它指的是英伟达提到了与光线追踪技术的兼容性，以便增强游戏视觉效果。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>with regard to - 关于，就……而言。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia's competitors, Intel and AMD, have also emphasized the potential of AI PCs, asserting their advantages with regard to security and performance.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由with（与……一起），regard（考虑，尊重）和to（朝向，向着）构成的，表示“关于，就……而言”。在这个例句中，它表示英伟达的竞争对手英特尔和超微半导体公司也强调了人工智能个人电脑的潜力，并断言它们在安全性和性能方面的优势。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company claims these AI-powered PCs offer enhanced security and responsiveness compared to cloud-based AI services. - 该公司声称，这些人工智能驱动的个人电脑与基于云的人工智能服务相比，提供了增强的安全性与响应能力。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company claims，其中主语是The company，谓语是claims，宾语是these AI-powered PCs offer enhanced security and responsiveness compared to cloud-based AI services。compared to cloud-based AI services是一个介词短语作状语，修饰offer enhanced security and responsiveness，表示与基于云的人工智能服务相比。这个句子的意思是说，该公司声称，这些人工智能驱动的个人电脑与基于云的人工智能服务相比，提供了增强的安全性与响应能力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has avoided the worst of the PC plunge by owning the market for accelerator chips used to create AI software in data centres. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则变化形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示该公司通过拥有用于在数据中心创建人工智能软件的加速器芯片的市场，避免了个人电脑暴跌的最糟糕的情况。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Intel and AMD have already touted AI PCs as a new era for the industry, arguing that AI software is more secure and responsive on the PC than over the internet</li>
<li>The new GeForce RTX 4080 SUPER can run Stable Diffusion XL image generation software 1.7 times faster than the equivalent model from the previous generation</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/47bc917a-2754-47f9-a3f0-2e9bcc89a823_7d2e88f9.jpg" /><figcaption>The Nvidia logo is seen during the Hon Hai Tech Day in Taipei, October 18, 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia, whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence software, announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”.</p><p>Nvidia unveiled three new desktop graphics chips with extra components that will let gamers, designers and other computer users make better use of AI on their personal machines without having to rely on remote services accessed over the internet. The chips, updated versions of existing offerings, will be offered at a “great new price,” the company said Monday in a presentation at the CES trade show.</p><p>Nvidia rivals Intel and Advanced Micro Devices have already touted what they say is a new era for the industry: AI PCs. The companies argue that AI software is more secure and responsive when it is run on the PCs themselves rather than over the internet. Nvidia now claims its graphics chips are the best engines to power the new types of laptops and desktops.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector" title="">Nvidia expands its reach in China’s electric vehicle sector</a></h3><p>The new GeForce RTX 4080 SUPER will get more processing cores and faster memory. It can run Stable Diffusion XL image generation software 1.7 times faster than the equivalent model from the previous generation of Nvidia technology, the company said. The new chip will also power games with ray tracing – building an image by calculating the path of individual rays of light – at 4K resolution.</p><p>The product is scheduled to go on sale January 31 for US$999. The company also unveiled an RTX 4070 Ti SUPER for US$799 and a 4070 Super for US$599, which will be available later this month.</p><p>Paired with new software and optimisations of AI models that Nvidia is also releasing, the products will offer an “order of magnitude” improvement over machines that are powered by Intel chips, according to Justin Walker, an Nvidia vice president.</p><p>Nvidia’s stock rose as much as 5 per cent in New York trading Monday, taking it back above US$500 a share to a record high. The stock more than tripled last year, giving the company a market value of more than US$1 trillion.</p><p>After a spike in sales during the pandemic, PC shipments have fallen steeply, leaving makers and component suppliers burdened with inventory and little growth. Nvidia has avoided the worst of the PC plunge by owning the market for accelerator chips used to create AI software in data centres. The explosion in demand for that more expensive type of chip has pushed Nvidia’s market value past US$1 trillion, making it the most valuable company in the history of the semiconductor industry.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>For computer chip makers in general, though, the majority of the volume they ship still goes into PCs. They are searching for a way to persuade laptop owners and corporate buyers to upgrade their equipment and have begun touting AI capabilities as a reason for new purchases.</p><p>Nvidia said the new chips will provide more realistic gaming with high-definition images enhanced by AI, which will also generate improved dialogue by in-game characters. In another example, the products will provide more responsive tools for image-editing software from companies such as Adobe. There are currently 500 applications that are tuned to work better with AI and Nvidia’s RTX technology, the company said.</p><p>Separately, Nvidia said the capabilities of its new products will not trigger rules put in place by the US government to limit the export of AI-related chips to China. The top-of-the-line GTX 4090 already fell afoul of those restrictions, requiring Nvidia to produce a less-capable version for that market.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s Vision Pro headset launches next month as company seeks to expand mixed-reality market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247747/apples-vision-pro-headset-launches-next-month-company-seeks-expand-mixed-reality-market</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Apple released a new, high-priced virtual reality headset called the Vision Pro, targeting a broader audience beyond just gamers and tech enthusiasts. Its operating system is compatible with over a million iPhone and iPad apps and will be available for purchase from February 2nd, with pre-orders starting January 19th. Many analysts believe Apple's entry into the market has the potential to significantly expand the technology's appeal.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's Vision Pro headset aims to broaden the appeal of virtual reality technology.</li>    <li>Theme: The launch of Apple's Vision Pro virtual reality headset and its potential impact on the VR market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The belief that Apple can expand the audience for VR technology beyond its current niche.</li>    <li>Main information: Features of the Vision Pro headset, including compatibility with iPhone and iPad apps, controlled with eye and hands gestures, and the ability to capture 3D videos.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果发布了一款名为 Vision Pro 的新款高价虚拟现实耳机，其目标受众不仅限于游戏玩家和技术爱好者，而是覆盖更广泛的人群。它的操作系统与超过一百万个 iPhone 和 iPad 应用程序兼容，并将于 2 月 2 日起正式发售，1 月 19 日开始预订。许多分析师认为，苹果进入该市场有可能极大地扩大该技术的吸引力。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果的 Vision Pro 耳机旨在扩大虚拟现实技术的吸引力。</li>    <li>主题：苹果 Vision Pro 虚拟现实耳机的发布及其对 VR 市场可能产生的影响。</li>    <li>观点：苹果可以将 VR 技术的受众群体扩展到当前小众群体之外的信念。</li>    <li>主要信息：Vision Pro 耳机的功能，包括与 iPhone 和 iPad 应用程序的兼容性、通过眼睛和手势控制，以及捕捉 3D 视频的能力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unveil (v.) - /ˌʌnˈveɪl/ 公开展示，揭幕。    <p>原文例句：Apple unveiled the sleek US$3,500 goggles at a software conference held at its Cupertino, California, headquarters eight months ago – an event that was designed to encourage developers to make apps tailored for a device that projects users into three-dimensional simulations of reality. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由un-（不，解除，否定）和veil（面纱，帷幕）组成，意思就是“掀开面纱，公开展示”。在这个例句中，Apple unveiled the sleek US$3,500 goggles表示苹果公司在八个月前举行的软件发布会上公开展示了这款售价 3500 美元的时尚护目镜。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>debut (n.) - /ˈdeɪbjuː/ 首次亮相，处女作。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s first new product since its smartwatch debut a decade ago could set the stage for the introduction of more affordable versions for a broader audience. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于法语，意思为“首次亮相”。在这个例句中，it 表示苹果智能手表的首次亮相。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>raked in (phr. v.) - /reɪk ɪn/ 赚取，收入。    <p>原文例句：Apple still raked in US$383 billion in sales, with the iPhone accounting for more than half that amount. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组来源于rake（耙子）和in（进入），表示“耙入，赚取”。在这个例句中，Apple still raked in US$383 billion in sales表示苹果公司仍然获得了3830 亿美元的销售额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take place - 发生，举行。    <p>原文例句：The event took place at the company’s headquarters in Cupertino, California. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“发生，举行”。在这个例句中，The event took place at the company’s headquarters in Cupertino, California.表示这次活动在加利福尼亚州库比蒂诺的公司总部举行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>be compatible with - 与兼容。    <p>原文例句：The new software is compatible with all major operating systems. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“与兼容”。在这个例句中，The new software is compatible with all major operating systems.表示该新软件与所有主流操作系统兼容。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The announcement, made in an exchange filing in Taiwan late Monday, did not give any further details, saying only that the investment was for “operational needs”. - 这一消息是在周一晚间台湾的一份交易文件中公布的，没有透露任何进一步的细节，只是说这笔投资是为了“运营需求”。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The announcement did not give any further details，其中主语是The announcement，谓语是did not give，宾语是any further details。made in an exchange filing in Taiwan late Monday是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰The announcement，表示这一消息是在周一晚间台湾的一份交易文件中公布的。saying only that the investment was for “operational needs”是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示这一消息的内容或方式，即只是说这笔投资是为了“运营需求”。这个句子的意思是说，这一消息没有透露任何进一步的细节，只是说这笔投资是为了“运营需求”，这一消息是在周一晚间台湾的一份交易文件中公布的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达虚拟的、假设的或不真实的情况。    <p>原文例句：If I were you, I would save my money for a rainy day. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是虚拟语气的一种形式，表示与事实相反的情况或假设的情况。在这个例句中，它表示If I were you, 表示“如果我是你”。I would save my money for a rainy day.表示“我会把钱存起来以备不时之需”。这个句子的意思是说，如果我是你，我会把钱存起来以备不时之需。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：The book was written by a famous author. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是被动语态的一种形式，表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。在这个例句中，The book表示“这本书”。was written表示“被写作”。by a famous author表示“由一位著名的作家”。这个句子的意思是说，这本书是由一位著名的作家写的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad, with pre-orders beginning January 19</li>
<li>Industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/f75364f6-d8ed-4081-90b8-cd86123a6fa9_94e8650c.jpg" /><figcaption>The Apple Vision Pro headset is displayed in a showroom on the Apple campus after its unveiling on June 5, 2023, in Cupertino, California. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>Apple’s high-priced headset for toggling between the real and digital world will be available in its stores beginning February 2, launching the trendsetting company’s push to broaden the appeal of what so far has been a niche technology.</p><p>Apple unveiled the sleek US$3,500 goggles at a software conference held at its Cupertino, California, headquarters eight months ago – an event that was designed to encourage developers to make apps tailored for a device that projects users into three-dimensional simulations of reality.</p><p>Apple’s announcement coincides with a major consumer electronics show in Las Vegas where the company has long been conspicuously absent.</p><p>Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad. Pre-orders begin January 19, but buyers will have to go to a store to be properly fitted for the goggles, which are controlled with the eyes and a few simple hand gestures.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247367/qualcomm-unveils-chip-mixed-reality-compete-apples-vision-pro" title="">Qualcomm unveils chip for mixed reality to compete with Apple’s Vision Pro</a></h3><p>Although Facebook owner Meta Platforms and other companies have been making virtual reality headsets for years with limited success, many industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far.</p><p>The Vision Pro already has got largely enthusiastic reviews among the media who were able to test it in tightly controlled demonstrations monitored by Apple, but the device’s price tag probably means relatively few unit sales during its first year on the market.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" class="image-inline caption" height="1271" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/c20a30fc-1af5-4a7c-af6e-4132fe5d819a_b9343cec.jpg" title="Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" width="2000" /><figcaption>Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even so, Apple’s first new product since its smartwatch debut a decade ago could set the stage for the introduction of more affordable versions for a broader audience. Right now, the Vision Pro will cost seven times more than Meta’s latest virtual-reality headset, the Quest 3.</p><p>In a sign that Apple is expecting the Vision Pro to pave the way to a bigger market, the company included the ability to take 3D videos that can be viewed through the goggles on its latest premium iPhones, the 15 Pro and 15 Pro Max. These videos are so realistic that the people and other images in them appear to be right in front of the viewer watching them.</p><p>Apple is looking for ways to juice its sales after suffering a slight decline in revenue during its last fiscal year ending in September. Apple still raked in US$383 billion in sales, with the iPhone accounting for more than half that amount.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung profit tumbles 35% as chip weakness persists</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>In the face of declining operating profit due to weak demand for consumer electronics, Samsung aims to catch up with its rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips and drive growth with new devices and foldables in 2024.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung's operating profit declines as it plans to catch up in high-density memory chips and launch new devices.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's response to economic uncertainty and declining demand for consumer electronics.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Analysts' cautious outlook on Samsung's rebound and the need for innovation in the memory chip market.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's sixth consecutive quarter of declining operating profit; plans to increase capacity in high-density memory chips; reliance on a new line-up of devices and foldables for growth in 2024.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>面对因消费电子产品需求疲软而导致的营业利润下滑，三星计划在2024年在新兴的高密度存储芯片领域追赶竞争对手SK海力士，并通过新设备和可折叠设备拉动增长。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星营业利润下滑，计划在高密度存储芯片领域追赶，推出新设备。</li>    <li>主题：三星对经济不确定性和消费电子产品需求下降的应对措施。</li>    <li>观点：分析师对三星反弹持谨慎态度，认为存储芯片市场需要创新。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星连续六个季度营业利润下降；计划增加高密度存储芯片产能；依靠新阵容的设备和可折叠设备在2024年实现增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>declining (adj.) - /dɪˈklaɪnɪŋ/ 递减的，下降的。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics posted its sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit, reflecting stubbornly weak demand for consumer electronics globally.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于decline（降低），表示“下降的，递减的”。在这个例句中，它描述了三星电子连续六个季度营业利润下降的情况。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>burgeoning (adj.) - /ˈbɜːrdʒənɪŋ/ 迅速增长的，蓬勃发展的。    <p>原文例句：Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于burgeon（萌芽），表示“迅速增长的，蓬勃发展的”。在这个例句中，它描述了高密度存储芯片领域正在快速增长，三星计划在这个领域追赶竞争对手SK海力士。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>foldables (n.) - /ˈfəʊldəbəlz/ 可折叠设备。    <p>原文例句：Samsung is also counting on a new line-up of devices and foldables to drive growth in 2024.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由foldable（可折叠的）构成的，表示“可折叠设备”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星计划在2024年推出的一系列新设备和可折叠设备。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>operating income - 营业收入。    <p>原文例句：Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由operating（运营的）和income（收入）构成的，表示“营业收入”。在这个例句中，它描述了韩国最大的公司三星电子营业收入下降35%，至2.8万亿韩元（约合21亿美元）。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>high-density memory chips - 高密度存储芯片。    <p>原文例句：Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由high-density（高密度的）和memory chips（存储芯片）构成的，表示“高密度存储芯片”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星计划在高密度存储芯片领域追赶竞争对手SK海力士，并计划在2024年将产能增加2.5倍。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“Prices are not rising that fast and the demand from certain sectors is not that strong.” - “价格涨得不够快，某些行业的  <ul><li>Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates</li>
<li>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/3104ffdf-5315-4dcc-bea4-5df736b732db_b268069a.jpg" /><figcaption>Visitors at the Samsung First Look preview at the Caesars Palace resort ahead of this weeks Consumer Electronics Show, January 7, 2024, in Las Vegas. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Samsung Electronics posted its sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit, reflecting stubbornly weak demand for consumer electronics globally.</p><p>Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates. Revenue came to 67 trillion won, compared with projections for 70.31 trillion won.</p><p>The results underscore how demand for smartphones and the memory chips that power modern electronics remains sluggish given economic uncertainty. In December, rival Micron Technology delivered a better-than-projected revenue outlook that suggested datacenter construction may make up for lukewarm computing and mobile device markets.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>“I think this shows that the rebound is slower than we all thought,” said Tom Kang, research director at Counterpoint Technology Market Research. “Prices are not rising that fast and the demand from certain sectors is not that strong.”</p><p>Samsung in October predicted the long-depressed US$160 billion memory market will bounce back gradually in 2024, driven by a boom in AI development. Prices should start climbing out of troughs around the latter part of 2023, executives said at the time.</p><p>The company will release a full earnings report, with divisional breakdowns, on January 31.</p><p>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024. HBM, an advanced chip that handles data more quickly, works with hardware such as Nvidia’s accelerators to speed up data processing for intensive tasks like training AI models.</p><p>Samsung is also counting on a new line-up of devices and foldables to drive growth in 2024. The Korean company is preparing to unveil its latest gadgets in the US later this month, at a time investors worry Apple’s iPhone 15 may be running out of steam mere months after launch.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tencent’s Pony Ma says 2021 WeChat photo privacy controversy was ‘misunderstanding’ that was fixed with update</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247704/tencents-pony-ma-says-2021-wechat-photo-privacy-controversy-was-misunderstanding-was-fixed-update</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In 2021, WeChat, China's popular social media app, faced privacy concerns due to a glitch that allowed the app to access user photo galleries even when not in use. Pony Ma Huateng, founder of Tencent Holdings, the parent company of WeChat, described the issue as "a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images."  <ul>    <li>Abstract: WeChat photo issue in 2021 caused widespread privacy concerns.</li>    <li>Theme: Explanation of the privacy issue involving WeChat's access to user photo galleries.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Pony Ma Huateng's perspective on the issue and the measures taken to resolve it.</li>    <li>Main information: Revelation of the glitch; Tencent's response and implementation of a new interface; reassurances regarding user authorization and cancellation of scanning.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2021 年，中国流行社交媒体应用程序微信因其允许应用程序在不使用时访问用户照片库的故障而面临隐私问题。微信母公司腾讯控股的创始人马化腾将该问题描述为“由于缓存图片加速而造成的误解”。  <ul>    <li>摘要：2021 年微信照片问题引发广泛的隐私担忧。</li>    <li>主题：解释涉及微信访问用户照片库的隐私问题。</li>    <li>观点：马化腾对该问题的看法以及为解决该问题采取的措施。</li>    <li>主要信息：故障的披露；腾讯的回应和实施新界面；关于用户授权和取消扫描的保证。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>widespread (adj.) - /waɪdˈsprɛd/ 普遍的，广泛的。    <p>原文例句：The 2021 WeChat photo issue sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time despite reassurances that the glitch had been fixed. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词是由wide（宽的）和spread（展开）构成的，表示“广泛的，普遍的”。在这个例句中，它指的是 2021 年的微信照片问题引起了广泛的隐私担忧。</p></li>    <li>reassurance (n.) - /ˌriːəˈʃʊərəns/ 保证，安抚。    <p>原文例句：Tencent said at the time that the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”, and it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词由reassure（使放心）和-ance（状态）构成的，表示“保证，安抚”。在这个例句中，它指的是腾讯当时所说的，该应用程序正在寻找新的图片，以便“让用户更快速、更流畅地发送照片”，并且它只在用户授权时访问图库。</p></li>    <li>strict (adj.) - /strɪkt/ 严格的，严厉的。    <p>原文例句：The Data Security Law and the Personal Information Protection Law, some of the world’s toughest data protection laws, went into effect in 2021 with strict penalties for the unauthorised collection, processing, storage and use of data generated in the country. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词表示“严格的，严厉的”。在这个例句中，它指的是《数据安全法》和《个人信息保护法》，作为世界上最严格的数据保护法之一，于 2021 年生效，对未经授权收集、处理、存储和使用在该国产生的数据的行为处以严厉的处罚。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in use - 在使用中，在使用。    <p>原文例句： WeChat, China’s largest social media app with 1.3 billion monthly active users (MAUs), was frequently accessing user photo galleries even when not in use, which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time. </p>    <p>例句讲解：由介词in（在）和名词use（使用）组成，是介词短语，意思是“在使用中，在使用”。在这个例句中，它表示微信，中国最大的社交媒体应用程序，拥有13亿月活跃用户（MAU），即使在不使用时也经常访问用户照片库，这在当时引发了广泛的隐私担忧。</p></li>    <li>private message - 私人信息，私信。    <p>原文例句：Ma told CSDNnews in a private WeChat message last Friday that this “old incident” in 2021 had been fixed, according to a screenshot shared by the outlet. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词短语指的是私人信息或私信。在这个例句中，它指的是 CSDNnews 报道中引述的马化腾在上周五通过微信发送的私人信息，称 2021 年发生的“旧事件”已经得到解决。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Pony Ma Huateng, founder, chairman and CEO of Tencent Holdings, has described a 2021 privacy controversy sparked by a photo issue with its all-purpose super app WeChat as a “misunderstanding”. - 腾讯控股有限公司的创始人、董事长兼首席执行官马化腾将 2021 年因其全能超级应用程序微信出现照片问题而引发的隐私争议描述为“误解”。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是 Pony Ma Huateng has described a 2021 privacy controversy as a “misunderstanding”，其中主语是 Pony Ma Huateng，谓语是has described，宾语是a 2021 privacy controversy，表语是a “misunderstanding”。定语从句是sparked by a photo issue with its all-purpose super app WeChat，其中关系词是sparked，修饰先行词a 2021 privacy controversy，表示这一隐私争议是由微信的全能超级应用程序出现照片问题引发的。</p></li>    <li>Tencent said at the time that the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”, and it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user. - 腾讯当时表示，该应用程序正在寻找新图片，以便“让用户更快速、更流畅地发送照片”，并且它只在用户授权时访问图库。 <p>句子分析：这是一个复句，由两个简单句构成。主句是 Tencent said that the app was looking for new images，其中主语是 Tencent，谓语是said，宾语是the app was looking for new images。从句是to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”,其中关系词是to，修饰先行词the app was looking for new images，表示该应用程序正在寻找新图片是为了“让用户更快速、更流畅地发送照片”。另一个简单句是it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user，其中主语是it，谓语是accessed，宾语是the gallery，状语是when authorised by the user，表示该应用程序只在用户授权时访问图库。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词短语 - 由动词和副词或介词组成的短语。    <p>原文例句：Pony Ma Huateng, founder, chairman and CEO of Tencent Holdings, has described a 2021 privacy controversy sparked by a photo issue with its all-purpose super app WeChat as a “misunderstanding”.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，“sparked by a photo issue”是一个动词短语，由动词“spark”和介词词组“by a photo issue”组成。这个动词短语作定语，修饰名词“privacy controversy”，表示这个隐私争议是由一个照片问题引发的。</p></li>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的主语承受的。    <p>原文例句：The glitch had been fixed.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，动词“fixed”的被动语态形式是“had been fixed”，表示这个故障已经被修复了。这种语态的结构是：助动词be + 过去分词。被动语态可以使句子更加客观，突出动作或状态本身，而不强调动作的执行者。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Ma described the issue as ‘a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images’</li>
<li>The 2021 WeChat photo issue sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time despite reassurances that the glitch had been fixed</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/daec20ec-0fa7-42e0-ad58-197447fdda39_11d7714e.jpg" /><figcaption>Ma described the WeChat issue as “a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images”. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Pony Ma Huateng, founder, chairman and CEO of Tencent Holdings, has described a 2021 privacy controversy sparked by a photo issue with its all-purpose super app WeChat as a “misunderstanding”, according to a local media report.</p><p>Thay year, a tech influencer found that WeChat, China’s largest social media app with 1.3 billion monthly active users (MAUs), was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3151762/tencents-wechat-stop-routine-scans-photos-after-tech-influencer" target="_self" title="">frequently accessing user photo galleries even when not in use</a>, which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time.</p><p>Ma described the issue as “a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images”, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Yicai on Monday.</p><p>He said the matter was solved by the roll-out of a new application programming interface within the operating system to fix the lag.</p><p>Tencent said at the time that the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”, and it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user. The company also said it would cancel the scanning in a new version of the app.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Yicai picked up Ma’s comments from CSDNnews, a tech news outlet run by the Chinese Software Developer Network.</p><p>Ma told CSDNnews in a private WeChat message last Friday that this “old incident” in 2021 had been fixed, according to a screenshot shared by the outlet.</p><p>Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment by the Post on Monday.</p><p>China has introduced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3147040/what-chinas-new-data-laws-are-and-their-impact-big-tech?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">new laws in recent years</a> that tighten scrutiny over how tech companies handle personal data.</p><p>The Data Security Law and the Personal Information Protection Law, some of the world’s toughest data protection laws, went into effect in 2021 with strict penalties for the unauthorised collection, processing, storage and use of data generated in the country.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245623/chinas-finance-influencers-face-stricter-rules-tencents-live-streaming-channels-beijing-moves-shore" title="">China’s finance live streamers face stricter rules on Tencent</a></h3><p>Tencent faced intense scrutiny in 2021 when tech influencer Hackl0us said on social media platform Weibo that the app periodically accessed user photos while running in the background.</p><p>The activity was discovered using Apple’s “Record App Activity” feature on its iOS 15 operating system at that time.</p><p>The influencer also said in 2021 that Tencent’s QQ messaging app and Taobao, Alibaba Group Holding’s top online shopping marketplace with roughly 900 million MAUs, had also been found routinely accessing user photos. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tightening noose: Hong Kong joins EU, US, South Korea and Singapore in tightening crypto rules, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247684/hong-kong-joins-eu-us-south-korea-and-singapore-tightening-crypto-regulations-2023-report-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  2023年，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币法规。根据TRM Labs的数据，几乎一半收紧加密货币法规的司法管辖区加强了消费者保护措施。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Global jurisdictions tighten cryptocurrency regulations, emphasizing consumer protection amid market volatility.</li>    <li>Theme: Governments worldwide increase scrutiny of cryptocurrencies, leading to regulatory tightening and enhanced consumer safeguards.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The need for robust regulation to address risks and protect investors in the volatile cryptocurrency sector.</li>    <li>Main information: TRM Labs report highlights increased consumer protection measures in 2023; major jurisdictions like the EU, Hong Kong, and the US implement new regulations; stablecoin issuers face stricter guidelines.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023年，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡、美国在内的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币法规。TRM Labs的数据显示，近一半收紧加密法规的司法管辖区加强了消费者保护措施。  <ul>    <li>摘要：全球司法管辖区收紧加密货币法规，强调在市场波动中保护消费者。</li>    <li>主题：全球政府加强对加密货币的审查，导致监管收紧和加强消费者保护。</li>    <li>观点：需要强有力的监管来应对风险并保护波动加密货币行业中的投资者。</li>    <li>主要信息：TRM Labs 报告突出了 2023 年消费者保护措施的增加；欧盟、香港和美国等主要司法管辖区实施了新法规；稳定币发行人面临更严格的准则。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rout (n.) - /raʊt/ 溃败，大败。    <p>原文例句：The collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms, including the stablecoin TerraUSD and exchange FTX, led to a market rout that wiped out trillions of dollars in value. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“rout”表示溃败，大败，通常用于形容军队或金融市场的崩溃。在这个例句中，它指的是加密货币市场的大幅下跌，导致数万亿美元的价值化为乌有。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>volatile (adj.) - /ˈvɑːlətaɪl/ 不稳定的，易变的。    <p>原文例句：Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“volatile”表示不稳定的，易变的，通常用于形容金融市场或经济状况。在这个例句中，它指的是加密货币市场的不稳定性，以及各国政府加强对该市场的监管。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>lay out - 制定，提出。    <P>原文例句：International organisations, including the G20, the Financial Action Task Force, the Financial Stability Board, International Monetary Fund, and the International Organization of Securities Commissions, all laid out global frameworks and policy recommendations for regulating cryptocurrencies. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“lay out”表示制定，提出，通常用于形容政策、计划或建议。在这个例句中，它指的是国际组织制定了关于监管加密货币的全球框架和政策建议。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Among prominent moves, the European Union’s Markets in Crypto Assets Regulation came into force in June last year, and Hong Kong’s new licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges went live, the firm noted. - 在引人注目的举措中，欧盟的加密资产市场法规于去年 6 月生效，而香港针对集中式加密交易所的新许可制度也已上线，该公司指出。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The firm noted，其中主语是The firm，谓语是noted，宾语是两个分句。第一个分句是the European Union’s Markets in Crypto Assets Regulation came into force in June last year，其中主语是the European Union’s Markets in Crypto Assets Regulation，谓语是came into force，宾语是June last year。第二个分句是Hong Kong’s new licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges went live，其中主语是Hong Kong’s new licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges，谓语是went live，宾语为空。这个句子的意思是说，在引人注目的举措中，欧盟的加密资产市场法规于去年 6 月生效，而香港针对集中式加密交易所的新许可制度也已上线，该公司指出。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列分句 - 表示两个或多个并列成分之间的关系。    <p>原文例句：Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个并列分句，由两个分句组成，第一个分句是Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns，其中主语是Governments around the world，谓语是have increased，宾语是their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies。第二个分句是many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector，其中主语是many，谓语是strengthening，宾语是consumer protection。这两个分句用and连接，表示并列关系。这个句子的意思是说，在过去的一年里，各国政府在经历了一系列的崩溃事件后，加强了对加密货币的审查，许多国家在波动性很强的加密货币行业加强了对消费者的保护。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, tightened cryptocurrency regulations</li>
<li>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures, according to TRM Labs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/70965061-8587-4332-9ba0-361c7665e6c9_67fe6e02.jpg" /><figcaption>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US tightened cryptocurrency regulations. Photo: Bloomberg </figcaption></figure><p>Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p><p>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the European Union, South Korea, Singapore, and the United States, tightened cryptocurrency regulations, according to a report published on Monday by blockchain analytics firm TRM Labs.</p><p>Those strengthening protection accounted for 80 per cent of the 21 jurisdictions studied by the firm, with the latter representing 70 per cent of global exposure to cryptocurrencies, said TRM Labs.</p><p>In 2022, the collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms, including the stablecoin TerraUSD and exchange FTX, led to a market rout that wiped out trillions of dollars in value.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" title="">Hong Kong to push retail access to spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a></h3><p>While 2023 began with the crypto ecosystem “reeling from the collapse of FTX”, the subsequent 12 months “saw an extraordinary boom in regulation across the globe”, the report says.</p><p>Among prominent moves, the European Union’s Markets in Crypto Assets Regulation came into force in June last year, and Hong Kong’s new licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges went live, the firm noted.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>Singapore, which the report described as “an early adopter of crypto regulation”, in November last year issued a set of rules aimed at curbing retail speculation in cryptocurrencies, and finalised its rules for stablecoins.</p><p>Meanwhile, South Korea and Australia also increased scrutiny of the cryptocurrency sector last year, the report says.</p><p>In the US, the Securities and Exchange Commission ramped up its enforcement actions against crypto firms in 2023, and the House Financial Services Committee also advanced bills last July aimed at creating a federal regulatory framework for the crypto market, with specific attention to stablecoins.</p><p>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures, according to TRM Labs.</p><p>It also noted that international organisations, including the G20, the Financial Action Task Force, the Financial Stability Board, International Monetary Fund, and the International Organization of Securities Commissions, all laid out global frameworks and policy recommendations for regulating cryptocurrencies.</p><p>Hong Kong, which in October 2022 announced a major initiative to support the virtual asset sector with the goal of becoming a global hub for such businesses, has implemented a mandatory licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges that allow them to accept retail investors.</p><p>Eleven companies have so far submitted applications for the licence in the city, including OKX, one of the largest exchanges by trading volume.</p><p>In December, the Asian financial hub also <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246415/hong-kong-regulators-propose-tougher-rules-sale-stablecoins-retail-investors?module=hard_link&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">proposed rules for stablecoin issuers</a>, which would ban companies without a licence from selling stablecoins to Hong Kong’s retail investors through regulated channels, or from actively marketing their tokens to the city.</p><p>The rules have been deemed as “extremely challenging” for stablecoin issuers, potentially deterring operators of the world’s biggest stablecoins, such as Tether and USDC, from entering the city, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246692/hong-kongs-proposed-stablecoin-rules-would-be-extremely-challenging-global-issuers-tether-and-usdc" target="_self" title="">experts told the Post last month</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Shanghai explainer on taxation of digital currency transaction drives speculation on potential easing of China’s crypto ban</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247683/shanghai-explainer-taxation-digital-currency-transaction-drives-speculation-potential-easing-chinas</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  上海市税务局发布了一篇关于个人数字货币交易征税的解释性文章，引起了当地加密货币爱好者的广泛猜测，一些人认为这可能表明中国对加密货币的严格禁令正在放松。文章中引用了国家税务总局2008年的一份声明，一些大陆的加密货币内容创作者由此认为政府开始承认加密货币合法性。但上海市税务局随后删除了这篇文章， mainland  法律专家指出，该解释性文章并不意味着中国在加密货币政策上的潜在改变。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese tax agency’s article explaining cryptocurrency transaction taxes sparks speculation about potential policy change.</li>    <li>Theme: Shanghai tax authority’s article on digital currency taxation leads to discussions on cryptocurrency legitimacy in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Some crypto enthusiasts interpret the article as a signal of potential relaxation in China’s strict crypto ban; experts clarify that the article does not suggest any policy change.</li>    <li>Main information: Article’s circulation on WeChat; reference to 2008 STA statement on taxing virtual tokens in video games; individuals’ income tax obligations for online virtual currency transactions; China’s ongoing crackdown on crypto-related activities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  上海市税务局发布了一篇关于对数字货币交易征税的解释文章，引起了当地加密货币爱好者的广泛猜测，一些人认为这可能表明中国对加密货币的严格禁令正在放松。文章中引用了国家税务总局2008年的一份声明，一些大陆的加密货币内容创作者由此认为政府开始承认加密货币合法性。但上海市税务局随后删除了这篇文章，大陆法律专家指出，该解释性文章并不意味着中国在加密货币政策上的潜在改变。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国税务局解释加密货币交易税收的文章引发了潜在政策变化的猜测。</li>    <li>主题：上海税务局关于数字货币税收的文章引发了关于中国加密货币合法性的讨论。</li>    <li>观点：一些加密货币爱好者将这篇文章解读为中国对严格的加密货币禁令可能放松的信号；专家澄清，这篇文章并不意味着政策有任何改变。</li>    <li>主要信息：文章在微信上的传播；引用 2008 年国家税务总局关于对视频游戏中的虚拟代币征税的声明；个人在线虚拟货币交易的所得税义务；中国持续打击加密货币相关活动。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ramp up (v.) - /ræmp ʌp/ 增加，提高。    <p>原文例句：China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个动词片语是由ramp（斜坡）和up（向上）构成的，表示“增加，提高”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国多年来一直加大对所有与加密货币相关的活动的打击力度。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>speculation (n.) - /ˌspekjʊˈleɪʃən/ 推测，猜测。    <p>原文例句：The explainer became widely circulated on Sunday after some local crypto enthusiasts suggested that it acknowledged cryptocurrencies’ legitimacy.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词来源于拉丁语，由specere（看）和-tion（动作或过程）构成的，表示“推测，猜测”。在这个例句中，它指的是一些当地加密货币爱好者猜测这篇文章承认了加密货币的合法性</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rigid (adj.) - /ˈrɪdʒɪd/ 严格的，僵化的。    <p>原文例句：China’s rigid ban on cryptocurrencies would be reviewed amid Beijing’s drive to expand adoption of the digital yuan.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词来源于拉丁语，由rigere（僵硬）和-id（形容词后缀）构成的，表示“严格的，僵化的”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国的加密货币严格禁令。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>amid (prep.) - /əˈmɪd/ 在……之中，在……当中。    <p>原文例句：China’s rigid ban on cryptocurrencies would be reviewed amid Beijing’s drive to expand adoption of the digital yuan.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个介词来源于古英语，意为“在……之中，在……当中”。在这个例句中，它表示中国的加密货币严格禁令可能会在北京推动数字人民币采用的过程中被审查。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. -多 年来，中国加大了对所有与加密货币相关的活动的打击力度，理由是存在金融稳定风险。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是China has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies，其中主语是China，谓语是has ramped up，宾语是its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies。citing financial stability risks是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示中国加大打击力度的理由，即理由是存在金融稳定风险。这个句子的意思是说，多年来，中国加大了对所有与加密货币相关的活动的打击力度，理由是存在金融稳定风险。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句 - 用以强调句子中的某些部分，突出它的意义。    <p>原文例句：That prompted some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是在英语中用于突出强调句子中某个成分的句型。基本结构是：It + be + 主语 + 谓语 + that + 要强调的部分。在这个例句中，强调部分是authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies，即当局开始承认加密货币的合法性。这个句子的意思是说，这促使大陆的一些加密货币主题的在线内容创作者认为，对这类交易征税表明当局开始承认加密货币的合法性。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The explainer became widely circulated on Sunday after some local crypto enthusiasts suggested that it acknowledged cryptocurrencies’ legitimacy</li>
<li>The Shanghai Municipal Tax Service has since deleted the article from its public WeChat account</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/dd38a0bb-3bd5-4e5f-aee4-d25bc7d830f4_a5b28db7.jpg" /><figcaption>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>An online article posted by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a> Municipal Tax Service, explaining levies imposed on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/digital-currencies" target="_self" title="">digital currency</a> transactions in China, has fanned speculation among local cryptocurrency enthusiasts that it signals a potential relaxation of the country’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3208481/chinese-economist-calls-review-rigid-cryptocurrency-ban-digital-yuan-fails-take?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">draconian ban on crypto operations</a>.</p><p>The explainer, “Common Misunderstandings Regarding Personal Income Tax on Business Income and Categorised Income”, became widely circulated on Sunday after it was published on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> by the Shanghai tax service on Thursday. It cited a 2008 statement by the State Taxation Administration (STA).</p><p>That prompted some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies. The Shanghai tax service subsequently deleted the explainer on Sunday from its public WeChat account.</p><p>The wide attention received by the Shanghai tax service’s explainer reflects the lingering hope among Chinese crypto circles that the country’s rigid ban on cryptocurrencies would be reviewed amid Beijing’s drive to expand adoption of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/china-digital-currency/news" target="_self" title="">digital yuan</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology last month announced plans to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" target="_self" title="">draft a national Web3 development plan</a> to suit the country’s needs, although it did not specifically mention cryptocurrencies.</p><p>Mainland legal experts, however, pointed out that the Shanghai tax service’s explainer does not suggest any potential change in the country’s cryptocurrency policy.</p><p>The published article is not an official policy document, and the STA statement it cited concerns virtual tokens used in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video games</a>, according to Guo Zhihao, a partner at Beijing-based Yingke Law Firm, in an article he posted on WeChat on Sunday.</p><p>The explainer had indicated that individuals who obtain virtual currencies from other players through online transactions and generate revenue by selling them at a higher price must pay income tax on such earnings. The Shanghai tax agency’s article detailed taxation in four scenarios, including loans obtained by individual investors from their investee companies and online monetary gifts.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3208481/chinese-economist-calls-review-rigid-cryptocurrency-ban-digital-yuan-fails-take" title="">Chinese economist calls for review of rigid crypto ban amid slow e-CNY adoption</a></h3><p>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. It maintains that stance even though it <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3216894/chinese-officials-pledge-support-hong-kongs-tech-web3-ambitions-digital-economy-summit?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">supports Hong Kong’s ambitions to become a major hub for virtual assets</a>, including cryptocurrencies.</p><p>While there is no official sign from Beijing about changing its position on cryptocurrencies, local crypto circles expect increased regulatory oversight on the taxation of virtual asset-related income on the mainland.</p><p>China has denied legal-tender status for cryptocurrencies, but has not opposed its attribution as property or commodity, according to an article published on Friday by Jin Jianzhi of the Shanghai Mankun Law Firm. The lawyer said the government can levy taxes on relevant transactions under the law.</p><p>The global cryptocurrency market, meanwhile, appears to be slowly recovering from a prolonged slump last year. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bitcoin" target="_self" title="">Bitcoin</a> prices gained more than 150 per cent from a year earlier on the back of expectations that the US Securities and Exchange Commission will soon approve <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" target="_self" title="">bitcoin exchange-traded funds</a>, which would make these virtual assets more attractive to mainstream investors.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: Chinese tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to premier consumer electronics show in Las Vegas</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  The Consumer Electronics Show (CES) 2024 has witnessed a significant surge in participation from Chinese tech companies, signaling their efforts to expand and shake off the impact of the COVID-19 era. With over 1,100 exhibitors from China, the show aims to showcase innovations and trends in technology, especially in artificial intelligence (AI), smart homes, green tech, and electric vehicles.</li>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese tech companies' strong presence at CES 2024 mirrors their pursuit of overseas growth and recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic.</li>    <li>Theme: The return of Chinese tech giants to CES and the emergence of smaller Chinese companies highlight the importance of the show as a platform for global technology collaborations.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The show provides an opportunity for Chinese companies to demonstrate AI innovations, e-commerce integration, and automotive technologies.</li>    <li>Main information: Alibaba Group, TikTok, and other major Chinese companies have significant representation at CES; AI is the major trend at the show; the number of Chinese companies has increased by 126% compared to 2023; issues like data privacy and geopolitical tensions continue to exist.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国科技公司今年大举回归拉斯维加斯举行的CES大会，参展商数量较去年增长一倍以上，其中包括字节跳动和阿里巴巴等大公司。随着中国企业试图通过海外增长摆脱疫情时代的阴霾，CES展会的126家中国参展商数量比2023年增加了一倍多。CES在其网站上列出了来自中国的1115家注册公司，比2023年展会开始时列出的493家增加了126%。这还不包括许多使用国际地址加入的最大牌公司。字节跳动及其子公司TikTok，以及TCL和联想等去年的知名硬件品牌都注册了其美国办事处的地址。即使是《南华早报》的所有者阿里巴巴集团控股有限公司，也通过其子公司阿里巴巴新加坡公司参与了此次展会。TikTok瞄准亚马逊领地的175亿美元购物业务。周日下午在开幕致辞中，消费技术协会消费者计划总监布莱恩·科米斯基表示：“大型参展商重返CES，真正展示了这是一个面向消费者和企业的平台，可能[能够]应对我们面临的一些重大挑战。”这标志着2023年的形势发生了逆转。当时，中国刚刚开始重新开放边境，但对许多公司来说，限制并没有解除得足够快，无法在1月第一周赶上展会。Consumer Technology Association（CTA）负责CES的副总裁兼展会总监约翰·凯利在11月29日接受《邮报》采访时表示：“今年报名参展的一些规模最大的中国公司……都将在展会上大展身手。”“但我们真正看到中国方面增长的领域是小型企业。”凯利表示，CTA预计参展商数量将达到新冠疫情前水平，看起来展会已经实现了这一目标。中国公司的数量超过了国营报纸《环球时报》报道的2020年展会1000家。CTA表示，该展会吸引了约4000家参展商，尽管数字还没有最终确定。凯利表示，CES预计将迎来13万人参加。人工智能（AI）预计将成为今年展会上的主要趋势，自ChatGPT在过去一年引发生成式AI军备竞赛以来，人工智能的作用变得更大。在展会对媒体的开幕致辞中，智能家居、绿色科技和电动汽车是其他重点领域。阿里巴巴被强调为使用机器学习平台“推动电子商务”的参展商之一。总部位于深圳的智能照明公司Govee正在整合生成式人工智能，使用户能够创造特定的氛围。Matt Haldane摄。即使是规模较小的公司也标榜自己使用AI。来自深圳的智能照明制造商Govee宣传使用生成式人工智能来帮助人们创造特定氛围，比如要求一个让人联想起香港天际线或芭比娃娃梦想豪宅的背景。一些无晶圆厂芯片设计公司也参加了展览，例如总部位于福州的移动芯片制造商Rockchip和总部位于武汉的自动驾驶芯片制造商Black Sesame。Black Sesame与汽车公司吉利和比亚迪签订了合同。Black Sesame芯片由台积电制造。小鹏汽车是展会上主要的电动汽车制造商之一，它将展示其新“飞行汽车”AeroHT。XPeng在2024年国际消费电子展上展示其AeroHT飞行汽车。照片：派发。中国科技巨头的回归之际，地缘政治紧张局势几乎与去年没有变化。美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平可能在11月会面，但尚未就升级对半导体和人工智能等技术的限制做出重大政策转变。TikTok及其总部位于北京的所有者字节跳动因数据隐私和国家安全问题而受到华盛顿的严格政治审查。这可能并未阻止TikTok出现在其最大市场上最大的消费电子展上。2023年国际消费电子展中国科技公司数量不到疫情前水平的一半。该公司代表将参加展会上的两个小组讨论，讨论体育和娱乐。然而，除了娱乐之外，字节跳动的大部分收入来自广告，并一直在努力发展其电子商务业务。其他中国公司即使想参加展会，也无法参展，因为它们已列入华盛顿的实体清单。其中包括全球最大的无人机制造商大疆和多家半导体公司。CTA的凯利表示：“从展会管理的角度来看，我们欢迎每家公司的参与。”“作为一家总部位于美国的行业协会，我们不允许列入某种实体清单的公司参与。那确实是我们唯一不允许参与的地方。”尽管如此，对于构成展会展出面积大部分的众多小型企业而言，CES可能更为重要。它仍然是同类活动中的首要活动。凯利说：“我们想说明，在拉斯维加斯的这四天是您时间利用率最高的时候，因为您不必环游世界与六大洲的各个业务合作伙伴会面。”“相反，您可以在拉斯维加斯会见您需要会见的来自全球科技行业的所有人，为期一周。”###  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国科技企业积极参展CES，体现他们拓展海外市场，摆脱新冠疫情影响的决心。</li>    <li>主题：中国科技巨头回归CES，小型科技企业也纷纷亮相。凸显CES作为全球科技合作平台的重要地位。</li>    <li>观点：展会为中国公司展示人工智能创新、电子商务融合、汽车科技等提供机会。</li>    <li>主要信息：阿里巴巴集团、抖音等科技大厂热烈参展；人工智能为展会主要趋势；中国参展企业数量较2023年增长126%；数据隐私和地缘政治紧张等问题客观存在。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Asia - /ˈeɪʒə/ 亚洲。    <p>原文例句：The move was considered a step toward reviving investment in the manufacturing sector of Asia. </p>    <p>例句讲解：亚洲是地球上人口最多、面积最大、且拥有最多国家的大陆。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>effectively - /ɪˈfɛktɪvli/ 有效地。    <p>原文例句：The new strategy includes a number of measures aimed at effectively tackling the problem of drug trafficking. </p>    <p>例句讲解：effectively 是副词，意思是有效果的、有效地、实际地，常用来修饰动词或形容词。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>overseas - /ˌəʊvərˈsiz/ 海外的。    <p>原文例句：Overseas tourists have been a major source of revenue for the country in recent years. </p>    <p>例句讲解：overseas 是形容词或副词，表示在国外、海外的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Firefox is also very competitive in terms of performance and speed. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示Firefox在性能和速度方面也很有竞争力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>take place - 发生，进行。    <P>原文例句：The conference will take place in San Francisco from March 10-12. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，带）和place（地方）构成的，表示“发生，进行”。在这个例句中，它表示会议将在3月1  <ul><li>AI is the major trend this year in the wake of ChatGPT, with many companies touting how they are integrating the tech into their products</li>
<li>The return of Chinese tech giants comes even as geopolitical tensions have barely budged from where they were last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/2545b743-77c1-45e1-83aa-b5a50e2cd69e_8fe19122.jpg" /><figcaption>Attendees arrive at the CES Unveiled event before the start of the CES tech show, January 7, 2024, in Las Vegas. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese companies have returned to Las Vegas for CES in full force this year, with more than double the number of exhibitors compared with last year, including big names like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance">ByteDance</a> and Alibaba.com, as companies try to shake off Covid-era blues with overseas growth.</p><p>CES lists 1,115 companies registered from China on its website, a 126 per cent increase over the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial">493 listed</a> at the beginning of the 2023 show. That does not include many of the biggest names on the list, which joined using international addresses.</p><p>ByteDance and its subsidiary <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a>, along with big hardware brands from last year like TCL and Lenovo are registered under their US offices. Even <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, owner of the South China Morning Post, has a presence through its subsidiary Alibaba.com Singapore.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247219/tiktok-eyes-us175-billion-shopping-business-amazons-turf" title="">TikTok eyes US$17.5 billion shopping business on Amazon’s turf</a></h3><p>“You have big exhibitors coming back, really showcasing that this is a platform that really pushes for consumers and enterprises and maybe [can] combat some of these major challenges that we’re facing,” Brian Comiskey, director of consumer programmes at the CTA, said after his opening remarks on Sunday afternoon.</p><p>This marks a stark reversal from 2023, when China had just started to reopen its borders but restrictions did not fall fast enough for many companies to make it to the show in the first week of January.</p><p>“Some of the largest Chinese companies that have signed up for participation this year … will all have a large presence at the show,” John Kelley, vice-president and show director for CES at the Consumer Technology Association (CTA), told the Post in an interview on November 29. “But where we’re really seeing growth on the Chinese side is smaller companies.”</p><p>Kelley said the CTA was anticipating numbers to reach pre-Covid levels, and it looks like the show has pulled it off. The number of Chinese companies is more than the 1,000 that state-run tabloid Global Times reported for the 2020 show. CTA said the show has attracted around 4,000 exhibitors, although numbers are not final yet. Kelley said CES expects to see 130,000 attendees.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence">Artificial intelligence (AI)</a> is expected to be the major trend at the show this year, playing an even larger role since ChatGPT ignited a generative AI arms race over the past year. Smart homes, green tech and electric vehicles were other areas highlighted during the show’s opening remarks to the media.</p><p>Alibaba was highlighted as one of the exhibitors using machine learning platforms to “power e-commerce”.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1306" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/d1856897-2d66-43bf-b0ad-271970378ed9_da47af5a.jpg" title="Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even much smaller companies are touting their use of AI. Govee, a smart lighting maker from Shenzhen, is advertising the use of generative AI to help people create specific moods, like asking for a backdrop that is evocative of the Hong Kong skyline or Barbie Dreamhouse.</p><p>Some fabless chip design firms are also exhibiting, such as Fuzhou-based mobile chip maker Rockchip and Wuhan-based autonomous driving chip maker Black Sesame, which contracts with electric car companies Geely and BYD. Black Sesame chips are manufactured by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a>, it said.</p><p>Xpeng is among the major electric vehicle makers at the show, where it will be demonstrating its new “flying car”, the AeroHT.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1067" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/b8c16129-faf2-4eac-924a-4824d9f25c14_5368aac5.jpg" title="XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>The return of Chinese tech giants comes even as geopolitical tensions have barely budged from where they were last year. US President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping may have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3241692/joe-biden-xi-jinping-meet-person-first-time-year-apec-sidelines" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3241692/joe-biden-xi-jinping-meet-person-first-time-year-apec-sidelines">met in November</a>, but there have been no major policy shifts around escalating restrictions on technology such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors">semiconductors</a> and AI.</p><p>TikTok and its Beijing-based owner ByteDance have been under intense political scrutiny in Washington over data privacy and national security concerns. This may not have deterred TikTok from showing up to the largest consumer electronics shows in its largest market.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial" title="">Number of Chinese tech firms at CES 2023 less than half of pre-pandemic level</a></h3><p>Representatives from the company will join two panels at the show to discuss sports and entertainment. Beyond entertainment, though, ByteDance makes much of its money through advertising and has been trying to grow its e-commerce business.</p><p>Other Chinese companies cannot exhibit at the show even if they want to because they have been listed on Washington’s Entity List. This includes the world’s largest drone maker DJI and a number of semiconductor companies.</p><p>“From a show management perspective, we welcome participation from every company,” CTA’s Kelley said. “As a US-based trade association, we cannot allow participation if they are on some sort of Entity List. That’s really the only place where we will not allow participation.”</p><p>Still, CES may be more important for the many small firms that make up the bulk of the show’s exhibition floor. It remains the premier event of its kind.</p><p>“We like to make the case that the four days you spend in Las Vegas is some of the most efficient use of your time in the sense that you don’t have to necessarily travel the world to meet with individual business partners on six different continents,” said Kelley. “Instead, you can come to Las Vegas and meet everybody that you need to meet from the global technology industry over the course of a week.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung set for smallest profit drop in 6 quarters on chip rebound</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247610/samsung-set-smallest-profit-drop-6-quarters-chip-rebound</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In the fourth quarter of 2023, Samsung Electronics is expected to announce a 14% decrease in its profit, mainly due to a drop in the chip division. However, the chip division's loss is expected to have reduced compared to the previous quarters, and the mobile business is estimated to have performed better. The company's overall profit decline is the smallest in the past six quarters, indicating signs of recovery.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung Electronics' fourth-quarter profit is expected to fall by 14% due to a decrease in chip division earnings.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's financial performance in the fourth quarter and the impact of the chip division's losses on its overall profit.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Analysts' perspectives on Samsung's earnings report and the industry-wide recovery in the memory chip market.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's expected operating profit, chip division's reduced loss, recovery in chip prices, increased supply of silicon wafers, and mobile business performance.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在2023年第四季度，三星电子预计利润下降14%，这主要是由于芯片部门收益下降。然而，芯片部门的损失预计将较前几个季度有所减少，移动业务的业绩估计会更好。该公司最近六个季度的总体利润降幅最小，显示出复苏迹象。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星电子第四季度利润预计将因芯片部门收益下降而下降14%。</li>    <li>主题：三星第四季度的财务表现以及芯片部门亏损对其整体利润的影响。</li>    <li>观点：分析人士对三星收益报告和内存芯片市场整体复苏的看法。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星预期的营业利润、芯片部门亏损减少、芯片价格复苏、增加硅晶片供应以及移动业务表现。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>quarter (n.) - /ˈkwɔːrtər/ 季度，四分之一。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters, analysts estimate, as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由quartus（第四）构成，表示“四分之一”。在这个例句中，它指的是季度，即一年的四个部分之一。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rebound (v.) - /rɪˈbaʊnd/ 反弹，回升。    <p>原文例句：as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，由re-（再）和bound（跳跃，弹跳）构成，表示“反弹，回升”。在这个例句中，它指的是半导体价格的反弹，即价格从低点向高点回升。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>according to - 根据，按照。    <P>原文例句：Samsung’s chip division likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由according（同意，认可）和to（向，到）构成的，表示“根据，按照”。在这个例句中，它表示根据八个预测的平均值，三星的芯片部门可能将其季度亏损减少到约1.2万亿韩元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters, analysts estimate, as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division. - 分析师估计，三星电子将报告六个季度以来最小的利润下降，因为半导体价格反弹减少了这家韩国企业集团主要芯片部门的亏损。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop，其中主语是Samsung Electronics，谓语是expected to report，宾语是its smallest profit drop。in six quarters是一个时间状语，表示在六个季度内。analysts estimate是一个现在时态的动词短语，作状语，表示分析师估计。as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division是一个原因状语，表示由于半导体价格反弹减少了这家韩国企业集团主要芯片部门的亏损。这个句子的意思是说，分析师估计，三星电子将报告六个季度以来最小的利润下降，因为半导体价格反弹减少了这家韩国企业集团主要芯片部门的亏损。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示比较。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters, analysts estimate, as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在英语中，形容词和副词的比较级用来比较两个或两个以上的事物或情况。比较级通常在形容词或副词后加-er或more构成。在这个例句中，smallest是形容词small的比较级，表示“最小的”，用来比较三星电子在六个季度中的利润下降幅度。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态持续到现在的结果或影响。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是一种时态，表示过去发生的动作或状态持续到现在的结果或影响。它的结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词形式。在这个例句中，at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024是一个时间状语，表示在2024年1月7日在首尔的Samsung Store。Photo: Bloomberg是一个现在完成时的名词性从句，表示布隆伯格的照片。这个句子的意思是说，2024年1月7日在首尔的Samsung Store有三星Galaxy Z Fold 5智能手机，这是布隆伯格的照片。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The world’s biggest maker of memory chips, smartphones and televisions is expected to show a 14 per cent fall in fourth-quarter profit</li>
<li>Samsung’s chip division likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts</li>
</ul><p>Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters, analysts estimate, as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division.</p><p>The world’s biggest maker of memory chips, smartphones and televisions is expected to show a 14 per cent fall in fourth-quarter profit when it announces preliminary earnings on Tuesday.</p><p>Operating profit likely fell to 3.7 trillion won (US$2.82 billion) in the October-December quarter, according to the average of an LSEG SmartEstimate from 30 analysts, weighted toward those who are more consistently accurate.</p><p>That would compare with an operating profit of 4.31 trillion won in the December quarter of the previous year. Samsung last reported a year-on-year quarterly profit increase for the second quarter of 2022.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/article/3245933/us-gather-chips-supply-chain-intelligence-boost-national-security" title="">US to gather chip supply chain intelligence to boost national security</a></h3><p>A solid set of results would justify Samsung’s sharp stock market run-up in the fourth quarter, which has made it Asia’s second-most valuable listed company after chip foundry rival Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co, with a market capitalisation of about US$390 billion.</p><p>Samsung’s chip division – traditionally its biggest earner – likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts. Analysts said its dynamic random access memory (DRAM) chips business returned to a profit.</p><p>Samsung had reported chip division losses of 4.36 trillion won and 3.75 trillion won in the second and third quarters, respectively, as a semiconductor glut from slow demand for gadgets driven by inflation pressures on consumers caused the worst industry downturn in decades.</p><p>However, prices of DRAM chips – used in various tech devices – and NAND flash chips – used to store data – rebounded in the December quarter, including for older chips, in a sign of an industry-wide recovery expected this year.</p><p>Mobile DRAM chip prices rose an estimated 18 to 23 per cent during the fourth quarter, while mobile NAND flash chip prices rose 10 to 15 per cent, according to data provider TrendForce.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/8f2d3cfa-7d39-4dd6-b8f2-d7fda417159f_34f54c2a.jpg" title="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>While Samsung has repeatedly cut production since the first half of 2023 to cope with the downturn, analysts and sources said Samsung took in more supply of silicon wafers, the building blocks for semiconductors, in the fourth quarter, signalling it is gearing up to increase DRAM chip production.</p><p>Samsung was also more aggressive in selling memory chips than competitors, such as SK Hynix, in the fourth quarter in a bid to lower inventory, analysts said.</p><p>Rival Micron Technology forecast a quarterly revenue above market estimates last month, in a sign of a recovery in the memory chip market in 2024.</p><p>Samsung’s mobile business likely saw an operating profit of around 2.5 trillion won, according to an average of forecasts from eight analysts, as shipments of its two flagship foldable models were estimated to have fallen about 1 million units each versus the third quarter.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Podcasts gain popularity in China as one in five internet users tuned in last year, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247572/podcasts-gain-popularity-china-one-five-internet-users-tuned-last-year-says-report</link>
<description><![CDATA[ ```html###<div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In China, online podcasts experienced a surge in popularity in 2023, with 220 million out of 1.1 billion internet users tuning into podcasts on Ximalaya.</li>    <li>The audience for podcasts in China skews towards young professionals in higher-tier cities, with the 24-40 age group and tier-one and tier-two city dwellers being the largest demographics of podcast listeners.</li>    <li>Consumers are increasingly willing to pay for premium podcast content, with over half of listeners subscribing to paid content and 22,000 podcast hosts earning a total of 9.8 million US dollars on Ximalaya in 2023.</li>    <li>Podcasts generated revenue through advertising from global brands like Coca-Cola and Cadillac and were popular for daily commuting and featured genres like health, lifestyle, history, technology, business, entertainment, fantasy, and thriller stories.</li>    <li>Censorship in China has influenced podcast content, with general news and politics being absent from popular genres due to strict restrictions.</li>    <li>Despite censorship, the podcast industry in China is thriving, benefiting from the adoption of generative AI tools that enhance efficiency and content creation.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>2023年，中国的网络播客经历了爆发式增长，在喜马拉雅平台上，超过2.2亿来自11亿网民收听播客。</li>    <li>播客的受众群体向一线城市的年轻专业人士倾斜，24-40岁年龄段和一线、二线城市的人群是最大的播客听众群体。</li>    <li>消费者越来越愿意为优质的播客内容付费，超过一半的听众订阅了付费内容，在2023年喜马拉雅平台上，超过2.2万名播客主播获得了总计980万美元的收入。</li>    <li>播客通过可口可乐、凯迪拉克等国际品牌的广告创收，并因其适合通勤收听以及囊括健康、生活、历史、科技、商业、娱乐、奇幻和惊悚等多种题材而广受欢迎。</li>    <li>中国的审查制度影响了播客内容，由于严格的限制，时政新闻等热门类型播客在中国缺失。</li>    <li>尽管存在审查制度，但中国的播客行业仍然蓬勃发展，并受益于采用增强效率和内容创作的生成式AI工具。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>niche (n.) - /nɪtʃ/ 利基市场，适合小部分受众的专门市场。    <p>原文例句：One in five internet users in China listened to a podcast last year, as the once niche sector gained popularity in 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“niche”源于法语，指的是适合小部分受众的专门市场，可以翻译为“利基市场”。在这个例句中，“niche sector”是指播客行业，曾经是一个小众市场，但在2023年变得越来越受欢迎。</p>    </li>    <li>monetization (n.) - /ˌmɑːnɪtɪˈzeɪʃən/ 货币化，将资源转换成经济效益。    <p>原文例句：Young professionals also helped Chinese podcasts attract advertisements from global brands, from food and beverage giant Coca-Cola to luxury US carmaker Cadillac, providing an additional monetisation channel for the industry.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“monetization”源于拉丁语，意为“货币化”，指的是将资源转换成经济效益。在这个例句中，“monetization”是指通过吸引来自可口可乐和凯迪拉克等国际品牌的广告，为播客行业提供额外的营收渠道。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tune into - 收听，收看。    <p>原文例句：More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts on Ximalaya’s platform last year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“tune into”是一个习语，意为“收听，收看”。在这个例句中，“tuned into”是指超过2.2亿中国网民在喜马拉雅平台上收听播客。</p>    </li>    <li>skew towards - 倾向于。    <p>原文例句：The audience for its podcasts skewed towards young Chinese professionals working in the country’s higher-tier cities, Ximalaya’s research showed.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“skew towards”是一个习语，意为“倾向于”。在这个例句中，“skewed towards”是指喜马拉雅平台播客的受众群体倾向于一线城市的年轻专业人士。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence (AI), which increases efficiency and helps with content creation, thanks to a suite of AI-powered audio tools Ximalaya launched last year. - 中国的播客行业也搭上了生成式人工智能 (AI) 的浪潮，这要归功于喜马拉雅去年推出的 AI 音频工具套件，该工具套件提高了效率，并帮助创建了内容。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence (AI)，主语是the podcast industry in China，谓语是is riding；从句which increases efficiency and helps with content creation是一个定语从句，修饰generative artificial intelligence (AI)；thanks to a suite of AI-powered audio tools Ximalaya launched last year是一个介词短语，作原因状语，修饰主句。整句话的意思是：中国的播客行业也搭上了生成式人工智能 (AI) 的浪潮，这要归功于喜马拉雅去年推出的 AI 音频工具套件，该工具套件提高了效率，并帮助创建了内容。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>一般现在时 - 表示现在或经常发生的事件或状态。    <p>原文例句：Consumers in China are also increasingly more inclined to pay for quality podcast content, with more than half signing up for premium content.</p>    <p>语法讲解：一般现在时用于表示现在或经常发生的事件或状态。其基本结构是：主语 + be动词/助动词 + 动词原形。在这个例句中，主语是Consumers in China，be动词是are，动词原形是inclined。整句话的意思是：中国的消费者也越来越愿意为优质的播客内容付费，超过一半的人订阅了付费内容。</p>    </li>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence (AI), which increases efficiency and helps with content creation, thanks to a suite of AI-powered audio tools Ximalaya launched last year.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在进行时用于表示正在发生的动作或状态。其基本结构是：主语 + be动词/助动词 + 动词ing。在这个例句中，主语是the podcast industry in China，be动词是is，动词ing为riding。整句话的意思是：中国的播客行业也搭上了生成式人工智能 (AI) 的浪潮，这要归功于喜马拉雅去年推出的 AI 音频工具套件，该工具套件提高了效率，并帮助创建了内容。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>###```  <ul><li>More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts on Ximalaya’s platform last year, across 31 genres</li>
<li>Young professionals helped Chinese podcasts attract ads from global brands such as drinks giant Coca-Cola and luxury carmaker Cadillac</li>
</ul><p>One in five internet users in China listened to a podcast last year, as the once niche sector gained popularity in 2023, according to a recently published research.</p><p>More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts hosted by Ximalaya last year, across 31 genres of programmes, according to research published on Friday by the Chinese podcast service provider.</p><p>The audience for its podcasts skewed towards young Chinese professionals working in the country’s higher-tier cities, Ximalaya’s research showed.</p><p>The user group aged between 24 and 40 years represented more than 60 per cent of podcast listeners in China, while those from tier-one and tier-two cities accounted for more than 65 per cent of the total audience.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after" title="">China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech must end, party paper says</a></h3><p>Consumers in China are also increasingly more inclined to pay for quality podcast content, with more than half signing up for premium content. More than 22,000 podcast hosts earned a combined total of 70 million yuan (US$9.8 million) on Ximalaya last year, the company revealed in its research.</p><p>Young professionals also helped Chinese podcasts attract advertisements from global brands, from food and beverage giant Coca-Cola to luxury US carmaker Cadillac, providing an additional monetisation channel for the industry, according to a separate report by market consultancy iResearch.</p><p>Chinese users primarily tuned into podcasts during their daily commutes, with health and lifestyle, Chinese history, global politics, frontier technology, business and entertainment, as well as fantasy and thriller stories among the most popular genres on the Ximalaya platform.</p><p>Chinese podcast preferences were partially the result of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3244838/chinas-online-censors-target-short-videos-artificial-intelligence-and-pessimism-latest-crackdown" target="_self" title="">the country’s strict censorship of online content.</a> General news and politics, two of the most popular genres among podcast listeners in Western countries, were missing from the list in China, according to Ethan Cramer-Flood, a researcher at market consultancy Insider Intelligence.</p><p>“In the West, maybe news and politics rank relatively highly, whereas in China it’s just nowhere to be found because the censorship regime is so strict there,” Flood said in an online discussion last November. “So it’s [topics] like lifestyle, fashion, pet care … sports [that] are all at the top of the list because [they are] nothing remotely controversial.”</p><p>Still, Chinese podcasts are flourishing despite the country’s online content crackdown. In 2023, Ximalaya’s platform hosted 5.2 million more podcast episodes than the year before.</p><p>The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence (AI), which increases efficiency and helps with content creation, thanks to a suite of AI-powered audio tools Ximalaya launched last year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
