<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Amazon’s Twitch to cut 500 employees, or 35% of staff, as soon as January 10 as business remains unprofitable</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247877/amazons-twitch-cut-500-employees-or-35-staff-soon-january-10-business-remains-unprofitable</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Twitch, a live-streaming platform, plans to lay off approximately 35% of its workforce, or about 500 employees, due to financial losses and the departure of several top executives.</li>    <li>The website's operating costs are significantly high, with 1.8 billion hours of live video content streamed monthly, despite Amazon's infrastructure support.</li>    <li>Twitch previously closed operations in South Korea due to high costs.</li>    <li>In recent years, the company has focused on advertising, but it remains unprofitable despite Amazon's acquisition nine years ago.</li>    <li>Several top executives left Twitch in late 2023, including the chief product officer, customer officer, and content officer.</li>    <li>The new CEO, Dan Clancy, has attempted to improve relationships with gaming celebrities who use Twitch, but losses continue.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>在线流媒体平台Twitch计划裁员约35%，即约500名员工，原因是公司亏损和多位高管离职。</li>    <li>该网站的运营成本非常高，每月有18亿小时的视频内容直播，尽管有亚马逊的基础设施支持。</li>    <li>Twitch此前已关闭了在韩国的运营部门，原因是成本过高。</li>    <li>近年来，该公司重点关注广告方面，但尽管九年前被亚马逊收购，它仍然无利可图。</li>    <li>在2023年底，多位Twitch高管宣布离职，包括首席产品官、首席客户官和首席内容官。</li>    <li>新任首席执行官丹·克兰西试图改善与在Twitch上直播游戏的主播之间的关系，但亏损仍在继续。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>exacerbate (v.) - /ɪgˈzæsərbeɪt/ 加剧，恶化。    <p>原文例句：Rising fuel and labor costs exacerbate the situation, and competing with Beijing's Belt and Road Initiative is driving up the price of labor in many countries.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由ex-（出，外）和acerbare（使苦）组成，意为“使恶化，加剧”。在这个例句中，它指的是不断上涨的燃料和劳动力成本加剧了局势，而与中国的'一带一路'倡议竞争正在推高许多国家的劳动力价格。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in order to - 为了。    <p>原文例句：Streaming services are also increasingly offering their own original content in order to compete with traditional TV channels.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这是一个常用的词组，表示目的或意图。在这个例句中，它表示流媒体服务也在越来越多地提供自己的原创内容，以便与传统电视频道竞争。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The cuts, which could be announced as soon as Wednesday, come amid concerns over losses at Twitch and after several top executives left the company in the span of a few months. - 这些裁员可能最早在星期三宣布，这是由于对Twitch亏损的担忧，以及多位高管在几个月内离开公司之后。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是These cuts come amid concerns over losses at Twitch and after several top executives left the company in the span of a few months，其中主语是These cuts，谓语是come，宾语是concerns over losses at Twitch and after several top executives left the company in the span of a few months。which could be announced as soon as Wednesday是一个定语从句，修饰These cuts，表示这些裁员可能最早在星期三宣布。amid concerns over losses at Twitch and after several top executives left the company in the span of a few months是一个介词短语，作状语，表示在对Twitch亏损的担忧和多位高管在几个月内离开公司之后。这个句子的意思是说，这些裁员可能最早在星期三宣布，这是由于对Twitch亏损的担忧，以及多位高管在几个月内离开公司之后。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词作状语 - 表示原因、条件、方式、目的等。    <p>原文例句： Despite struggling with double-digit inflation, Kenya attracted $1.4 billion of investment in March last year, making it the second largest recipient in sub-Saharan Africa, after South Africa.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是用非谓语动词作状语的一种方式，可以表示原因、条件、方式、目的等。结构是：分词+其他。分词可以是现在分词或过去分词。在这个例句中，despite struggling with double-digit inflation是一个分词短语作状语，表示尽管肯尼亚正在与两位数的通货膨胀作斗争。making it the second largest recipient in sub-Saharan Africa, after South Africa是一个分词短语作状语，表示使它成为撒哈拉以南非洲的第二大接收国，仅次于南非。这个句子的意思是说，尽管肯尼亚正在与两位数的通货膨胀作斗争，但它在去年3月吸引了14亿美元的投资，使其成为撒哈拉以南非洲的第二大接收国，仅次于南非。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The cuts come after Twitch’s chief product officer, chief customer officer and chief content officer left in the final months of 2023</li>
<li>Running a large-scale website supporting 1.8 billion hours of live video content a month is enormously expensive, company executives have said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/8e0079a2-e991-49d9-b8f1-4083c640dff1_9b4dff42.jpg" /><figcaption>Twitch plans to make another round of job cuts as soon as Wednesday. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Amazon.com’s live-streaming site Twitch is poised to cut 35 per cent of its staff, or about 500 workers, according to people familiar with the plans, the latest in a series of job reductions there.</p><p>The cuts, which could be announced as soon as Wednesday, come amid concerns over losses at Twitch and after several top executives left the company in the span of a few months. A Twitch spokesperson declined to comment.</p><p>Running a large-scale website supporting 1.8 billion hours of live video content a month is enormously expensive, despite Twitch’s reliance on Amazon’s infrastructure, company executives have said.</p><p>In December, Twitch chief executive officer Dan Clancy said the company would cease operations in South Korea, where the costs are “prohibitively expensive”, according to a blog post he wrote.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Twitch has increased its focus on advertising in recent years. Nine years after Amazon’s acquisition of the company, the business remains unprofitable, according to the people, who asked not to be identified discussing private information.</p><p>In the final months of 2023, several top executives announced their departures, including Twitch’s chief product officer, chief customer officer and chief content officer. Twitch also lost its chief revenue officer, who worked on Twitch from within Amazon’s ads unit.</p><p>“It’s always bittersweet when talented leaders move on to pursue new opportunities,’’ a Twitch spokesperson said at the time. “We are incredibly grateful for their contributions to Twitch and our community, and wish them all the best.”</p><p>The former employees all declined to comment.</p><p>Since he took the position in March 2023, Clancy has been on a cross-country charm offensive to mend relations with the gaming celebrities who make a living streaming on Twitch.</p><p>Many of them chafed at Twitch’s original approach to ads, which the company reworked after criticism. Streamers have praised Clancy’s desire to listen to their concerns after years of complaints that the service was out of touch with its users.</p><p>The new chief has struggled to stem losses, however. Twitch undertook two rounds of lay-offs last year, cutting over 400 positions, part of wider job reductions at Amazon.</p><p>The online retail giant initiated its biggest-ever corporate job cuts in 2022, which it expanded to 27,000 positions across the company. It continued in October with a new round of cuts to its music division, which encompasses the company’s audio streaming platform and digital storefront for songs.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s DingTalk updates workplace collaboration app with new AI agent amid growing client demand</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247831/alibabas-dingtalk-updates-workplace-collaboration-app-new-ai-agent-amid-growing-client-demand</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba's DingTalk 7.5 incorporates an AI agent feature powered by the Tongyi Qianwen large language model. </li>    <li>This AI agent aims to streamline and customize user workflows, based on feedback from over 700,000 corporate clients. </li>    <li>The goal is to create an AI agent platform with low entry barriers, targeting substantial market growth over the next three years. </li>    <li>DingTalk aims to become an AI agent platform with low entry barriers, targeting substantial market growth in the next three years. </li>    <li>Belle International uses a customized AI agent on DingTalk to track parcel shipment issues, with plans to expand its use to other cases.</li>    <li>ByteDance's Feishu also offers an AI bot, the Feishu Intelligent Buddy, for daily task assistance, as well as a platform for corporate clients to build custom AI bots.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>阿里巴巴旗下的钉钉7.5版本加入了AI智能助手功能，由其内部的通讯语言模型“同义千文”提供支持。</li>    <li>AI智能助手旨在优化和个性化用户工作流程，基于70多万企业客户的反馈。</li>    <li>钉钉的目标是成为一个准入门槛较低的AI智能助手平台，预计未来三年市场将有大幅增长。</li>    <li>时装零售巨头百丽国际在钉钉平台上推出了一个定制的AI智能助手，用于跟踪包裹运输问题，并计划将其应用范围扩大到更多情况中。</li>    <li>字节跳动的飞书也提供了一个AI机器人助手“飞书智能助理”，可以帮助用户处理日常工作，例如起草电子邮件、整理电子表格和总结长篇报告。</li>    <li>飞书还宣布推出一个平台，帮助企业客户根据自身业务需求构建和定制AI机器人助手。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>customise (v.) - /ˈkʌstəmʌɪz/ 定制，自定义。    <p>原文例句：The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou, capital of eastern Zhejiang province, is designed to address feedback gleaned from more than 700,000 corporate clients, said Ye Jun, president of DingTalk, in a statement. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“customize”的意思是“定制，自定义”，它是由“custom”（习惯，习俗）和“-ize”（使……成为……）组成的。在这个句子中，“customize”是指根据客户的反馈来定制和调整钉钉的功能，使其更符合客户的需求。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>substantial (adj.) - /səbˈstænʃəl/ 大量的，重大的。    <p>原文例句：Ye added that DingTalk’s goal is to become an AI agent platform with low entry barriers, with the marketplace expected to grow substantially in the next three years. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“substantial”的意思是“大量的，重大的”，它是由“sub”（在……之下）和“stance”（站立，立场）组成的。在这个句子中，“substantial”是指钉钉AI智能助手平台的市场预计将在未来三年内有大幅增长。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>corporate clients - 企业客户。    <p>原文例句： The development comes amid a flurry of activity in the AI sector as Chinese companies rush to incorporate ChatGPT-like services into their products and after a similar move by ByteDance’s rival app Feishu. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“corporate clients”是指企业客户，是那些使用钉钉平台的企业和组织。在这个句子中，“corporate clients”是指那些使用钉钉平台的企业和组织。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou, capital of eastern Zhejiang province, is designed to address feedback gleaned from more than 700,000 corporate clients, said Ye Jun, president of DingTalk, in a statement. - 钉钉7.5版本加入了人工智能代理功能，该功能由东部浙江省首府杭州举行的企业活动中宣布，旨在解决来自70多万企业客户的反馈，钉钉总裁叶军在一份声明中表示。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，结构比较复杂，主句是is designed to address feedback gleaned from more than 700,000 corporate clients，主语是The AI agent feature，谓语是is designed to address，宾语是feedback gleaned from more than 700,000 corporate clients。said Ye Jun, president of DingTalk, in a statement是一个插入语，提供有关此声明的信息。这个句子的意思是说，钉钉7.5版本加入了人工智能代理功能，该功能由东部浙江省首府杭州举行的企业活动中宣布，旨在解决来自70多万企业客户的反馈，钉钉总裁叶军在一份声明中表示。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式作目的语 - 动词不定式可以作目的语，表示说话者或主语希望做某事或打算做某事。    <p>原文例句：The development comes amid a flurry of activity in the AI sector as Chinese companies rush to incorporate ChatGPT-like services into their products and after a similar move by ByteDance’s rival app Feishu. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，“incorporate ChatGPT-like services into their products”是一个动词不定式作目的语，表示中国公司希望把ChatGPT这样的服务整合到他们的产品中。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>动词不定式作表语 - 动词不定式可以作表语，表示说话者或主语对某事的看法或态度。    <p>原文例句：The goal is to become an AI agent platform with low entry barriers, with the marketplace expected to grow substantially in the next three years. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，“to become an AI agent platform with low entry barriers”是一个动词不定式作表语，表示钉钉的目标是成为一个准入门槛较低的AI智能助手平台。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>DingTalk’s AI agent function is powered by Alibaba’sTongyi Qianwen large language model</li>
<li>The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/30e71220-1a5a-4efb-b280-5bfdcfbd741d_5ecb7eee.jpg" /><figcaption>The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou. Photo: VCG via Getty Images </figcaption></figure><p>Alibaba Group Holding’s DingTalk launched an updated version of its workplace collaboration app on Tuesday with the addition of an artificial intelligence (AI) agent function to help users streamline and customise their workflow.</p><p>The development comes amid a flurry of activity in the AI sector as Chinese companies rush to incorporate ChatGPT-like services into their products and after a similar move by ByteDance’s rival app Feishu. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>The AI agent feature announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou, capital of eastern Zhejiang province, is designed to address feedback gleaned from more than 700,000 corporate clients, said Ye Jun, president of DingTalk, in a statement.</p><p>The new tool is expected to promote greater adoption of AI products in the industry, according to the company.</p><p>“As the tide of AI-generated content increasingly finds its way into productivity and [business] use cases, AI agents have emerged as the most suitable gateway for AI applications,” said Ye.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242571/bytedance-adds-ai-assistant-office-tool-feishu-joining-rivals-tencent-and-alibaba-workplace-chatbot" title="">ByteDance brings AI to office tool Feishu, taking on Tencent and Alibaba</a></h3><p>Ye added that DingTalk’s goal is to become an AI agent platform with low entry barriers, with the marketplace expected to grow substantially in the next three years.</p><p>As of the end of 2023, Dingtalk had over 700 million users. It also has 25 million organisations, including corporate and educational institutions that use its platform, of which 120,000 are paying clients, said Ye.</p><p>Shoes and apparel giant Belle International has rolled out a customised AI agent on its DingTalk platform to track parcel shipment issues, with plans to expand the use of the agent to more cases, including stock allocation.</p><p>DingTalk’s addition of an AI agent function, powered by the group’s Tongyi Qianwen large language model (LLM), comes after ByteDance’s Feishu made a similar push last November.</p><p>LLMs are the deep learning models, pre-trained on vast amounts of data, that underpin chatbots such as OpenAI’s ChatGPT, which took the world by storm a year ago with its ability to understand complex questions and respond with human-like text.</p><p>At the launch of Feishu 7, ByteDance introduced an AI bot dubbed Feishu Intelligent Buddy, which can help users with daily tasks such as drafting emails, drawing up spreadsheets and summarising long reports.</p><p>Feishu also announced a platform to enable its corporate clients to build and customise AI bots according to business needs, it said at the time.</p><p>After a year of hype over AI chatbots, Chinese Big Tech firms including Alibaba, ByteDance and Baidu have been rushing to build competitor products to ChatGPT, with applications spanning the finance, legal, manufacturing, retail and public sectors.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s logistics arm Cainiao offers shoppers in US grouped delivery service, cutting shipping times to five days</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247829/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-offers-shoppers-us-grouped-delivery-service-cutting-shipping-times</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2> Cainiao, Alibaba's logistics arm, will launch a consolidated shipping service in the US, allowing consumers to package multiple online purchases from various platforms and ship them together from China, reducing delivery times and costs. The service targets Chinese consumers and students in the US who frequently purchase goods from Chinese e-commerce sites. Cainiao aims to tap into the growing cross-border e-commerce market and expand its global presence.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Cainiao introduces consolidated shipping service in the US to optimize cross-border e-commerce deliveries for Chinese consumers.</li>    <li>Theme: Cainiao's strategic move to cater to Chinese consumers in the US and enhance cross-border logistics efficiency.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The increasing demand for streamlined cross-border shipping solutions driven by the popularity of Chinese e-commerce sites among overseas consumers.</li>    <li>Main information: Consolidated shipping service covering air and sea routes; targeting Chinese consumers and students in the US; potential cost reduction and faster delivery times; expansion of Cainiao's global logistics network.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  菜鸟作为阿里巴巴的物流部门，将率先在美国推出集合发货服务，允许消费者从不同的平台上购买多件物品并从中国一起发货，缩短交货时间并降低成本。该服务主要针对那些经常从中国电子商务网站购买商品的中国消费者和学生。菜鸟旨在通过此举来打入不断壮大的跨境电子商务市场并扩大其全球业务。         <ul>    <li>摘要：菜鸟在美国推出整合发货服务，为在美华人用户优化跨境电子商务配送。</li>    <li>主题：菜鸟的战略举措，致力于满足美籍华人消费者的需求并增强跨境物流效率。</li>    <li>观点：由于中国电商网站在海外消费者中的欢迎程度不断上升，对精简的跨境运输解决方案的需求越来越高。</li>    <li>主要信息：整合发货服务同时涵盖空运和海运路线;目标用户为美籍华人消费者和留学生;能够降低成本和缩短交付时间;扩大菜鸟的全球物流网络。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>consolidated (adj.) - /kənˈsɑːlɪdeɪtɪd/  合并的，集中的。    <p>原文例句：The so-called “consolidated shipping” service, covering both air and sea transport routes, will collect multiple online shopping orders placed by users on various platforms in a warehouse before shipping them from China. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由con-（一起）和solidated（固体）构成的，表示“合并的，集中的”。在这个例句中，它指的是“consolidated shipping”服务，即菜鸟将多个平台上的多个用户的订单集中在一个仓库里，然后统一从中国发货。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>parcel (n.) - /ˈpɑːrsəl/ 包裹，小包。    <p>原文例句：If the parcel is sent via air, delivery times may be reduced five days after the items are sent out from the warehouse.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle French，表示“包裹，小包”。在这个例句中，它指的是包裹，即装有物品的纸盒或袋子等物品。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>reduce to - 减少至，降低到。    <P>原文例句：If the parcel is sent via air, delivery times may be reduced five days after the items are sent out from the warehouse. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由reduce（减少）和to（到）构成的，表示“减少至，降低到”。在这个例句中，它表示如果包裹是通过空运发送，那么在物品从仓库发出后五天内，送货时间可能会减少</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics unit, Cainiao, will open a new service for consumers in the US to allow them to package several items they have bought together, cutting delivery times to as little as five days. - 菜鸟，阿里巴巴集团控股的物流部门，将在美国为消费者开设一项新服务，允许他们将购买的几件物品打包在一起，从而将交货时间缩短至短短五天。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Cainiao will open a new service，其中主语是Cainiao，谓语是will open，宾语是a new service。for consumers in the US to allow them to package several items they have bought together, cutting delivery times to as little as five days是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示菜鸟开设这项新服务的目的是为了让消费者可以将购买的几件物品打包在一起，从而将交货时间缩短至短短五天。这个句子的意思是说，菜鸟，阿里巴巴集团控股的物流部门，将在美国为消费者开设一项新服务，允许他们将购买的几件物品打包在一起，从而将交货时间缩短至短短五天。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式短语作目的状语 - 表示动作或状态的目的。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics unit, Cainiao, will open a new service for consumers in the US to allow them to package several items they have bought together, cutting delivery times to as little as five days. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是不定式短语的一种用法，表示动作或状态的目的。结构是：to + 动词原形 + 其他。其中to + 动词原形表示一个动作或状态的目的，其他是这个动作或状态的具体内容。在这个例句中，to allow them to package several items they have bought together, cutting delivery times to as little as five days是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示菜鸟开设这项新服务的目的是为了让消费者可以将购买的几件物品打包在一起，从而将交货时间缩短至短短五天。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态发生的时间、原因、方式等。    <p>原文例句：If the parcel is sent via air, delivery times may be reduced five days after the items are sent out from the warehouse.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是过去分词短语的一种用法，表示动作或状态发生的时间、原因、方式等。结构是：过去分词 + 其他。其中过去分词表示一个动作或状态已经发生，其他是这个动作或状态发生的时间、原因、方式等。在这个例句中，sent out from the warehouse是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示物品从仓库发出后这个动作发生的时间，即如果包裹是通过空运发送，那么在物品从仓库发出后五天内，送货时间可能会减少。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Cainiao said cross-border shipping service would mainly help Chinese consumers in US who tend to buy lots of goods on Chinese sites</li>
<li>The so-called ‘consolidated shipping’ service covers both air and sea transport routes</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/8c90f6e8-359a-4cee-bbfa-62226abce761_8e97fde8.jpg" /><figcaption>The so-called ‘consolidated shipping’ service covers both air and sea transport routes. Photo: Handout  </figcaption></figure><p>Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics unit, will open a new service for consumers in the US to allow them to package several items they have bought together, cutting delivery times to as little as five days.</p><p>Cainiao said in a statement on Tuesday that the cross-border shipping service would mainly help Chinese consumers and students in the US who tend to buy lots of goods on Chinese e-commerce sites. As of 2020, there were roughly 60 million Chinese living outside the country, according to a report by Huaqiao University.</p><p>If the parcel is sent via air, delivery times may be reduced five days after the items are sent out from the warehouse. If by sea, the new service may cut the cost to as low as 12 yuan (US$1.7), depending on the size of the parcel, according to the statement.</p><p>The new overseas service comes ahead of Cainiao’s planned US$1 billion listing in Hong Kong. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247710/alibabas-aliexpress-pdd-owned-temu-face-supply-chain-challenges-south-korea-amid-rapid-business" title="">Alibaba’s AliExpress, PDD-owned Temu face supply chain challenges in South Korea</a></h3><p>The so-called “consolidated shipping” service, covering both air and sea transport routes, will collect multiple online shopping orders placed by users on various platforms in a warehouse before shipping them from China.</p><p>Prior to its US expansion, Cainiao provided consolidated shipping to shoppers in other markets outside mainland China, including Hong Kong, Singapore and Australia.</p><p>In November, Cainiao and Alibaba were part of a consortium that made a US$57 million offer to buy Chinese logistics company Best. Best is a major courier in China and has a presence in Southeast Asia. In the third quarter of 2023, Best’s global businesses achieved revenue of US$37.7 million, contributing to 12.4 per cent of the total.</p><p>Cainiao has its eye on the overseas market, and recorded more than 1.5 billion cross-border e-commerce parcel deliveries in its recent financial year to March, making it one of the world’s top logistics services providers, according to its prospectus.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to a Post report in September that cited people familiar with the situation. The listing is part of a group-wide restructuring of Alibaba, as the e-commerce titan seeks to free up decision- making amid increased competition.</p><p>Established in 2013, Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s e-commerce empire, handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023. Alibaba announced it would spin off Cainiao in the restructuring announced in March.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China TV makers Hisense and TCL promote AI, live sports at US show</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247808/ces-2024-china-tv-makers-hisense-and-tcl-promote-ai-live-sports-us-show</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese TV brands Hisense and TCL showcased their latest products and technologies at CES 2024 in Las Vegas.</li>    <li>Both companies emphasized their focus on artificial intelligence (AI) and making screens the center of the home.</li>    <li>Hisense introduced its new 110-inch ULED X television with advanced brightness and backlight zones.</li>    <li>TCL unveiled the world's largest mini-LED TV at 115 inches.</li>    <li>Both companies highlighted the advantages of mini-LED technology in offering superior image quality.</li>    <li>Hisense presented its laser TVs, including the world's largest sound-emitting screen, and a rollable laser TV.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国电视品牌海信和TCL在拉斯维加斯举行的2024年CES大会上展示了它们最新的产品和技术。</li>    <li>两家公司都强调了它们对人工智能（AI）的关注，并致力于把屏幕变成家庭的中心。</li>    <li>海信推出了新的110英寸ULED X电视，具有先进的亮度和背光区域。</li>    <li>TCL发布了世界上最大的115英寸Mini-LED电视。</li>    <li>两家公司都强调了Mini-LED技术在提供卓越图像质量方面的优势。</li>    <li>海信展示了它的激光电视，包括世界上最大的发声屏幕和可卷曲的激光电视。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>flagship (adj.) - /ˈflæɡʃɪp/ 旗舰，领先的。    <p>原文例句：The flagship product from Hisense this year is its new 110-inch ULED X television with a brightness of 10,000 nits and 40,000 backlight zones.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Flagship在这里用作形容词，意为“旗舰的，领先的”。在这个例句中，它指的是海信今年的旗舰产品——新款110英寸ULED X电视。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>prominent (adj.) - /ˈprɑːmɪnənt/ 突出，显赫的。    <p>原文例句：Mini LEDs featured prominently in the presentations of both Hisense and TCL, as they each presented their brands as the best option for finding this tech in TVs that cost just a few hundred dollars, rather than thousands.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Prominent在这里用作形容词，意为“突出的，显赫的”。在这个例句中，它指的是Mini-LED技术在海信和TCL的演示中非常突出，因为他们都将自己的品牌定位为寻找这种技术的最优选择，而这些电视的价格仅数百美元，而不是数千美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>integrate (v.) - /ˈɪntɪɡreɪt/ 整合，集成。    <p>原文例句：Hisense said that mini LEDs – which cram more LEDs into a display to offer a greater range of contrast and image quality – are now integrated into all its models, including one for under US$500.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Integrate在这里用作动词，意为“整合，集成”。在这个例句中，它指的是海信表示，Mini-LED技术——它将更多的LED集成到显示屏中以提供更大的对比度和图像质量范围——现在已集成到其所有型号中，包括一款售价低于500美元的型号。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>omnipresent (adj.) - /ˌɑːmnɪˈpreznt/ 无处不在的，普遍存在的。    <p>原文例句：Seemingly omnipresent at CES 2024, AI was mentioned repeatedly during both presentations, as it has been by rivals like Samsung and LG.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Omnipresent在这里用作形容词，意为“无处不在的，普遍存在的”。在这个例句中，它指的是人工智能（AI）似乎在2024年CES大会上无处不在，在海信和TCL的演示中都反复提到，就像三星和LG等竞争对手一样。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>the latest lineup - 最新阵容。    <p>原文例句：Chinese television set makers Hisense and TCL unveiled their latest line-ups at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday, with an emphasis on artificial intelligence (AI) and making screens the center of the home, while pushing into new areas like cars.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“The latest lineup”在这里表示“最新阵容”。在这个例句中，它指的是海信和TCL在中国拉斯维加斯举行的2024年CES大会上发布的最新电视产品阵容。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in-house - 内部，公司内部。    <p>原文例句：David Gold, president of Hisense USA, said the company’s ability to produce displays and even its own AI chipsets without third parties is something that sets it apart.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“In-house”在这里表示“内部，公司内部”。在这个例句中，它指的是海信美国公司总裁大卫·戈德表示，该公司能够在不借助第三方的情况下生产显示屏甚至其自己的AI芯片组，使其脱颖而出。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>make everything - 制造所有东西。    <p>原文例句：“When you think about global players, I think we are one of less than a handful of companies that have everything that it takes to be able to truly provide a smart home solution,” Gold said after the Hisense presentation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Make everything”在这里表示“制造所有东西”。在这个例句中，它指的是戈德在海信演示后表示，“说到全球参与者，我认为我们是少数几家拥有提供真正智能家居解决方案所需的一切的公司之一”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Both companies offered competing narratives, presenting themselves as the biggest Chinese brands in the US television space. - 两家公司都提供了相互竞争的叙述，将自己描绘成美国电视领域最大的中国品牌。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Both companies offered competing narratives，其中主语是Both companies，谓语是offered，宾语是competing narratives。presenting themselves as the biggest Chinese brands in the US television space是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示两家公司将自己描绘成美国电视领域最大的中国品牌。这个句子的意思是说，两家公司都提供了相互竞争的叙述，将自己描绘成美国电视领域最大的中国品牌。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>It has also followed many of its Chinese peers – like Xiaomi and Huawei Technologies – into the auto sector. - 它还跟随许多中国同行（例如小米和华为技术）进入汽车行业。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是It has also followed，其中主语是It，谓语是has followed。many of its Chinese peers是一个介词短语作宾语，表示它的许多中国同行。– like Xiaomi and Huawei Technologies是一个插入语，表示像小米和华为技术这样的公司。into the auto sector是一个介词短语作宾语，表示进入汽车行业。这个句子的意思是说，它还跟随许多中国同行（例如小米和华为技术）进入汽车行业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Hisense said that mini LEDs – which cram more LEDs into a display to offer a greater range of contrast and image quality – are now integrated into all its models, including one for under US$500.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时的句子，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。在这个例句中，have是助动词，been是be的过去分词，integrated是现在分词。这个句子表示，海信表示，Mini-LED技术——它将更多的LED集成到显示屏中以提供更大的对比度和图像质量范围——现在已集成到其所有型号中，包括一款售价低于500美元的型号。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>  <ul><li>The two biggest Chinese TV brands offered competing narratives about their global stature and AI processing capabilities</li>
<li>The companies emphasised their ability to produce much of their technology in-house and how they are branching out into areas like AR</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/d720b3c6-868e-43ae-b6f8-e7b08d7057b0_128316fa.jpg" /><figcaption>Hisense USA president David Gold on stage at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese television set makers Hisense and TCL unveiled their latest line-ups at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday, with an emphasis on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence">artificial intelligence (AI)</a> and making screens the centre of the home, while pushing into new areas like cars.</p><p>Both companies offered competing narratives, presenting themselves as the biggest Chinese brands in the US television space. They also boasted about their supply chain prowess and the ability to manufacture leading technologies in-house.</p><p>David Gold, president of Hisense USA, said the company’s ability to produce displays and even its own AI chipsets without third parties is something that sets it apart.</p><p>“When you think about global players, I think we are one of less than a handful of companies that have everything that it takes to be able to truly provide a smart home solution,” Gold said after the Hisense presentation. “We have all the ingredients, all the components. There are very few companies out there that can do the same.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>The flagship product from Hisense this year is its new 110-inch ULED X television with a brightness of 10,000 nits and 40,000 backlight zones.</p><p>Not to be outdone, TCL announced what it said is the world’s largest mini-LED TV at 115 inches. TCL referred to itself as a “great global power” with 32 research and development centres and 43 manufacturing sites around the world.</p><p>Mini LEDs featured prominently in the presentations of both Hisense and TCL, as they each presented their brands as the best option for finding this tech in TVs that cost just a few hundred dollars, rather than thousands.</p><p>Hisense said that mini LEDs – which cram more LEDs into a display to offer a greater range of contrast and image quality – are now integrated into all its models, including one for under US$500.</p><p>Hisense also introduced its new so-called laser TVs, which are projectors combined with an ambient-light-rejecting screen. The company said its newest 8K Sonic Laser TV is the “world’s largest sound-emitting screen”, offering a sound bar-like experience built into the projector. It is also offering a new Rollable Laser TV, which is exactly what it sounds like: a projector screen that rolls up and disappears, offering a cleaner look at home when not in use.</p><p>Both companies used sports to draw attention to their new TVs. As more viewers switch to streaming, the focus on live television has largely fallen to sports, a major reason households remain subscribed to cable and satellite TV packages.</p><p>TCL leaned into this heavily, inviting sportscasters including Charissa Thompson and former National Football League player Charles Woodson on stage for nearly the entire duration of the presentation.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/e0266ca3-3156-4fd7-af77-61200f190c62_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Hisense highlighted the ability of its AI chips to enhance picture quality by identifying whether the video is coming from streaming, cable or another source.</p><p>“[Our AI is] about recognising what content it is, the quality, the factor in which it’s being displayed – whether it’s streaming, cable, DVDs, Blu-ray – and finding the way to enhance that picture quality,” Gold said. “Usually you put in one setting and never change it again. What we’re trying to do with AI is automatically detect, ‘Oh, now you’re watching football, let’s move to a sport setting’.”</p><p>Seemingly omnipresent at CES 2024, AI was mentioned repeatedly during both presentations, as it has been by rivals like Samsung and LG.</p><p>TCL talked of enhancing access to its AI processing with three levels of its AIPQ processors, which include “pro” and “ultra” versions. The AI processors are now offered in its cheaper S Class series.</p><p>While TVs are typically the highlight for these events from the Chinese display giants, they are also chasing other trends in the industry. TCL mentioned the latest version of the RayNeo X2 smart glasses, which can display images on the lenses to do things like offer real-time text translation. TCL incubated RayNeo.</p><p>The company also highlighted its newest smartphones and tablets with an emphasis on its Nxtpaper display, which is meant to be easier on the eyes like e-reader displays.</p><p>Hisense is working on its own augmented reality (AR) glasses and a virtual reality headset, but both are just prototypes for now.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1229" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/5dbb9d8d-418e-45e8-ade6-ea407301ebfc_dc8aec28.jpg" title="Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>It has also followed many of its Chinese peers – like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a> – into the auto sector. It is working on bringing its projector technology into cars to, among other things, turn the windscreen into an AR display. The company said this enhances safety because drivers do not need to take their eyes off the road when getting information like navigation.</p><p>“If you’re on the road and your smart refrigerator can tell you, ‘hey, you’re out of eggs; so on your way home, stop by and pick up some eggs,’ that’s the idea that we’re going for,” Gold said.</p><p>Many tech firms are betting on cars as the next big area of growth. As leaders in electric vehicles, Chinese companies are benefiting from the trend. Carmakers <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto">Li Auto</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/great-wall-motors" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/great-wall-motors">Great Wall Motor</a>, Zeekr and Xiaomi will all <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector">use Nvidia’s Drive tech</a> for autonomous driving, the chip firm announced on Monday.</p><p>Samsung and Sony also discussed their own partnerships with carmakers in their presentations on Monday. Sony has partnered with Honda on its Afeela joint venture, while Samsung is partnering with Hyundai to bring its SmartThings platform to cars.</p><p>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>JD.com’s on-demand delivery unit, Dada Nexus, loses 46 per cent of US stock value overnight amid internal inquiry into potential fraud</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247804/jdcoms-demand-delivery-unit-dada-nexus-loses-46-cent-us-stock-value-overnight-amid-internal-inquiry</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Internal audit of Dada reveals US$140 million of suspicious revenue and costs, raising concerns about Chinese tech stocks.</li>    <li>Theme: Potential fraud at JD.com-affiliated Dada Nexus could damage investor faith in Chinese technology businesses.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of financial misconduct on investor confidence in Chinese stocks; the significance of robust corporate governance practices.</li>    <li>Main information: Internal audit uncovers questionable revenue and costs; potential overstatement of online advertising, marketing, and operational expenses; Dada's chairman and CFO resign.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>摘要：内部审计发现公司账目中存在 1.4 亿美元的可疑收入和成本，引发人们对中国科技股的担忧。</li>    <li>主题：京东关联公司达达集团的潜在欺诈行为可能损害投资者对中国科技企业的信心。</li>    <li>观点：财务违规对投资者信心和企业管理的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：内部审计发现可疑收入和成本；在线广告、营销和运营支出可能存在夸大；达达集团董事长和 CFO 辞职。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>routine (adj.) - /ruːˈtiːn/ 常规的，例行的。    <p>原文例句：A routine internal audit at Dada found US$140 million worth of questionable revenue and costs in the firm’s books for the first three quarters of 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：routine的意思是 "日常的，常规的"。在这个例句中，routine是形容词，用来说明审计是 "常规的内部审计"，强调审计是按常规进行的，不是特殊的或一次性的审计。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>potential (adj.) - /pəˈtenʃəl/ 潜在的。    <p>原文例句：A potential case of fraud at JD.com-affiliated, on-demand delivery firm Dada Nexus could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese tech stocks.</p>    <p>例句讲解：potential的意思是 "潜在的"。在这个例句中，potential是形容词，用来说明欺诈案件是 "潜在的"，强调欺诈案件尚未被证实，但存在发生的可能性。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>suspicious (adj.) - /səˈspɪʃəs/ 可疑的。    <p>原文例句：Dada Nexus, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit, according to its corporate filing.</p>    <p>例句讲解：suspicious的意思是 "可疑的"。在这个例句中，suspicious是形容词，用来说明收入和成本是 "可疑的"，强调收入和成本存在问题，需要进一步调查。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>overstate (v.) - /ˌoʊvərˈsteɪt/ 夸大。    <p>原文例句：While the amount that is subject of the inquiry makes up just about a third of Dada’s total revenue in the September quarter, a potential fraud in the company’s books could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese internet stocks.</p>    <p>例句讲解：overstate的意思是 "夸大"。在这个例句中，overstate是动词，用来说明欺诈行为可能 "夸大了"收入和成本，强调欺诈行为可能导致收入和成本被夸大，从而误导投资者。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>internal audit - 内部审计。    <p>原文例句：A routine internal audit at Dada found US$140 million worth of questionable revenue and costs in the firm’s books for the first three quarters of 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：内部审计是指对公司的财务状况、经营状况和内部控制制度进行的审计。内部审计的目的是确保公司的财务信息是准确可靠的，公司的经营活动是合规的，公司的内部控制制度是有效的。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>on-demand - 按需的，随叫随到的。    <p>原文例句：Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com wins antitrust lawsuit against Alibaba</p>    <p>例句讲解：随叫随到是指根据需要而提供服务或产品。在这个例句中，on-demand delivery firm Dada Nexus是指提供按需配送服务的公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Dada Nexus, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit, according to its corporate filing. - 达达集团运营着京东到家和达达现在两大业务，根据该公司提交的企业文件，在 2023 年前三个季度的例行内部审计中，其账目中发现了价值 10 亿元人民币（合 1.4 亿美元）的可疑收入和成本。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Dada Nexus found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023，其中主语是Dada Nexus，谓语是found，宾语是1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs。which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now是一个定语从句，修饰主语Dada Nexus，表示达达集团运营着京东到家和达达现在两大业务。during a routine internal audit是一个介词短语，作时间状语，表示在例行内部审计期间。according to its corporate filing是一个介词短语，作原因状语，表示根据该公司的企业文件。这个句子的意思是说，达达集团运营着京东到家和达达现在两大业务，在 2023 年前三个季度的例行内部审计中，其账目中发现了价值 10 亿元人民币（合 1.4 亿美元）的可疑收入和成本。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词作状语 - 分词可以作状语，用来修饰动词或形容词，表示原因、条件、时间、地点、方式、目的等。    <p>原文例句：Dada Nexus, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit, according to its corporate filing.</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词作状语包括现在分词作状语和过去分词作状语。现在分词作状语表示动作、行为或状态与主句动作、行为或状态同时发生，过去分词作状语表示动作、行为或状态发生在主句动作、行为或状态之前。在这个例句中，during a routine internal audit是一个介词短语，作时间状语，表示在例行内部审计期间。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>A routine internal audit at Dada found US$140 million worth of questionable revenue and costs in the firm’s books for the first three quarters of 2023</li>
<li>Shanghai-based Dada has reported the potential case of fraud to police, according to local media</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/c047f84e-6340-412a-9bce-843911227d91_14f4c464.jpg" /><figcaption>A potential case of fraud at JD.com-affiliated, on-demand delivery firm Dada Nexus could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese tech stocks. Image: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>An on-demand delivery firm affiliated with Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> lost 46 per cent of its stock value in New York on Monday, following an inquiry into “suspicious” data during an internal audit, dealing a fresh blow to confidence in China’s tech stocks.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3195587/jdcoms-logistics-arm-pushes-ahead-unmanned-robotic-grocery-deliveries" target="_self" title="">Dada Nexus</a>, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit, according to its corporate filing. Parent JD.com’s share price tumbled 3 per cent on Tuesday in Hong Kong.</p><p>Nasdaq-listed Dada said an estimated 500 million yuan of online advertising and marketing service revenue plus another 500 million yuan of operations and support costs for the first three quarters of 2023 may have been overstated.</p><p>While the amount that is subject of the inquiry makes up just about a third of Dada’s total revenue in the September quarter, a potential fraud in the company’s books could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> stocks.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/933378cf-3ccc-42bf-a060-3d2efc2145c7_55c83460.jpg" title="Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The investigation at Dada comes nearly a month since the company’s chairman, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241791/chinese-e-commerce-giant-jdcom-removes-veteran-executive-retail-ceo-after-brutal-singles-day-price" target="_self" title="">Xin Liju</a>n, stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” effective on December 19. In that same corporate announcement of management changes at Dada, Chen Zhaoming resigned as the firm’s chief financial officer.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a>-based Dada, according to a report by Chinese news outlet The Paper, has reported the potential fraud case to local police.</p><p>A JD.com representative referred the South China Morning Post to Dada’s US filing and declined to provide further details. Dada did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Tuesday.</p><p>Dada had earlier said it was working with third-party agencies, including an accounting company and a law firm, to conduct an independent review of the case.</p><p>In separate filings with regulators, both JD.com and Dada said they are committed to maintaining high corporate-governance standards and internal controls.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246715/chinese-e-commerce-giant-jdcom-wins-antitrust-lawsuit-against-alibaba-which-was-ordered-beijing" title="">Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com wins antitrust lawsuit against Alibaba</a></h3><p>Founded in Shanghai in 2014, Dada runs two core businesses: parent JD.com’s on-demand retail platform JD Daojia and its own Dada Now. Both these operations work with bricks-and-mortar retailers and merchants on fulfilment, including delivery of online orders to consumers in under roughly an hour.</p><p>JD Daojia operates in more than 1,700 counties, districts and cities across mainland China, while Dada Now does business in 2,700 domestic locations.</p><p>In November, Dada reported that total third-quarter revenue rose 20.4 per cent year on year to 2.9 billion yuan.</p><p>On-demand delivery is a hotly contested field on the mainland, where Dada competes against the likes of food delivery giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> and JD.com rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, which owns the Post.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia rolls out new chips, claims leadership of &#39;AI PC&#39; race</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247752/nvidia-rolls-out-new-chips-claims-leadership-ai-pc-race</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  英伟达公司在CES 2023上发布了三款新的桌面显卡，并表示这些显卡将帮助游戏玩家和PC用户更好地利用人工智能技术。英伟达强调，使用人工智能技术进行游戏和图像处理比依靠互联网更加安全和快速。新发布的显卡将提供更快的处理速度和更优质的图像。英伟达还宣布了新的软件和优化模型，以配合新的显卡产品。英伟达股价在周一上涨了5%，创下历史新高。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Nvidia unveils new desktop graphics chips with improved AI capabilities.</li>    <li>Theme: Nvidia promotes the use of AI technology in personal computers and claims it is more secure and responsive than AI over the internet.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: AI-powered PCs offer enhanced gaming, image editing, and other applications by utilizing Nvidia's graphics chips.</li>    <li>Main information: Introduction of three new desktop graphics chips; comparison with previous-generation models; availability and pricing; Nvidia's market dominance and financial performance; targeting PC users and corporate buyers for AI-powered upgrades.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  英伟达公司在CES 2023上发布了三款新的桌面显卡，并表示这些显卡将帮助游戏玩家和PC用户更好地利用人工智能技术。英伟达强调，使用人工智能技术进行游戏和图像处理比依靠互联网更加安全和快速。新发布的显卡将提供更快的处理速度和更优质的图像。英伟达还宣布了新的软件和优化模型，以配合新的显卡产品。英伟达股价在周一上涨了5%，创下历史新高。  <ul>    <li>摘要：英伟达推出新款台式机显卡，具备增强的人工智能功能。</li>    <li>主题：英伟达宣传在个人电脑中使用人工智能技术，并声称其比通过互联网使用人工智能更安全、响应速度更快。</li>    <li>观点：使用人工智能技术的电脑通过利用英伟达的图形芯片，可以在游戏、图像编辑和其他应用程序中提供增强的功能。</li>    <li>主要信息：推出三款新的台式机显卡；与前几代机型的比较；产品供应和价格；英伟达的市场主导地位和财务表现；针对 PC 用户和企业买家进行人工智能驱动升级。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tout (v.) - /taʊt/ 兜售，推销。    <p>原文例句：Intel and AMD have already touted AI PCs as a new era for the industry, arguing that AI software is more secure and responsive on the PC than over the internet.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle English的touten，意为“喊叫，叫卖”。在这个例句中，它表示“兜售，推销，宣扬”。</p></li>    <li>lure (v.) - /lʊər/ 诱骗，吸引。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia, whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software, announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle English的luren，意为“引诱，诱惑”。在这个例句中，它表示“诱骗，吸引”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>without having to rely on - 不必依靠，无须借助。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia unveiled three new desktop graphics chips with extra components that will let gamers, designers and other computer users make better use of AI on their personal machines, without having to rely on remote services accessed over the internet. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由without（不，没有）, having（有，拥有）, to（介词，表示目的或方向）, rely on（依靠，依赖）构成。它表示“不必依靠，无须借助”。在这个例句中，它表示游戏玩家、设计师和其他计算机用户不必依靠通过互联网访问的远程服务，就能在他们的个人计算机上更好地利用人工智能。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia, whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software, announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”. - 英伟达公司在数据中心领域拥有主导地位的芯片技术，该公司宣布推出新产品，以帮助个人电脑行业利用“人工智能电脑”吸引消费者。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Nvidia announced new products，其中主语是Nvidia，谓语是announced，宾语是new products。whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software是一个定语从句，修饰Nvidia，表示英伟达公司在数据中心领域拥有主导地位的芯片技术。to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”是一个不定式作目的状语，修饰announced，表示推出新产品是为了帮助个人电脑行业利用“人工智能电脑”吸引消费者。这个句子的意思是说，英伟达公司宣布推出新产品，以帮助个人电脑行业利用“人工智能电脑”吸引消费者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示已经完成的动作或持续到现在的状态。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia, whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software, announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是由have/has + 过去分词构成的。它表示一个动作或状态从过去开始一直持续到说话的时刻，强调动作或状态已经完成或持续了相当长的时间。在这个例句中，dominates是动词dominate的现在完成时，表示英伟达公司的芯片技术已经主导了数据中心领域相当长的时间。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的主语以外的人或事物执行的。    <p>原文例句：The new GeForce RTX 4080 Super will get more processing cores and faster memory.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是由be + 过去分词构成的。它表示动作或状态是由句子中的主语以外的人或事物执行的，强调动作或状态本身而不是执行动作或状态的人或事物。在这个例句中，will get是动词get的被动语态，表示新的GeForce RTX 4080 Super显卡将获得更多的处理核心和更快的内存。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Intel and AMD have already touted AI PCs as a new era for the industry, arguing that AI software is more secure and responsive on the PC than over the internet</li>
<li>The new GeForce RTX 4080 Super&nbsp;can run Stable Diffusion XL image generation software 1.7 times faster than the equivalent model from the previous generation</li>
</ul><p>Nvidia, whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software, announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”.</p><p>Nvidia unveiled three new desktop graphics chips with extra components that will let gamers, designers and other computer users make better use of AI on their personal machines, without having to rely on remote services accessed over the internet. The chips, updated versions of existing offerings, will be offered at a “great new price”, the company said on Monday in a presentation at the CES trade show in Las Vegas.</p><p>The company's major rivals, Intel and Advanced Micro Devices, have already touted what they say is a new era for the industry: AI PCs. The companies argue that AI software is more secure and responsive when it is run on the PCs themselves rather than over the internet.</p><p>Nvidia now claims its graphics chips are the best engines to power the new types of laptops and desktops.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector" title="">Nvidia expands its reach in China’s electric vehicle sector</a></h3><p>The new GeForce RTX 4080 Super will get more processing cores and faster memory. It can run Stable Diffusion XL image generation software 1.7 times faster than the equivalent model from the previous generation of Nvidia technology, the company said. The new chip will also power games with ray tracing – building an image by calculating the path of individual rays of light – at 4K resolution.</p><p>The product is scheduled to go on sale from January 31 for US$999. The company also unveiled an RTX 4070 Ti Super for US$799 and a 4070 Super for US$599, which will be available later this month.</p><p>Paired with new software and optimisations of AI models that Nvidia is also releasing, the products will offer an “order-of-magnitude” improvement over machines that are powered by Intel chips, according to Justin Walker, an Nvidia vice-president.</p><p>Nvidia’s stock rose as much as 5 per cent in New York trading on Monday, taking it back above US$500 a share to a record high. The stock more than tripled last year, giving the company a market value of more than US$1 trillion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>After a spike in sales during the pandemic, PC shipments have fallen steeply, leaving makers and component suppliers burdened with inventory and little growth. Nvidia has avoided the worst of the PC plunge by owning the market for accelerator chips used to create AI software in data centres. The explosion in demand for that more expensive type of chip has pushed Nvidia’s market value past US$1 trillion, making it the most valuable company in the history of the semiconductor industry.</p><p>For chip makers in general, though, the majority of the volume they ship still goes into PCs. They are searching for a way to persuade laptop owners and corporate buyers to upgrade their equipment and have begun touting AI capabilities as a reason for new purchases.</p><p>Nvidia said the new chips will provide more realistic gaming with high-definition images enhanced by AI, which will also generate improved dialogue by in-game characters. In another example, the products will provide more responsive tools for image-editing software from companies such as Adobe. There are currently 500 applications that are tuned to work better with AI and Nvidia’s RTX technology, the company said.</p><p>Separately, Nvidia said the capabilities of its new products will not trigger rules put in place by the US government to limit the export of AI-related chips to China. The top-of-the-line GTX 4090 already fell afoul of those restrictions, requiring Nvidia to produce a less-capable version for that market.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s Vision Pro headset launches next month, as US tech giant seeks to expand mixed-reality market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247747/apples-vision-pro-headset-launches-next-month-company-seeks-expand-mixed-reality-market</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple announces its Vision Pro virtual reality headset, compatible with over a million iPhone and iPad apps, targeting a broader audience beyond gamers and tech enthusiasts.</li>    <li>The sleek $3,500 goggles controlled by eye movements and hand gestures will be available in stores from February 2.</li>    <li>The device's high price may limit initial sales, but Apple intends to introduce more affordable versions in the future.</li>    <li>The headset coincides with CES 2023 but Apple remains absent from the event.</li>    <li>Despite facing a revenue decline, Apple seeks to boost sales with the Vision Pro and anticipates a larger market.</li>    <li>The headset's potential for 3D video capture aims to enhance the immersive experience.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>苹果发布 Vision Pro 虚拟现实头戴设备，兼容百万款 iPhone 和 iPad 应用程序，目标受众从游戏玩家和技术爱好者拓展至更广泛人群。</li>    <li>售价 3500 美元的时尚头戴设备将于 2 月 2 日在商店发售，可通过眼球和手势进行控制。</li>    <li>受高价影响，该设备的初期销量可能有限，但苹果计划在未来推出更大众化的版本。</li>    <li>苹果发布这款设备时正值 CES 2023 举办期间，但公司并未现身本次展会。</li>    <li>尽管面临收入下降，苹果仍希望通过 Vision Pro 提振销量，并预期更大的市场。</li>    <li>该头戴设备具有 3D 视频拍摄功能，旨在增强沉浸式体验。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sleek (adj.) - /sliːk/ 光滑的，流畅的。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s high-priced headset for toggling between the real and digital world will be available in its stores beginning February 2, launching the trendsetting company’s push to broaden the appeal of what so far has been a niche technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于古英语slic（光滑），意味着“光滑的，流畅的”。在这个例句中，它描述了苹果公司即将发布的虚拟现实头戴设备的时尚外观和流畅设计。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>conspicuously (adv.) - /kənˈspɪkjuəsli/ 显而易见地，明显地。    <p>原文例句：Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad. Pre-orders begin January 19, but buyers will have to go to a store to be properly fitted for the goggles, which are controlled with the eyes and a few simple hand gestures.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语conspicere（看，观察），表示“显而易见地，明显地”。在这个例句中，它表明苹果公司的虚拟现实眼镜将在 1 月 19 日开始接受预订，并且买家需要到商店进行验配，才能正确使用这款眼镜。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make waves - 引起注意，产生影响。    <p>原文例句：In a sign that Apple is expecting the Vision Pro to pave the way to a bigger market, the company included the ability to take 3D videos that can be viewed through the goggles on its latest premium iPhones, the 15 Pro and 15 Pro Max. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由make（做，制造）和waves（波浪，涟漪）组成，表示“引起注意，产生影响”。在这个例句中，它意味着苹果公司为其旗舰机型iPhone 15 Pro和15 Pro Max增加了3D视频录制功能，这表明苹果公司希望通过这款设备在虚拟现实领域掀起波澜。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple’s announcement coincides with the annual CES trade show in Las Vegas, where the company has long been conspicuously absent. - 苹果公司的这款产品的发布适逢一年一度的拉斯维加斯国际消费电子展 (CES)，长期以来，该公司一直缺席该展会。<p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是Apple’s announcement coincides with the annual CES trade show，从句是where the company has long been conspicuously absent。主句谓语是coincides，“同时发生”；从句谓语是has been，“一直是”。主句主语是Apple’s announcement，“苹果公司宣布”，其核心是Apple “苹果公司”。从句主语是the company，“公司”，其核心是where “何处”。这个句子的意思是说，苹果公司的产品发布适逢一年一度的拉斯维加斯国际消费电子展，长期以来，该公司一直缺席该展会。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词的用法 - 分词可以作定语，状语或表语。    <p>原文例句：The company has long been conspicuously absent from the annual CES trade show in Las Vegas.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中的absent是一个分词，作定语，修饰名词company，表示该公司长期以来一直缺席CES贸易展。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时的用法 - 现在完成时表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple has long been conspicuously absent from the annual CES trade show in Las Vegas.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中的has been absent是现在完成时态，表示苹果公司长期以来一直缺席CES贸易展，强调这一状态一直持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad, with pre-orders beginning January 19</li>
<li>Industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far</li>
</ul><p>Apple’s high-priced headset for toggling between the real and digital world will be available in its stores beginning February 2, launching the trendsetting company’s push to broaden the appeal of what so far has been a niche technology.</p><p>Apple unveiled the sleek US$3,500 goggles at a software conference held at its Cupertino, California, headquarters eight months ago – an event that was designed to encourage developers to make apps tailored for a device that projects users into three-dimensional simulations of reality.</p><p>Apple’s announcement coincides with the annual CES trade show in Las Vegas, where the company has long been conspicuously absent.</p><p>Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad. Pre-orders begin January 19, but buyers will have to go to a store to be properly fitted for the goggles, which are controlled with the eyes and a few simple hand gestures.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247367/qualcomm-unveils-chip-mixed-reality-compete-apples-vision-pro" title="">Qualcomm unveils chip for mixed reality to compete with Apple’s Vision Pro</a></h3><p>Although Facebook owner Meta Platforms and other companies have been making virtual-reality headsets for years with limited success, many industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far.</p><p>The Vision Pro already has got largely enthusiastic reviews among the media who were able to test it in tightly controlled demonstrations monitored by Apple, but the device’s price tag probably means relatively few unit sales during its first year on the market.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" class="image-inline caption" height="1271" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/c20a30fc-1af5-4a7c-af6e-4132fe5d819a_b9343cec.jpg" title="Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" width="2000" /><figcaption>Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even so, Apple’s first new product since its smartwatch debuted a decade ago could set the stage for the introduction of more affordable versions for a broader audience. Right now, the Vision Pro will cost seven times more than Meta’s latest virtual-reality headset, the Quest 3.</p><p>In a sign that Apple is expecting the Vision Pro to pave the way to a bigger market, the company included the ability to take 3D videos that can be viewed through the goggles on its latest premium iPhones, the 15 Pro and 15 Pro Max. These videos are so realistic that the people and other images in them appear to be right in front of the viewer watching them.</p><p>Apple is looking for ways to juice its sales after suffering a slight decline in revenue during its last fiscal year ended September. Apple still raked in US$383 billion in sales, with the iPhone accounting for more than half that amount.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung profit tumbles 35% as chip weakness persists</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Samsung Electronics reported a 35% decline in operating income, with estimates falling below expectations. The company aims to catch up with SK Hynix in the high-density memory chip market and expand capacity by 2.5 times in 2024. Despite efforts to increase demand for consumer electronics and foldable smartphones, the rebound in the market is slower than anticipated.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung Electronics' operating income falls, reflecting weak demand for consumer electronics.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's strategies to address declining profits in the consumer electronics industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The challenges faced by Samsung in the competitive memory chip market and the impact of sluggish demand on the tech industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's sixth consecutive quarter of declining operating profit; plans to increase capacity in the high-density memory chip market; expectations for a gradual rebound in the memory market in 2024 driven by AI development.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  三星电子报告称营业利润下降 35%，低于分析师预期的平均水平 3.7 万亿韩元，为 2.8 万亿韩元（21 亿美元）。该公司目前的目标是在快速增长的内存芯片领域赶超竞争对手 SK 海力士，计划到 2024 年增加 2.5 倍的产能。尽管努力增加对消费电子产品和可折叠智能手机的需求，但市场的反弹速度比预期慢。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星电子营业利润下滑，反映出消费电子产品的需求疲软。</li>    <li>主题：三星应对消费电子行业利润下降的策略。</li>    <li>观点：三星在竞争激烈的存储芯片市场中面临的挑战以及需求疲软对科技行业的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星连续六个季度营业利润下降；计划在高密度存储芯片市场增加产能；预计 2024 年存储器市场将逐步反弹，这将得益于人工智能的发展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sluggish (adj.) - /ˈslʌɡɪʃ/ 迟钝的，惰性的。    <p>原文例句：Revenue came to 67 trillion won, compared with projections for 70.31 trillion won.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“sluggish”意思是“缓慢的，迟钝的”。在这个句子中，“sluggish”用来形容收入的增长情况，意思是“收入增长缓慢”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>accelerator (n.) - /əkˈsɛlərˌeɪtər/ 加速器，促进增长的因素。    <p>原文例句：HBM, an advanced chip that handles data more quickly, works with hardware such as Nvidia’s accelerators to speed up data processing for intensive tasks like training AI models.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“accelerator”意思是“加速器”。在这个句子中，“accelerator”用来描述一种先进的芯片，这种芯片可以处理数据，并与英伟达的硬件一起工作，以加速数据处理，以便完成像训练人工智能模型这样的密集型任务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>catch up with - 赶上。    <p>原文例句：Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“catch up with”意思是“赶上”。在这个句子中，“catch up with”用来形容三星的目标，即在快速增长的内存芯片领域赶上竞争对手 SK 海力士。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>drive growth - 推动增长。    <p>原文例句：Samsung is also counting on a new line-up of devices and foldable smartphones to drive growth in 2024.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“drive growth”意思是“推动增长”。在这个句子中，“drive growth”用来形容三星对新产品和可折叠智能手机的期望，即这些产品可以推动三星在 2024 年的增长。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung Electronics posted its sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit, reflecting stubbornly weak demand for consumer electronics globally.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Samsung Electronics posted its sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit，其中主语是Samsung Electronics，谓语是posted，宾语是its sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit。reflecting stubbornly weak demand for consumer electronics globally是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示三星电子连续六个季度营业利润下降的原因，即由于全球对消费电子产品的需求疲软。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始到现在已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始到现在已经完成的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的完成性。结构是：have/has + 过去分词。在这个句子中，现在完成时态由“aims”表示，意思是三星现在打算在快速增长的内存芯片领域赶上竞争对手 SK 海力士。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>比较级和最高级 - 用于比较两个或多个事物或情况。    <p>原文例句：Samsung aims to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级和最高级用于比较两个或多个事物或情况。比较级表示“比……更”，最高级表示“最”。在这个句子中，“increase capacity by 2.5 times”表示“增加产能 2.5 倍”，其中“times”是“倍”的意思，比较级“by 2.5 times”表示“比 2.5 倍更多”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>South Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates</li>
<li>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024</li>
</ul><p>Samsung Electronics posted its sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit, reflecting stubbornly weak demand for consumer electronics globally.</p><p>South Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates. Revenue came to 67 trillion won, compared with projections for 70.31 trillion won.</p><p>The results underscore how demand for smartphones and the memory chips that power modern electronics remains sluggish given economic uncertainty.</p><p>In December, rival Micron Technology delivered a better-than-projected revenue outlook that suggested data centre construction may make up for the lukewarm computing and mobile devices markets.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>“I think this shows that the rebound is slower than we all thought,” said Tom Kang, research director at Counterpoint Technology. “Prices are not rising that fast and the demand from certain sectors is not that strong.”</p><p>Samsung in October predicted the long-depressed US$160 billion memory market will bounce back gradually in 2024, driven by a boom in artificial intelligence (AI) development. Prices should start climbing out of troughs around the latter part of 2023, executives said at the time.</p><p>The company will release a full earnings report, with divisional breakdowns, on January 31.</p><p>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024. HBM, an advanced chip that handles data more quickly, works with hardware such as Nvidia’s accelerators to speed up data processing for intensive tasks like training AI models.</p><p>Samsung is also counting on a new line-up of devices and foldable smartphones to drive growth in 2024. The Korean tech conglomerate is preparing to unveil its latest gadgets in the US later this month, at a time investors worry Apple’s iPhone 15 may be running out of steam mere months after launch.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s AliExpress, PDD-owned Temu face supply chain challenges in South Korea amid rapid business expansion</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247710/alibabas-aliexpress-pdd-owned-temu-face-supply-chain-challenges-south-korea-amid-rapid-business</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese e-commerce platforms AliExpress and Temu are gaining popularity in South Korea, but they face challenges in terms of delivery time and product quality.</li>    <li>Korean consumers are concerned about long delivery times and unstable product quality from these platforms.</li>    <li>AliExpress and Temu have taken steps to improve their supply chain efficiency and reduce delivery times in South Korea.</li>    <li>The platforms are also grappling with the issue of copycat merchandise, with many sellers offering counterfeit products.</li>    <li>Korean consumers are divided in their opinions, with some appreciating the low prices offered by Chinese platforms while others prefer the reliability and quality of domestic platforms.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国电商平台AliExpress和Temu在韩国风靡一时，但它们在配送时间和产品质量方面面临挑战。</li>    <li>韩国消费者担心从这些平台购买的产品配送时间长且产品质量不稳定。</li>    <li>AliExpress和Temu已采取措施提高其供应链效率并减少在韩国的配送时间。</li>    <li>这些平台还面临着山寨商品的问题，许多卖家提供假冒产品。</li>    <li>韩国消费者的看法不一，一些人喜欢中国平台提供的低价，而另一些人则更喜欢本土平台的可靠性和质量。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>cautious (adj.) - 小心的，谨慎的。    <p>原文例句：But on the flip side, some consumers in Korea remain cautious about replacing local online retail sites, such as Coupang and Gmarket, owing to the Chinese platforms’ supply chain problems that include long delivery time and unstable product quality.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语cavere（小心），其比较级和最高级分别为more cautious和most cautious，表示“小心谨慎”。在这个例句中，它表示韩国一些消费者由于中国平台配送时间长和产品质量不稳定等供应链问题，仍然谨慎地对待替代本地在线零售网站的问题。</p></li>    <li>projected (v.) - 投影，预测。    <p>原文例句：South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语proicere（投射），其过去式和过去分词均为projected，表示“投射，预测，预估”。在这个例句中，它表示根据在线数据库ECDB的一份报告，韩国被列为全球第四大电子商务市场，预计2023年的收入为1398亿美元。</p></li>    <li>guarantee (n.) - 保证，担保。    <p>原文例句：The Alibaba unit last March launched a new service called AliExpress Choice that aims to provide Korean consumers with “delivery guarantees and more affordable prices”, touting up to a “three-day delivery window”.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语garantie，其动词形式为guarantee，表示“保证，担保，确保，担保”。在这个例句中，它表示阿里巴巴旗下的速卖通去年3月推出了一项名为AliExpress Choice的新服务，旨在为韩国消费者提供“配送保证和更实惠的价格”，并宣称提供“三天的配送窗口”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>crack under the weight of - 不堪重负。    <p>原文例句：In South Korea, couriers crack under the weight of same-day deliveries    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由crack（断裂，破裂）和under the weight of（在……的重压下）组成的，表示“不堪重负”。在这个例句中，它描述了在韩国，快递员不堪重负，难以应对当日达送货服务。</p></li>    <li>gain direct access to - 直接获取。    <p>原文例句：Chinese platforms have paved the way for many Korean consumers to gain direct access to China-made goods at extremely low prices.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由gain（获得）和direct access to（直接获取）组成的，表示“直接获取”。在这个例句中，它表示中国平台为许多韩国消费者提供了直接获取中国制造商品的机会，且价格极低。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>But on the flip side, some consumers in Korea remain cautious about replacing local online retail sites, such as Coupang and Gmarket, owing to the Chinese platforms’ supply chain problems that include long delivery time and unstable product quality.    <p>句子分析：这是一个复句，由两个并列分句But on the flip side, some consumers in Korea remain cautious about replacing local online retail sites, such as Coupang and Gmarket,和owing to the Chinese platforms’ supply chain problems that include long delivery time and unstable product quality组成，用逗号隔开。第一个分句表示但是另一方面，一些韩国消费者仍然谨慎地对待替代本地在线零售网站的问题，如Coupang和Gmarket。第二个分句表示这主要归因于中国平台供应链存在的问题，包括配送时间长和产品质量不稳定。这个句子的意思是说，但是另一方面，一些韩国消费者仍然谨慎地对待替代本地在线零售网站的问题，如Coupang和Gmarket，这主要归因于中国平台供应链存在的问题，包括配送时间长和产品质量不稳定。</p></li>    <li>AliExpress and Temu work with domestic logistics service providers such as CJ Logistics Corp, the oldest and largest parcel delivery firm in South Korea.    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是AliExpress and Temu，谓语是work，宾语是with domestic logistics service providers such as CJ Logistics Corp, the oldest and largest parcel delivery firm in South Korea。这个句子的意思是说，AliExpress和Temu与韩国最古老、最大的包裹递送公司CJ Logistics Corp等国内物流服务提供商合作。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Chinese platforms have paved the way for many Korean consumers to gain direct access to China-made goods at extremely low prices.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态由have/has和过去分词构成，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。have/has是have的现在时或过去时，过去分词是动词的过去式或过去分词形式。在这个例句中，have paved the way表示中国平台为许多韩国消费者提供了直接获取中国制造商品的机会，且价格极低。这个动作从过去某个时间开始，一直持续到现在，所以使用现在完成时态。</p></li>    <li>比较级 - 比较两个或多个事物或情况的差异。    <p>原文例句：Woo found, for example, a laptop stand on AliExpress that costs 30,000 won (US$23) and comes with free shipping, which was a deal around 50 per cent cheaper than those offered by local retail sites.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是形容词或副词的一种形式，用于比较两个或多个事物或情况的差异。比较级通常在形容词或副词后加上-er或more，或者在形容词前加上less。在这个例句中，cheaper表示更便宜，是形容词cheap的比较级形式。这个形容词比较了AliExpress上笔记本电脑支架的价格和本地零售网站上笔记本电脑支架的价格，发现AliExpress上的笔记本电脑支架更便宜。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Despite their popularity, AliExpress and Temu lag behind the competition in South Korea in terms of fast delivery and product quality assurance</li>
<li>Korean consumers find that proliferation of copycat merchandise is a major problem for Chinese online shopping platforms</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/429e5290-226a-46f7-b76d-3c56e51b65b3_f7ecc5a8.jpg" /><figcaption>Online retail platforms AliExpress and Temu ranked as the two fastest-growing apps in South Korea in 2023, according to market research firm WiseApp. Photos: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giants are now the fastest-growing online platforms for Korean shoppers, but they are still grappling with problems of long delivery time and unstable product quality, according to consumers and retail industry officials.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3243140/discount-e-commerce-giant-pdd-nearly-doubles-quarterly-revenue-closing-alibaba-meituan-also-chalks" target="_self" title="">PDD</a>, two of the largest e-commerce companies in China, have been aggressively expanding their foothold in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a>, offering prices as low as US$1 for some small gadgets on their overseas shopping platforms <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3213632/alibabas-aliexpress-steps-investment-spain-and-south-korea-chinas-e-commerce-players-look-growth" target="_self" title="">AliExpress</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244193/chinese-budget-e-commerce-app-temu-snatching-business-us-dollar-stores-ahead-lucrative-holiday" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>, respectively. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Launched in South Korea in 2018, AliExpress saw its monthly active users surpass 7 million as of last November, nearly doubling the number recorded a year earlier, according to mobile market research firm WiseApp. Temu, which started Korean operations in July, averages 3.5 million users per month. WiseApp ranked the two Chinese platforms as the fastest-growing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">apps</a> in Korea in 2023.</p><p>But on the flip side, some consumers in Korea remain cautious about replacing local online retail sites, such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/2174243/softbank-doubles-down-korean-online-retailer-coupang-us2-billion" target="_self" title="">Coupang</a> and Gmarket, owing to the Chinese platforms’ supply chain problems that include long delivery time and unstable product quality.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/a4611340-1803-40fa-8f74-caa324044017_1126e908.jpg" title="South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Lawrence Woo, a 38-year-old office worker in Seoul, started using AliExpress a year ago after he was lured by the platform’s low prices. Woo found, for example, a laptop stand on AliExpress that costs 30,000 won (US$23) and comes with free shipping, which was a deal around 50 per cent cheaper than those offered by local retail sites.</p><p>Still, Woo said he was confused about the delivery time of merchandise he bought on AliExpress. For instance, it took AliExpress two months to deliver a smartphone camera protector film that he bought last autumn.</p><p>“The delivery time is too long,” Woo said. “I tried to cancel the order, but the customer service was not working.”</p><p>On Temu, product shipping times would range from six to 20 days, according to the Chinese budget shopping app’s website.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3108619/south-korea-some-couriers-are-paying-same-day-deliveries-their" title="">In South Korea, couriers crack under the weight of same-day deliveries</a></h3><p>By comparison, Korean e-commerce giant Coupang is capable of shortening delivery times to within a day through its signature Rocket Delivery service.</p><p>Both AliExpress and Temu work with domestic logistics service providers such as CJ Logistics Corp, the oldest and largest parcel delivery firm in South Korea.</p><p>“It depends on [these companies’] supply chain,” said Zhuang Shuai, founder and chief analyst at Chinese market consultancy Bailian. “For instance, whether the sellers are local merchants or Chinese merchants, and whether the platforms have their own warehouses.”</p><p>Zhuang indicated that Chinese shopping platforms face both policy and cultural barriers in their overseas expansion. “Just like how <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon</a> did not succeed in China, it is also not easy for Chinese companies to operate overseas,” he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235863/alibabas-cainiao-and-aliexpress-start-5-day-global-delivery-service-consumers-uk-spain-netherlands" title="">Alibaba’s Cainiao and AliExpress start ‘5-day global delivery’ service</a></h3><p>Despite those challenges, both AliExpress and Temu have pushed initiatives to improve supply chain efficiency in South Korea.</p><p>The Alibaba unit last March launched a new service called AliExpress Choice that aims to provide Korean consumers with “delivery guarantees and more affordable prices”, touting up to a “three-day delivery window”. AliExpress also expanded the capacity of its warehouses in Weihai and Yantai, two cities in eastern Shandong province, which is close to the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/korean-peninsula-0" target="_self" title="">Korean peninsula</a>.</p><p>Long-time AliExpress user Lee Ye-seul, a 35-year-old resident of Seoul, said the platform’s delivery speed has improved, pointing out that some products she recently ordered arrived within four days of her online purchase. Still, she lamented another major problem: copycat designs widely seen on Chinese e-commerce platforms.</p><p>Lee indicated that there were many merchants on AliExpress selling smartphone cases designed with characters from popular Korean or Japanese brands, such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/article/3131357/hello-kitty-story-how-sanrio-went-silk-sandals-global-superstar" target="_self" title="">Sanrio</a>. “It’s hard to tell if the product you’re buying is plagiarised or an original design,” she said.</p><p>Echoing Lee’s view on copycat merchandise, office worker Woo said it was tough to determine the authenticity of branded products on Chinese shopping platforms. He suggested that these platforms set up a “patrol system” to punish counterfeiters.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" title="">How Temu, an app for US shoppers, helped PDD catch up with Alibaba in market value</a></h3><p>Products bought from AliExpress are “unknowingly circulating” on Korean second-hand sales sites as counterfeits, according to Kang Hyoung-goo, a professor of finance at Hanyang University in Seoul.</p><p>“It is a stumbling block to expanding global outreach through K-fashion exports,” Kang said.</p><p>South Korea has become one of the major battlefields for Alibaba and PDD, as both count on overseas markets to maintain their business momentum amid sluggish user growth and weak spending in their home market.</p><p>Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, followed by Japan, according to a report from online database ECDB.</p><p>Although Chinese platforms have paved the way for many Korean consumers to gain direct access to China-made goods at extremely low prices, Woo and Lee both indicated that these online marketplaces would not become their prime destinations for shopping.</p><p>“I will keep using such platforms, but I’d rather turn to Coupang or Naver Shopping for daily necessities or fashion items,” Woo said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
