<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>TuSimple will continue its drive to Asia-Pacific in wake of autonomous truck firm’s decision to delist from Nasdaq</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3249140/tusimple-will-continue-its-drive-asia-pacific-wake-autonomous-truck-firms-decision-delist-nasdaq</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  TuSimple, a self-driving truck company, is shifting its focus from the US to the Asia-Pacific (APAC) region, particularly to China, Japan, and Australia, in order to take advantage of regulatory support and a robust supply chain for its commercial goals. The company has already begun testing autonomous trucks in Japan and Shanghai and plans to delist from Nasdaq to streamline its operations and navigate its transformation as a private firm better. However, the company faces challenges such as a lack of a clear path to profitability, ongoing government investigations, and industry-wide downsizing, all of which are hindering the growth of the autonomous driving sector.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: TuSimple's shift to APAC targets commercial opportunities and delisting strategy.</li>    <li>Theme: The company's move to the Asia-Pacific region seeks regulatory support, a strong supply chain, and a favorable environment for autonomous truck development.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The article discusses TuSimple's strategic decisions in the context of industry challenges, including the lack of profitability, government investigations, and consolidation.</li>    <li>Main information: TuSimple's focus on APAC, test runs in Japan and Shanghai, delisting plans, workforce reduction, and the broader industry downturn.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary:</h2>  自动驾驶卡车公司图森未来正将业务重心从美国转移至亚太地区，特别是中国、日本和澳大利亚，旨在利用当地的监管支持和强大的供应链来实现其商业目标。该公司已在日本和上海开始测试自动驾驶卡车，并计划从纳斯达克退市，以简化运营并更好地转型为私营企业。然而，该公司也面临着一些挑战，例如缺乏清晰的盈利路径、持续的政府调查和全行业裁员，所有这些都阻碍了自动驾驶行业的发展。  <ul>    <li>摘要：图森未来向亚太地区转移目标是商业机会和退市战略。</li>    <li>主题：公司向亚太地区转移寻求监管支持、强大的供应链以及有利于自动驾驶卡车发展的环境。</li>    <li>观点：文章在行业挑战的背景下探讨了图森未来的战略决策，包括缺乏盈利、政府调查和整合。</li>    <li>主要信息：图森未来对亚太地区的关注、在日本和上海的测试运行、退市计划、员工裁减以及更广泛的行业不景气。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>voluntarily (adv.) - /ˈvɒləntərɪli/ 自愿地，主动地。    <p>原文例句：TuSimple this week announced a plan to voluntarily delist from Nasdaq, with its last trading day expected to be around February 7.</p>    <p>例句讲解：由voluntary（自愿的，主动的）加-ly后缀构成，表示“自愿地，主动地”。在这个例句中，它用来修饰动词delist，表示图森未来本周宣布了一项自愿从纳斯达克退市的计划，其最后交易日预计在2月7日左右。</p></li>    <li>pivot (v.) - /ˈpɪvət/ 改变方向，转向，转动。    <p>原文例句：TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC. </p>    <p>例句讲解：由pivot（支轴）加-t后缀构成，表示“改变方向，转向，转动”。在这个例句中，它用来表示图森未来正在将重点转移到亚太地区。</p></li>    <li>profitability (n.) - /ˌprɑːfɪtəˈbɪləti/ 利润率，有利可图性。    <p>原文例句：The lack of a clear path to profitability and real commercialisation is a challenge for the industry</p>    <p>例句讲解：由profit（利润）加-able（可获利的）再加-ity后缀构成，表示“利润率，有利可图性”。在这个例句中，它用来表示缺乏明确的盈利路径和真正的商业化是该行业面临的一个挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>autonomous truck - 自动驾驶卡车    <p>原文例句：Autonomous truck company TuSimple Holdings will continue to pivot to the Asia-Pacific (APAC) region for better commercial opportunities and in line with its plan to delist from the Nasdaq exchange</p>    <p>例句讲解：由autonomous（自动的）和truck（卡车）构成，表示“自动驾驶卡车”。在这个例句中，它用来表示自动驾驶卡车公司图森未来将继续转向亚太地区，以获得更好的商业机会，并符合其从纳斯达克交易所退市的计划。</p></li>    <li>last trading day - 最后交易日    <p>原文例句：TuSimple this week announced a plan to voluntarily delist from Nasdaq, with its last trading day expected to be around February 7</p>    <p>例句讲解：由last（最后的）和trading day（交易日）构成，表示“最后交易日”。在这个例句中，它用来表示图森未来本周宣布了一项自愿从纳斯达克退市的计划，其最后交易日预计在2月7日左右。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC, including China, Japan and Australia, where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help the firm’s commercial goals.    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是TuSimple，谓语是is shifting its focus to APAC，宾语是regulatory support and a strong supply chain。其中，where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help the firm’s commercial goals是一个定语从句，修饰先行词APAC，说明APAC对图森未来实现其商业目标的帮助。这个句子的意思是，图森未来正在将重点转移到亚太地区，包括中国、日本和澳大利亚，那里的监管支持和强大的供应链可以帮助该公司实现其商业目标。</p></li>    <li>It was also the first company to deploy autonomous trucks on pilot tests between the cities of Tucson and Phoenix in Arizona and Las Vegas, Nevada in 2018.    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，由两个简单句组成，用and连接。主语是It，谓语是was also the first company to deploy autonomous trucks on pilot tests，宾语是autonomous trucks。其中，between the cities of Tucson and Phoenix in Arizona and Las Vegas, Nevada in 2018是一个介词短语，作状语，修饰谓语动词deploy autonomous trucks，说明了自动驾驶卡车在哪些城市之间进行了试点测试。这个句子的意思是，该公司也是第一家在2018年于亚利桑那州图森市和菲尼克斯市以及内华达州拉斯维加斯市之间进行自动驾驶卡车试点测试的公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由分词及其修饰语构成的短语，在句中作定语、状语或表语。    <p>原文例句：Autonomous truck company TuSimple Holdings will continue to pivot to the Asia-Pacific (APAC) region for better commercial opportunities and in line with its plan to delist from the Nasdaq exchange</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，Autonomous truck company TuSimple Holdings是一个分词短语，作主语，修饰谓语动词will continue to pivot。这个短语是由分词Autonomous truck company和其修饰语TuSimple Holdings构成的。</p></li>    <li>定语从句 - 由关系代词或关系副词引导的从句，在句中作定语。    <p>原文例句：TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC, including China, Japan and Australia, where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help the firm’s commercial goals.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help the firm’s commercial goals是一个定语从句，修饰先行词APAC，说明APAC对图森未来实现其商业目标的帮助。这个从句是由关系副词where引导的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC, including China, Japan and Australia, where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help</li>
<li>TuSimple this week announced a plan to voluntarily delist from Nasdaq, with its last trading day expected to be around February 7</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/9379da4f-2af9-460b-b031-733718defcaa_f6769707.jpg" /><figcaption>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC. Photo: Handout </figcaption></figure><p>Autonomous truck company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217769/tusimple-working-resolving-us-issues-after-management-turmoil-and-pushing-ahead-autonomous-driving?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">TuSimple Holdings</a> will continue to pivot to the Asia-Pacific (APAC) region for better commercial opportunities and in line with its plan to delist from the Nasdaq exchange, said chief executive officer Lu Cheng.</p><p>TuSimple is shifting its focus to APAC, including China, Japan and Australia, where regulatory support and a strong supply chain can help the firm’s commercial goals, Lu said in a Friday interview, as the self-driving industry continues to push for profitability.</p><p>“For autonomous trucks, we have to integrate the advanced software capabilities – the virtual driver – with reliable and scalable hardware that includes the truck itself, Tier-1 components coupled with the right use case,” Lu said. “That’s one of the benefits of focusing our business more on APAC because of the maturity of the hardware supply chain.”</p><p>The company started test runs of Level 4 autonomous trucks in Japan last year, and conducted full autonomous runs – without a human in the truck – on public roads in Shanghai. Level 4 is considered to be fully autonomous driving, although a human driver can still request control, and the car still has a cockpit.</p><p>San Diego, California-based TuSimple, which carried out an initial public offering (IPO) in 2021, announced its plan to voluntarily delist from Nasdaq on Wednesday, with its last trading day on the exchange expected to be around February 7.</p><p>The company cited changes in the capital markets for “pre-commercialised companies” and significantly increased stock price volatility as part of its rationale for delisting. It also said being a private firm would help the company better navigate its transformation.</p><p>The company’s shares closed at US$0.49 on Thursday, trading around 98 per cent lower than its debut price of US$40.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244089/autonomous-trucking-company-tusimple-cease-us-operations-amid-new-round-lay-offs-focus-asia-pacific" title="">Autonomous trucking firm TuSimple to exit US amid new lay-offs, focus on Asia</a></h3><p>Lu said the company could explore another IPO down the road “when the company makes more progress and the market conditions make sense”, but it has no timeline or location in mind at the present time.</p><p>TuSimple said last month that it was cutting 75 per cent of its workforce and winding down its operations in the US. The retreat comes amid further consolidation in the autonomous driving industry, with several leading players announcing lay-offs and downsizing in the past year.</p><p>Last July, Alphabet unit Waymo announced that it would slow down work in the self-driving truck field under its Via subsidiary. Last May, Embark Technology – an early proponent of self-driving truck software development in the US – delisted from the Nasdaq and went private via a merger, after running out of capital to pursue commercial production.</p><p>The lack of a clear path to profitability and real commercialisation is a challenge for the industry, which includes technology, hardware supply chain, and regulatory issues, Lu said. “Being able to move from demos and pilots to actually providing a real service that is profitable is the biggest challenge,” he added.</p><p>TuSimple reported a US$248.6 million loss from operations in the first nine months of 2023, narrowing from a US$341.7 million loss in the same period in the previous year.</p><p>TuSimple, once considered a star in the global autonomous driving sector and a leader in US self-driving truck development, has focused on Level 4 autonomy. It was also the first company to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/2169885/driverless-tech-start-aims-replace-15-million-truckers-us-china?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">deploy autonomous trucks on pilot tests</a> between the cities of Tucson and Phoenix in Arizona and Las Vegas, Nevada in 2018.</p><p>The company has been grappling with a US government investigation, corporate disputes and lay-offs since 2022.</p><p>The US Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS), an inter-agency panel that reviews the national security implications of foreign investments in the US, kicked off an investigation of TuSimple with the FBI and the Securities and Exchange Commission in 2022.</p><p>The inquiry revolves around whether TuSimple co-founder and then-chief executive Hou Xiaodi <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217769/tusimple-working-resolving-us-issues-after-management-turmoil-and-pushing-ahead-autonomous-driving?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">made illegal funding or technology transfers to Hydron</a>, a Chinese autonomous truck start-up established by another TuSimple co-founder Chen Mo in 2021.</p><p>How was fired by the company’s board in October 2022 after an internal investigation, with it citing a “loss in trust and confidence” in connection with the alleged sharing of confidential information with Hydron.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong eyes ‘more flexible’ path in regulating spot cryptocurrency ETFs as US races ahead with approvals</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249086/hong-kong-eyes-more-flexible-path-regulating-spot-crypto-etfs-us-races-ahead-approvals</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong plans to introduce spot cryptocurrency ETFs compared to the U.S., which allows both cash and in-kind subscriptions. </li>    <li>The U.S. spots Bitcoin ETF market remains largely unregulated, leading to SEC's skepticism about spot Bitcoin transactions.</li>    <li>Hong Kong's regulatory approach towards virtual asset transactions provides more comfort for the city's Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) to approve spot cryptocurrency ETFs. </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>香港计划推出现货加密货币ETF，而美国则允许现金和实物认购两种方式。</li>    <li>美国的现货比特币ETF市场在很大程度上仍然不受监管，导致SEC对现货比特币交易持怀疑态度。</li>    <li>香港对虚拟资产交易的监管方式为该市的证券及期货事务监察委员会（SFC）批准现货加密货币ETF提供了更多的支持。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>substitution (n.) - /ˌsʌbstəˈtuːʃ(ə)n/ 替换，更换。    <p>原文例句：In children, the vowel [tʌ] is often substituted by [a], as [bʌt] for [bæt].</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由sub-（在……之下）和stituere（代表，代替）构成，意思是“替换，更换”。在这个例句中，它指的是在儿童的语言中，元音[tʌ]经常被元音[a]替换，例如，[bʌt]代替[bæt]。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sophisticated (adj.) - /səʊˈfɪstɪkeɪtɪd/ 精致的，复杂的。    <p>原文例句：We need to ensure that our financial system remains sophisticated, competitive and resilient to external shocks.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由so-（很，非常）和phisticus（巧妙的，狡猾的）构成，意思是“复杂的，精致的”。在这个例句中，它指的是我们需要确保我们的金融体系仍然复杂、有竞争力和能够抵御外部冲击。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>along with - 伴随，随着。    <P>原文例句：The nearby Australian island of Tasmania is, along with New Zealand, often referred to as a remnant of the ancient supercontinent Gondwana.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由along（沿着，沿着）和with（和，一起）构成的，意思是“伴随，随着”。在这个例句中，它表示塔斯马尼亚岛和新西兰经常被认为是古代超级大陆冈瓦纳的残余。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The recently passed tax cuts are expected to boost the economy by stimulating investment and consumer spending. - 最近通过的减税措施预计将通过刺激投资和消费支出提振经济。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The tax cuts are expected to boost the economy，其中主语是The tax cuts，谓语是are expected to boost，宾语是the economy。recently passed是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰tax cuts，表示这些减税措施是最近通过的。by stimulating investment and consumer spending是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示减税措施提振经济的方式，即通过刺激投资和消费支出。这个句子的意思是说，最近通过的减税措施预计将通过刺激投资和消费支出提振经济。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>祈使句 - 表示请求，命令或建议。    <p>原文例句：Please don't get us fired. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个祈使句，结构是：Please + 动词原形。其中Please表示请求或命令，动词原形表示要请求或命令对方做的事情。在这个例句中，它表示请求对方不要让我们被解雇。这个句子的意思是说，请不要让我们被解雇。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>A key difference between Hong Kong’s proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs and the US is that the city will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions</li>
<li>The SFC and Hong Kong Monetary Authority’s plan to authorise spot cryptocurrency ETFs has given the industry optimism about the city’s prospects of becoming a cryptocurrency hub</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/cfc5c501-3421-4cf4-a330-cfc6070fee33_e8f94cca.jpg" /><figcaption>Stacks of cryptocurrency coin representations are set against the backdrop of the Hong Kong flag. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure><p>Hong Kong is set to develop a more flexible regime for cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs), even though the US leads in both approval speed and market size, experts said.</p><p>A key difference between Hong Kong’s proposed rules for spot cryptocurrency ETFs and products approved in the US is that Hong Kong will allow both cash and in-kind subscriptions. Under such rules, participating dealers can directly use bitcoin to subscribe to or redeem the ETF’s shares, whereas in the US, such subscriptions and redemptions are only allowed with cash.</p><p>The different approach reflects a divergence of virtual asset regulatory frameworks, where the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) “appears reluctant to allow licensed dealers to touch bitcoin” when subscribing for and redeeming ETF shares because spot bitcoin trades are unregulated in the US, according to Andrew Fei, a partner at King &amp; Wood Mallesons in Hong Kong.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3248972/hong-kong-securities-watchdog-puts-virtual-asset-trading-platforms-aramex-and-difx-alert-list" title="">Hong Kong securities watchdog puts virtual asset trading platforms on fraud alert</a></h3><p>Regulators in Hong Kong last month said that they will allow retail access to spot virtual asset ETFs, and are willing to accept applications from funds hoping to offer such products to the public.</p><p>After nine spot bitcoin ETFs in the US, offered by fund giants including BlackRock and Fidelity, attracted nearly US$2 billion in their first three days of trading, virtual asset industry participants in Hong Kong have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248282/hong-kong-needs-speed-approval-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-after-us-launch-industry" target="_self" title="">urged the Hong Kong government to speed up</a> the approval of the city’s own offerings.</p><p>“I hope that Hong Kong, amid the rapid development and intense competition in the virtual asset sector, can seize a spot globally as quickly as possible,” Legislative Council member Johnny Ng Kit-chong wrote in a post on X, formerly Twitter, last week. “[Hong Kong should] strive to be the first to implement relevant policies and products particularly in Asia.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246415/hong-kong-regulators-propose-tougher-rules-sale-stablecoins-retail-investors" title="">Hong Kong regulators propose licensing for sale of stablecoins to public</a></h3><p>In a statement last week, SEC chair Gary Gensler said that despite its approval of spot bitcoin ETFs, the regulator “did not approve or endorse bitcoin”, which is “primarily a speculative, volatile asset that’s also used for illicit activity including ransomware, money laundering, sanction evasion, and terrorist financing”.</p><p>“In the US, the spot bitcoin market is largely unregulated and the SEC remains somewhat sceptical about spot bitcoin transactions,” Fei said.</p><p>However, because spot virtual asset transactions on licensed virtual asset trading platforms are regulated in Hong Kong, the city’s Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) “appears to be more comfortable with virtual asset ETFs”, he added.</p><p>The SFC and the Hong Kong Monetary Authority’s joint plan to authorise spot cryptocurrency ETFs has given the industry <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual?module=hard_link&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">optimism</a> about the city’s prospects of becoming a cryptocurrency hub.</p><p>“Hong Kong’s regulatory environment, known for adaptability, positions it well in navigating the evolving world of digital assets,” said Dmitry Lapidus, senior liquid analyst at US venture capital firm CoinFund.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Nasdaq board in Times Square, New York, shows video of the opening bell as Bitcoin Spot ETF’s are launched on the Nasdaq Exchange on January 11. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1335" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/a280c4ae-0893-40b7-9b49-19d29cae20e5_a57dc0a9.jpg" title="The Nasdaq board in Times Square, New York, shows video of the opening bell as Bitcoin Spot ETF’s are launched on the Nasdaq Exchange on January 11. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Nasdaq board in Times Square, New York, shows video of the opening bell as Bitcoin Spot ETF’s are launched on the Nasdaq Exchange on January 11. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Hong Kong is one of the few major jurisdictions in the world that has a clear vision on regulating virtual assets now, and I truly believe this move will continue to serve Hong Kong as a global financial hub in the coming days,” said Kennix Chan, executive director at Victory Securities Company Limited.</p><p>But the city will face strong competition from jurisdictions like the US, experts noted.</p><p>The American cryptocurrency market is poised to be much larger for US and world investors, especially when the ones offering the spot cryptocurrency ETFs are finance heavyweights such as Blackrock, Fidelity, Franklin, and Invesco, said Jack Poon, professor of practice for fintech and entrepreneurship at the Hong Kong Polytechnic University.</p><p>“They have a huge existing customer base and a brand that retail investors feel comfortable with,” Poon said, adding that they are also offering low fees that issuers in Hong Kong may not be able to absorb in the long term.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba co-founder Jack Ma praises rural teachers for their educational passion and ‘belief in the future’ in annual address</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249115/alibaba-co-founder-jack-ma-praises-rural-teachers-their-educational-passion-and-belief-future-annual</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Alibaba co-founder Jack Ma met with rural teachers in China and praised them for their efforts to bring out the creativity, curiosity and confidence of students in challenging conditions, expressing his admiration for their sincere passion for education and their belief in the future. He has met with rural teachers for nine consecutive years in the run-up to the Chinese Lunar New Year and has launched several educational initiatives to support rural education and teachers. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post, and Ma has advocated for agricultural and educational development and environmental protection in recent years.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Jack Ma praises rural teachers' commitment to education.</li>    <li>Theme: Ma's message of support and admiration for rural teachers' efforts in fostering student creativity, curiosity, and confidence.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of rural teachers in shaping the future of China's countryside.</li>    <li>Main information: Ma's meeting with rural teachers, his praise for their passion and belief in the future, and his initiatives to support rural education.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  阿里巴巴共同创始人马云在中国农历新年前夕连续九年会见农村老师，盛赞他们努力在乡村艰苦条件下激发学生创造力、好奇心和自信心，对他们对教育的真挚热爱和对未来的信念表达了钦佩。马云自2019年辞去电商巨头阿里巴巴董事局主席以来一直保持低调，已经连续九年在中国农历新年前夕会见中国乡村教师。马云公益基金会乡村教师计划和马云乡村教师奖于2015年9月16日正式启动。据该基金会网站介绍，每年选拔100名优秀乡村教师，每人资助10万元人民币（约合14260美元）用于支持乡村教育。阿里巴巴拥有南华早报。近年来，马云一直倡导农业和教育发展以及环境保护。马云在2019年为数千名员工举行告别活动时，以一把吉他和平头摇滚巨星造型签退，并投身多项教育事业，包括2016年启动的乡村校长计划，以及2017年启动的师范生和乡村学校计划。这些项目已经培养了120名乡村校长，招募了800名师范生，并改造了63所乡村寄宿制学校。  <ul>    <li>摘要：马云赞扬乡村教师对教育的付出与努力。</li>    <li>主题：马云为农村教师在培养学生创造力、好奇心和自信心方面所做的努力传达了支持和赞赏之意。</li>    <li>观点：乡村教师对于塑造中国乡村未来发展的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：马云会见乡村教师，赞扬了乡村教师对教育事业的热爱和对未来的信心，并推出了多项支持乡村教育的举措。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>foster (v.) - /ˈfɒːstə/ 培养，促进。    <p>原文例句：The projects have fostered 120 rural principals, enlisted 800 pre-service teachers, and revamped 63 boarding schools in rural areas.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：“foster”在句中作谓语动词，意为“培养，促进，鼓励”。“fostered 120 rural principals”表示“培养了120名乡村校长”，“enlisted 800 pre-service teachers”表示“招募了800名师范生”，“revamped 63 boarding schools in rural areas”表示“改造了63所乡村寄宿制学校”。该句概括了马云公益基金会乡村教师计划取得的成果，突出了该计划对乡村教育的支持和发展的作用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>revamp (v.) - /rɪˈvæmp/ 改造，翻新。    <p>原文例句：The projects have fostered 120 rural principals, enlisted 800 pre-service teachers, and revamped 63 boarding schools in rural areas.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：“revamp”在句中作谓语动词，意为“改造，翻新，使焕然一新”。“revamped 63 boarding schools in rural areas”表示“改造了63所乡村寄宿制学校”。该句概括了马云公益基金会乡村教师计划取得的成果，突出了该计划对乡村教育的支持和发展的作用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the run up to - 在……之前，在……的准备阶段。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba co-founder Ma has met with rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：“in the run up to”是一个固定搭配，意为“在……之前，在……的准备阶段”。“in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year”表示“在中国农历新年前夕”。该词组突出了马云对乡村教师的重视和关心，他连续九年在中国农历新年前夕会见乡村教师，并对他们表达赞扬和支持。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Jack Ma, co-founder of Alibaba Group Holding, has praised the mentality of rural teachers in China and their “belief in the future”, in a message of public support from the increasingly reclusive Chinese billionaire.    <p>句子分析：</p>    <p>该句是复合句，由两个简单句组成，用“and”连接。主句是“Jack Ma has praised the mentality of rural teachers in China and their “belief in the future””，其中“Jack Ma”是主语，“has praised”是谓语，“the mentality of rural teachers”和“their “belief in the future””是宾语。从句是“in a message of public support from the increasingly reclusive Chinese billionaire”，其中“in a message of public support”是状语，“from the increasingly reclusive Chinese billionaire”是介词短语作定语。该句主要介绍了马云对中国乡村教师的赞扬，以及他表达支持的背景。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>关系从句 - 定语从句。    <p>原文例句：Ma, who has maintained a low profile since stepping down as chairman of e-commerce giant Alibaba in 2019, has met with Chinese rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：关系从句又称定语从句，是指在复合句中充当定语的从句。关系从句由关系词和从句构成，关系词连接主句和从句，从句是对主句中某一成分的修饰和限定。在该句中，“who has maintained a low profile since stepping down as chairman of e-commerce giant Alibaba in 2019”是一个关系从句，其中“who”是关系词，连接主句和从句，“has maintained a low profile since stepping down as chairman of e-commerce giant Alibaba in 2019”是关系从句，是对主句中“Ma”的修饰和限定，说明了马云自2019年辞去阿里巴巴董事局主席以来一直保持低调。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Ma expressses his admiration for their efforts to bring out the creativity, curiosity and confidence of students in the countryside</li>
<li>Alibaba co-founder Ma has met with rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/c86b1bc7-27d2-4497-8b44-73ac9588866e_487c5401.jpg" /><figcaption>Alibaba founder Jack Ma praises rural teachers for their ‘belief in the future’. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Jack Ma, co-founder of Alibaba Group Holding, has praised the mentality of rural teachers in China and their “belief in the future”, in a message of public support from the increasingly reclusive Chinese billionaire.</p><p>In a videotaped speech issued by the Jack Ma Foundation on Thursday, Ma – a former teacher himself – is seen speaking to a group of rural Chinese teachers, expressing his admiration for their efforts to bring out the creativity, curiosity and confidence of students amid challenging conditions in the countryside.</p><p>Ma, 59, praises their “sincere passion for education” and their “belief in the future”, according to excerpts of his comments issued by the Foundation.</p><p>Ma, who has maintained a low profile since stepping down as chairman of e-commerce giant Alibaba in 2019, has met with Chinese rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245634/jack-ma-backed-fishery-and-agriculture-company-18-meters-starts-sale-seafood-products-alibabas" title="">Jack Ma-backed firm 1.8 Meters starts online sales via Alibaba’s Freshippo and Tmall</a></h3><p>The Jack Ma Rural Teachers Initiative and Jack Ma Rural Teachers Award were officially launched on September 16, 2015. Every year, 100 outstanding rural teachers are shortlisted and granted 100,000 yuan (US$14,260) each to support rural education, according to the Foundation’s website. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>In recent years Ma has advocated for agricultural and educational development, as well as environmental protection. Ma, who signed off with a guitar and a rock star wig at a farewell event for thousands of employees in 2019, has pursued several educational causes, including the Rural Principal Initiative, launched in 2016, and the Pre-Service Teachers and Rural School Initiative, both launched in 2017.</p><p>The projects have fostered 120 rural principals, enlisted 800 pre-service teachers, and revamped 63 boarding schools in rural areas.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TikTok owner ByteDance allows employees to cash in stock options earlier under new payroll policy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249073/tiktok-owner-bytedance-allows-employees-cash-stock-options-earlier-under-new-payroll-policy</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  To motivate employees and adapt to market uncertainties, ByteDance revised its compensation system. The key changes include accelerating the vesting of stock awards, standardizing annual bonuses, and allowing for merit-based awards. While some employees welcome the flexibility, others raise concerns about potential tax implications. ByteDance's IPO plans remain uncertain due to international scrutiny of TikTok and challenges in expanding overseas.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: ByteDance revises compensation to retain talent amid IPO limbo.</li>    <li>Theme: ByteDance's efforts to maintain employee satisfaction and motivation during a period of IPO uncertainty.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of aligning compensation strategies with business goals and market conditions.</li>    <li>Main information: Accelerated stock vesting schedule, standardized cash bonuses, and merit-based incentives; mixed reactions among employees; ongoing IPO challenges and potential tax implications.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  为了激励员工并适应市场的不确定性，字节跳动修改了其薪酬制度。主要变化包括加速股票奖励的归属、标准化年度奖金以及允许基于绩效的奖励。虽然一些员工欢迎这种灵活性，但另一些员工则对潜在的税收影响表示担忧。由于 TikTok 与中国的关系受到国际社会的密切关注，以及海外扩张的挑战，字节跳动 IPO 的计划仍然不确定。  <ul>    <li>摘要：字节跳动在 IPO 期间不确定性中修改薪酬以留住人才。</li>    <li>主题：字节跳动在 IPO 不确定时期努力保持员工满意度和积极性的举措。</li>    <li>观点：薪酬策略与业务目标和市场条件保持一致的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：加速的股票归属时间表、标准化的现金奖金和基于绩效的激励措施；员工的反应不一；持续的 IPO 挑战和潜在的税收影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>vest (v.) - /vɛst/ 归属，赋予权利。    <p>原文例句：Workers will get 25 per cent of their equity grants after the second year, and again in the third year, with all remaining shares to be vested after the fourth year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古法语，其基本意思是“给予权利或所有权”。在这个例句中，它表示员工在第二年、第三年和第四年分别获得25%的股权赠款，而所有剩余股份在第四年后归属。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>merit (n.) - /ˈmɛrɪt/ 优点，功绩。    <p>原文例句：In its latest reform, ByteDance also standardised its annual bonuses to three months worth of salary, all granted in cash, with additional sums to be given on merit and in equity form.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古法语，其基本意思是“美德，优点”。在这个例句中，表示员工的年终奖金除了基本的三个月工资外，还根据员工的功绩和贡献给予额外的奖金。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>cash in (v.) - /kæʃ ɪn/ 兑现，套现。    <P>原文例句：As ByteDance remains a private firm, the only way for staff to cash in their stock options is to sell to their employer.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组的意思是“兑现，套现”。在这个例句中，这句话的含义是，由于字节跳动仍然是一家私营公司，员工只能通过将其股票期权出售给公司本身来兑现股票期权。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance, owner of global short video hit TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin, has adjusted its payroll policy to allow employees to sell their stock options faster, as plans for an initial public offering (IPO) remain in limbo. - 字节跳动，全球热门短视频 TikTok 及其中国兄弟应用抖音的所有者，调整了其薪酬政策，允许员工更快地出售其股票期权，因为该公司首次公开募股 (IPO) 的计划仍处于不确定状态。<p>句子分析：这是一个复句，由逗号隔开的主句和从句组成。主句是ByteDance has adjusted its payroll policy to allow employees to sell their stock options faster，其中主语是ByteDance，谓语是has adjusted，宾语是its payroll policy。从句是as plans for an initial public offering (IPO) remain in limbo，其中主语是plans，谓语是remain。这个句子的意思是说，字节跳动已经调整了其薪酬政策，允许员工更快地出售他们的股票期权，因为该公司首次公开募股的计划仍处于不确定状态。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 用于比较两个对象或多个对象之间的差异。    <p>原文例句：Previously, employees had been allowed to decide if they wanted their bonuses to be given entirely or partially in cash.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是形容词或副词的一种形式，用来比较两个或多个事物之间的差异。在比较级中，形容词或副词会加上-er或more，如果是比较多个事物，则用more。在这个例句中，比较级是more，用来比较员工以前在奖金发放方面有更多的选择，而现在则没有那么多的选择。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物引起的。    <p>原文例句：The company’s share buy-back programme has taken place twice a year since 2017. </p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是一种语法结构，表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物引起的，一般是通过在动词的过去分词前加上be动词来表示。在这个例句中，动词take place的过去分词是taken place，be动词是has，因此句子的被动语态形式是The company’s share buy-back programme has taken place twice a year since 2017，表示该公司从2017年开始每年两次进行股票回购计划。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Under the new rule, staff will receive 20 per cent of their total stock awards after their first year of service, up from 15 per cent previously</li>
<li>Annual bonuses have been standardised to three months worth of salary, all granted in cash, with additional sums to be given on merit</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/6e2d688a-a5f7-4f1f-9db6-7f74a061f980_9463801a.jpg" /><figcaption>ByteDance’s logo is seen at the company’s office in Shanghai. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>ByteDance, owner of global short video hit TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin, has adjusted its payroll policy to allow employees to sell their stock options faster, as plans for an initial public offering (IPO) remain in limbo.</p><p>Under the new rule, applicable to ByteDance’s 110,000 employees worldwide, workers will receive 20 per cent of their total stock awards after their first year of service, up from 15 per cent previously, according to two people briefed on the matter on Thursday.</p><p>Thereafter, stock grants will be vested on a quarterly basis rather than annually, as was previously the case. Workers will get 25 per cent of their equity grants after the second year, and again in the third year, with all remaining shares to be vested after the fourth year.</p><p>ByteDance did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246294/after-tiktok-owner-bytedance-cuts-fat-focus-fundamentals-social-commerce-challenges-and-us-election" title="">TikTok owner ByteDance spent 2023 cutting the fat, but fresh challenges loom</a></h3><p>The four-year time-based vesting schedule is commonly adopted by businesses to encourage staff to stay longer. As ByteDance remains a private firm, the only way for staff to cash in their stock options is to sell to their employer.</p><p>The Beijing-based company’s share buy-back programme has taken place twice a year since 2017. The most recent one, in November, priced the stock at US$160 per share.</p><p>In its latest reform, ByteDance also standardised its annual bonuses to three months worth of salary, all granted in cash, with additional sums to be given on merit and in equity form. Previously, employees had been allowed to decide if they wanted their bonuses to be given entirely or partially in cash.</p><p>The change affects thousands of employees who are used to receiving higher bonuses, such as product design and optimisation staff whose bonuses had reached the level of six months’ salary. To offset the impact, the company has promised product managers pay rises.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A lights display by Douyin at a shopping centre in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/3078775a-24a5-417f-9719-ee6ae9394d11_1126e908.jpg" title="A lights display by Douyin at a shopping centre in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" width="2000" /><figcaption>A lights display by Douyin at a shopping centre in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure></div><p>The new policy has generated mixed reactions among employees at China’s most-valuable start-up.</p><p>One person said some staff may be happy to find more flexibility if they are considering a job change in the middle of the year. Another person said now that employees could not receive all bonuses as stock options, they could be charged higher income taxes.</p><p>Prospects for a ByteDance IPO remain uncertain amid intense scrutiny in the US over TikTok’s ties to China, as well as challenges in other overseas markets.</p><p>At home, ByteDance has retreated from the video gaming sector. It confirmed earlier this month that it was in talks with multiple potential buyers, including Tencent Holdings, to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations" target="_self" title="">sell its video-game operations</a>.</p><p>In December, the unicorn offered to buy back up to US$5 billion worth of shares from existing investors, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244025/tiktok-owner-bytedance-offers-buy-back-us5-billion-worth-investor-shares-ipo-prospects-remain-slim" target="_self" title="">valuing it at US$268 billion</a>, or about 10 per cent lower than a year earlier when ByteDance organised a US$3 billion share buy-back for earlier investors, the Post reported.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>World Economic Forum: CATL’s Robin Zeng calls for setting aside geopolitical tensions to address EV battery materials shortage</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3249090/world-economic-forum-catls-robin-zeng-calls-setting-aside-geopolitical-tensions-address-ev-battery</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  在电池材料短缺、气候危机等全球性问题面前，世界各国应摒弃地缘政治分歧，携手合作，推进电动汽车电池技术的创新与发展，建立弹性的供应链，实现交通运输领域的脱碳。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Global collaboration is crucial to address battery material shortages and tackle climate crisis.</li>    <li>Theme: The founder of CATL emphasizes the urgent need for international collaboration and technological innovation in the EV battery industry to ensure a sustainable and resilient supply chain.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Geopolitical issues should be set aside to prioritize the development of battery recycling technologies and reduce dependency on critical materials.</li>    <li>Main information: CATL's leadership in battery recycling and its commitment to sharing technologies with overseas carmakers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  面对电池材料短缺、气候危机等全球性问题，世界各国应该摒弃地缘政治分歧，携手合作，推进电动汽车电池技术创新与发展，建立弹性的供应链，实现交通运输领域的脱碳。  <ul>    <li>摘要：全球合作对于解决电池材料短缺和应对气候危机至关重要。</li>    <li>主题：CATL创始人强调了在电动汽车电池行业进行国际合作和技术创新的紧迫性，以确保可持续和弹性的供应链。</li>    <li>观点：地缘政治问题应该被搁置一边，以优先发展电池回收技术并减少对关键材料的依赖。</li>    <li>主要信息：CATL在电池回收方面的领先地位及其向海外汽车制造商分享技术的承诺。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>set aside - 搁置，放弃。    <p>原文例句：Geopolitical tensions must be set aside as the world faces shortages of critical battery materials such as lithium, nickel and cobalt due to surging demand.    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由set（设置，设定）和aside（放在一边）构成的，表示“搁置，放弃”。在这个例句中，它指的是地缘政治紧张局势必须被搁置，因为世界正面临着锂、镍和钴等关键电池材料短缺的问题。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>collaborate - 合作，协作。</li>    <p>原文例句：Countries – from government leaders to businesses and non-governmental organisations – must collaborate to accelerate innovation in the EV battery industry. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于拉丁语，由com-（一起）和laborare（工作）组成，表示“一起工作，合作”。在这个例句中，它指的是各国，包括政府领导人、企业和非政府组织，必须合作以加速电动汽车电池行业的创新。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>decarbonise - 脱碳，降低碳排放。    <p>原文例句：As an essential part of decarbonising the automotive ecosystem, the EV transition requires technological innovation, a sustainable and responsible supply chain and the concerted efforts of all stakeholders. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词是由de-（去除）和carbon（碳）构成的，表示“减少碳排放，脱碳”。在这个例句中，它指的是电动汽车转型作为汽车生态系统脱碳的重要组成部分，需要技术创新、可持续和负责任的供应链以及所有利益相关者的共同努力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>due to - 由于，因为。    <P>原文例句：Geopolitical tensions must be set aside as the world faces shortages of critical battery materials such as lithium, nickel and cobalt due to surging demand.  </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由due（应，应得的）和to（为了）构成的，表示“由于，因为”。在这个例句中，它表示地缘政治紧张局势必须被搁置，因为世界正面临着锂、镍和钴等关键电池材料短缺的问题，而这种情况是由于需求激增而造成的。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：The Fujian-based company is willing to share its technologies and help overseas carmakers address their battery shortages. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示福建这家公司愿意分享其技术，并帮助海外汽车制造商解决他们的电池短缺问题。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Geopolitical tensions must be set aside as the world faces shortages of critical battery materials such as lithium, nickel and cobalt due to surging demand. - 地缘政治紧张局势必须被搁置，因为世界正面临着锂、镍和钴等关键电池材料短缺的问题，而这种情况是由于需求激增而造成的。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Geopolitical tensions must be set aside，其中主语是Geopolitical tensions，谓语是must be set aside。as the world faces shortages of critical battery materials such as lithium, nickel and cobalt due to surging demand是一个现在分词短语作原因状语，表示地缘政治紧张局势必须被搁置的原因是世界正面临着锂、镍和钴等关键电池材料短缺的问题，而这种情况是由于需求激增而造成的。这个句子的意思是说，地缘政治紧张局势必须被搁置，因为世界正面临着锂、镍和钴等关键电池材料短缺的问题，而这种情况是由于需求激增而造成的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>‘We are fighting climate change … so whatever the geopolitical issues are, we have to find a way,’ CATL founder tells Davos panel</li>
<li>By 2042, China will no longer need to mine new mineral materials because of its mature battery recycling market: Zeng</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/4d47a3f8-9ba6-43ca-a388-054f3db16628_c80f5359.jpg" /><figcaption>CATL showcases its ‘Superfast Charging Battery Shenxing’ at the 2023 International Motor Show in Munich, in this file photo from September last year. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>Geopolitical tensions must be set aside as the world faces shortages of critical battery materials such as lithium, nickel and cobalt due to surging demand, said Robin Zeng Yuqun, founder of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248522/china-evs-catl-worlds-top-battery-maker-plans-first-plant-beijing-supply-li-auto-and-xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Contemporary Amperex Technology Ltd (CATL)</a>, the world’s largest manufacturer of batteries for electric vehicles (EVs).</p><p>Countries – from government leaders to businesses and non-governmental organisations – must collaborate to accelerate innovation in the EV battery industry to ensure a resilient supply chain, reduce dependency on critical metals and decarbonise the transport sector to tackle the climate crisis, Zeng told the World Economic Forum meeting in Davos.</p><p>“We should really avoid any geopolitical issues in [battery] recycling technologies,” he said during a panel on Wednesday. “If we can provide these recycling technologies to Europe, to the US and to the rest of the world, it’d be very easy to manage mining issues.</p><p>“The demand for critical materials might increase by five times in the next 10 years, considering the fast growth of the industry. But at the end of the day, when we achieve 100 per cent electric cars, there will be very tiny amounts of new critical materials to be mined.”</p><p>China leads the world in battery recycling technologies, an important solution for addressing battery material shortages.</p><p>For instance, Zeng told the forum that CATL currently has the capacity to recycle as much as 99.6 per cent of precious metals such as nickel, cobalt and manganese, and up to 91 per cent of lithium, higher than Europe’s capacity of 70 per cent to 80 per cent. Last year, CATL recycled 100,000 tonnes of waste batteries through its subsidiary Brump to create 13,000 tonnes of lithium carbonate, he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3244015/chinese-ev-battery-giant-catl-will-set-research-and-development-centre-hong-kong-win-government" title="">EV battery giant CATL to open research and development centre in Hong Kong</a></h3><p>But CATL’s business has been affected by the fraught relations between Beijing and the West. In December, for instance, CATL was accused of posing a national security threat in the US and was banned from a US military base. The allegation was based on a letter from US lawmakers led by Republican senator Marco Rubio that said CATL enjoyed a close relationship with the Chinese leadership in Beijing.</p><p>“We are fighting climate change … so whatever the geopolitical issues are, we have to find a way,” Zeng said during the panel.</p><p>As sales of EVs continue to break records around the world, governments and carmakers are increasingly concerned about the persistent shortages of lithium, nickel and cobalt, which could put the net-zero transition under threat.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3231316/catl-produce-worlds-fastest-ev-battery-offers-400km-driving-range-just-10-minutes-charging-keep" title="">CATL to make battery offering 400km driving range from 10-minute charge</a></h3><p>S&amp;P Global forecast that a more than 270 per cent increase in lithium production levels is needed to meet the estimated demand from the EV battery sector by 2030. Nickel and cobalt are also expected to be critical, but to a lesser degree as the deployment of iron-based chemistries will remedy their potential shortage, it said.</p><p>The Fujian-based company is willing to share its technologies and help overseas carmakers address their battery shortages, Zeng said. By 2042, China will no longer need to mine new mineral materials because of its mature battery recycling market, he added.</p><p>CATL is increasingly <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3215488/tesla-talks-catl-chinas-leading-ev-battery-maker-building-plant-us" target="_self" title="">expanding its capacity overseas</a> with plants in Germany and Hungary. It is also partnering with Amsterdam-based multinational carmaker Stellantis and Ford Motor to build battery factories in Europe and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3210118/chinas-catl-provide-know-how-fords-new-us35-billion-electric-car-battery-plant-us" target="_self" title="">Michigan in the US</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>As an essential part of decarbonising the automotive ecosystem, the EV transition requires technological innovation, a sustainable and responsible supply chain and the concerted efforts of all stakeholders, Zeng said during another panel on Thursday.</p><p>Advancing mining and refinery technology helps to increase the supply of lithium and to alleviate shortages, he said. Increasing energy density helps improve material efficiency and therefore reduces the demand for raw materials.</p><p>Finding an alternative at lower costs, such as sodium-ion batteries or cobalt-free cathode materials, is also a solution for reducing dependency on critical materials such as lithium, he said.</p><p>According to Zeng, CATL introduced its first generation of sodium-ion batteries in 2021 and is currently working on its second generation, which will give cars a driving range of 400 to 500 kilometres per charge.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>How China is making its dream of flying cars, drones and sky cities come true</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3248760/how-china-making-its-dream-flying-cars-drones-and-sky-cities-come-true</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In its drive to build a robust low-altitude economy, China is implementing strategies such as developing flying vehicles, drones, and regulatory frameworks. The establishment of economic demonstration zones, test bases, and infrastructure unveils a supportive ecosystem for the sector's growth. This strategy aligns with China's commitment to addressing economic challenges, investing in technology, and fostering progress in industries like artificial intelligence, green energy, and private space flight.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's low-altitude economy focuses on integrating advanced aerial technologies, including flying vehicles and drones, into various aspects of daily life and urban planning.</li>    <li>Theme: China's emphasis on developing a low-altitude economy to drive innovation and transform industries.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The role of government support, infrastructure development, and policy frameworks in advancing the low-altitude economy.</li>    <li>Main information: Policy measures like economic demonstration zones, test bases, and infrastructural construction; financial investments in companies like Xpeng; standardization and safety regulations in Shenzhen; and the potential of drones in agriculture, delivery services, and emergency responses.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国为了建设强大的低空经济，正在实施一些发展飞行器、无人机，以及管理框架的策略。通过建立经济示范区、检测基地以及基础设施，便揭示了有利于该领域发展的生态系统。这个策略与中国解决经济挑战，投资科技和促进人工智能、绿色能源以及私人空间飞行的进步是一致的。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国的低空经济侧重于将飞行器和无人机等先进航空技术融入到日常生活和城市规划的各个方面。</li>    <li>主题：中国强调发展低空经济以推动创新并改造行业。</li>    <li>观点：政府支持、基础设施发展和政策框架在促进低空经济发展中的作用。</li>    <li>主要信息：经济示范区、检测基地和基础设施建设等政策措施；对像小鹏汽车这样的公司的财政投资；深圳的标准化和安全法规；无人机在农业、配送服务和紧急响应中的潜力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>propeller (n.) - /prəˈpɛlər/ 螺旋桨，桨叶。    <p>原文例句：Built sleekly in the shape of a sports car, with propellers that unfurl, the futuristic vehicle evoked visions of flying vehicles seen in films such as Star Wars and The Fifth Element.</p>    <p>例句讲解：螺旋桨是一块扁平的、薄的材料，通常由金属或塑料制成，安装在飞机、船只或其他车辆的前部或后部，旋转而产生推力，推动这些机器前进。在这个例句中，它指的是飞行汽车的螺旋桨。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>infrastructure (n.) - /ˈɪnfrəstrʌktʃər/ 基础设施。    <p>原文例句：While US flying car companies such as Kittyhawk (backed by Google founder Larry Page) shut down in 2022 due to commercialising and scaling difficulties, China’s policy support is fostering a more conducive ecosystem for nascent technologies like this to advance and benefit society.</p>    <p>例句讲解：基础设施包括道路、桥梁、水坝、电厂和其他结构设施，是国家经济发展的命脉。在这个例句中，它指的是中国正在建设的低空经济基础设施，包括经济示范区、测试基地、机场和无人机起降站等。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>low-altitude economy - 低空经济。    <P>原文例句：An EHang autonomous aerial vehicle conducting a demonstration flight at the Baoan District Low-Altitude Economy Investment Promotion Conference in Shenzhen last year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由low（低）和altitude（高度）和economy（经济）构成的，表示以低空航空技术为基础，发展起来的经济形态。在这个例句中，它指的是中国正在建设的低空经济。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>artificial intelligence - 人工智能。    <P>原文例句：China has highlighted the low-altitude economy as a core industry, deserving of special attention, at its annual central economic work conference last month, together with artificial intelligence, the digital economy, green energy, biomedicine and private space flight. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由artificial（人造的）和intelligence（智能）构成的，表示以电子计算机作为核心并通过对人的神经系统进行模拟来实现智能的机器。在这个例句中，它指的是中国正在重点发展的五大核心产业之一。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>While US flying car companies such as Kittyhawk (backed by Google founder Larry Page) shut down in 2022 due to commercialising and scaling difficulties, China’s policy support is fostering a more conducive ecosystem for nascent technologies like this to advance and benefit society. - 虽然美国飞行汽车公司如小鹰公司（由谷歌创始人拉里·佩奇支持）在2022年因商业化和规模化困难而倒闭，但中国的政策支持正在为像这样的新兴技术培育一个更有利的生态系统，以使其发展和惠及社会。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是China’s policy support is fostering a more conducive ecosystem for nascent technologies like this to advance and benefit society，其中主语是China’s policy support，谓语是is fostering，宾语是a more conducive ecosystem。While US flying car companies such as Kittyhawk (backed by Google founder Larry Page) shut down in 2022 due to commercialising and scaling difficulties是一个时间状语从句，表示美国飞行汽车公司倒闭的时间和原因。这个句子的意思是说，虽然美国飞行汽车公司因商业化和规模化困难而倒闭，但中国的政策支持正在为像这样的新兴技术培育一个更有利的生态系统，以使其发展和惠及社会。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作的承受者。    <p>原文例句：Financial and infrastructural support is creating a conducive ecosystem for China’s ‘low altitude economy’, integrating advanced aerial tech into everyday life and urban planning.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态的结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be的时态和语态要根据主语和句子时态进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分的形式。被动语态表示动作的承受者，强调动作或状态本身。在这个例句中，be用的是is，表示现在时态，主语是Financial and infrastructural support，谓语是creating，宾语是a conducive ecosystem。这个句子的意思是说，财政和基础设施支持正在为中国的“低空经济”创造一个有利的生态系统，将先进的飞行技术融入到日常生活和城市规划中。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>介词短语 - 表示名词或代词之间的关系。    <p>原文例句：This year, Shenzhen announced China’s first regulations over the low-altitude economy.</p>    <p>语法讲解：介词短语是由介词和名词或代词构成的，表示名词或代词之间的关系。介词短语可以作状语、定语或宾语。在这个例句中，over the low-altitude economy是介词短语，作介词announced的宾语，表示深圳宣布了针对低空经济的首批法规。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Policy, financial and infrastructural support is creating a conducive ecosystem for China’s ‘low altitude economy’, integrating advanced aerial tech into everyday life and urban planning</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/95294f31-6a7b-449b-ae1b-5cb7ef61e7b8_e137b3d0.jpg" /><figcaption>An EHang autonomous aerial vehicle conducting a demonstration flight at the Baoan District Low-Altitude Economy Investment Promotion Conference in Shenzhen last year. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3247413/ai-will-be-spotlight-consumer-electronics-show-2024-glasses-blind-shoes-make-you-walk-faster-and" target="_self" title="">CES 2024</a> consumer electronics show in Las Vegas last week mesmerised tech observers from around the world with more than 4,000 exhibitors, from start-ups to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" target="_self" title="">tech giants</a>. Over 1,000 companies were <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248469/alibaba-tiktok-woo-us-ai-and-live-streaming-e-commerce-ces-trade-show-setting-tone-2024" target="_self" title="">from China</a>, demonstrating the country’s impressive contributions to global technology.</p><p>In particular spotlight was China’s electric vehicle (EV) industry, after China was recently crowned the world’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247833/china-solidify-its-position-worlds-top-car-exporter-2024-it-banks-manufacturing-heft-ubs" target="_self" title="">largest car exporter</a>, accounting for about half of global EV sales. At the tech showcase, Xpeng astonished with its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" target="_self" title="">“flying car”</a>, the AeroHT eVTOL.</p><p>Built sleekly in the shape of a sports car, with propellers that unfurl, the futuristic vehicle evoked visions of flying vehicles seen in films such as <em>Star Wars</em> and <em>The Fifth Element</em>. The model, thought to be years away from broad use, completed a successful test flight in October 2022.</p><p>At CES, Xpeng also showcased its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" target="_self" title="">Land Aircraft Carrier</a>, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car, for which the company will take pre-orders in the fourth quarter this year, with deliveries to start a year later.</p><p>The Chinese government is keen for companies to continue making leaps in flying vehicle technology and last year announced a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3237594/china-outlines-vision-green-aviation-nev-industry-c919-models" target="_self" title="">“green aviation” development plan</a>, including for electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft, or eVTOL. This is part of an official strategy to support a “<a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245769/chinas-low-altitude-economy-set-take-vast-potential-could-contribute-us700-billion-2025" target="_self" title="">low altitude economy</a>”.</p><p>The low-altitude economy refers to a comprehensive realm of industries centred around civil-manned and unmanned aerial vehicles, including manufacturing, low-altitude flight operations and integrated services.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Xpeng launched its modular Land Aircraft Carrier, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/bfdb3d00-6397-4d67-82cf-a01cf3c2ebc0_00d05c81.jpg" title="Xpeng launched its modular Land Aircraft Carrier, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Xpeng launched its modular Land Aircraft Carrier, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>China’s green aviation plan presented actionable items to boost the innovation and deployment of flying cars. Important measures include setting up economic demonstration zones and test bases for low-flying aircraft. The plan includes the construction of infrastructure to integrate flying vehicles into urban transport and the daily commute.</p><p>While US flying car companies such as Kittyhawk (backed by Google founder Larry Page) shut down in 2022 due to commercialising and scaling difficulties, China’s policy support is fostering a more conducive ecosystem for nascent technologies like this to advance and benefit society.</p><p>Xpeng’s AeroHT eVTOL, for instance, unlike other flying vehicles such as by German company Volocopter and Hyundai’s Supernal, which was showcased at CES 2024, can transform between terrestrial and aerial modes.</p><p>While the inventions by Volocopter and Supernal resemble personal helicopters, Xpeng’s AeroHT eVTOL has propellers that emerge in flying mode and fold into the car’s body after use. This allows it to navigate road traffic and fit into a standard car park space.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People view the XPeng AeroHT “modular flying car” at the CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada, on January 11. Photo: AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1202" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/c8aea417-015f-46e6-bfce-0a8c0a29a6fb_e4c01113.jpg" title="People view the XPeng AeroHT “modular flying car” at the CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada, on January 11. Photo: AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>People view the XPeng AeroHT “modular flying car” at the CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada, on January 11. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>Another factor that enhances the research and development of flying cars in China is close public-private collaboration. For instance, in 2021, the Guangdong government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3125538/china-electric-cars-xpeng-receives-us77-million-investment" target="_self" title="">invested 500 million yuan</a> (US$70 million) in Xpeng. Guangdong’s Zhaoqing city has also supported Xpeng’s expansion, last year signing an investment agreement for a project worth 2 billion yuan. This type of financial and infrastructural support creates a nurturing ecosystem that enables Chinese EV makers to quickly transform concept cars into mass products.</p><p>China has highlighted the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245769/chinas-low-altitude-economy-set-take-vast-potential-could-contribute-us700-billion-2025" target="_self" title="">low-altitude economy</a> as a core industry, deserving of special attention, at its annual <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3244856/chinas-development-biggest-political-priority-key-econ-meeting-leaders-vow-counter-risks-lift" target="_self" title="">central economic work conference</a> last month, together with artificial intelligence, the digital economy, green energy, biomedicine and private space flight. The vision is for China to address its economic challenges by investing in technology and industry, unlocking the country’s growth potential.</p><p>In addition to flying cars, drones are another area of China’s low-altitude economy that promises to revolutionise its agriculture, delivery services, emergency responses and more. Already, Shenzhen, China’s hi-tech hub, has <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246693/chinas-low-altitude-economy-takes-skies-unmanned-passenger-drone-completes-maiden-commercial-flight" target="_self" title="">declared plans</a> to build itself a “city in the sky”.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/2184687/how-dji-went-university-dorm-project-worlds-biggest-drone-company" target="_self" title="">China’s DJI</a> is the world’s largest drone manufacturer with 70 per cent of the global market share. Its drone technology has helped in the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/2183603/drone-maker-dji-eyes-enterprise-business-transformation-hardware-maker" target="_self" title="">automation of farming</a>, including planning, sowing, weeding, watering and monitoring crop growth. Food delivery platform Meituan, for example, has <a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3224049/how-chinese-tech-giant-meituan-cracked-food-delivery-drone-densely-built-shenzhen-and-implications" target="_self" title="">embraced drones</a>, speeding up its commercial transactions and slashing its labour cost. In 2022, the drone industry in Shenzhen alone generated a market value of 75 billion yuan.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Shenzhen is building a grid of over 600 landing/take-off stations for low-altitude aircraft from by 2025. This will facilitate their deployment and reduce operational costs for companies. Infrastructural support is essential in this industry, especially when the aim is to promote widespread public usage.</p><p>With more companies developing flying cars and other low-altitude aircraft in China, industry regulation is also maturing. This year, Shenzhen announced China’s first regulations over the low-altitude economy. Effective from February 1, these regulations aim to standardise the construction of low-altitude flight infrastructure, coordinate the management of low-altitude airspace and flight services, and set safety standards.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/travel-leisure/article/3227433/rise-shenzhen-chinas-silicon-valley-seaside-town-fast-moving-city-secret-pockets-tranquillity" title="">The rise of Shenzhen, from seaside town to China’s Silicon Valley</a></h3><p>They stipulate the construction of a low-altitude flight service platform, providing services like flight approval applications, intelligent flight monitoring and message alerts to units or individuals conducting low-altitude flight activities.</p><p>The fierce market competition in China’s EV industry has certainly contributed to the industry’s exponential growth. But China’s institutional support also plays a role in quickly making hi-tech advancements accessible to ordinary citizens, and not just a few privileged individuals.</p><p>Although there are still gaps between the big cities and the underdeveloped areas, China’s policy principle that new technologies should improve people’s lives and livelihoods makes for a promising future.</p><p>The development of China’s low-altitude economy could serve as an inspirational model for the world, showing the potential for the integration of advanced aerial technologies into everyday life and urban planning.</p><p><strong>Gerui Wang is a visiting scholar at Stanford University</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ChatGPT boosted user numbers and time spent on Microsoft’s Bing, but fails to dent Google’s search dominance</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249012/chatgpt-boosted-user-numbers-and-time-spent-microsofts-bing-fails-dent-googles-search-dominance</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  微软宣布将ChatGPT集成到其必应搜索引擎后近一年，必应的市场份额仅略微提升了不到1个百分点。尽管必应在推出ChatGPT后吸引了大量用户，但与谷歌相比，其市场份额仍很小，仅占全球搜索市场的3.4%。微软的努力表明，颠覆搜索市场的挑战很大。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Bing's modest rise in market share despite AI integration highlights the challenges in disrupting Google's dominance in the search market.</li>    <li>Theme: Market share gains for Microsoft's Bing search engine are limited, indicating that AI alone cannot easily challenge Google's longstanding dominance.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Generative AI holds promise for transforming search, but Google's entrenched position and user habits pose obstacles for competitors.</li>    <li>Main information: Data shows Bing's market share increase, but it remains a minor player compared to Google; efforts to enhance Bing's attractiveness, such as integrating DALL-E 3, led to a surge in usage; Google's SGE and Gemini project hint at future competitive offerings.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  自微软宣布将 ChatGPT 集成到必应搜索引擎以来已经过去将近一年，必应的市场份额仅增长了不到 1 个百分点。尽管必应在推出 ChatGPT 后吸引了大量用户，但与谷歌相比，其市场份额仍然很小，仅占全球搜索市场的 3.4%。微软的努力表明，颠覆搜索市场的挑战非常大。  <ul>    <li>摘要：必应在集成人工智能后市场份额小幅提升，凸显了挑战谷歌搜索市场主导地位的困难。</li>    <li>主题：微软必应搜索引擎的市场份额增长有限，表明仅靠人工智能不足以轻松挑战谷歌的长期主导地位。</li>    <li>观点：生成式人工智能有望改变搜索，但谷歌根深蒂固的地位和用户习惯给竞争者设置了障碍。</li>    <li>主要信息：数据显示必应的市场份额有所增长，但与谷歌相比仍然是微不足道的小角色；增加必应吸引力的努力，例如集成 DALL-E 3，导致使用量激增；谷歌的 SGE 和 Gemini 项目暗示了未来的竞争性产品。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>chip away at - (vi.) 逐渐削弱、蚕食。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft is betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由chip（削减）和away at（一点点地削减）组成，表示“逐渐削弱、蚕食”。在这个例句中，它指的是微软希望生成式人工智能会改变广告商分配其搜索支出的方式。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rebrandings - (n.) - 重塑品牌，重新塑造品牌形象。    <p>原文例句：Multiple rebrandings and redesigns since its 2009 debut did little to boost Bing’s popularity.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词是由re-（重新）和branding（品牌塑造）组成的，表示“重新塑造品牌形象”。在这个例句中，它指的是自2009年首次推出以来，必应多次进行重新塑造品牌形象和重新设计，但收效甚微。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>long struggled for relevance - 长期为相关性而苦苦挣扎。    <p>原文例句：Bing has long struggled for relevance and attracted more mockery than recognition over the years as a serious alternative to Google.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由long（长时间地）,struggled（奋斗）,for（为了）,relevance（相关性）组成，表示长期努力想获得关联性。在这个例句中，它指的是必应多年来一直在努力获得相关性，而不是像谷歌那样被广泛认可为一个可靠的替代品，反而引起了更多的嘲笑。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>reverse those declines - 逆转那些下降。    <p>原文例句：The ChatGPT reboot at least helped reverse those declines.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由reverse（逆转）,those（那些）,declines（下降）组成，表示逆转那些下降。在这个例句中，它指的是推出 ChatGPT 至少有助于扭转那些用户使用必应总时长下降的局面。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Alphabet division also retains considerable advantages. - 字母表部门还保留了相当大的优势。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是The Alphabet division，谓语是retains，宾语是considerable advantages。also是一个副词，表示“也”。considerable是一个形容词，表示“相当大的”。advantages是一个名词，表示“优势”。这个句子的意思是说，字母表部门还保留了相当大的优势。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>For Microsoft, the shift is an opportunity to propel Bing forward. - 对于微软来说，这种转变是一个推动必应前进的机会。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是For Microsoft，谓语是is，宾语是an opportunity to propel Bing forward。the是一个冠词，表示“这个”。shift是一个名词，表示“转变”。an是一个冠词，表示“一个”。opportunity是一个名词，表示“机会”。propel是一个动词，表示“推进”。Bing是一个专有名词，表示“必应”。forward是一个副词，表示“前进”。这个句子的意思是说，对于微软来说，这种转变是一个推动必应前进的机会。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某一时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Multiple rebrandings and redesigns since its 2009 debut did little to boost Bing’s popularity.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去完成时态的句子，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had是have的过去式，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词形式。这种时态表示在过去某一时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，过去完成时态表示自2009年首次推出以来，必应多次进行重新塑造品牌形象和重新设计，但收效甚微。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态的句子，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，现在完成时态表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The market share of Microsoft’s search engine rose less than 1 percentage point since the ChatGPT announcement</li>
<li>Microsoft is betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/f958a4b4-35bc-43ff-923e-d785b6e45d9d_84591264.jpg" /><figcaption>The Microsoft Bing app. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>When Microsoft announced it was baking ChatGPT into its Bing search engine last February, bullish analysts declared the move an “iPhone moment” that could upend the search market and chip away at Google’s dominance.</p><p>“The entire search category is now going through a sea change,” chief executive officer Satya Nadella said at the time. “That opportunity comes very few times.”</p><p>Almost a year later, the sea has yet to change.</p><p>The new Bing – powered by OpenAI’s generative artificial intelligence (AI) technology – dazzled internet users with conversational replies to queries asked in a natural way.</p><p>But Microsoft’s search engine ended 2023 with just 3.4 per cent of the global search market, according to data analytics firm StatCounter, up less than 1 percentage point since the ChatGPT announcement.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1416" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/081a8c1b-b628-46e0-b984-6897c60d3a63_b10d85c3.jpg" title="Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>Bing has long struggled for relevance and attracted more mockery than recognition over the years as a serious alternative to Google. Multiple rebrandings and redesigns since its 2009 debut did little to boost Bing’s popularity.</p><p>A month before Microsoft infused the search engine with generative AI, people were spending 33 per cent less time using it than they had 12 months earlier, according to SensorTower.</p><p>The ChatGPT reboot at least helped reverse those declines. In the second quarter of 2023, US monthly active users more than doubled year over year to 3.1 million, according to a Bloomberg Intelligence analysis of SensorTower mobile app data.</p><p>Overall, users were spending 84 per cent more time on the search engine, the data show. By year-end, Bing’s monthly active users had increased steadily to 4.4 million, according to SensorTower.</p><p>To build on the momentum, Microsoft has been adding more AI tools to Bing. In October, the company integrated the latest version of OpenAI’s image-generating model, DALL-E 3. Visitors can use it to create realistic-looking images with simple text prompts.</p><p>The offering does nothing to enhance Bing’s search abilities. But its addition generated a spike in usage, according to Jordi Ribas, Microsoft’s corporate vice-president of search and AI.</p><p>“We noticed an increase in usage by 10 times and that took us by surprise because if you think about it, DALL-E 2 was already quite good,” he said in an interview. “It really made a difference in the engagement and the users that came to our product.”</p><p>Yusuf Mehdi, Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, declined to specify how many active users Bing has.</p><p>“Look, it’s still early days and new behaviours are being built,” he said. “We’re still learning new things, but have millions and millions of people using the new tools.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" class="image-inline caption" height="1257" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/751251ee-f99c-42e4-bf34-d1aa45378b12_882215d8.jpg" title="Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" width="2000" /><figcaption>Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even as the Bing team adds crowd-pleasers, Google has been racing to develop its own AI tools.</p><p>In May, it launched an experimental version of its search engine called the “search generative experience”, which delivers conversational responses atop the familiar list of links. Dubbed SGE for short, it is still not widely available. However, Google plans to embed its most powerful large language model, Gemini, into SGE sometime this year.</p><p>The Alphabet division also retains considerable advantages. It has more than 90 per cent of the market and is the default search engine on Apple hardware, including iPhones, giving Google crucial critical mass. The more people who use it, the more the search engine knows and the more Google can use that data to deliver and rank results in a way people find useful.</p><p>The retooling of search by both technology giants reflects a shared conviction that generative AI will fundamentally change the way people seek and receive answers online.</p><p>For Microsoft, the shift is an opportunity to propel Bing forward. But the incremental gains so far make clear that buzzy AI features alone probably will not transform it into a formidable search player.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>“We are at the gold rush moment when it comes to AI and search,” said Shane Greenstein, an economist and professor at Harvard Business School, who has studied the commercialisation of the internet.</p><p>“At the moment, I doubt AI will move the needle because, in search, you need a flywheel: the more searches you have, the better answers are. Google is the only firm who has this dynamic well-established.”</p><p>Still, Greenstein said Bing, being the underdog, has more latitude to experiment. “Google has to be careful not to hurt its brand and product when it comes to testing new AI tools,” he said. “Bing can afford to take the risk. It has nothing to lose.”</p><p>Microsoft is also betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending. The current ad model rests on costs-per-click, but AI-powered searches are getting consumers to answers faster and more directly without a litany of blue links, according to marketing chief Mehdi.</p><p>“We have advertisers telling us they’re getting better outcomes as a result of our AI efforts and are deeply interested in how this works,” he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Reddit aims to launch IPO in March, sources say, in first stock market debut of a social media firm since 2019</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248999/reddit-aims-launch-ipo-march-sources-say-first-stock-market-debut-social-media-firm-2019</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Reddit计划二月进行公开申报，三月初启动路演，三月底完成IPO。这家公司的主要收入来源是广告，联合创始人史蒂夫·霍夫曼去年六月表示，公司尚未实现盈利。  <ul>    <li>Abstract:社交媒体平台Reddit计划于三月进行首次公开募股（IPO）。</li>    <li>Theme: Reddit计划首次公开募股，这是自2019年Pinterest首次公开募股以来主要社交媒体公司的首次公开募股。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Reddit面临TikTok和Facebook等公司的竞争；部分Reddit用户支持公司的首次公开募股。</li>    <li>Main information: Reddit在2021年12月秘密提交了首次公开募股申请；计划于2月底进行公开申报，3月初启动路演，3月底完成首次公开募股；公司计划在首次公开募股中出售约10%的股份。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Reddit计划在3月份进行首次公开募股（IPO），这是自2019年Pinterest首次公开募股以来主要社交媒体平台的首次公开募股。Reddit的主要收入来源是广告，但尚未实现盈利。该公司计划在2月底进行公开申报，3月初启动路演，3月底完成IPO。Reddit计划在IPO中出售约10%的股份，但具体的估值将在上市前确定。Reddit的IPO计划可能会因市场波动等因素而推迟。  <ul>    <li>摘要：社交媒体平台Reddit计划于三月进行首次公开募股（IPO）。</li>    <li>主题：Reddit计划首次公开募股，这是自2019年Pinterest首次公开募股以来主要社交媒体公司的首次公开募股。</li>    <li>观点：Reddit面临TikTok和Facebook等公司的竞争；部分Reddit用户支持公司的首次公开募股。</li>    <li>主要信息：Reddit在2021年12月秘密提交了首次公开募股申请；计划于2月底进行公开申报，3月初启动路演，3月底完成首次公开募股；公司计划在首次公开募股中出售约10%的股份。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>offering (n.) - /ˈɔːfərɪŋ/ 供应的东西，出价。    <p>原文例句：The offering would also test the willingness of some Reddit users to back the company’s stock market debut. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于offer（提供），表示“供应的东西，出价”。在这个例句中，它指的是Reddit的首次公开募股，即公司股票首次向公众出售。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>meme (n.) - /miːm/ 模仿，网络迷因。    <p>原文例句：Many investors posting on the platform have helped fuel dozens of “meme” stock rallies in the last three years, from retailer GameStop to movie operator AMC Entertainment Holdings. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于imitate（模仿），表示“模仿，网络迷因”。在这个例句中，它指的是在社交媒体上广为流传的、通常带有讽刺或幽默性质的图片、视频或文字。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>confidentially (adv.) - /ˈkɒnfɪdɛnʃəli/ 秘密地，保密地。    <p>原文例句：Reddit, which filed confidentially for its IPO in December 2021, is planning to make its public filing in late February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March, two of the sources said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于confident（有信心的），表示“秘密地，保密地”。在这个例句中，它指的是Reddit在2021年12月秘密提交了首次公开募股申请。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the last three years - 在过去的三年里。    <P>原文例句：Many investors posting on the platform have helped fuel dozens of “meme” stock rallies in the last three years. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在），the（这，那个，那些），three（三）和years（年）构成的，表示“在过去的三年里”。在这个例句中，它表示在过去的三年里，许多投资者在平台上发布信息，帮助推高了数十只“迷因”股票。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company, which generates its revenue primarily through advertising, has yet to turn a profit, co-founder Steve Huffman said last June. - 这家公司的主要收入来源是广告，联合创始人史蒂夫·霍夫曼去年六月表示，公司尚未实现盈利。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是The company has yet to turn a profit，其中主语是The company，谓语是has yet to turn a profit，宾语是a profit。which generates its revenue primarily through advertising是一个定语从句，修饰主语The company，表示这家公司的主要收入来源是广告。co-founder Steve Huffman said last June是一个过去时态的句子，作状语，修饰主句，表示史蒂夫·霍夫曼去年六月表示。这个句子的意思是说，这家公司的主要收入来源是广告，但是联合创始人史蒂夫·霍夫曼去年六月表示，公司尚未实现盈利。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示Reddit联合创始人亚历克西斯·奥哈尼安和他的妻子、网球明星塞雷娜·威廉姆斯在2022年合影。这个句子的意思是说，Reddit联合创始人亚历克西斯·奥哈尼安和他的妻子、网球明星塞雷娜·威廉姆斯在2022年合影。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Reddit is planning to make its public filing in February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March, sources say</li>
<li>The company, which generates its revenue primarily through advertising, has yet to turn a profit, co-founder Steve Huffman said last June</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/ceae1676-ec0a-453c-90b8-caa1d3c7da8a_ae468ee4.jpg" /><figcaption>Reddit is hoping to launch its IPO as soon as March, according to people familiar with the matter. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Social media platform Reddit has drawn up detailed plans to launch its initial public offering (IPO) in March, moving forward with a listing it has been eyeing for more than three years, according to people familiar with the matter.</p><p>It would be the first IPO of a major social media company since Pinterest’s debut in 2019, and would come as Reddit and its peers face stiff competition for advertising dollars from the likes of TikTok and Facebook.</p><p>The offering would also test the willingness of some Reddit users to back the company’s stock market debut. Many investors posting on the platform have helped fuel dozens of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3119536/gamestop-frenzy-how-reddit-nerds-sparked-wall" target="_self" title="">“meme” stock rallies</a> in the last three years, from retailer GameStop to movie operator AMC Entertainment Holdings.</p><p>Reddit, which filed confidentially for its IPO in December 2021, is planning to make its public filing in late February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March, two of the sources said.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP" class="image-inline caption" height="2581" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/a63256c8-0f58-4d2a-92c3-f97df71b18ee_a6b611e2.jpg" title="Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP" width="2000" /><figcaption>Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The San Francisco-based company, which was valued at about US$10 billion in a funding round in 2021, is seeking to sell about 10 per cent of its shares in the IPO, the sources added. It will decide on what IPO valuation it will pursue closer to the time of the listing, according to the sources.</p><p>The sources cautioned that Reddit’s IPO plans could be pushed back, as has happened in the past, and asked not to be identified discussing confidential deliberations.</p><p>A Reddit spokesperson declined to comment.</p><p>Founded in 2005 by web developer Steve Huffman and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3087871/reddit-co-founder-alexis-ohanian-resigns-urges-black-board" target="_self" title="">entrepreneur Alexis Ohanian</a>, Reddit became best known for its niche discussion groups and its users voting “up” or “down” on the content posted by other members.</p><p>The company, which generates its revenue primarily through advertising and also offers premium access for US$5.99 per month, has yet to turn a profit, Huffman said in a Reddit post last June.</p><p>In the past, the company has attributed its losses to investing in the platform and its users engaging less with advertising on its site than other social media.</p><p>The company held back from pulling the IPO trigger until it came closer to profitability. Bouts of market volatility that shut down the IPO market for much of the last two years also contributed to it delaying its plans.</p><p>Reddit expected to generate slightly over US$800 million in advertising revenue in 2023, up more than 20 per cent from a year earlier, The Information reported last month.</p><p>Reddit said last year it would charge companies for access to its application programming interface, which is used by technology companies to train <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">large-language models used in artificial intelligence</a>. The move upset some users who rely on third-party apps to access Reddit.</p><p>Large social media stocks have rebounded over the past year, driven mainly by a rally in technology stocks as interest rates peaked. Shares of Meta Platforms, which operates Facebook, have more than trebled in value over the past 12 months, while Snap’s shares rose 60 per cent over the same period.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China remains a tough market to stage a comeback for world’s former top smartphone vendor Samsung</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248969/china-remains-tough-market-stage-comeback-worlds-former-top-smartphone-vendor-samsung</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung has shifted its focus toward the high-end segment of the Chinese smartphone market, particularly foldable handsets, to regain its former glory. Due to reputation damage from the Galaxy Note 7 issue and intense competition from domestic vendors, Samsung faced a decline in its Chinese market share and is now attempting a comeback despite ongoing challenges.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's strategic shift and challenges in the mainland China smartphone market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Samsung's strategic shift is influenced by market conditions, reputation issues, and competition.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's previous dominance and decline in the Chinese market; reasons for the decline, including inappropriate operations, reputation damage, and competition from local brands; Samsung's current strategy of focusing on high-end foldable models; ongoing challenges posed by the US-China tech war and the relocation of production facilities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星将重点转向中国智能手机市场的高端领域，尤其是可折叠手机，以重获昔日的辉煌。由于 Galaxy Note 7 事件造成的声誉损害以及来自国内供应商的激烈竞争，三星在中国市场的份额面临下降，目前正试图卷土重来，尽管面临着持续的挑战。</li>    <li>主题：三星在大中华区智能手机市场上的战略转变和挑战。</li>    <li>观点：三星的战略转变受到市场状况、声誉问题和竞争的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星之前在中国市场上的统治地位和衰落；衰落的原因，包括不当的操作、声誉受损和来自本土品牌的竞争；三星目前专注于高端折叠机型的策略；中美科技战以及生产设施的搬迁所带来的持续挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>foldable (adj.) - /ˈfəʊldəbl/ 可折叠的。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy Z Fold5 and Z Flip5 3D foldable smartphone displays are seen at the company’s flagship store in Shanghai on October 23, 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词表示可以折叠或被折叠。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>premium (adj.) - /ˈpriːmiəm/ 优质的，高档的。    <p>原文例句：“Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end market in China, particularly with the introduction of foldable models,” Counterpoint’s Lam said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词表示“高档的、优质的”，通常用来形容价格昂贵、质量优良的产品或服务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：Samsung, which was unseated by Apple in terms of annual smartphone shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023, still has ambitions to return to its former glory on the mainland.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示在全球年度智能手机出货量方面</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>While Huawei has largely retreated from the Korean market primarily because of local consumers’ loyalty to homegrown Android handsets, Samsung is slowly trying to stage a comeback in China. - 华为在很大程度上退出韩国市场，主要是因为当地消费者对本土安卓手机的忠诚度，但三星正在慢慢尝试在中国卷土重来。<p>句子分析：这是一个虽然（while）复句，主句是Samsung is slowly trying to stage a comeback in China，从句是Huawei has largely retreated from the Korean market primarily because of local consumers’ loyalty to homegrown Android handsets。虽然（while）复句表示虽然前一个分句所述情况存在，但后一个分句所述情况仍然发生。在这个例句中，它表示虽然华为在很大程度上退出韩国市场，但三星正在慢慢尝试在中国卷土重来。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 表示对句中的某个成分进行强调。    <p>原文例句：Samsung, which was unseated by Apple in terms of annual smartphone shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023, still has ambitions to return to its former glory on the mainland.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句型是一种特殊的句型，表示对句中的某个成分进行强调。强调句型通常将需要强调的成分放在句首或句末。如果放在句首，则用逗号隔开。在这个例句中，需要强调的成分是Samsung，放在句首，用逗号隔开。这个句子的意思是说，在全球年度智能手机出货量方面被苹果超越的三星，仍有雄心重返中国大陆的昔日辉煌。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去开始到现在为止已经完成的动作。    <p>原文例句：Samsung has shut down multiple production bases on the mainland, including its last smartphone plant in Huizhou, a city in southern Guangdong province, and last personal computer factory in Suzhou, a bustling metropolis in Jiangsu.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个时态表示从过去开始到现在为止已经完成的动作或状态。结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。在这个例句中，它表示三星关闭了多个生产基地，包括其在广东省惠州市的最后一家智能手机工厂和在江苏省苏州市的最后一家个人电脑工厂。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland’s smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets</li>
<li>The company has closed various production bases in China, including its last smartphone plant in Huizhou and last personal computer factory in Suzhou</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/bf4f1a5f-c528-4f08-b9c2-588ca952e7dd_16946b13.jpg" /><figcaption>Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy Z Fold5 and Z Flip5 3D foldable smartphone displays are seen at the company’s flagship store in Shanghai on October 23, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>A resident of eastern Jiangsu province, 48-year-old Shen Ling used to own a number of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphones</a> in the 2010s, attracted by the devices’ well-designed appearance and popularity among consumers across mainland China.</p><p>“It was once an age of glory for Samsung in China, when so many of my friends were using the brand for its high-end market standing,” Shen said. “I also chose to buy a Samsung phone at that time for the same reason.”</p><p>But Samsung’s strong run in the world’s largest smartphone market took a disastrous turn in late 2016, when the company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/enterprises/article/2027114/samsung-permanently-shuts-note-7-production" target="_self" title="">permanently halted production of its Galaxy Note 7 handset</a> amid increased concerns about the device catching fire. That followed widespread criticism from Chinese consumers after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/2023711/samsung-insists-note-7-china-safe-after-6th-reported-battery-explosion" target="_self" title="">several incidents where the handset’s battery exploded</a>. In January 2017, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korean</a> electronics giant admitted that those incidents were <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/2064560/samsungs-galaxy-note-7-fires-caused-battery-design-manufacturing-issues" target="_self" title="">caused by battery manufacturing and design issues</a> after an internal investigation.</p><p>“The harm to Samsung’s image was devastating,” Shen said. “It made me unsure if I could trust the quality of its future handsets.” Shen finally decided to switch to a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> smartphone in 2020.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/08229e1a-0baf-487d-a0d0-871525d20f84_5b21820d.jpg" title="A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook</figcaption></figure></div><p>Samsung was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/social-gadgets/article/2134770/how-samsung-went-no-1-also-ran-chinas-smartphone-market-and-can" target="_self" title="">once the biggest smartphone vendor on the mainland</a>, with a market share of about 20 per cent in 2013. The Korean firm ranked dead last among the market’s major handset vendors by 2018, with just a 1 per cent share and has since remained around that level.</p><p>The company’s fall in mainland China’s smartphone market was partly due to “a combination of inappropriate operations leading to a damaged reputation”, said Ivan Lam, a senior analyst for Counterpoint Research. He also indicated that major Chinese vendors – including Huawei, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/vivo" target="_self" title="">Vivo</a> – rose to become strong domestic and international competitors.</p><p>But Samsung, which was unseated by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> in terms of annual smartphone shipments worldwide <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above?utm_source=rss_feed" target="_self" title="">for the first time in 2023</a>, still has ambitions to return to its former glory on the mainland.</p><p>While Huawei has largely retreated from the Korean market primarily because of local consumers’ loyalty to homegrown Android handsets, Samsung is slowly trying to stage a comeback in China. Still, Samsung’s mission has become more difficult amid the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248694/china-gdp-beijings-long-do-list-boost-economy-2024" target="_self" title="">shaky post-pandemic economic recovery</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>“Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end market in China, particularly with the introduction of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foldable-phones" target="_self" title="">foldable models</a>,” Counterpoint’s Lam said. “The current strategy for Samsung in China appears to be characterised by conservatism, stability and continuity.”</p><p>Over the past few years, Samsung continued to launch new smartphone models on the mainland. It has also been working with some Chinese Big Tech companies, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>, to help step up localisation of its smartphones’ content ecosystem.</p><p>The reason Samsung did not fully leave mainland China was obvious: the country remains the world’s largest computing, smartphone, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> market. Continued operation in the vast market has become more important for the Korean conglomerate, as its sales have been hit hard by sluggish global consumer electronics demand.</p><p>In its earnings guidance released last week, Samsung said it expected to post its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" target="_self" title="">sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit</a>. The company estimated that its operating earnings for 2023 plunged 84.9 per cent year on year to 6.54 trillion won (US$4.86 billion), while annual revenue was expected to drop 14.6 per cent to 258.16 trillion won.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" title="">Samsung profit tumbles 35% as chip weakness persists</a></h3><p>Samsung’s sharpened focus on the premium segment of China’s smartphone market has managed to attract a growing number of new users. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a> university student Cynthia Xia, for example, started using Samsung’s foldable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3192963/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-4-vs-motorola-razr-foldable-smartphones" target="_self" title="">Galaxy Z Flip 4</a> smartphone in 2022.</p><p>“I was totally attracted by the design and its flexibility to adopt customised settings,” Xia said. “I think no other brands are doing as well as Samsung in foldable phones.”</p><p>Still, Samsung’s outlook in the world’s second-largest economy is complicated by the ongoing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/us-china-tech-war-rivalry/news" target="_self" title="">US-China tech war</a>, which has cast a shadow over the Korean firm’s supply chain network on the mainland.</p><p>Although Samsung, along with memory chip rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3218776/south-korean-chip-maker-sk-hynix-denies-reports-it-selling-firms-dalian-flash-memory-fab-assuring" target="_self" title="">SK Hynix</a>, last year secured indefinite waivers from Washington to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3237485/tech-war-us-waiver-china-export-restrictions-advanced-semiconductor-equipment-south-koreas-samsung" target="_self" title="">ship advanced semiconductor-manufacturing equipment</a> for their China plants, the tech conglomerate has been downsizing its production facilities and number of employees in the country.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3014564/samsungs-last-china-smartphone-factory-closing-raising" title="">Will closing last Samsung smartphone factory hurt China’s role in global value chain?</a></h3><p>Over the past several years, Samsung has shut down multiple production bases on the mainland, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3014564/samsungs-last-china-smartphone-factory-closing-raising" target="_self" title="">its last smartphone plant</a> in Huizhou, a city in southern Guangdong province, and last personal computer factory in Suzhou, a bustling metropolis in Jiangsu. The company had 17,891 employees on the mainland in 2022, which was in stark contrast to its peak of 63,316 in 2013, according to Samsung’s Sustainability Report.</p><p>The relocation of Samsung’s factories from the mainland showed how the company “strategically deprioritised the Chinese market, resulting in reduced investment in brand and channel building”, Counterpoint’s Lam said.</p><p>With Samsung’s recently launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248863/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-smartphones-come-google-gemini-ai-technology-fight-apple-iphones" target="_self" title="">Galaxy 24 series, which features artificial intelligence technology</a>, all eyes are on how the company can help revive and bring change to the global smartphone market.</p><p>Still, that new handset is not expected to make a big splash on the mainland.</p><p>“None of my friends are using Samsung’s phones nowadays, so why wouldn’t I stick with domestic brands when they offer similar functionalities at lower prices?” Shen from Jiangsu said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei releases preview version of updated HarmonyOS Next as it accelerates shift away from Android</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248956/huawei-releases-preview-version-updated-harmonyos-next-it-accelerates-shift-away-android</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese tech giant Huawei unveiled the developer preview version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS Next, targeting the Chinese market and competing with Google's Android and Apple's iOS. Over 200 industry partners have started developing native apps for HarmonyOS, and the company aims to have 5,000 partners onboard by the end of 2024. HarmonyOS Next will no longer support Android-based applications but will focus on building a robust ecosystem of native apps, with Huawei investing in innovation and supporting developers. The adoption of HarmonyOS is growing, currently running on over 800 million devices.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei's HarmonyOS Next developer preview release targets Chinese market.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's HarmonyOS aims to compete with Android and iOS in China, with a focus on native app development.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Huawei's investment in HarmonyOS reflects its commitment to building a domestic mobile operating system alternative.</li>    <li>Main information: HarmonyOS Next developer preview release, target launch date in Q4 2023, native app development by partners, investment in innovation and developer support, growing adoption on over 800 million devices.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国科技巨头华为推出其自研移动操作系统 HarmonyOS Next 的开发者预览版，目标是在中国市场与谷歌的 Android 和苹果的 iOS 竞争。超过 200 个行业合作伙伴已经开始为 HarmonyOS 开发原生应用程序，该公司计划到 2024 年底拥有 5,000 个合作伙伴。HarmonyOS Next 将不再支持基于 Android 的应用程序，而是专注于构建一个强大的原生应用程序生态系统，华为将投资创新并支持开发者。HarmonyOS 的采用量正在增长，目前已在超过 8 亿台设备上运行。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为 HarmonyOS Next 开发者预览版发布，目标是中国市场。</li>    <li>主题：华为 HarmonyOS 旨在与国内的 Android 和 iOS 竞争，重点是原生应用程序开发。</li>    <li>观点：华为对 HarmonyOS 的投资反映了其致力于构建国产移动操作系统替代品的决心。</li>    <li>主要信息：HarmonyOS Next 开发者预览版发布，目标在 2023 年第四季度发布，合作伙伴开发原生应用程序，投资创新和开发者支持，在超过 8 亿台设备上采用量不断增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>codify (v.) - /ˈkɒdɪˌfaɪ/ 编纂成法典，使成法典，制定法律条文。    <p>原文例句：For years, the company has been quietly building its software ecosystem and codifying its own operating system.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由com-（一起）和facere（做）组成，表示“使……成为法律，使……成为法典”。在这个例句中，它表示该公司多年来一直在悄悄地构建其软件生态系统并制定自己的操作系统。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>native (adj.) - /ˈneɪtɪv/ 本地，原产的，native speaker，母语者。    <p>原文例句：Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native apps for HarmonyOS.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，意思是“本地，原生的”。在这个例句中，它表示有超过200个行业合作伙伴已经开始为HarmonyOS开发应用程序。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>ecosystem (n.) - /ˈiːkəʊˌsɪstəm/ 生态系统，生态环境。    <p>原文例句：To encourage development of a more robust ecosystem for HarmonyOS, Huawei will also work with more than 280 companies and over 300 educational institutions to cultivate developers for the operating system.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Greek，由oikos（住处）和systema（系统）组成，表示“生态系统，生物群落及其环境”。在这个例句中，它表示为了促进HarmonyOS更强大的生态系统，华为还将与280多家公司和300多家教育机构合作，为操作系统培养开发人员。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take on - 挑战，承担，接手。    <p>原文例句：as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant takes on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，取）和on（在……之上）组成，表示“挑战，承担，接手”。在这个例句中，它表示这家受美国制裁的电信设备巨头将在中国市场挑战谷歌的Android和苹果的iOS。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>aimed at - 针对，旨在，努力的方向。    <p>原文例句：Huawei’s HarmonyOS is aimed at replacing Google’s Android operating system in China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由aim（瞄准，目标）和at（在……处）组成，表示“针对，旨在，努力的方向”。在这个例句中，它表示华为的HarmonyOS旨在在中国取代谷歌的Android操作系统。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights - HarmonyOS预计将在2024年在中国超过苹果的iOS：TechInsights。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是HarmonyOS预计将在2024年超过苹果的iOS，其中主语是HarmonyOS，谓语是预计将在2024年超过，宾语是苹果的iOS。Huawei’s是名词性物主代词，修饰HarmonyOS，表示华为的HarmonyOS。tipped是过去分词，作定语，修饰HarmonyOS，表示据预计。in China是介词短语，作地点状语，表示在中国。TechInsights是名词性物主代词，修饰TechInsights，表示TechInsights的预测。这个句子的意思是说，据TechInsights的预测，HarmonyOS预计将在2024年在中国超过苹果的iOS。</p></li>    <li>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday. - HarmonyOS Next的开发者预览版于周四向编码人员开放。</p>    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next，谓语是was made available，宾语是to coders。on Thursday是时间状语，表示周四。这个句子的意思是说，HarmonyOS Next的开发者预览版于周四向编码人员开放。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话者对某件事的主观判断或猜测。    <p>原文例句：Huawei’s HarmonyOS is tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights</p>    <p>语法讲解：本句中，“tipped to beat”是虚拟语气的用法，是对未来可能发生的事情的一种猜测。在虚拟语气的句子中，谓语动词通常要用“be+过去分词”的形式。这个句子的意思是，根据TechInsights的预测，HarmonyOS有望在2024年在中国超过苹果的iOS。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday</li>
<li>Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native apps for HarmonyOS</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/f12f9442-2dd3-4de3-a881-63405dd3a097_26cc2667.jpg" /><figcaption>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has unveiled the latest version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS for developers, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant takes on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p><p>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday, and the operating system will be launched for commercial use in the fourth quarter of this year, Huawei said at its developer conference.</p><p>HarmonyOS Next, billed as a major upgrade to Huawei’s mobile platform, will no longer support Android-based applications.</p><p>Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native HarmonyOS apps, and the company aims to get 5,000 partners on board by the end of 2024, Zhu Yonggang, president of Huawei Consumer Business Cloud Services, said at the Thursday event.</p><p>Meituan, the delivery services giant, has already finished the first version of its HarmonyOS app in the first batch of development partners, while other internet firms, such as lifestyle social media platform Xiaohongshu and online mapping service Amap, have also made progress.</p><p>Amap is backed by Alibaba Group Holding, the Post’s owner.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" title="">Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights</a></h3><p>To encourage development of a more robust ecosystem for HarmonyOS, Huawei will also work with more than 280 companies and over 300 educational institutions to cultivate developers for the operating system, according to a company release.</p><p>Huawei will also invest 7 billion yuan (US$983 million) to support innovation in areas from HarmonyOS native apps to Software Development Kit (SDK), a toolset used to help developers build apps for a particular platform, according to posts published on HarmonyOS’s official Weibo account.</p><p>The adoption of HarmonyOS has been growing. Since its launch in August 2019, HarmonyOS currently runs on over 800 million devices, according to Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group, speaking at the Thursday event.</p><p>HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List. Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>Driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment with its P60 Pro model, HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year, according to a report by TechInsights earlier this month.</p><p><em>Additional reporting by Ben Jiang</em></p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
