<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China price wars help spark US$157 billion rout in mainland consumer stocks, as firms including Alibaba, Yum China and BYD drag the market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248377/china-price-wars-help-spark-us157-billion-rout-mainland-consumer-stocks-firms-including-alibaba-yum</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese stock market, notably consumer-related stocks, grapples with weak consumer demand and lack of positive drivers.</li>    <li>Companies, including giants like Alibaba and BYD, engage in price promotions to attract cautious consumers.</li>    <li>The MSCI China Consumer sector lags, losing $157 billion in value since September 2023.</li>    <li>Tesla and other EV makers slash prices amid intense competition, affecting industry profitability.</li>    <li>Concerns grow about corporate earnings, deflation, and the need for government stimulus to prevent further economic slowdown.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国股市，尤其是消费类股票，因需求疲软和缺乏积极驱动因素而备受煎熬。</li>    <li>包括阿里巴巴和比亚迪在内的巨头通过降价促销来吸引谨慎的消费者。</li>    <li>自2023年9月以来，MSCI中国消费板块表现不佳，市值损失约1570亿美元。</li>    <li>特斯拉和其他电动汽车制造商因竞争激烈而降价，影响了行业盈利能力。</li>    <li>人们日益担忧企业收益、通货紧缩以及为防止经济进一步放缓而需要政府刺激措施。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tepid (adj.) - /ˈtɛpɪd/ 不热烈。    <p>原文例句：The seemingly relentless decline in prices of Chinese goods amid tepid consumer demand is denting expectations that corporate earnings can revive the flagging stock market. </p>    <p>例句讲解：tepid是一个形容词，意思是“不热烈，不振奋，不景气”。在这个例句中，它描述了中国商品价格持续下跌的情况，尤其是消费需求疲软，导致人们对企业收益能否提振低迷股市的预期受到打击。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>promotion (n.) - /prəˈmoʊʃən/ 促销。    <p>原文例句：From electric vehicles (EVs) to fast food, companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation. </p>    <p>例句讲解：promotion是一个名词，意思是“促销活动，宣传”。在这个例句中，它描述了从电动汽车到快餐，各行各业的公司都参与到了一场促销大战中，目的是吸引那些对就业前景感到担忧、并目睹持续不断的房地产低迷损害财富创造的消费者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fall by - 下降，减少。    <p>原文例句：The aggregate market value of companies included in the two consumer indexes has fallen by about US$157 billion since. </p>    <p>例句讲解：fall by是一个动词短语，意思是“下降，减少”。在这个例句中，它表示包含在两个消费者指数中的公司的总市值自那以后下降了大约1570亿美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>wage a battle of - 发起……的战斗。    <p>原文例句：From electric vehicles (EVs) to fast food, companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation. </p>    <p>例句讲解：wage a battle of是一个动词短语，意思是“发起……的战斗”。在这个例句中，它描述了从电动汽车到快餐，各行各业的公司都参与到了一场促销大战中，目的是吸引那些对就业前景感到担忧、并目睹持续不断的房地产低迷损害财富创造的消费者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Salary cuts and job losses have remained among the top concerns of households, they wrote, adding that the number of consumers anticipating the economy to worsen ticked up by two percentage points from November to 13 per cent. - 工资削减和失业仍然是家庭最关心的问题之一，他们写道，并补充说，预计经济将恶化的消费者数量从11月的11%上升了两个百分点，达到13%。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Salary cuts and job losses have remained among the top concerns of households，其中主语是Salary cuts and job losses，谓语是have remained。they wrote是一个插入语，表示这句话是他们写的。adding that the number of consumers anticipating the economy to worsen ticked up by two percentage points from November to 13 per cent是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰they wrote，表示他们补充说，预计经济将恶化的消费者数量从11月的11%上升了两个百分点，达到13%。这个句子的意思是说，工资削减和失业仍然是家庭最关心的问题之一，他们写道，并补充说，预计经济将恶化的消费者数量从11月的11%上升了两个百分点，达到13%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>副词作状语 - 表示动作或状态的性质或方式。    <p>原文例句：Companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation是一个副词作状语，修饰动词engaging，表示促销的目的或方式，即为了吸引那些对就业前景感到担忧、并目睹持续不断的房地产低迷损害财富创造的消费者。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The number of consumers anticipating the economy to worsen ticked up by two percentage points from November to 13 per cent. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，ticked up by two percentage points from November to 13 per cent是一个过去完成时，表示在从11月到13%的这一段时间内，预计经济将恶化的消费者数量上升了两个百分点。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023</li>
<li>The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include Alibaba, Yum China Holdings and BYD, which have all been offering big discounts</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/b3e8597a-be7a-4197-85aa-c1a7be1f6626_e063aefc.jpg" /><figcaption>People fly dragon-shaped kites on the Bund in front of buildings in Pudong’s Lujiazui Financial District in Shanghai on January 9, 2024. China’s stock market suffers from a lack of positive drivers ahead of the Lunar New Year. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>The seemingly relentless decline in prices of Chinese goods amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247712/chinas-retail-sales-weaken-year-falling-home-prices-jobs-outlook-feed-consumer-insecurity-ubs" target="_self" title="">tepid consumer demand</a> is denting expectations that corporate earnings can revive the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-stock-market" target="_self" title="">flagging stock market</a>.</p><p>From <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicles</a> (EVs) to fast food, companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3244649/china-inflation-4-takeaways-novembers-data-deflationary-pressure-heightened" target="_self" title="">Consumer prices</a> fell for a third-straight month in December, the longest streak since 2009, deepening concerns about companies’ profits and share prices.</p><p>“That’s all symbolic of a very weak consumption environment that includes lack of consumer confidence and weak income growth,” said Ng Xin-yao, an investment director for Asian equities at abrdn. “We are cautious on fourth-quarter earnings across most sectors, and would assume that continues in the first quarter unless the government starts doing something massive to support the economy.”</p><p>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/msci" target="_self" title="">MSCI China Index</a> since the end of September, after the real estate measure. The aggregate market value of companies included in the two consumer indexes has fallen by about US$157 billion since.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/c17c04b3-1a34-4b5f-9767-75f9273ed6e5_8a6158cb.jpg" title="Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include e-commerce giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, restaurant operator <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3209531/kfc-pizza-hut-operator-yum-china-open-1300-stores-worst-over-posts-earnings-decline-2022" target="_self" title="">Yum China Holdings</a> and EV maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD Co</a> – which have all been offering big discounts. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>The world’s second-largest stock market has started 2024 on a dismal note, with the MSCI China gauge already down more than 4 per cent so far this year. It capped a third straight annual decline in 2023.</p><p>“The bigger picture is that the weak demand is leading to a deflationary environment, which particularly bodes ill for businesses that cannot achieve higher volumes with lower prices,” said Daisy Li, a fund manager at EFG Asset Management HK.</p><p>The EV industry has been among the worst hit by intense competition as growth slows, with Chinese makers following the lead of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> in lowering prices to boost sales. BYD and local peers including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a> have shed billions of dollars in market value in the past few months.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing" title="">Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</a></h3><p>“Retail prices are falling fast,” Morgan Stanley analysts wrote in their 2024 outlook report for the Chinese EV sector. “While local brands, in general, have fared better than luxury and foreign brands in terms of widening discounts, we expect discounts to further widen into the first quarter this year on the back of seasonality effects.”</p><p>Even China’s vaunted <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants have been impacted, with Alibaba and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> seeing their stock prices tumble, as they wage a fierce battle for market share. The price war has made US-listed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247286/pdd-halts-development-local-services-offering-avoid-head-competition-meituan-and-eleme-report-says" target="_self" title="">PDD Holdings</a>, operator of discount sites <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="">Pinduoduo</a> on the mainland and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>, one of the rare bright spots in China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> industry.</p><p>Many economy and market observers are hoping for interest-rate cuts and government spending to help prevent the nation from entering a deflationary spiral.</p><p>Fund managers have said the next catalyst they are watching is pricing and sales data around the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/lunar-new-year" target="_self" title="">Lunar New Year</a> in February, which will offer more clues on consumer confidence.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>The next few weeks may also be key for policy action, given Chinese leaders will soon gear up for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/national-peoples-congress" target="_self" title="">National People’s Congress</a>. That annual legislative session, held in March, is where the government is expected to announce its official growth target for 2024.</p><p>A Morgan Stanley survey conducted late last month suggests seasonally better consumer sentiment ahead of the holidays. However, “sustainability is in doubt amid slowing economic recovery”, analysts including Lillian Lou wrote in a note.</p><p>Salary cuts and job losses have remained among the top concerns of households, they wrote, adding that the number of consumers anticipating the economy to worsen ticked up by two percentage points from November to 13 per cent.</p><p>In all, there is little hope for a quick fix. Citigroup expects consensus estimates to fall for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-ning-company-ltd" target="_self" title="">Li Ning</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3217413/anta-sports-seeks-us15-billion-equity-placement-market-discount-triggering-stocks-worst-sell-six" target="_self" title="">Anta Sports Products</a> around the upcoming results season, hurt by foreign competition and pushes into lower-tier cities with cheaper products.</p><p>Fast-food companies are still locked in a protracted fight for customers, with some offering full meals for around US$3. It is difficult to make money at such low prices.</p><p>“We expect industry margins to erode until the irrational price war ends,” Kevin Yin, an analyst at JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co., wrote in a note, while cutting estimates for Yum China. “No player is immune” to the headwinds created by the nation’s slowing demand growth, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Stanford students win hearts in China with US$32,000 household robot that can cook shrimp and wash pans</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248330/stanford-students-win-hearts-china-us32000-household-robot-can-cook-shrimp-and-wash-pans</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  US researchers have developed a two-handed robot named Mobile Aloha that can cook, clean, and wipe surfaces, among other tasks. The robot, built by Stanford University PhD candidates, can be remotely controlled or operate autonomously through imitation learning. It took three months to develop and cost US$32,000 to build.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Two-handed robot Mobile Aloha autonomously performs household tasks through imitation learning.</li>    <li>Theme: Technological advancements in robotics and AI; the potential role of domestic robots in the smart home ecosystem.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The benefits and limitations of using AI and imitation learning to teach robots complex tasks; the growing market for domestic robots.</li>    <li>Main information: Capabilities of Mobile Aloha; development process and challenges; potential applications of domestic robots.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  美国研究人员开发出一种名为 Mobile Aloha 的双手机器人，可以烹饪、清洁和擦拭表面等任务。这款机器人由斯坦福大学博士候选人建造，可以通过远程控制或通过模仿学习来自主运行。它花了三个月才开发出来，建造费用为 32,000 美元。  <ul>    <li>摘要：双手机器人 Mobile Aloha 通过模仿学习自主执行家庭任务。</li>    <li>主题：机器人技术和人工智能的进步；家用机器人作为智能家居生态系统中的潜在作用。</li>    <li>观点：使用人工智能和模仿学习来教授机器人复杂任务的好处和局限性；家用机器人的市场不断增长。</li>    <li>主要信息：Mobile Aloha 的功能；开发过程和挑战；家用机器人的潜在应用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>deduction (n.) - /dɪˈdʌkʃən/ - 推论，演绎。    <p>原文例句：The deduction is a valid form of reasoning.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“推理”来自于拉丁语deducere（从上向下引），指从一个或多个已知原理通过逻辑推理得出结论的过程。在这个例子中，“推理”是一个有效且常用的逻辑手段，帮助人们得出合乎逻辑的结论。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>prototype (n.) - /ˈprōtəˌtīp/ - 原型，样机。    <p>原文例句：The engineers have built a prototype of the new robot.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“原型”源自希腊语protos（第一）和typos（类型），指第一个或最原始的形式。它是一个为进一步开发或改进而创建的概念模型或示例。在这个例子中，工程师们构建了新机器人的原型，以便进行测试和评估。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>constraint (n.) - /kənˈstrānt/ - 限制，约束。    <p>原文例句：The company is facing several constraints in its production process.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“约束”源自拉丁语constringere（将一起拉紧），指限制、束缚或阻碍。在这个例子中，公司在生产过程中遇到了多种限制因素，阻碍了其生产顺利进行。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>incorporate into - 并入，纳入。    <p>原文例句：The company has incorporated new technology into its production process.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“纳入”的词根为in（在）和corporate（公司，法人），指将某物正式或合法地加入某种组织、团体或结构中。在这个例子中，公司将新技术纳入了其生产过程，以提高效率或改善产品质量。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The two-handed robot, named Mobile Aloha, can be remotely controlled by a human user or work autonomously through imitation learning. - 这款名为 Mobile Aloha 的双手机器人可以通过人类用户远程控制，也可以通过模仿学习自主工作。<p>句子分析：这个句子是一个主谓宾结构的复合句，主语是 The two-handed robot, named Mobile Aloha，谓语是 can be remotely controlled by a human user or work autonomously through imitation learning。其中，can be remotely controlled by a human user 是一个被动语态结构，表示“可以被人类用户远程控制”；work autonomously through imitation learning 是一个主动语态结构，表示“可以通过模仿学习自主工作”。这个句子的意思是说，这款名为 Mobile Aloha 的双手机器人可以通过人类用户远程控制，也可以通过模仿学习自主工作。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The engineers have built a prototype of the new robot.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。结构是：have/has + 过去分词。在这个例子中，have built是现在完成时态，表示工程师们已经建造了新机器人的原型，这个动作从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的状态。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作的承受者。    <p>原文例句：The new robot was unveiled at the technology conference.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态表示动作的承受者。结构是：be + 过去分词。在这个例子中，was unveiled是过去时态的被动语态，表示新机器人被揭幕了，这个动作的承受者是新机器人。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Mobile Aloha, a two-handed system, can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning</li>
<li>It is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, the inventors say</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/a5391667-ecfe-41e0-ba55-d4bcc8573340_5eb9826c.jpg" /><figcaption>Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning. Photo: Screenshot</figcaption></figure><p>A US$32,000 robot developed by a team at Stanford University has caught the attention of Chinese online users, after a video showing the two-handed robot cooking a three-course meal went viral.</p><p>Mobile Aloha, built by two computer-science PhD candidates from China, is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p><p>After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, according to the project’s website.</p><p>It took three months to develop the robot, according to Zipeng Fu, who co-leads the project with Tony Zhao, advised by Stanford assistant professor Chelsea Finn. Fu and Zhao are also student researchers at Google DeepMind, an artificial intelligence (AI) research laboratory.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Fu said they had to tackle both hardware and software challenges. To save cost, they assembled the machine on their own. The goal was to make a robot that could “complete complex home or office tasks that were not shown to be possible previously”.</p><p>The robot can walk at 1.42 metres per second, roughly equivalent to human speed, reach as high as 2 metres and extend one metre beyond its base, the team said.</p><p>When it comes to the software, the duo took a “data-driven AI approach using human demonstration data to teach the robot” instead of the traditional way of “tons of programming and manual tuning” that is not scalable, Fu said.</p><p>The robot cost US$32,000 to build, including on-board power and computing. Fu said he and Zhao, who have open-sourced the whole system, “don’t have any business plan at the moment”.</p><p>As the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ageing-society" target="_self" title="">global population gets older</a>, domestic robots are expected to play a critical role in the smart home ecosystem. The market is estimated to grow at an annual rate of nearly 20 per cent from US$8.6 billion this year to US$22.5 billion by 2029, according to market research firm Mordor Intelligence.</p><p>Global tech giants have been betting big on the sector. In 2021, American online retailer Amazon.com unveiled Astro, a nearly US$1,000 household robot designed for home monitoring. Japanese electronics giant Sony launched the latest generation of its Aibo robot dog in 2018, priced at around US$2,900.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s Big Tech firms from Tencent to Alibaba cut external investments further in 2023 amid troubled economy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248311/chinas-big-tech-firms-tencent-alibaba-cut-external-investments-further-2023-amid-troubled-economy</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  The investment deals made by the three internet giants, Alibaba, Tencent, and Baidu were significantly reduced in the past year. Among them, Tencent saw the most significant decline, with the number of deals dropping from 95 in 2022 to 39 in 2023, representing a decrease of about 60%. Alibaba and Baidu also saw a decline in their investment activities. The decline in investments is attributed to factors such as the economic slowdown, regulatory pressures, and geopolitical tensions.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: The slowdown in external investments by China's internet companies due to economic, regulatory, and political issues.</li>    <li>Theme: The changing investment landscape of China's internet giants.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of economic headwinds, regulatory tightening, and geopolitical tensions on investment activities.</li>    <li>Main information: The significant reduction in investment deals by Alibaba, Tencent, and Baidu; the focus of Tencent's investments on corporate services, healthcare, and video games; Alibaba's focus on advanced manufacturing firms; and the interest of Chinese tech giants in AI and large language models.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  去年，阿里巴巴、腾讯、百度三大互联网巨头的投资交易减少了近 40%。智能手机制造商小米以 82 笔投资位居同类公司投资榜首。  <ul>    <li>摘要：经济、监管和政治问题导致中国互联网企业对外投资放缓。</li>    <li>主题：中国互联网巨头投资格局的变化。</li>    <li>观点：经济逆风、监管趋严和地缘政治紧张局势对投资活动的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：阿里巴巴、腾讯和百度投资交易大幅减少；腾讯投资主要集中在企业服务、医疗保健和视频游戏；阿里巴巴关注先进制造企业；中国科技巨头对人工智能和大语言模型的兴趣。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>slash (v.) - /slæʃ/ 减少，削减。    <p>原文例句：Smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor among its peers by number of investments, with 82 deals made in 2023</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语sleán，意为“砍，切”。在这个例句中，它表示Xiaomi在2023年进行了82笔投资，成为同类公司中投资数量最多的投资者。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>regulatory (adj.) - /ˈrɛg.jʊ.lə.tɔː.ri/ 监管的，管制的。    <p>原文例句：Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语regere，意为“统治，管理”。在这个例句中，它表示一系列监管收紧措施使中国互联网巨头实际上已停止扩张。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>have virtually stopped - 实际上已停止。    <P>原文例句：Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由have、virtually和stopped构成，意为“实际上已经停止”。在这个例句中，它表示一系列监管收紧措施使中国互联网巨头实际上已停止扩张。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Among them, Tencent saw the most significant decline, with the number of deals dropping from 95 in 2022 to 39 in 2023, representing a decrease of about 60%. - 其中，腾讯的降幅最为显着，其交易数量从2022年的95笔下降至2023年的39笔，降幅约为60%。<p>句子分析：这是一个句子，主句是Tencent saw the most significant decline，其中主语是Tencent，谓语是saw，宾语是the most significant decline。with the number of deals dropping from 95 in 2022 to 39 in 2023, representing a decrease of about 60%是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰谓语saw，表示腾讯的交易数量从2022年的95笔下降至2023年的39笔，降幅约为60%。这个句子的意思是说，其中，腾讯的降幅最为显着，其交易数量从2022年的95笔下降至2023年的39笔，降幅约为60%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it have virtually stopped expanding表示一系列监管收紧措施使中国互联网巨头实际上已停止扩张，强调这种停止状态从过去的某个时间一直持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>by number of - 按数量。    <p>原文例句：Smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor among its peers by number of investments.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个词组由by和number of构成，意为“按数量”。在这个例句中，它表示Smartphone maker Xiaomi按投资数量成为同类公司中的第一大投资者。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Total investment deals made by Alibaba, Tencent and Baidu plunged by nearly 40 per cent last year, data from ITJuzi shows</li>
<li>Smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor among its peers by number of investments, with 82 deals made in 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/44791123-3b25-419d-83ab-8b90abaff588_62f5b773.jpg" /><figcaption>The Tencent headquarters in Shenzhen. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>China’s internet giants from Alibaba Group Holding to Tencent Holdings slashed external investments last year amid an economic slowdown, regulatory headwinds and geopolitical tensions, according to data compiled by a Chinese consultancy.</p><p>Total investment deals made by Alibaba, Tencent and Baidu plunged by nearly 40 per cent to 102 in 2023, with Tencent – known for its expansive holdings in China’s internet sector – seeing the largest reduction in deals, data from ITJuzi showed.</p><p>The social media and video gaming titan struck 39 investment contracts with 37 companies last year, a sharp decline from the 95 and 299 deals it made in 2022 and 2021, respectively.</p><p>Web search and artificial intelligence (AI) firm Baidu participated in 24 investment deals last year, down from 52 in 2021. E-commerce giant Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, took part in 39 deals, a fall from 91 in 2021, according to ITJuzi.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/7597aa81-09a5-4a11-9eec-a437d76b7f0a_d667e456.jpg" title="The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure></div><p>2021 was a watershed year for Chinese internet firms, as Beijing kicked off a campaign to rein in the “disorderly expansion of capital”. Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding.</p><p>Tencent’s investments last year were mainly related to corporate services, healthcare and video games. Advanced manufacturing firms were Alibaba’s top picks, with eight related deals being struck by the Hangzhou-based company and its affiliates during the year.</p><p>Alibaba, which is grappling with anaemic consumer spending at home, made four investment deals in the e-commerce sector, three of them outside China.</p><p>AI was another investment favourite among Chinese tech giants last year, as they raced to build and promote their local rivals to OpenAI’s ChatGPT.</p><p>Tencent and Alibaba each backed seven and four AI start-ups developing large language models (LLMs), the technology which underpins chatbots like ChatGPT, which can understand complex questions and give humanlike responses.</p><p>Last year, Alibaba’s in-house research facility Damo Academy also launched a research laboratory to recruit more than a hundred postdoctoral candidates to work on cutting-edge areas, including AI and semiconductors.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1325" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/5991da2b-d385-4951-b2a1-8a232f9ce1c4_bc1c8442.jpg" title="Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Other major Chinese tech companies made even fewer investments.</p><p>TikTok owner ByteDance struck five external investment deals last year, while online shopping platform operator JD.com made just two.</p><p>ByteDance’s largest deal in 2023 was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244634/tiktok-restarts-e-commerce-indonesia-us15-billion-investment-goto-gojek-tokopedia-unit" target="_self" title="">a US$1.5 billion investment into Indonesia’s biggest e-commerce firm Tokopedia</a>, which allows the Beijing-based company to restart its local online shopping business after Indonesian regulators banned TikTok Shop.</p><p>Meanwhile, Chinese smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor by number of investments, with 82 deals made during the year.</p><p>The company, also based in Beijing, in December launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246558/xiaomi-unveils-its-first-ev-su7-setting-its-sights-tesla-highly-competitive-china-market" target="_self" title="">its first electric vehicle, the SU7</a>, designed to compete against the likes of Tesla and Porsche in China’s hotly contested car market.</p><p>In that same month, Xiaomi invested in three start-ups in the vehicle and transport industry, according to ITJuzi.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong needs to speed up approval of spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds after US launch, industry insiders say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248282/hong-kong-needs-speed-approval-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-after-us-launch-industry</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong is urged to authorize spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs) to remain competitive in the global market.</li>    <li>The US has already launched spot bitcoin ETFs, attracting significant investment.</li>    <li>Industry experts believe Hong Kong should follow suit to maintain its position as a financial hub.</li>    <li>Spot crypto ETFs provide investors with exposure to virtual assets without directly buying crypto tokens.</li>    <li>China is unlikely to follow suit due to its strict cryptocurrency regulations.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>业内人士敦促香港授权现货加密货币交易所交易基金 (ETF)，以保持在全球市场的竞争力。</li>    <li>美国已经推出现货比特币 ETF，吸引了大量投资。</li>    <li>行业专家认为，香港应效仿美国，以保持其作为金融中心的地位。</li>    <li>现货加密货币 ETF 让投资者无需直接购买加密货币代币即可接触虚拟资产。</li>    <li>由于中国严格的加密货币监管，中国不太可能效仿。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>bolstering (v.) 加强，巩固。    <p>原文例句：Hong Kong should soon follow the United States’ lead in authorising spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs), bolstering the city’s ambition to become a major virtual-asset hub in Asia, according to industry insiders.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由bolster（支撑）和-ing（现在分词后缀）构成的，表示“加强，巩固”。在这个例句中，它指的是香港通过授权现货加密货币交易所交易基金来加强其成为亚洲主要虚拟资产中心的雄心。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>landmark (adj.) 地标性的，里程碑式的。    <p>原文例句：Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust, Grayscale Bitcoin Trust and ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF, among others – began trading on Thursday, following the US Securities and Exchange Commission’s landmark approval that is expected to help bring the cryptocurrency industry closer to the more regulated world of traditional finance.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由land（土地）和mark（标记）构成的，表示“地标性的，里程碑式的”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国证券交易委员会的批准是具有里程碑意义的，它有望使加密货币行业更接近受监管的传统金融世界。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>legitimacy (n.) 合法性，正当性。    <p>原文例句：These funds “give the crypto industry more legitimacy and also opens up more collaboration opportunities with mainstream finance”, said RJ Ke, a researcher with ethereum scaling start-up Taiko.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由legitimate（合法的）和-acy（名词后缀）构成的，表示“合法性，正当性”。在这个例句中，它指的是这些基金为加密货币行业带来了更多的合法性和正当性，也为与主流金融的合作创造了更多机会。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in principle - 原则上，从原则上讲。    <P>原文例句：Day pointed out that the SFC’s statement in December about being prepared to authorise such funds has “in principle opened a pathway for issuers to launch spot crypto ETFs in Hong Kong”.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在）和principle（原则）构成的，表示“原则上，从原则上讲”。在这个例句中，它表示香港证监会12月关于准备授权此类基金的声明原则上为发行人推出了在香港推出现货加密货币ETF的途径。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong needs to launch spot virtual asset ETFs as soon as possible to “ensure that the city remains competitive in the global cryptocurrency market and strengthen its position as a global financial centre”, said Mao Shixing, also known as “Discus Fish”, who is the co-founder and chief executive of digital asset custody solutions provider Cobo. - 毛世兴说，香港需要尽快推出现货虚拟资产ETF，以“确保香港在全球加密货币市场保持竞争力，并加强其作为全球金融中心的地位”。毛世兴也是数字资产托管解决方案提供商Cobo的联合创始人兼首席执行官。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Hong Kong needs to launch spot virtual asset ETFs as soon as possible，其中主语是Hong Kong，谓语是needs to launch，宾语是spot virtual asset ETFs。as soon as possible是一个时间状语，表示“尽快”。to “ensure that the city remains competitive in the global cryptocurrency market and strengthen its position as a global financial centre”是一个目的状语，表示“为了确保香港在全球加密货币市场保持竞争力并加强其作为全球金融中心的地位”。这个句子的意思是说，毛世兴表示，香港需要尽快推出现货虚拟资产ETF，以确保香港在全球加密货币市场保持竞争力，并加强其作为全球金融中心的地位。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The Chinese government banned banks from handling bitcoin in 2013 and forced cryptocurrency exchanges to move offshore in 2017. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示中国政府从2013年开始禁止银行处理比特币，并迫使加密货币交易所在2017年搬到海外。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：China’s state media recently emphasised the risks involved in spot cryptocurrency ETFs. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个语态，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词。被动语态表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的，强调动作或状态的承受者或被影响者。在这个例句中，它表示中国的国家媒体最近强调了现货加密货币ETF涉及的风险。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Hong Kong has fallen behind the US in authorising spot cryptocurrency ETFs, even though regulators in December said the city was prepared to do so</li>
<li>Industry insiders urge local regulators to step up approvals to strengthen the city’s competitiveness in the global cryptocurrency market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/3b2dd50a-a4ac-4010-9e13-b8b9d2dcf87f_4276bf76.jpg" /><figcaption>The successful launch of spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds in the US is expected to help move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong</a> should soon follow the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>’ lead in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">authorising spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a> (ETFs), bolstering the city’s ambition to become a major <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3197838/hong-kong-unveils-policies-develop-virtual-assets-industry-challenging-singapore-hub-status" target="_self" title="">virtual-asset hub in Asia</a>, according to industry insiders.</p><p>While the city’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/sfc" target="_self" title="">Securities and Futures Commission</a> (SFC) in December said it was prepared to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" target="_self" title="">authorise retail access to spot virtual asset ETFs</a>, the actual launch of such products has already fallen behind the US, according to Wang Yi, the head of quantitative investment at CSOP Asset Management, which currently runs two <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/digital-currencies" target="_self" title="">cryptocurrency</a> futures ETFs.</p><p>US-listed spot <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bitcoin" target="_self" title="">bitcoin</a> ETFs saw US$4.6 billion worth of shares trade hands on Thursday, according to a Reuters report that cited LSEG data, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248152/us-bitcoin-etfs-trades-soar-us46-billion-first-day-after-landmark-sec-approval" target="_self" title="">investors jumped into the landmark products</a> approved by the US securities regulator on Wednesday.</p><p>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust, Grayscale Bitcoin Trust and ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF, among others – began trading on Thursday, following the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">US Securities and Exchange Commission’s landmark approval</a> that is expected to help bring the cryptocurrency industry closer to the more regulated world of traditional finance.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/9cebdb57-e859-4c52-8114-95780d50fca8_a66cec46.jpg" title="Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The successful US launch of spot bitcoin ETFs is expected to help move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city.</p><p>Spot cryptocurrency ETFs enable investors to gain exposure to virtual assets without directly buying any crypto tokens.</p><p>These funds “give the crypto industry more legitimacy and also opens up more collaboration opportunities with mainstream finance”, said RJ Ke, a researcher with ethereum scaling start-up Taiko. “Hong Kong is likely to accelerate bitcoin ETF applications in the coming months.”</p><p>Around 10 fund management firms are preparing to launch spot virtual asset-backed ETFs in Hong Kong, according to Chinese media Caixin’s interview on Wednesday of Livio Weng, chief operating officer at <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239953/hong-kongs-hashkey-launches-first-crypto-trading-app-retail-investors-gives-away-new-token" target="_self" title="">crypto trading app operator HashKey Group</a>. Weng said that up to eight companies were at an “advanced stage” to launch.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" title="">US regulator SEC authorises spot bitcoin ETFs in cryptocurrency breakthrough</a></h3><p>Bitcoin jumped about 3.4 per cent to US$47,500, following the spot crypto ETF approvals in the US. That was nearly three times the level that the original cryptocurrency reached in November 2022, when <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3199385/crypto-exchange-giant-ftx-collapses-files-bankruptcy-protection-global-digital-currency-market-posts" target="_self" title="">failed crypto exchange FTX filed for bankruptcy</a> to send bitcoin’s price below US$17,000.</p><p>Hong Kong needs to launch spot virtual asset ETFs as soon as possible to “ensure that the city remains competitive in the global cryptocurrency market and strengthen its position as a global financial centre”, said Mao Shixing, also known as “Discus Fish”, who is the co-founder and chief executive of digital asset custody solutions provider Cobo.</p><p>Mao said the US approvals could impact other jurisdictions because “the SEC is one of the most influential and reputable financial regulators in the world”, adding that the agency’s initiatives “often serve as important references for financial regulators in other countries and regions”.</p><p>“However, each country and region has its own independent stance and regulatory objectives,” he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" title="">Hong Kong to push retail access to spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a></h3><p>Echoing the Cobo head’s view, Donald Day, chief operating officer at digital asset platform VDX, said the SEC’s decision would make its peers “seriously consider whether similar ETFs would be permissible and desirable”.</p><p>Day pointed out that the SFC’s statement in December about being prepared to authorise such funds has “in principle opened a pathway for issuers to launch spot crypto ETFs in Hong Kong”.</p><p>With the US, there are now nine markets around the world that have allowed the operation of spot crypto ETFs. The other markets include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/canada?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Canada</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/germany?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Germany</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/switzerland?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Switzerland</a>, and tax havens such as the Cayman Islands in the Caribbean and Jersey near the coast of northwestern France, according to market analytics firm CoinGecko.</p><p>Mainland China, however, is unlikely to follow suit.</p><p>In December, China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology said it will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" target="_self" title="">draft a national Web3 development plan</a> to suit the country’s needs. But the announcement did not mention cryptocurrencies even though Beijing maintains its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3216894/chinese-officials-pledge-support-hong-kongs-tech-web3-ambitions-digital-economy-summit?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">support for Hong Kong’s ambition to become a major virtual-asset hub</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" title="">Beijing to draft national Web3 development plan amid strict cryptocurrency ban</a></h3><p>The Chinese government banned banks from handling bitcoin in 2013 and forced cryptocurrency exchanges to move offshore in 2017. In 2021, the country’s regulators reiterated the state’s prohibition on all financial institutions from engaging in crypto-related activities.</p><p>China’s state media recently emphasised the risks involved in spot cryptocurrency ETFs.</p><p>The US approval of spot bitcoin ETFs “would make the cryptocurrency market even more frantic, providing fertile ground for illegal transactions such as money laundering”, according to a report by the International Financial News, a newspaper under the People’s Daily, which cited Shanghai Jiao Tong University assistant professor Li Nan.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
