<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Nvidia expands its reach in China’s electric vehicle sector</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Nvidia announced at the CES tech conference in Las Vegas that four Chinese electric vehicle brands, Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr, and the new EV unit of Xiaomi, will employ its DRIVE technology to power automated driving systems. This decision highlights Nvidia's determination to expand in China despite stricter U.S. export regulations.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese automakers choose Nvidia's technology for automated driving.</li>    <li>Theme: Nvidia's DRIVE technology gains traction among Chinese electric vehicle manufacturers.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The growing importance of China's EV market for Nvidia and other semiconductor manufacturers; the impact of U.S. export controls on Nvidia's operations in China.</li>    <li>Main information: Adoption of Nvidia's DRIVE technology by four Chinese automakers; the competitive landscape of China's EV industry; the challenges faced by Nvidia in balancing Chinese demand with U.S. export restrictions.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  英伟达在拉斯维加斯举行的CES技术大会上宣布，四家中国电动汽车品牌——理想汽车、长城汽车、极氪汽车以及小米汽车，都将采用英伟达的DRIVE技术来为自动驾驶系统提供动力。这一决定凸显了英伟达在中国扩张的决心，尽管美国收紧了出口管制政策。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国汽车制造商选择英伟达的技术用于自动驾驶。</li>    <li>主题：英伟达的DRIVE技术在中国电动汽车制造商中获得青睐。</li>    <li>观点：中国电动汽车市场对英伟达和其他半导体制造商的重要性日益增加；美国出口管制对英伟达在中国业务的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：四家中国汽车制造商采用英伟达的DRIVE技术；中国电动汽车行业竞争格局；英伟达在平衡中国需求与美国出口限制方面面临的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>automated (adj.) - /ˈɔːtəˌmeɪtɪd/ 自动化的。    <p>原文例句：Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday. </p>    <p>例句讲解：automated一词源自希腊语automatos（自我运动），意思是“自动化的”。在这个例句中，它指的是由机器或计算机自动控制和操作的。例如：“The company plans to automate its production lines in order to increase efficiency.”（该公司计划将其生产线自动化，以提高效率。）</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>chip (n.) - /tʃɪp/ 芯片。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips, while complying with US controls on semiconductor exports to China. </p>    <p>例句讲解：chip一词源自古英语cippan（切碎），意思是“芯片”。在这个例句中，它指的是一种小型电子器件，通常由硅制成，用于放大、整流或控制电流。例如：“The latest smartphones are equipped with powerful chips that enable faster processing speeds.”（最新的智能手机配备了强大的芯片，可以实现更快的处理速度。）</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in compliance with - 符合，遵守。    <P>原文例句：Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</P>    <p>例句讲解：in compliance with是一组介词短语，意思是“符合，遵守”。在这个例句中，它表示英伟达及其在美国的竞争对手在满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求的同时，也必须遵守美国对出口到中国的先进半导体更严格的控制规定。例如：“The company must ensure that its products are in compliance with all applicable regulations.”（该公司必须确保其产品符合所有适用的法规。）</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China. - 英伟达及其在美国的竞争对手在满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求的同时，也必须遵守美国对出口到中国的先进半导体更严格的控制规定。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips，其中主语是Nvidia and its US-based rivals，谓语是face challenges meeting demands，宾语是powerful chips。while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示在遵守美国对出口到中国的先进半导体更严格的控制规定的同时。这个句子的意思是说，英伟达及其在美国的竞争对手在满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求的同时，也必须遵守美国对出口到中国的先进半导体更严格的控制规定。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示英伟达及其在美国的竞争对手从过去的某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>非谓语动词 - 可以充当句子成分的动词形式。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia’s DRIVE technology gains traction among Chinese electric vehicle manufacturers. </p>    <p>语法讲解：非谓语动词是指不能单独作谓语的动词形式，包括不定式、分词和动名词。在句子中，非谓语动词可以充当主语、宾语、表语、定语和状语等成分。在这个例句中，gains traction是分词作谓语，表示“获得吸引力”。例如：“The company’s new product launch was met with positive reviews.”（该公司的新产品发布获得了积极的评价。）</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday</li>
<li>Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips, while complying with US controls on semiconductor exports to China</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/ca10cd80-a417-41ba-821c-f909879abb0a_5739d5f7.jpg" /><figcaption>A Nvidia logo at the company’s headquarters in Taipei, Taiwan. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia said four Chinese electric vehicle brands will use its technology as the brains for automated driving systems, underscoring the US chip maker’s determination to expand in China despite Washington’s tighter export rules.</p><p>Chinese carmakers Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Chinese telecommunications company Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday at the CES technology conference in Las Vegas.</p><p>China’s rising EV brands are a key market for Nvidia’s automotive technology business. Chinese carmakers are racing each other to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays and automated driving functions. That has created a growth opportunity for Nvidia, Intel, Qualcomm and other semiconductor manufacturers.</p><p>Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>In related CES announcements, Nvidia said it is working with advertising giant WPP, Lotus and six other companies to develop more advanced online shopping tools. Using Nvidia technology, carmakers and dealers hope to create online shopping sites with three dimensional graphics and more lifelike graphics, said Danny Shapiro, Nvidia’s vice-president for automotive.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tencent’s Pony Ma says 2021 WeChat photo privacy controversy was ‘misunderstanding’ that was fixed with update</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247704/tencents-pony-ma-says-2021-wechat-photo-privacy-controversy-was-misunderstanding-was-fixed-update</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Pony Ma, CEO of Tencent, recently explained the 2021 WeChat photo incident as a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images, assuring that the issue had been fixed. Previously, concerns emerged due to WeChat accessing user photo galleries while not in use. Tencent claimed it was necessary to improve speed and smoothness of photo sharing when authorized. China has since introduced stricter laws regulating data handling by tech companies, leading to increased scrutiny.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tencent CEO clarifies 2021 WeChat photo issue as a misunderstanding, addressing privacy concerns.</li>    <li>Theme: Resolving the controversy surrounding the incident and emphasizing the importance of data protection in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Pony Ma's explanation aims to alleviate privacy concerns, highlighting the company's efforts to comply with new data protection laws in China.</li>    <li>Main information: Pony Ma's characterization of the issue as a misunderstanding; Tencent's previous justification for accessing user photos; China's heightened scrutiny of tech companies' data handling.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  腾讯CEO马化腾近日就2021年微信照片事件做出说明，将其归因于图片高速缓存加速造成的误解，并保证该问题已经得到解决。此前，有消息指出微信在未使用时也会访问用户照片库，引发隐私方面的担忧。对此，腾讯澄清是为了提高有授权条件下图片发送的速度和流畅度。中国的相关监管部门近年已颁布了多项法律法规，加强对科技企业处理个人数据行为的管理，进行严厉的审查。  <ul>    <li>摘要：就微信照片事件引发隐私担忧，腾讯CEO做出解释，强调数据保护的重要性。</li>    <li>主题：解决事件引起的争议，凸显中国数据保护的责任感。</li>    <li>观点：马化腾的解释旨在消除公众对隐私问题的担忧，强调腾讯对于遵守中国新数据保护法律的重视。</li>    <li>主要信息：马化腾将问题定性为误解；腾讯以往对访问用户照片的辩解；中国加大了对科技企业数据处理行为的审查力度。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sparks (v.) - /spɑːrz/ 点燃，引起。    <p>原文例句：The 2021 WeChat photo issue sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time despite reassurances that the glitch had been fixed.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由spark（火花，小火星）衍生而来，表示“点燃，引起，爆发”。在这个例句中，它指的是2021年微信照片事件引发了广泛的隐私担忧，即使有人保证这个问题已经修复了。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>routinely (adv.) - /ˈruːtɪnli/ 例行地，惯常地。    <p>原文例句：The influencer also said in 2021 that Tencent’s QQ messaging app and Taobao, Alibaba Group Holding’s top online shopping marketplace with roughly 900 million MAUs, had also been found routinely accessing user photos.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由routine（惯例，常例）派生而来，表示“例行地，惯常地，有规律地”。在这个例句中，它指的是有影响力的人还表示，腾讯的QQ消息应用程序和淘宝网，阿里巴巴集团控股的顶级在线购物市场，拥有大约9亿MAU，也被发现经常访问用户照片。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Privacy controversy - 隐私争议。    <p>原文例句：A 2021 privacy controversy sparked by a photo issue with its all-purpose super app WeChat as a “misunderstanding”, according to a local media report.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由privacy（隐私）和controversy（争议）构成的，表示“隐私争议”。在这个例句中，它指的是2021年微信照片事件引发的隐私争议，据当地媒体报道，马化腾将此称为“误解”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Data protection law - 数据保护法。    <p>原文例句：China has introduced new laws in recent years that tighten scrutiny over how tech companies handle personal data.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由data（数据）和protection（保护）组成的，表示“数据保护法”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国近年来颁布的新法律，加强了对科技公司处理个人数据行为的监督。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tencent faced intense scrutiny in 2021 when tech influencer Hackl0us said on social media platform Weibo that the app periodically accessed user photos while running in the background. - 2021年，科技博主Hackl0us在社交媒体平台微博上表示，该应用程序会定期访问用户照片，即使在后台运行也是如此，腾讯因此面临严格审查。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Tencent faced intense scrutiny，其中主语是Tencent，谓语是faced intense scrutiny。when tech influencer Hackl0us said on social media platform Weibo that the app periodically accessed user photos while running in the background是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示腾讯面临严格审查的时间或原因，即当科技博主Hackl0us在社交媒体平台微博上表示该应用程序会定期访问用户照片即使在后台运行也是如此时。这个句子的意思是说，2021年，科技博主Hackl0us在社交媒体平台微博上表示，该应用程序会定期访问用户照片，即使在后台运行也是如此，腾讯因此面临严格审查。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 表示对句子中某个成分的强调。    <p>原文例句：Tencent said at the time that the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”, and it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句型，结构是：It is/was + 被强调成分 + that/who + 其他。其中it is/was是强调句型的标志，被强调成分是句子中需要强调的部分。在这个例句中，被强调成分是the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”，表示腾讯当时表示，该应用程序正在寻找新图像，以便“让用户更快、更顺畅地发送照片”。这个句子的意思是说，腾讯当时表示，该应用程序正在寻找新图像，以便“让用户更快、更顺畅地发送照片”，并且它只在用户授权的情况下才会访问图库。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Ma described the issue as ‘a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images’</li>
<li>The 2021 WeChat photo issue sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time despite reassurances that the glitch had been fixed</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/daec20ec-0fa7-42e0-ad58-197447fdda39_11d7714e.jpg" /><figcaption>Ma described the WeChat issue as “a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images”. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Pony Ma Huateng, founder, chairman and CEO of Tencent Holdings, has described a 2021 privacy controversy sparked by a photo issue with its all-purpose super app WeChat as a “misunderstanding”, according to a local media report.</p><p>Thay year, a tech influencer found that WeChat, China’s largest social media app with 1.3 billion monthly active users (MAUs), was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3151762/tencents-wechat-stop-routine-scans-photos-after-tech-influencer" target="_self" title="">frequently accessing user photo galleries even when not in use</a>, which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time.</p><p>Ma described the issue as “a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images”, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Yicai on Monday.</p><p>He said the matter was solved by the roll-out of a new application programming interface within the operating system to fix the lag.</p><p>Tencent said at the time that the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”, and it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user. The company also said it would cancel the scanning in a new version of the app.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Yicai picked up Ma’s comments from CSDNnews, a tech news outlet run by the Chinese Software Developer Network.</p><p>Ma told CSDNnews in a private WeChat message last Friday that this “old incident” in 2021 had been fixed, according to a screenshot shared by the outlet.</p><p>Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment by the Post on Monday.</p><p>China has introduced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3147040/what-chinas-new-data-laws-are-and-their-impact-big-tech?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">new laws in recent years</a> that tighten scrutiny over how tech companies handle personal data.</p><p>The Data Security Law and the Personal Information Protection Law, some of the world’s toughest data protection laws, went into effect in 2021 with strict penalties for the unauthorised collection, processing, storage and use of data generated in the country.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245623/chinas-finance-influencers-face-stricter-rules-tencents-live-streaming-channels-beijing-moves-shore" title="">China’s finance live streamers face stricter rules on Tencent</a></h3><p>Tencent faced intense scrutiny in 2021 when tech influencer Hackl0us said on social media platform Weibo that the app periodically accessed user photos while running in the background.</p><p>The activity was discovered using Apple’s “Record App Activity” feature on its iOS 15 operating system at that time.</p><p>The influencer also said in 2021 that Tencent’s QQ messaging app and Taobao, Alibaba Group Holding’s top online shopping marketplace with roughly 900 million MAUs, had also been found routinely accessing user photos. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong joins EU, US, South Korea and Singapore in tightening crypto regulations in 2023, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247684/hong-kong-joins-eu-us-south-korea-and-singapore-tightening-crypto-regulations-2023-report-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  世界各地政府在过去的一年里加强了对加密货币的审查，许多国家加强了对这个波动行业的消费者保护。根据区块链分析公司 TRM Labs 发布的一份报告，2023 年包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的 17 个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币监管。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 全球多个司法管辖区加强了加密货币监管，旨在保护消费者并应对市场动荡。</li>    <li>Theme: 加密货币监管的收紧反映了各国对这个新兴行业日益重视，以及对投资者保护的迫切需求。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 加密货币监管的收紧有助于保护消费者，降低市场风险，促进加密货币行业的健康发展。</li>    <li>Main information: 全球 17 个司法管辖区收紧加密货币监管；加密货币平台倒闭导致市场动荡；欧盟、香港、新加坡等地推出新法规；稳定币监管受到关注；国际组织发布全球框架和政策建议。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  全球多个司法管辖区加强了加密货币监管，旨在保护消费者并应对市场动荡。根据区块链分析公司 TRM Labs 发布的一份报告，2023 年包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的 17 个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币监管。  <ul>    <li>摘要：全球多地加强加密货币监管，保护消费者，应对市场波动。</li>    <li>主题：加密货币监管收紧反映各国对新兴行业重视，保护投资者迫切。</li>    <li>观点：监管收紧有助于保护消费者，降低市场风险，促进加密货币行业健康发展。</li>    <li>主要信息：全球 17 地收紧监管；加密货币平台倒闭导致市场动荡；欧盟、香港、新加坡等地推出新法规；稳定币监管受关注；国际组织发布全球框架和政策建议。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Scrutiny (n.) - /ˈskrutinɪ/ 审查，仔细检查。    <p>原文例句：Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语scrutinium，意为“检查，调查”。它指的是对某人或某事的仔细检查或审查。在这个例句中，它表示世界各地的政府在过去的一年里加强了对加密货币的审查。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Volatile (adj.) - /ˈvɑːlətaɪl/ 易变的，不稳定的。    <p>原文例句：Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语volatilis，意为“飞行的，不稳定的”。它指的是容易变化或不稳定的东西。在这个例句中，它表示加密货币行业是一个波动性很强的行业，价格经常大幅波动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Framework (n.) - /ˈfreɪmwɜːk/ 框架，结构。    <p>原文例句：International organizations, including the G20, the Financial Action Task Force, the Financial Stability Board, International Monetary Fund, and the International Organization of Securities Commissions, all laid out global frameworks and policy recommendations for regulating cryptocurrencies.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语frame，意为“框架，结构”。它指的是一个支撑或包含某事物的结构或系统。在这个例句中，它表示国际组织制定了全球框架和政策建议来监管加密货币。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the past year - 在过去的一年里，去年。    <p>原文例句：Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由介词in，名词year和介词past组成，表示在过去的一年里。在这个例句中，它表示世界各地的政府在过去的一年里加强了对加密货币的审查。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>lay out - 制定，提出。    <p>原文例句：International organizations, including the G20, the Financial Action Task Force, the Financial Stability Board, International Monetary Fund, and the International Organization of Securities Commissions, all laid out global frameworks and policy recommendations for regulating cryptocurrencies.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由动词lay和副词out组成，表示制定，提出。在这个例句中，它表示国际组织制定了全球框架和政策建议来监管加密货币。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the European Union, South Korea, Singapore, and the United States, tightened cryptocurrency regulations. - 在 2023 年，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的 17 个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币监管。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是17 jurisdictions，谓语是tightened，宾语是cryptocurrency regulations。including Hong Kong, the European Union, South Korea, Singapore, and the United States是一个介词短语作状语，修饰动词tightened，表示收紧加密货币监管的司法管辖区包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国。这个句子的意思是说，在 2023 年，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的 17 个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币监管。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在 completed 的动作或状态。      <p>原文例句：International organizations, including the G20, the Financial Action Task Force, the Financial Stability Board, International Monetary Fund, and the International Organization of Securities Commissions, all laid out global frameworks and policy recommendations for regulating cryptocurrencies.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在 完成的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和完成性。其结构是：have/has+过去分词。在这个例句中，laid out是lay的过去分词，表示制定，提出。这个句子的意思是说，国际组织，包括G20、金融行动特别工作组、金融稳定委员会、国际货币基金组织和国际证券委员会组织，都制定了全球框架和政策建议来监管加密货币。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, tightened cryptocurrency regulations</li>
<li>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures, according to TRM Labs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/70965061-8587-4332-9ba0-361c7665e6c9_67fe6e02.jpg" /><figcaption>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US tightened cryptocurrency regulations. Photo: Bloomberg </figcaption></figure><p>Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p><p>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the European Union, South Korea, Singapore, and the United States, tightened cryptocurrency regulations, according to a report published on Monday by blockchain analytics firm TRM Labs.</p><p>Those strengthening protection accounted for 80 per cent of the 21 jurisdictions studied by the firm, with the latter representing 70 per cent of global exposure to cryptocurrencies, said TRM Labs.</p><p>In 2022, the collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms, including the stablecoin TerraUSD and exchange FTX, led to a market rout that wiped out trillions of dollars in value.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" title="">Hong Kong to push retail access to spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a></h3><p>While 2023 began with the crypto ecosystem “reeling from the collapse of FTX”, the subsequent 12 months “saw an extraordinary boom in regulation across the globe”, the report says.</p><p>Among prominent moves, the European Union’s Markets in Crypto Assets Regulation came into force in June last year, and Hong Kong’s new licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges went live, the firm noted.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>Singapore, which the report described as “an early adopter of crypto regulation”, in November last year issued a set of rules aimed at curbing retail speculation in cryptocurrencies, and finalised its rules for stablecoins.</p><p>Meanwhile, South Korea and Australia also increased scrutiny of the cryptocurrency sector last year, the report says.</p><p>In the US, the Securities and Exchange Commission ramped up its enforcement actions against crypto firms in 2023, and the House Financial Services Committee also advanced bills last July aimed at creating a federal regulatory framework for the crypto market, with specific attention to stablecoins.</p><p>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures, according to TRM Labs.</p><p>It also noted that international organisations, including the G20, the Financial Action Task Force, the Financial Stability Board, International Monetary Fund, and the International Organization of Securities Commissions, all laid out global frameworks and policy recommendations for regulating cryptocurrencies.</p><p>Hong Kong, which in October 2022 announced a major initiative to support the virtual asset sector with the goal of becoming a global hub for such businesses, has implemented a mandatory licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges that allow them to accept retail investors.</p><p>Eleven companies have so far submitted applications for the licence in the city, including OKX, one of the largest exchanges by trading volume.</p><p>In December, the Asian financial hub also <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246415/hong-kong-regulators-propose-tougher-rules-sale-stablecoins-retail-investors?module=hard_link&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">proposed rules for stablecoin issuers</a>, which would ban companies without a licence from selling stablecoins to Hong Kong’s retail investors through regulated channels, or from actively marketing their tokens to the city.</p><p>The rules have been deemed as “extremely challenging” for stablecoin issuers, potentially deterring operators of the world’s biggest stablecoins, such as Tether and USDC, from entering the city, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246692/hong-kongs-proposed-stablecoin-rules-would-be-extremely-challenging-global-issuers-tether-and-usdc" target="_self" title="">experts told the Post last month</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Shanghai explainer on taxation of digital currency transaction drives speculation on potential easing of China’s crypto ban</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247683/shanghai-explainer-taxation-digital-currency-transaction-drives-speculation-potential-easing-chinas</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>An article by the Shanghai Municipal Tax Service sparked speculation that China might soften its stance on cryptocurrencies due to tax implications.</li>    <li>The article, since deleted, cited a 2008 statement from the State Taxation Administration that outlined taxation rules for virtual tokens in video games.</li>   <li>Legal experts say the article does not signal a policy change, as it merely explains existing income tax regulations for digital currency transactions.</li>    <li>China maintains its strict ban on cryptocurrencies, despite supporting Hong Kong's goal to be a virtual asset hub, including cryptocurrencies.</li>    <li>The global cryptocurrency market is showing signs of recovery, with Bitcoin prices surging over the past year.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>上海市税务局一篇关于中国数字货币交易征税的文章引发了当地加密货币爱好者的猜测，认为这可能意味着中国可能放松对加密货币的严厉禁止。</li>    <li>这篇文章已被删除，引用了国家税务局2008年的一份声明，其中概述了针对视频游戏中的虚拟代币的税收规则。</li>    <li>法律专家表示，这篇文章并不意味着政策改变，因为它只是解释了针对数字货币交易的现行所得税法规。</li>    <li>中国维持对加密货币的严格禁止，尽管它支持香港成为包括加密货币在内的虚拟资产中心的目标。</li>    <li>全球加密货币市场正在显现出复苏迹象，比特币价格在过去一年中飙升。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>legitimacy (n.) - /lɪˈdʒɪtɪməsi/ 合法性，正当性。    <p>原文例句：That prompted some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由legis（法律），-ti-（行为或状态）和-macy（状态或条件）组成，表示“合法性，正当性”。在这个例句中，它指的是加密货币的合法性或正当性，即承认加密货币是合法的或正当的。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>D​​raconian (adj.) - /drəʊˈkɔːniən/ 严厉的，残酷的。    <p>原文例句：China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Greek，由drakon（龙）和-ian（属于或与……有关的）组成，表示“龙的，严厉的，残酷的”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国对加密货币相关活动的严厉打击，即中国政府采取了严厉的措施来打击加密货币相关活动。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>spark speculation - 引起猜测。    <P>原文例句：The explainer became widely circulated on Sunday after some local crypto enthusiasts suggested that it acknowledged cryptocurrencies’ legitimacy. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由spark（点燃，激发）和speculation（猜测，推测）组成的，表示“引起猜测”。在这个例句中，它表示上海市税务局的这篇文章在当地加密货币爱好者中引发了猜测，即这篇文章承认了加密货币的合法性。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>virtual token - 虚拟代币。    <P>原文例句：The published article is not an official policy document, and the STA statement it cited concerns virtual tokens used in video games, according to Guo Zhihao, a partner at Beijing-based Yingke Law Firm, in an article he posted on WeChat on Sunday. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由virtual（虚拟的）和token（代币）组成的，表示“虚拟代币”。在这个例句中，它指的是在视频游戏中使用的虚拟代币，即一种数字资产，可以在游戏中使用。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. - 中国近年来加大了对所有与加密货币相关活动的打击力度，理由是存在金融稳定风险。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是China has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies，其中主语是China，谓语是has ramped up，宾语是its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies。citing financial stability risks是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示打击的原因或理由，即援引金融稳定风险。这个句子的意思是说，中国近年来加大了对所有与加密货币相关活动的打击力度，理由是存在金融稳定风险。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The wide attention received by the Shanghai tax service’s explainer reflects the lingering hope among Chinese crypto circles that the country’s rigid ban on cryptocurrencies would be reviewed amid Beijing’s drive to expand adoption of the digital yuan. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示中国加密圈对数字人民币推广的期待一直没有消退，即中国加密圈长期以来一直希望国家放松对加密货币的严格禁止。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The explainer became widely circulated on Sunday after some local crypto enthusiasts suggested that it acknowledged cryptocurrencies’ legitimacy</li>
<li>The Shanghai Municipal Tax Service has since deleted the article from its public WeChat account</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/dd38a0bb-3bd5-4e5f-aee4-d25bc7d830f4_a5b28db7.jpg" /><figcaption>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>An online article posted by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a> Municipal Tax Service, explaining levies imposed on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/digital-currencies" target="_self" title="">digital currency</a> transactions in China, has fanned speculation among local cryptocurrency enthusiasts that it signals a potential relaxation of the country’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3208481/chinese-economist-calls-review-rigid-cryptocurrency-ban-digital-yuan-fails-take?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">draconian ban on crypto operations</a>.</p><p>The explainer, “Common Misunderstandings Regarding Personal Income Tax on Business Income and Categorised Income”, became widely circulated on Sunday after it was published on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> by the Shanghai tax service on Thursday. It cited a 2008 statement by the State Taxation Administration (STA).</p><p>That prompted some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies. The Shanghai tax service subsequently deleted the explainer on Sunday from its public WeChat account.</p><p>The wide attention received by the Shanghai tax service’s explainer reflects the lingering hope among Chinese crypto circles that the country’s rigid ban on cryptocurrencies would be reviewed amid Beijing’s drive to expand adoption of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/china-digital-currency/news" target="_self" title="">digital yuan</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology last month announced plans to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" target="_self" title="">draft a national Web3 development plan</a> to suit the country’s needs, although it did not specifically mention cryptocurrencies.</p><p>Mainland legal experts, however, pointed out that the Shanghai tax service’s explainer does not suggest any potential change in the country’s cryptocurrency policy.</p><p>The published article is not an official policy document, and the STA statement it cited concerns virtual tokens used in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video games</a>, according to Guo Zhihao, a partner at Beijing-based Yingke Law Firm, in an article he posted on WeChat on Sunday.</p><p>The explainer had indicated that individuals who obtain virtual currencies from other players through online transactions and generate revenue by selling them at a higher price must pay income tax on such earnings. The Shanghai tax agency’s article detailed taxation in four scenarios, including loans obtained by individual investors from their investee companies and online monetary gifts.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3208481/chinese-economist-calls-review-rigid-cryptocurrency-ban-digital-yuan-fails-take" title="">Chinese economist calls for review of rigid crypto ban amid slow e-CNY adoption</a></h3><p>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. It maintains that stance even though it <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3216894/chinese-officials-pledge-support-hong-kongs-tech-web3-ambitions-digital-economy-summit?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">supports Hong Kong’s ambitions to become a major hub for virtual assets</a>, including cryptocurrencies.</p><p>While there is no official sign from Beijing about changing its position on cryptocurrencies, local crypto circles expect increased regulatory oversight on the taxation of virtual asset-related income on the mainland.</p><p>China has denied legal-tender status for cryptocurrencies, but has not opposed its attribution as property or commodity, according to an article published on Friday by Jin Jianzhi of the Shanghai Mankun Law Firm. The lawyer said the government can levy taxes on relevant transactions under the law.</p><p>The global cryptocurrency market, meanwhile, appears to be slowly recovering from a prolonged slump last year. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bitcoin" target="_self" title="">Bitcoin</a> prices gained more than 150 per cent from a year earlier on the back of expectations that the US Securities and Exchange Commission will soon approve <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" target="_self" title="">bitcoin exchange-traded funds</a>, which would make these virtual assets more attractive to mainstream investors.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: Chinese tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to premier consumer electronics show in Las Vegas</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese companies are making a strong comeback at the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) this year, with more than double the number of exhibitors compared to last year. Artificial Intelligence (AI) is expected to be the major trend at the show, with many companies showcasing their use of generative AI and machine learning.  Despite geopolitical tensions, major Chinese tech companies like ByteDance and Alibaba are exhibiting at CES, highlighting their commitment to overseas growth.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese tech giants return to CES in full force, showcasing AI and seeking overseas growth.</li>    <li>Theme: Chinese companies' strong presence at CES 2023 reflects their drive for global expansion and innovation.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of CES as a platform for Chinese companies to showcase their technological advancements and connect with global partners.</li>    <li>Main information: Increased participation of Chinese companies at CES 2023; Focus on AI and generative AI technologies; Challenges faced by Chinese companies due to geopolitical tensions; Importance of CES for small firms to connect with global industry players.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国公司今年大举回归消费电子展（CES），参展商数量较去年增加一倍以上。预计人工智能（AI）将成为今年展会的主要趋势，许多公司展示了其在生成式AI和机器学习方面的应用。尽管存在地缘政治紧张局势，字节跳动和阿里巴巴等中国主要科技公司仍在CES上展出，凸显了他们对海外增长的承诺。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国科技巨头强势回归CES，展示人工智能，寻求海外发展。</li>    <li>主题：中国企业在CES 2023上的强劲表现反映了他们对全球扩张和创新的推动。</li>    <li>观点：CES作为中国企业展示技术进步、与全球合作伙伴建立联系的平台的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国企业在CES 2023上参与度提高；专注于AI和生成式AI技术；中国企业因地缘政治紧张局势面临的挑战；CES对于小企业与全球行业参与者建立联系的重要性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>    <ul>    <li>touting (v.) - /ˈtaʊtɪŋ/ 推销，宣扬。    <p>原文例句：The company was touting its new product as the most advanced on the market. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle English，表示“使凸起，使鼓胀”，现在多用于比喻意义，意为“推销，宣扬”。在这个例句中，它指的是该公司正在宣扬其新产品是市场上最先进的产品。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>arms race (n.) - 武器竞赛，军备竞赛。    <p>原文例句：The two countries were engaged in a fierce arms race, each trying to outdo the other in terms of military strength. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由arm（武器）和race（比赛）构成的，表示“武器竞赛，军备竞赛”。在这个例句中，它指的是这两个国家正在进行激烈的军备竞赛，都试图在军事实力上胜过对方。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>showcase (v.) - /ˈʃəʊkeɪs/ 展示，展出。    <p>原文例句：The museum is showcasing a new exhibition of Impressionist paintings. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由show（展示）和case（箱子）组成的，表示“展示，展出”。在这个例句中，它指的是博物馆正在展示一批新的印象派绘画展品。</p></li>   </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Brian Comiskey, director of consumer programmes at the CTA, said after his opening remarks on Sunday afternoon: “You have big exhibitors coming back, really showcasing that this is a platform that really pushes for consumers and enterprises and maybe [can] combat some of these major challenges that we’re facing.” - 布莱恩·科米斯基，CTA消费者计划主管，在周日下午开幕致辞后表示：“你看到大展商们回归，他们真正展示出这是一个真正推动消费者和企业的平台，也许[能够]应对我们面临的一些主要挑战。”<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是You have big exhibitors coming back，其中主语是You，谓语是have big exhibitors coming back，宾语是big exhibitors；really showcasing that this is a platform that really pushes for consumers and enterprises and maybe [can] combat some of these major challenges that we’re facing是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰big exhibitors，表示这些大展商真的展示出这是一个真正推动消费者和企业的平台，也许[能够]应对我们面临的一些主要挑战。这个句子的意思是说，大展商们回来展示这是一个真正推动消费者和企业的平台，也许[能够]应对我们面临的一些主要挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2><ul>    <li>反意疑问句 - 用于确认或寻求对所陈述事实或询问的同意或反对。    <p>原文例句：CES lists 1,115 companies registered from China on its website, a 126 per cent increase over the 493 listed at the beginning of the 2023 show, doesn’t it?</p>    <p>语法讲解：反意疑问句是一种疑问句，通常在陈述句后面加上一个与陈述句中所表达的信息相反或不一致的疑问句，以寻求对所陈述事实或询问的同意或反对。反意疑问句通常用陈述句中最后一个助动词或情态动词的相反形式加not构成，再跟在陈述句后面，并用逗号隔开。在这个例句中，反意疑问句是doesn’t it，表示对陈述句CES lists 1,115 companies registered from China on its website, a 126 per cent increase over the 493 listed at the beginning of the 2023 show的确认或寻求同意。</p></li>  </ul> <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达说话者对客观事实的看法、态度或愿望。    <p>原文例句：The company was touting its new product as if it were the most advanced on the market. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种语气，用于表达说话者对客观事实的看法、态度或愿望。虚拟语气通常用would、should、could、might、may等情态动词或助动词加动词原形构成。在这个例句中，虚拟语气用的是were，表示该公司的态度，即他们想宣扬他们的新产品是市场上最先进的产品。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>AI is the major trend this year in the wake of ChatGPT, with many companies touting how they are integrating the tech into their products</li>
<li>The return of Chinese tech giants comes even as geopolitical tensions have barely budged from where they were last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/2545b743-77c1-45e1-83aa-b5a50e2cd69e_8fe19122.jpg" /><figcaption>Attendees arrive at the CES Unveiled event before the start of the CES tech show, January 7, 2024, in Las Vegas. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese companies have returned to Las Vegas for CES in full force this year, with more than double the number of exhibitors compared with last year, including big names like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance">ByteDance</a> and Alibaba.com, as companies try to shake off Covid-era blues with overseas growth.</p><p>CES lists 1,115 companies registered from China on its website, a 126 per cent increase over the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial">493 listed</a> at the beginning of the 2023 show. That does not include many of the biggest names on the list, which joined using international addresses.</p><p>ByteDance and its subsidiary <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a>, along with big hardware brands from last year like TCL and Lenovo are registered under their US offices. Even <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, owner of the South China Morning Post, has a presence through its subsidiary Alibaba.com Singapore.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247219/tiktok-eyes-us175-billion-shopping-business-amazons-turf" title="">TikTok eyes US$17.5 billion shopping business on Amazon’s turf</a></h3><p>“You have big exhibitors coming back, really showcasing that this is a platform that really pushes for consumers and enterprises and maybe [can] combat some of these major challenges that we’re facing,” Brian Comiskey, director of consumer programmes at the CTA, said after his opening remarks on Sunday afternoon.</p><p>This marks a stark reversal from 2023, when China had just started to reopen its borders but restrictions did not fall fast enough for many companies to make it to the show in the first week of January.</p><p>“Some of the largest Chinese companies that have signed up for participation this year … will all have a large presence at the show,” John Kelley, vice-president and show director for CES at the Consumer Technology Association (CTA), told the Post in an interview on November 29. “But where we’re really seeing growth on the Chinese side is smaller companies.”</p><p>Kelley said the CTA was anticipating numbers to reach pre-Covid levels, and it looks like the show has pulled it off. The number of Chinese companies is more than the 1,000 that state-run tabloid Global Times reported for the 2020 show. CTA said the show has attracted around 4,000 exhibitors, although numbers are not final yet. Kelley said CES expects to see 130,000 attendees.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence">Artificial intelligence (AI)</a> is expected to be the major trend at the show this year, playing an even larger role since ChatGPT ignited a generative AI arms race over the past year. Smart homes, green tech and electric vehicles were other areas highlighted during the show’s opening remarks to the media.</p><p>Alibaba was highlighted as one of the exhibitors using machine learning platforms to “power e-commerce”.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1306" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/d1856897-2d66-43bf-b0ad-271970378ed9_da47af5a.jpg" title="Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even much smaller companies are touting their use of AI. Govee, a smart lighting maker from Shenzhen, is advertising the use of generative AI to help people create specific moods, like asking for a backdrop that is evocative of the Hong Kong skyline or Barbie Dreamhouse.</p><p>Some fabless chip design firms are also exhibiting, such as Fuzhou-based mobile chip maker Rockchip and Wuhan-based autonomous driving chip maker Black Sesame, which contracts with electric car companies Geely and BYD. Black Sesame chips are manufactured by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a>, it said.</p><p>Xpeng is among the major electric vehicle makers at the show, where it will be demonstrating its new “flying car”, the AeroHT.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1067" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/b8c16129-faf2-4eac-924a-4824d9f25c14_5368aac5.jpg" title="XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>The return of Chinese tech giants comes even as geopolitical tensions have barely budged from where they were last year. US President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping may have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3241692/joe-biden-xi-jinping-meet-person-first-time-year-apec-sidelines" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3241692/joe-biden-xi-jinping-meet-person-first-time-year-apec-sidelines">met in November</a>, but there have been no major policy shifts around escalating restrictions on technology such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors">semiconductors</a> and AI.</p><p>TikTok and its Beijing-based owner ByteDance have been under intense political scrutiny in Washington over data privacy and national security concerns. This may not have deterred TikTok from showing up to the largest consumer electronics shows in its largest market.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial" title="">Number of Chinese tech firms at CES 2023 less than half of pre-pandemic level</a></h3><p>Representatives from the company will join two panels at the show to discuss sports and entertainment. Beyond entertainment, though, ByteDance makes much of its money through advertising and has been trying to grow its e-commerce business.</p><p>Other Chinese companies cannot exhibit at the show even if they want to because they have been listed on Washington’s Entity List. This includes the world’s largest drone maker DJI and a number of semiconductor companies.</p><p>“From a show management perspective, we welcome participation from every company,” CTA’s Kelley said. “As a US-based trade association, we cannot allow participation if they are on some sort of Entity List. That’s really the only place where we will not allow participation.”</p><p>Still, CES may be more important for the many small firms that make up the bulk of the show’s exhibition floor. It remains the premier event of its kind.</p><p>“We like to make the case that the four days you spend in Las Vegas is some of the most efficient use of your time in the sense that you don’t have to necessarily travel the world to meet with individual business partners on six different continents,” said Kelley. “Instead, you can come to Las Vegas and meet everybody that you need to meet from the global technology industry over the course of a week.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung set for smallest profit drop in 6 quarters on chip rebound</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247610/samsung-set-smallest-profit-drop-6-quarters-chip-rebound</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Global chip production company Samsung is anticipating a 14% drop in earnings for the fourth quarter of 2022. However, a rebound in prices for semiconductor chips is expected to lessen losses and drive the industry towards recovery. Samsung's chip division may show reduced quarterly losses, indicating a potential path towards profitability.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung's earnings projection reflects the fluctuating nature of the chip industry.</li>    <li>Theme: The impact of fluctuating chip prices and market dynamics on Samsung's financial performance.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Analysts' estimations of Samsung's financial results and the semiconductor industry's outlook.</li>    <li>Main information: Anticipated 14% decrease in fourth-quarter profits, improvement in chip division performance, and signs of recovery in memory chip prices.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  全球芯片制造公司三星预计 2022 年第四季度的收益将下降 14%。然而，半导体芯片价格的反弹预计将减少亏损并推动行业走向复苏。三星的芯片部门可能出现季度亏损减少，这表明芯片部门有望实现盈利。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星的盈利预测反映了芯片行业波动的本质。</li>    <li>主题：芯片价格和市场动态波动对三星财务业绩的影响。</li>    <li>观点：分析师对三星财务业绩和半导体行业前景的估计。</li>    <li>主要信息：预计第四季度利润下降 14%，芯片部门业绩改善以及存储芯片价格复苏迹象。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>estimate (v.) - /ˈestɪmeɪt/ 估计，预测。    <p>原文例句：That would compare with an operating profit of 4.31 trillion won in the December quarter of the previous year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：estimate 是一个动词，意为“估计，预测”，由 es-（表示“向外”）和 stem（表示“站立、固定”）组成，其原意为“站出来、确定、设定”。在这个句子中，它表示三星第四季度的营业利润预计将与去年12月季度的营业利润进行比较。</p></li>    <li>rebound (n.) - /rɪˈbaʊnd/ 回弹，反弹。    <p>原文例句：Rebounding prices for DRAM chips, used in various tech devices, and NAND flash chips, used to store data, signaled an industry-wide recovery. </p>    <p>例句讲解：rebound 是一个名词，意为“回弹，反弹”，由 re-（表示“重新”）和 bound（表示“跳跃，弹跳”）组成，其原意为“重新跳起，重新弹起”。在这个句子中，它表示 DRAM 芯片和 NAND 闪存芯片的价格反弹，这表明了整个行业正在复苏。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>set of results - 结果集，一组结果。    <p>原文例句：A solid set of results would justify Samsung’s sharp stock market run-up in the fourth quarter. </p>    <p>例句讲解：set of results 是一个词组，意为“结果集，一组结果”。在这个句子中，它表示一系列的业绩结果。</p></li>    <li>market capitalisation - 市值，市场资本。    <p>原文例句：That has made it Asia’s second-most valuable listed company after chip foundry rival Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co, with a market capitalisation of about US$390 billion. </p>    <p>例句讲解：market capitalisation 是一个词组，意为“市值，市场资本”。在这个句子中，它表示公司的市值。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung’s chip division – traditionally its biggest earner – likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts. - 三星的芯片部门——传统上是其最大的收入来源——根据八份预测计算，可能将季度亏损减少到约 1.2 万亿韩元。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Samsung's chip division，谓语是likely reduced，宾语是its quarterly loss。likely reduced是一个过去式动词，表示“可能减少”。its quarterly loss是一个名词短语，作宾语，表示“其季度亏损”。around 1.2 trillion won是一个介词短语，作地点状语，表示“约 1.2 万亿韩元”。这个句子的意思是说，三星的芯片部门——传统上是其最大的收入来源——根据八份预测计算，可能将季度亏损减少到约 1.2 万亿韩元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词 - 可以充当形容词或名词的非限定性动词形式。    <p>原文例句：Rebounding prices for DRAM chips, used in various tech devices, and NAND flash chips, used to store data, signaled an industry-wide recovery. </p>    <p>语法讲解：分词是一种非限定性动词形式，可以充当形容词或名词。在这个句子中，used in various tech devices 和 used to store data 都是分词短语，分別作定语，修饰DRAM chips 和 NAND flash chips。这两个分词短语表示了 DRAM 芯片和 NAND 闪存芯片的用途，即 DRAM 芯片用于各种技术设备，而 NAND 闪存芯片用于存储数据。</p></li>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达假设、愿望、建议或推测的情态动词。    <p>原文例句：That would compare with an operating profit of 4.31 trillion won in the December quarter of the previous year. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种情态动词，用于表达假设、愿望、建议或推测。在这个句子中，would compare with 是虚拟语气的过去式，表示“将与……进行比较”。这个虚拟语气表示了三星第四季度的营业利润将与去年 12 月季度的营业利润进行比较。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The world’s biggest maker of memory chips, smartphones and televisions is expected to show a 14 per cent fall in fourth-quarter profit</li>
<li>Samsung’s chip division likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts</li>
</ul><p>Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters, analysts estimate, as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division.</p><p>The world’s biggest maker of memory chips, smartphones and televisions is expected to show a 14 per cent fall in fourth-quarter profit when it announces preliminary earnings on Tuesday.</p><p>Operating profit likely fell to 3.7 trillion won (US$2.82 billion) in the October-December quarter, according to the average of an LSEG SmartEstimate from 30 analysts, weighted toward those who are more consistently accurate.</p><p>That would compare with an operating profit of 4.31 trillion won in the December quarter of the previous year. Samsung last reported a year-on-year quarterly profit increase for the second quarter of 2022.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/article/3245933/us-gather-chips-supply-chain-intelligence-boost-national-security" title="">US to gather chip supply chain intelligence to boost national security</a></h3><p>A solid set of results would justify Samsung’s sharp stock market run-up in the fourth quarter, which has made it Asia’s second-most valuable listed company after chip foundry rival Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co, with a market capitalisation of about US$390 billion.</p><p>Samsung’s chip division – traditionally its biggest earner – likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts. Analysts said its dynamic random access memory (DRAM) chips business returned to a profit.</p><p>Samsung had reported chip division losses of 4.36 trillion won and 3.75 trillion won in the second and third quarters, respectively, as a semiconductor glut from slow demand for gadgets driven by inflation pressures on consumers caused the worst industry downturn in decades.</p><p>However, prices of DRAM chips – used in various tech devices – and NAND flash chips – used to store data – rebounded in the December quarter, including for older chips, in a sign of an industry-wide recovery expected this year.</p><p>Mobile DRAM chip prices rose an estimated 18 to 23 per cent during the fourth quarter, while mobile NAND flash chip prices rose 10 to 15 per cent, according to data provider TrendForce.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/8f2d3cfa-7d39-4dd6-b8f2-d7fda417159f_34f54c2a.jpg" title="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>While Samsung has repeatedly cut production since the first half of 2023 to cope with the downturn, analysts and sources said Samsung took in more supply of silicon wafers, the building blocks for semiconductors, in the fourth quarter, signalling it is gearing up to increase DRAM chip production.</p><p>Samsung was also more aggressive in selling memory chips than competitors, such as SK Hynix, in the fourth quarter in a bid to lower inventory, analysts said.</p><p>Rival Micron Technology forecast a quarterly revenue above market estimates last month, in a sign of a recovery in the memory chip market in 2024.</p><p>Samsung’s mobile business likely saw an operating profit of around 2.5 trillion won, according to an average of forecasts from eight analysts, as shipments of its two flagship foldable models were estimated to have fallen about 1 million units each versus the third quarter.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Podcasts gain popularity in China as one in five internet users tuned in last year, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247572/podcasts-gain-popularity-china-one-five-internet-users-tuned-last-year-says-report</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese podcasts have been gaining popularity among young professionals, attracting advertisers and paid subscribers. Despite censorship restrictions, podcasts cover a wide range of topics, from health and lifestyle to frontier technology.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Podcasts in China have become popular, attracting young professionals and advertisements from global brands.</li>    <li>Theme: The rise of Chinese podcasts and their impact on the media landscape.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The potential of podcasts as a monetizable platform for content creators and advertisers; the influence of censorship on podcast content in China.</li>    <li>Main information: Statistics on podcast listeners and revenue; demographics of podcast listeners; popular podcast genres; the role of generative AI in podcast creation.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国播客在年轻专业人士中越来越受欢迎，吸引了广告商和付费订阅者。尽管存在审查限制，但播客涵盖了广泛的主题，从健康和生活方式到前沿技术。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国的播客越来越受欢迎，吸引了年轻的专业人士和来自全球品牌广告。</li>    <li>主题：中国播客的兴起及其对媒体格局的影响。</li>    <li>观点：播客作为内容创作者和广告商可获利平台的潜力；审查制度对中国播客内容的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：播客听众和收入统计数据；播客听众的人口统计情况；热门播客类型；生成式人工智能在播客创作中的作用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>niche (n.) - /niːʃ/ 利基，壁龛，专门领域。    <p>原文例句：One in five internet users in China listened to a podcast last year, as the once niche sector gained popularity in 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“niche”意思是“壁龛”、“专门领域”，特指某个行业或领域中很小的部分或市场。在这个例子中，它指的是播客行业，该行业曾经是小众行业，但在2023年变得越来越受欢迎。</p></li>    <li>tier (n.) - /tɪər/ 层，阶层，等级。    <p>原文例句：The audience for its podcasts skewed towards young Chinese professionals working in the country’s higher-tier cities, Ximalaya’s research showed. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“tier”意思是“层”、“阶层”、“等级”，表示不同级别或层次的划分。在这里，它指的是中国城市的分级，如一线城市、二线城市等。据喜马拉雅的研究表明，其播客听众主要集中在年轻的中国专业人士，他们分布在中国一二线城市。</p></li>    <li>monetisation (n.) - /ˌmʌnɪtaɪˈzeɪʃən/ 货币化，商业化。    <p>原文例句：Young professionals also helped Chinese podcasts attract advertisements from global brands, from food and beverage giant Coca-Cola to luxury US carmaker Cadillac, providing an additional monetisation channel for the industry. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“monetisation”意思是“货币化”、“商业化”，是指将产品或服务转换为可产生经济效益的形式。在这个例子中，它指的是年轻的专业人士帮助中国播客从全球品牌吸引广告，例如食品饮料巨头可口可乐和美国豪华汽车制造商凯迪拉克，这为播客行业提供了一个额外的商业化渠道。</p></li>    <li>commutes (n.) - /kəˈmjuːts/ 通勤。    <p>原文例句：Chinese users primarily tuned into podcasts during their daily commutes, with health and lifestyle, Chinese history, global politics, frontier technology, business and entertainment, as well as fantasy and thriller stories among the most popular genres on the Ximalaya platform. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“commutes”意思是“通勤”，是指每天上下班或上学放学的交通过程。在这里，它指的是中国用户主要在日常通勤期间收听播客，而健康和生活方式、中国历史、全球政治、前沿技术、商业和娱乐以及奇幻和惊悚故事是喜马拉雅平台上最受欢迎的播客类型。</p></li>  </ul>   </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>gain popularity - 变得流行，受欢迎。    <p>原文例句：One in five internet users in China listened to a podcast last year, as the once niche sector gained popularity in 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“gain popularity”意思是“变得流行”、“受欢迎”，表示某事物或现象逐渐受到人们的喜爱和欢迎。在这个例子中，它指的是中国有五分之一的互联网用户在2023年收听播客，随着播客行业的兴起，播客变得越来越受欢迎。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts hosted by Ximalaya last year, across 31 genres of programmes, according to research published on Friday by the Chinese podcast service provider. - 根据中国播客服务提供商上周五发布的研究报告，去年超过 2.2 亿中国网民在喜马拉雅收听了 31 类播客节目。    <p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的复杂句，主语是 More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users，谓语是tuned into podcasts hosted by Ximalaya last year，宾语是 31 genres of programmes。其中，More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users是一个介词短语，修饰主语，表示超过 2.2 亿中国网民。across 31 genres of programmes是一个介词短语，修饰谓语，表示 31 类播客节目。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Young professionals also helped Chinese podcasts attract advertisements from global brands, from food and beverage giant Coca-Cola to luxury US carmaker Cadillac, providing an additional monetisation channel for the industry. </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态由 have/has 和过去分词构成，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例子中，它表示年轻的专业人士帮助中国播客从全球品牌吸引了广告，从食品饮料巨头可口可乐到美国豪华汽车制造商凯迪拉克，为该行业提供了一个额外的商业化渠道。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts on Ximalaya’s platform last year, across 31 genres</li>
<li>Young professionals helped Chinese podcasts attract ads from global brands such as drinks giant Coca-Cola and luxury carmaker Cadillac</li>
</ul><p>One in five internet users in China listened to a podcast last year, as the once niche sector gained popularity in 2023, according to a recently published research.</p><p>More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts hosted by Ximalaya last year, across 31 genres of programmes, according to research published on Friday by the Chinese podcast service provider.</p><p>The audience for its podcasts skewed towards young Chinese professionals working in the country’s higher-tier cities, Ximalaya’s research showed.</p><p>The user group aged between 24 and 40 years represented more than 60 per cent of podcast listeners in China, while those from tier-one and tier-two cities accounted for more than 65 per cent of the total audience.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after" title="">China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech must end, party paper says</a></h3><p>Consumers in China are also increasingly more inclined to pay for quality podcast content, with more than half signing up for premium content. More than 22,000 podcast hosts earned a combined total of 70 million yuan (US$9.8 million) on Ximalaya last year, the company revealed in its research.</p><p>Young professionals also helped Chinese podcasts attract advertisements from global brands, from food and beverage giant Coca-Cola to luxury US carmaker Cadillac, providing an additional monetisation channel for the industry, according to a separate report by market consultancy iResearch.</p><p>Chinese users primarily tuned into podcasts during their daily commutes, with health and lifestyle, Chinese history, global politics, frontier technology, business and entertainment, as well as fantasy and thriller stories among the most popular genres on the Ximalaya platform.</p><p>Chinese podcast preferences were partially the result of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3244838/chinas-online-censors-target-short-videos-artificial-intelligence-and-pessimism-latest-crackdown" target="_self" title="">the country’s strict censorship of online content.</a> General news and politics, two of the most popular genres among podcast listeners in Western countries, were missing from the list in China, according to Ethan Cramer-Flood, a researcher at market consultancy Insider Intelligence.</p><p>“In the West, maybe news and politics rank relatively highly, whereas in China it’s just nowhere to be found because the censorship regime is so strict there,” Flood said in an online discussion last November. “So it’s [topics] like lifestyle, fashion, pet care … sports [that] are all at the top of the list because [they are] nothing remotely controversial.”</p><p>Still, Chinese podcasts are flourishing despite the country’s online content crackdown. In 2023, Ximalaya’s platform hosted 5.2 million more podcast episodes than the year before.</p><p>The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence (AI), which increases efficiency and helps with content creation, thanks to a suite of AI-powered audio tools Ximalaya launched last year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
