<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Samsung to kick off year of AI phones with new launch this month</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247104/samsung-kick-year-ai-phones-new-launch-month</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Samsung plans to launch its new flagship smartphone, the Galaxy S24, on January 17, focusing on artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities to boost sales. The rise of generative AI, such as OpenAI's ChatGPT and Dall-E, has driven the tech industry's interest in integrating AI into mobile devices. Samsung and Qualcomm are seen as leaders in this field, with Counterpoint Research estimating over a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI to be shipped by 2027.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung's focus on AI for the Galaxy S24 and the increasing integration of generative AI into smartphones.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's strategic move to leverage AI in its smartphones to drive sales and innovation.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of AI integration into smartphones, with Samsung and Qualcomm positioned as frontrunners.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's Galaxy S24 launch, market estimates for smartphones with generative AI, and the role of OpenAI's tools in shaping the generative AI trend.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  三星计划于1月17日在加利福尼亚州圣何塞发布其新款旗舰智能手机Galaxy S24，重点关注人工智能（AI）功能以提振销售。随着生成式AI的兴起，例如OpenAI的ChatGPT和Dall-E，科技行业对将AI集成到移动设备中的兴趣日益浓厚。三星和高通被视为该领域的领导者，Counterpoint Research估计到2027年将有超过10亿部具有生成式AI的智能手机出货。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星在Galaxy S24中关注人工智能以及将生成式人工智能集成到智能手机中。</li>    <li>主题：三星在智能手机中利用人工智能以推动销售和创新的战略举措。</li>    <li>观点：将人工智能集成到智能手机中的重要性，三星和高通被定位为领跑者。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星Galaxy S24发布会，智能手机生成式人工智能市场估计，以及OpenAI工具在塑造生成式人工智能趋势中的作用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rely on (v.) - /rɪˈlaɪ ɑːn/ 依赖，信赖。    <p>原文例句：In past years, Samsung and fellow mobile makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语意思是“依靠，依赖”。在这个例句中，三星和其他手机制造商依靠相机技术和柔性显示屏的改进在市场上脱颖而出。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>flagship (n.) - /ˈflæɡʃɪp/ 旗舰，旗舰店。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device on January 17 in San Jose, California</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词意思是“旗舰，旗舰店”。在这个例句中，三星电子宣布计划于1月17日在加利福尼亚州圣何塞发布其下一款旗舰设备。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>livestream (v.) - /ˈlaɪvˌstriːm/ 直播。    <p>原文例句：The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词意思是“直播”。在这个例句中，“Galaxy AI is coming”的宣传片承诺“Galaxy AI即将到来”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>integrate (v.) - /ˈɪntrəɡreɪt/ 整合，合并。    <p>原文例句：The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词意思是“整合，合并”。在这个例句中，“集成技术的下个阶段是将其整合到设备中”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>built-in (adj.) - /ˈbɪlt ɪn/ 内置的，内置的。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语意思是“内置的，内置的”。在这个例句中，预计到2027年底之前，将会有超过10亿部具有生成式AI功能的智能手机出货。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>current product offerings - 当前产品产品    <p>原文例句：“Samsung and Qualcomm are immediate leaders as current product offerings and capabilities position them as first movers,”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组意思是“当前产品产品”。在这个例句中，“三星和高通被认为是现阶段的领导者，因为当前的产品产品和功能使他们能够成为先驱。”</p></li>   </ul>  <ul>    <li>generative AI - 生成式人工智能    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组意思是“生成式人工智能”。在这个例句中，预计到2027年底之前，将会有超过10亿部具有生成式AI功能的智能手机出货。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device on January 17 in San Jose, California – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – with a livestreamed event. - 三星电子宣布计划于1月17日在加利福尼亚州圣何塞发布其下一款旗舰设备（可能被称为Galaxy S24），并通过网络直播活动进行。</li>    <p>句子分析：这个句子是复杂长句，包含一个主句和两个分句。主句是Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device on January 17 in San Jose, California，其中主语是Samsung Electronics，谓语是announced，宾语是it plans to launch its next flagship device on January 17 in San Jose, California。第一个分句是likely to be known as the Galaxy S24，其中likely to be known as是现在分词短语作状语，修饰主语it，表示“可能被称为Galaxy S24”。第二个分句是with a livestreamed event，其中with a livestreamed event是介词短语作状语，修饰整个句子，表示“举办网络直播活动”。这个句子的意思是，三星电子宣布计划于1月17日在加利福尼亚州圣何塞发布其下一款旗舰设备（可能被称为Galaxy S24），并以网络直播活动的方式进行。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态发生的时间、方式、原因或目的。    <p>原文例句：likely to be known as the Galaxy S24</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在分词短语，作状语，修饰主语it，表示“可能被称为Galaxy S24”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>介词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态发生的时间、地点、方式、原因或目的。    <p>原文例句：with a livestreamed event</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个介词短语，作状语，修饰整个句子，表示“举办网络直播活动”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In past years, Samsung and fellow mobile makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out</li>
<li>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/7ec45056-5dac-41c9-9c8d-90ebe51417b8_a1a0985b.jpg" /><figcaption>Samsung employees show models of the Galaxy S23 Fan Edition during its rollout in Seoul, South Korea, December 8, 2023. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>The world’s most prolific smartphone maker is leaning into artificial intelligence as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.</p><p>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device on January 17 in San Jose, California – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – with a livestreamed event. The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming.” In past years, Samsung and fellow mobile makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out, but 2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246310/huawei-launches-new-nova-smartphones-without-giving-details-chip-attention-remains-fixed-its" title="">Huawei launches new Nova smartphones without giving details on chip</a></h3><p>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates. OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Dall-E tools, which generate text or visual responses to users’ queries, are at the forefront of a generative-AI wave that is swept across the tech industry – and helped make Nvidia a trillion-dollar company by providing the key AI-training accelerators. The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices, as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year.</p><p>“Samsung and Qualcomm are immediate leaders as current product offerings and capabilities position them as first movers,” the Counterpoint researchers wrote in December. “Similar to what it did with foldables, Samsung is likely to capture almost 50 per cent share for the next two years, followed by key Chinese OEMs like Xiaomi, Vivo, Honor and Oppo.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
