<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Nvidia expands its reach in China’s electric vehicle sector</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  US chip maker Nvidia's expansion in China; automobile manufacturers' use of Nvidia's automated driving technology; challenges in meeting Chinese demands and complying with US export controls.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Amidst US export restrictions, Nvidia's expansion in China through partnerships with automotive manufacturers.</li>    <li>Theme: Navigating the complexities of international trade and technology in the automotive industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The strategic importance of China's rising EV industry for global semiconductor manufacturers; the impact of geopolitical tensions on technology partnerships.</li>    <li>Main information: Four Chinese brands using Nvidia's DRIVE technology for automated driving; the growing demand for advanced in-vehicle technology in China; challenges in meeting Chinese demand for powerful chips under US export controls.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  美国芯片制造商英伟达在中国扩张；汽车制造商使用英伟达的自动驾驶技术；满足中国需求和遵守美国出口管制的挑战。  <ul>    <li>摘要：在受到美国出口限制的情况下，英伟达通过与汽车制造商的合作在中国扩张。</li>    <li>主题：在汽车行业中驾驭国际贸易和技术的复杂性。</li>    <li>观点：中国崛起的电动汽车产业对全球半导体制造商的战略重要性；地缘政治紧张局势对技术合作伙伴关系的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：四家中国品牌使用英伟达的DRIVE技术进行自动驾驶；中国对先进车载技术的日益增长的需求；在美国出口管制下满足中国对强大芯片需求的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>underscoring (v.) - /ˌʌndəˈskɔːrɪŋ/ 强调，突出。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia said four Chinese electric vehicle brands will use its technology as the brains for automated driving systems, underscoring the US chip maker's determination to expand in China despite Washington's tighter export rules. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于under（在……之下）和score（记分），表示“强调，突出”。在这个例句中，underscoring the US chip maker's determination to expand in China despite Washington's tighter export rules表示强调了这家美国芯片制造商决心在中国扩张，尽管华盛顿已经收紧了出口管制。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>underscoring (v.) - /ˈkɔːmplɑːɪns/ 合规，遵守。    <p>原文例句：Other chipmakers such as Qualcomm and Intel have also reported similar concerns, underscoring the complex challenges of navigating international trade and technology as geopolitical tensions mount. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由com-（一起）和placere（使高兴）组成，表示“使高兴，使满意”。在这个例句中，it is working with advertising giant WPP, Lotus and six other companies to develop more advanced online shopping tools.表示英伟达正在与广告巨头WPP、莲花汽车和其他六家公司合作，开发更高级的在线购物工具。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in-vehicle infotainment displays - 车载信息娱乐显示屏。    <p>原文例句：Chinese carmakers are racing each other to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays and automated driving functions. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由in-vehicle（车载的），infotainment（信息娱乐）和displays（显示屏）组成，表示“车载信息娱乐显示屏”。在这个例句中，it refers to infotainment systems that provide entertainment and information to car occupants, such as audio systems, GPS navigation, and internet connectivity.表示中国汽车制造商正在竞相推出更先进的车载信息娱乐显示屏和自动驾驶功能。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>three dimensional graphics - 三维图形。    <p>原文例句：Danny Shapiro, Nvidia's vice-president for automotive, said, "Using Nvidia technology, carmakers and dealers hope to create online shopping sites with three dimensional graphics and more lifelike graphics." </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由three dimensional（三维的）和graphics（图形）组成，表示“三维图形”。在这个例句中，it refers to computer-generated images that appear to have three dimensions, such as height, width, and depth. Danny Shapiro, Nvidia's vice-president for automotive, said, "Using Nvidia technology, carmakers and dealers hope to create online shopping sites with three dimensional graphics and more lifelike graphics."表示丹尼·夏皮罗，英伟达汽车部门副总裁说，“使用英伟达技术，汽车制造商和经销商希望创建具有三维图形和更逼真的图形的在线购物网站”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia said four Chinese electric vehicle brands will use its technology as the brains for automated driving systems. - 英伟达表示，四家中国电动汽车品牌将使用其技术作为自动驾驶系统的核心。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是Nvidia said，其中主语是Nvidia，谓语是said，宾语是four Chinese electric vehicle brands will use its technology as the brains for automated driving systems。这个句子的意思是说，英伟达表示四家中国电动汽车品牌将使用其技术作为自动驾驶系统的核心。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Chinese carmakers are racing each other to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays and automated driving functions. - 中国汽车制造商正在竞相推出更先进的车载信息娱乐显示屏和自动驾驶功能。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Chinese carmakers are racing each other，其中主语是Chinese carmakers，谓语是are racing each other。第一个并列从句是to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays，其中主语是to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays，谓语是launch。第二个并列从句是and automated driving functions，其中主语是automated driving functions，谓语是automated。这个句子的意思是说，中国汽车制造商正在竞相推出更先进的车载信息娱乐显示屏和自动驾驶功能。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句 - 用以增强句子的语气，强调句子的重要成分。    <p>原文例句：Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday at the CES technology conference in Las Vegas. </p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句的结构是：It is/was + 被强调部分 + that/who + 其他部分。在这个例句中，被强调的部分是Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi，其他部分是will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving。这个句子的意思是说，是李想汽车、长城汽车、极氪以及小米汽车将使用英伟达的DRIVE技术来为自动驾驶提供动力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用以表示虚拟、假设、期望、意愿等。    <p>原文例句：Danny Shapiro, Nvidia's vice-president for automotive, said, "Using Nvidia technology, carmakers and dealers hope to create online shopping sites with three dimensional graphics and more lifelike graphics." </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气的结构是：should/could/would/might + 其他部分。在这个例句中，虚拟语气是hope to create，其中hope是虚拟语气助词，to create是虚拟语气的主语+谓语，其他部分是online shopping sites with three dimensional graphics and more lifelike graphics。这个句子的意思是说，丹尼·夏皮罗，英伟达汽车部门副总裁说，“使用英伟达技术，汽车制造商和经销商希望创建具有三维图形和更逼真的图形的在线购物网站”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div>  <ul><li>Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday</li>
<li>Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips, while complying with US controls on semiconductor exports to China</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/ca10cd80-a417-41ba-821c-f909879abb0a_5739d5f7.jpg" /><figcaption>A Nvidia logo at the company’s headquarters in Taipei, Taiwan. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia said four Chinese electric vehicle brands will use its technology as the brains for automated driving systems, underscoring the US chip maker’s determination to expand in China despite Washington’s tighter export rules.</p><p>Chinese carmakers Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Chinese telecommunications company Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday at the CES technology conference in Las Vegas.</p><p>China’s rising EV brands are a key market for Nvidia’s automotive technology business. Chinese carmakers are racing each other to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays and automated driving functions. That has created a growth opportunity for Nvidia, Intel, Qualcomm and other semiconductor manufacturers.</p><p>Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>In related CES announcements, Nvidia said it is working with advertising giant WPP, Lotus and six other companies to develop more advanced online shopping tools. Using Nvidia technology, carmakers and dealers hope to create online shopping sites with three dimensional graphics and more lifelike graphics, said Danny Shapiro, Nvidia’s vice-president for automotive.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tencent’s Pony Ma says 2021 WeChat photo privacy controversy was ‘misunderstanding’ that was fixed with update</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247704/tencents-pony-ma-says-2021-wechat-photo-privacy-controversy-was-misunderstanding-was-fixed-update</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  WeChat's founder Pony Ma described the 2021 privacy issue, where the app was found accessing user photo galleries without permission, as a "misunderstanding". Ma attributed it to "cache acceleration of images" and said the matter was resolved by updating the operating system. WeChat's privacy issue had sparked concerns, leading to stricter data protection laws in China.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Pony Ma clarifies the WeChat photo privacy issue as a misunderstanding due to cache acceleration.</li>    <li>Theme: Addressing the privacy concerns surrounding WeChat's unauthorized access to user photo galleries.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The incident was a technical issue, not an intentional violation of privacy; the importance of data protection laws.</li>    <li>Main information: Ma's explanation of the issue as cache acceleration; the implementation of new laws in China to regulate data handling.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  微信创始人马化腾将 2021 年的隐私问题（当时发现该应用程序在未经允许的情况下访问用户照片库）描述为“误解”。马化腾将其归因于“图片缓存加速”，并表示通过更新操作系统来解决该问题。微信的隐私问题引发了担忧，导致中国收紧了数据保护法。  <ul>    <li>摘要：马化腾澄清微信照片隐私问题是由于缓存加速造成的误解。</li>    <li>主题：解决围绕微信未经授权访问用户照片库的隐私问题。</li>    <li>观点：该事件是一个技术问题，而不是故意侵犯隐私行为；保护数据法律的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：马化腾对该问题的解释是缓存加速；中国实施新法律以规范数据处理。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>spark (v.) - /spɑːrk/ 引发，点燃。    <p>原文例句：The 2021 WeChat photo issue sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time despite reassurances that the glitch had been fixed. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语，由spercan（闪耀）转变而来，意为“产生或引发，点燃”。在这个例句中，它指的是2021年的微信照片问题引发了广泛的隐私担忧。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>access (n.) - /ˈæk.ses/ 访问权，通道。    <p>原文例句：WeChat, China’s largest social media app with 1.3 billion monthly active users (MAUs), was frequently accessing user photo galleries even when not in use, which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语，由acces（可以接近的东西）转变而来，意为“进入或接近某物的权利或机会，通道”。在这个例句中，它指的是微信这款中国最大的社交媒体应用程序，拥有13亿月活跃用户，它经常访问用户的照片库，即使在不使用的情况下，这也引发了当时广泛的隐私担忧。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>spark widespread privacy concerns - 引发广泛的隐私担忧。    <P>原文例句：The 2021 WeChat photo issue sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由spark（引发，点燃），widespread（广泛的）和privacy concerns（隐私担忧）构成的，表示“引发广泛的隐私担忧”。在这个例句中，它指的是2021年的微信照片问题引发了广泛的隐私担忧。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tencent said at the time that the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”, and it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user. - 腾讯当时表示，该应用正在寻找新图片，以便“让用户发送照片更快更流畅”，并且只有在用户授权的情况下才会访问图库。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Tencent said at the time，其中主语是Tencent，谓语是said，宾语是that the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”。from CSDNnews, a tech news outlet run by the Chinese Software Developer Network是一个前置词短语作状语，修饰Tencent，表示腾讯当时表示的内容或来源，即腾讯当时表示，该应用正在寻找新图片，以便“让用户发送照片更快更流畅”。and it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰Tencent，表示腾讯当时表示的内容或方式，即腾讯当时表示，该应用只能在用户授权的情况下才会访问图库。这个句子的意思是说，腾讯当时表示，该应用正在寻找新图片，以便“让用户发送照片更快更流畅”，并且只有在用户授权的情况下才会访问图库。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动名词短语 - 表示一个动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：He said the matter was solved by the roll-out of a new application programming interface within the operating system to fix the lag.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个由动名词（roll-out）和介词（of）及其宾语（a new application programming interface within the operating system）组成的短语，表示一个动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示新应用程序编程接口的推出解决了一个问题。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示一个动作或状态从过去某个时间开始，一直持续到说话时为止。    <p>原文例句：China has introduced new laws in recent years that tighten scrutiny over how tech companies handle personal data.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式（或不规则动词的过去分词）。这种时态表示一个动作或状态从过去某个时间开始，一直持续到说话时为止。在这个例句中，它表示中国近年来出台了新的法律，收紧了对科技公司处理个人数据的方式的审查。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Ma described the issue as ‘a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images’</li>
<li>The 2021 WeChat photo issue sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time despite reassurances that the glitch had been fixed</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/daec20ec-0fa7-42e0-ad58-197447fdda39_11d7714e.jpg" /><figcaption>Ma described the WeChat issue as “a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images”. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Pony Ma Huateng, founder, chairman and CEO of Tencent Holdings, has described a 2021 privacy controversy sparked by a photo issue with its all-purpose super app WeChat as a “misunderstanding”, according to a local media report.</p><p>Thay year, a tech influencer found that WeChat, China’s largest social media app with 1.3 billion monthly active users (MAUs), was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3151762/tencents-wechat-stop-routine-scans-photos-after-tech-influencer" target="_self" title="">frequently accessing user photo galleries even when not in use</a>, which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time.</p><p>Ma described the issue as “a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images”, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Yicai on Monday.</p><p>He said the matter was solved by the roll-out of a new application programming interface within the operating system to fix the lag.</p><p>Tencent said at the time that the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”, and it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user. The company also said it would cancel the scanning in a new version of the app.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Yicai picked up Ma’s comments from CSDNnews, a tech news outlet run by the Chinese Software Developer Network.</p><p>Ma told CSDNnews in a private WeChat message last Friday that this “old incident” in 2021 had been fixed, according to a screenshot shared by the outlet.</p><p>Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment by the Post on Monday.</p><p>China has introduced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3147040/what-chinas-new-data-laws-are-and-their-impact-big-tech?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">new laws in recent years</a> that tighten scrutiny over how tech companies handle personal data.</p><p>The Data Security Law and the Personal Information Protection Law, some of the world’s toughest data protection laws, went into effect in 2021 with strict penalties for the unauthorised collection, processing, storage and use of data generated in the country.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245623/chinas-finance-influencers-face-stricter-rules-tencents-live-streaming-channels-beijing-moves-shore" title="">China’s finance live streamers face stricter rules on Tencent</a></h3><p>Tencent faced intense scrutiny in 2021 when tech influencer Hackl0us said on social media platform Weibo that the app periodically accessed user photos while running in the background.</p><p>The activity was discovered using Apple’s “Record App Activity” feature on its iOS 15 operating system at that time.</p><p>The influencer also said in 2021 that Tencent’s QQ messaging app and Taobao, Alibaba Group Holding’s top online shopping marketplace with roughly 900 million MAUs, had also been found routinely accessing user photos. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong joins EU, US, South Korea and Singapore in tightening crypto regulations in 2023, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247684/hong-kong-joins-eu-us-south-korea-and-singapore-tightening-crypto-regulations-2023-report-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Major jurisdictions worldwide strengthened cryptocurrency regulations in 2023.</li>    <li>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures.</li>    <li>Prominent moves include the European Union's Markets in Crypto Assets Regulation and Hong Kong's new licensing regime for centralized crypto exchanges.</li>    <li>Singapore issued rules to curb retail speculation and finalized regulations for stablecoins.</li>    <li>South Korea, Australia, and the US also increased scrutiny of the cryptocurrency sector.</li>    <li>International organizations established frameworks and policy recommendations for regulating cryptocurrencies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>2023年，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币法规。</li>    <li>根据TRM Labs的数据，在2023年收紧加密法规的司法管辖区中，近一半增加了消费者保护措施。</li>    <li>其中突出举措包括欧盟的加密资产市场监管条例和香港对中心化加密交易所颁布的新许可制度。</li>    <li>新加坡颁布了旨在遏制加密货币零售投机的规则，并最终确定了对稳定币的规章制度。</li>    <li>报告称，韩国、澳大利亚和美国也在去年加大了对加密货币行业的审查力度。</li>    <li>国际组织制定了监管加密货币的框架和政策建议。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Scrutiny (n.) - 仔细检查，审查。    <p>原文例句：Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语scrutinium（检查），表示“仔细检查，审查”。在这个例句中，它指的是政府在经历一系列崩溃后加大对加密货币的审查力度。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Jurisdiction (n.) - 司法管辖区，权限范围。    <p>原文例句：In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, tightened cryptocurrency regulations.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语jurisdictio（法权），表示“司法管辖区，权限范围”。在这个例句中，它指的是包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的17个司法管辖区。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Volatile (adj.) - 波动的，不稳定的。    <p>原文例句：Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语volatilis（飞行的），表示“波动的，不稳定的”。在这个例句中，它指的是加密货币行业波动性很大，容易出现价格剧烈波动的情况。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Ramp up - 加快，加强。    <p>原文例句：In the US, the Securities and Exchange Commission ramped up its enforcement actions against crypto firms in 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由ramp（斜坡）和up（向上）组成，表示“加快，加强”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国证券交易委员会在2023年加强了对加密货币公司的执法行动。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, tightened cryptocurrency regulations. - 在2023年，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币法规。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是17 jurisdictions，谓语是tightened，宾语是cryptocurrency regulations。其中17 jurisdictions是一个并列主语，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国。tightened是一个过去式动词，表示“收紧”。cryptocurrency regulations是一个名词短语，表示“加密货币法规”。这个句子的意思是说，在2023年，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币法规。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列主语 - 两个或两个以上的主语并列在一起，谓语动词与最近的主语保持一致。    <p>原文例句：In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, tightened cryptocurrency regulations.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个并列主语的例子。主语17 jurisdictions是一个并列主语，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国。谓语动词tightened与最近的主语US保持一致。这个句子的意思是说，在2023年，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币法规。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>过去式 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, tightened cryptocurrency regulations.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去式的例子。动词tightened是一个过去式动词，表示“收紧”。这个句子的意思是说，在2023年，包括香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币法规。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, tightened cryptocurrency regulations</li>
<li>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures, according to TRM Labs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/70965061-8587-4332-9ba0-361c7665e6c9_67fe6e02.jpg" /><figcaption>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US tightened cryptocurrency regulations. Photo: Bloomberg </figcaption></figure><p>Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p><p>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the European Union, South Korea, Singapore, and the United States, tightened cryptocurrency regulations, according to a report published on Monday by blockchain analytics firm TRM Labs.</p><p>Those strengthening protection accounted for 80 per cent of the 21 jurisdictions studied by the firm, with the latter representing 70 per cent of global exposure to cryptocurrencies, said TRM Labs.</p><p>In 2022, the collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms, including the stablecoin TerraUSD and exchange FTX, led to a market rout that wiped out trillions of dollars in value.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" title="">Hong Kong to push retail access to spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a></h3><p>While 2023 began with the crypto ecosystem “reeling from the collapse of FTX”, the subsequent 12 months “saw an extraordinary boom in regulation across the globe”, the report says.</p><p>Among prominent moves, the European Union’s Markets in Crypto Assets Regulation came into force in June last year, and Hong Kong’s new licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges went live, the firm noted.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>Singapore, which the report described as “an early adopter of crypto regulation”, in November last year issued a set of rules aimed at curbing retail speculation in cryptocurrencies, and finalised its rules for stablecoins.</p><p>Meanwhile, South Korea and Australia also increased scrutiny of the cryptocurrency sector last year, the report says.</p><p>In the US, the Securities and Exchange Commission ramped up its enforcement actions against crypto firms in 2023, and the House Financial Services Committee also advanced bills last July aimed at creating a federal regulatory framework for the crypto market, with specific attention to stablecoins.</p><p>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures, according to TRM Labs.</p><p>It also noted that international organisations, including the G20, the Financial Action Task Force, the Financial Stability Board, International Monetary Fund, and the International Organization of Securities Commissions, all laid out global frameworks and policy recommendations for regulating cryptocurrencies.</p><p>Hong Kong, which in October 2022 announced a major initiative to support the virtual asset sector with the goal of becoming a global hub for such businesses, has implemented a mandatory licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges that allow them to accept retail investors.</p><p>Eleven companies have so far submitted applications for the licence in the city, including OKX, one of the largest exchanges by trading volume.</p><p>In December, the Asian financial hub also <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246415/hong-kong-regulators-propose-tougher-rules-sale-stablecoins-retail-investors?module=hard_link&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">proposed rules for stablecoin issuers</a>, which would ban companies without a licence from selling stablecoins to Hong Kong’s retail investors through regulated channels, or from actively marketing their tokens to the city.</p><p>The rules have been deemed as “extremely challenging” for stablecoin issuers, potentially deterring operators of the world’s biggest stablecoins, such as Tether and USDC, from entering the city, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246692/hong-kongs-proposed-stablecoin-rules-would-be-extremely-challenging-global-issuers-tether-and-usdc" target="_self" title="">experts told the Post last month</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Shanghai explainer on taxation of digital currency transaction drives speculation on potential easing of China’s crypto ban</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247683/shanghai-explainer-taxation-digital-currency-transaction-drives-speculation-potential-easing-chinas</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  一篇上海税务局发布的解释文章从侧面引起了中国加密爱好者的广泛关注和讨论。该文章解答了有关数字货币交易个人所得税的常见问题，还提到了国家税务总局2008年的一份文件。一些人认为，这暗示着中国政府可能正在放松对加密货币的管制，或认可其合法性。然而，上海税务局随后删除了这篇文章，并有法律专家解释称，这篇文章并不代表中国政府在加密货币政策上的任何改变。文章没有正式政策文件和文件仅仅是针对虚拟游戏中的令牌。文章涉及四个不同的场景，包括个人投资者从被投资公司获得的贷款、在线货币礼品等。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Article raises speculation on China's softening stance on cryptocurrencies.</li>    <li>Theme: Misinterpretations regarding the taxation of cryptocurrency-related income in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Legal implications of taxing cryptocurrency transactions and the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies.</li>    <li>Main information: Article deletion, expert opinions, and implications for crypto regulation in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  一篇由上海市税务局发布的关于数字货币交易个人所得税的解释文章，引发了当地加密爱好者的广泛关注和猜测。有人认为，这篇文章表明中国政府可能会放松对加密货币的管制，或者至少认可其合法性。然而，上海税务局随后删除了这篇文章，并有法律专家解释称，这篇文章并不代表中国政府在加密货币政策上的任何改变。文章没有正式政策文件，其引用的文件仅仅是针对虚拟游戏中的令牌。文章涉及四个不同的场景，包括个人投资者从被投资公司获得的贷款、在线货币礼品等。  <ul>    <li>摘要：文章引发了对中国放松对加密货币立场的猜测。</li>    <li>主题：对中国加密货币相关收入征税的常见误解。</li>    <li>观点：对加密货币交易征税的法律含义以及加密货币的合法性。</li>    <li>主要信息：文章被删除、专家意见以及对中国加密货币监管的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ramp up (v.) - /ræmp ʌp/ 增加，加强，扩大。    <p>原文例句：China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由ramp（坡道）和up（向上）构成的，表示“增加，加强，扩大”。在这个例句中，它意为“加强打击”。</p></li>    <li>virtual asset (n.) - /ˈvɜːrtʃʊəl æsɪt/ 虚拟资产。    <p>原文例句：China has denied legal-tender status for cryptocurrencies, but has not opposed its attribution as property or commodity, according to an article published on Friday by Jin Jianzhi of the Shanghai Mankun Law Firm. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由virtual（虚拟的）和asset（资产）构成的，表示“虚拟资产”。在这个例句中，它特指加密货币。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>      <li>in the wake of - 在……之后，继……之后。    <p>原文例句：The Shanghai Municipal Tax Service has since deleted the article from its public WeChat account.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面）和the wake of（……之后）构成的，表示“在……之后，继……之后”。在这个例句中，it意为“在……之后”。</p></li>   </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>      <li>That prompted some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies. - 这促使了一些大陆的加密主题在线内容创作者认为，对这些交易征税表明当局开始承认加密货币的合法性。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是That prompted some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies，其中主语是That，谓语是prompted，宾语是some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies。这是一个复合宾语，其中suggest是动词，宾语从句to taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies中，主语是to taxing such transactions，谓语是show，宾语是authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies。这是一个现在进行时态的句子，表示动作或状态正在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示一种假设、猜测、愿望或可能性。    <p>原文例句：The explainer had indicated that individuals who obtain virtual currencies from other players through online transactions and generate revenue by selling them at a higher price must pay income tax on such earnings.</p>    <p> 语法讲解：这种语气方式通常使用过去时态或过去完成时态，但所表达的意思却与现在、将来或过去无关，而是表示一种假设、猜测、愿望或可能性。在这个例句中，虚拟语气出现在must 之后，表示一种必须做的事情，但前提是满足某种条件，即个人通过网络交易从其他玩家那里获得虚拟货币，并以更高的价格出售它们来产生收入。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The explainer became widely circulated on Sunday after some local crypto enthusiasts suggested that it acknowledged cryptocurrencies’ legitimacy</li>
<li>The Shanghai Municipal Tax Service has since deleted the article from its public WeChat account</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/dd38a0bb-3bd5-4e5f-aee4-d25bc7d830f4_a5b28db7.jpg" /><figcaption>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>An online article posted by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a> Municipal Tax Service, explaining levies imposed on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/digital-currencies" target="_self" title="">digital currency</a> transactions in China, has fanned speculation among local cryptocurrency enthusiasts that it signals a potential relaxation of the country’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3208481/chinese-economist-calls-review-rigid-cryptocurrency-ban-digital-yuan-fails-take?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">draconian ban on crypto operations</a>.</p><p>The explainer, “Common Misunderstandings Regarding Personal Income Tax on Business Income and Categorised Income”, became widely circulated on Sunday after it was published on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> by the Shanghai tax service on Thursday. It cited a 2008 statement by the State Taxation Administration (STA).</p><p>That prompted some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies. The Shanghai tax service subsequently deleted the explainer on Sunday from its public WeChat account.</p><p>The wide attention received by the Shanghai tax service’s explainer reflects the lingering hope among Chinese crypto circles that the country’s rigid ban on cryptocurrencies would be reviewed amid Beijing’s drive to expand adoption of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/china-digital-currency/news" target="_self" title="">digital yuan</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology last month announced plans to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" target="_self" title="">draft a national Web3 development plan</a> to suit the country’s needs, although it did not specifically mention cryptocurrencies.</p><p>Mainland legal experts, however, pointed out that the Shanghai tax service’s explainer does not suggest any potential change in the country’s cryptocurrency policy.</p><p>The published article is not an official policy document, and the STA statement it cited concerns virtual tokens used in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video games</a>, according to Guo Zhihao, a partner at Beijing-based Yingke Law Firm, in an article he posted on WeChat on Sunday.</p><p>The explainer had indicated that individuals who obtain virtual currencies from other players through online transactions and generate revenue by selling them at a higher price must pay income tax on such earnings. The Shanghai tax agency’s article detailed taxation in four scenarios, including loans obtained by individual investors from their investee companies and online monetary gifts.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3208481/chinese-economist-calls-review-rigid-cryptocurrency-ban-digital-yuan-fails-take" title="">Chinese economist calls for review of rigid crypto ban amid slow e-CNY adoption</a></h3><p>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. It maintains that stance even though it <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3216894/chinese-officials-pledge-support-hong-kongs-tech-web3-ambitions-digital-economy-summit?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">supports Hong Kong’s ambitions to become a major hub for virtual assets</a>, including cryptocurrencies.</p><p>While there is no official sign from Beijing about changing its position on cryptocurrencies, local crypto circles expect increased regulatory oversight on the taxation of virtual asset-related income on the mainland.</p><p>China has denied legal-tender status for cryptocurrencies, but has not opposed its attribution as property or commodity, according to an article published on Friday by Jin Jianzhi of the Shanghai Mankun Law Firm. The lawyer said the government can levy taxes on relevant transactions under the law.</p><p>The global cryptocurrency market, meanwhile, appears to be slowly recovering from a prolonged slump last year. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bitcoin" target="_self" title="">Bitcoin</a> prices gained more than 150 per cent from a year earlier on the back of expectations that the US Securities and Exchange Commission will soon approve <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" target="_self" title="">bitcoin exchange-traded funds</a>, which would make these virtual assets more attractive to mainstream investors.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: Chinese tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to premier consumer electronics show in Las Vegas</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese companies return to CES in large numbers, showcasing their latest technological advancements and seeking overseas growth in the post-pandemic era. Artificial intelligence, smart homes, green technology, and electric vehicles are key themes of the event.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese tech giants return to CES showcasing AI, smart homes and green technology. </li>    <li>Theme: Chinese companies seek overseas growth at CES, highlighting technological advancements.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: CES provides a platform for Chinese companies to showcase their innovations and connect with global partners. </li>    <li>Main information: 1,115 Chinese companies registered at CES, up 126% from 2023; AI expected to be a major trend; exhibitors include ByteDance, TikTok, Alibaba and Govee.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国公司今年大举回归CES，展示其最新的技术进步，并在后疫情时代寻求海外增长。人工智能、智能家居、绿色技术和电动汽车是本次展会的关键主题。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国科技巨头回归CES，展示人工智能、智能家居和绿色技术。</li>    <li>主题：中国企业寻求在CES上实现海外增长，突出技术进步。</li>    <li>观点：CES为中国企业提供了一个展示创新成果并与全球合作伙伴建立联系的平台。</li>    <li>主要信息：CES注册中国公司1,115家，比2023年增长126%；预计人工智能将成为主要趋势；参展商包括字节跳动、TikTok、阿里巴巴和Govee。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>emerged (v.) - /ɪˈmɜːdʒd/ 浮现，显现。    <p>原文例句：Artificial intelligence (AI) is expected to be the major trend at the show this year, playing an even larger role since ChatGPT ignited a generative AI arms race over the past year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由e-（出）和mergere（潜入）组成，表示“浮出水面，显现，出现”。在这个例句中，它描述了人工智能（AI）预计将成为今年展会的主要趋势，自ChatGPT在过去一年点燃生成式人工智能的军备竞赛以来，扮演着更大的角色。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>arms race - 军备竞赛。    <p>原文例句：Artificial intelligence (AI) is expected to be the major trend at the show this year, playing an even larger role since ChatGPT ignited a generative AI arms race over the past year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由arms（武器）和race（竞赛）组成，表示“军备竞赛，军备竞赛”。在这个例句中，它描述了生成式人工智能的军备竞赛，自ChatGPT在过去一年点燃生成式人工智能的军备竞赛以来，人工智能（AI）预计将成为今年展会的主要趋势。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese companies have returned to Las Vegas for CES in full force this year, with more than double the number of exhibitors compared with last year, including big names like ByteDance and Alibaba.com, as companies try to shake off Covid-era blues with overseas growth. - 今年中国企业大举回归拉斯维加斯参加 CES 展会，参展商数量比去年翻了一番，包括字节跳动和阿里巴巴等知名企业。这些企业希望借助海外增长摆脱疫情时期的困扰。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Chinese companies have returned to Las Vegas for CES in full force，其中主语是Chinese companies，谓语是have returned，宾语是to Las Vegas for CES in full force。with more than double the number of exhibitors compared with last year是一个介词短语作状语，表示参展商数量比去年翻了一番。including big names like ByteDance and Alibaba.com是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示包括字节跳动和阿里巴巴等知名企业。as companies try to shake off Covid-era blues with overseas growth是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示这些企业希望借助海外增长摆脱疫情时期的困扰。这个句子的意思是说，今年中国企业大举回归拉斯维加斯参加 CES 展会，参展商数量比去年翻了一番，包括字节跳动和阿里巴巴等知名企业。这些企业希望借助海外增长摆脱疫情时期的困扰。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词结构 - 由分词（现在分词或过去分词）和其宾语或补语组成的结构。    <p>原文例句：Artificial intelligence (AI) is expected to be the major trend at the show this year, playing an even larger role since ChatGPT ignited a generative AI arms race over the past year. </p>    <p>语法讲解：分词结构可以起到多种作用，包括作定语、状语和表语。在这个例句中，playing an even larger role since ChatGPT ignited a generative AI arms race over the past year是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示自ChatGPT在过去一年点燃生成式人工智能的军备竞赛以来，扮演着更大的角色。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>AI is the major trend this year in the wake of ChatGPT, with many companies touting how they are integrating the tech into their products</li>
<li>The return of Chinese tech giants comes even as geopolitical tensions have barely budged from where they were last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/2545b743-77c1-45e1-83aa-b5a50e2cd69e_8fe19122.jpg" /><figcaption>Attendees arrive at the CES Unveiled event before the start of the CES tech show, January 7, 2024, in Las Vegas. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese companies have returned to Las Vegas for CES in full force this year, with more than double the number of exhibitors compared with last year, including big names like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance">ByteDance</a> and Alibaba.com, as companies try to shake off Covid-era blues with overseas growth.</p><p>CES lists 1,115 companies registered from China on its website, a 126 per cent increase over the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial">493 listed</a> at the beginning of the 2023 show. That does not include many of the biggest names on the list, which joined using international addresses.</p><p>ByteDance and its subsidiary <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a>, along with big hardware brands from last year like TCL and Lenovo are registered under their US offices. Even <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, owner of the South China Morning Post, has a presence through its subsidiary Alibaba.com Singapore.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247219/tiktok-eyes-us175-billion-shopping-business-amazons-turf" title="">TikTok eyes US$17.5 billion shopping business on Amazon’s turf</a></h3><p>“You have big exhibitors coming back, really showcasing that this is a platform that really pushes for consumers and enterprises and maybe [can] combat some of these major challenges that we’re facing,” Brian Comiskey, director of consumer programmes at the CTA, said after his opening remarks on Sunday afternoon.</p><p>This marks a stark reversal from 2023, when China had just started to reopen its borders but restrictions did not fall fast enough for many companies to make it to the show in the first week of January.</p><p>“Some of the largest Chinese companies that have signed up for participation this year … will all have a large presence at the show,” John Kelley, vice-president and show director for CES at the Consumer Technology Association (CTA), told the Post in an interview on November 29. “But where we’re really seeing growth on the Chinese side is smaller companies.”</p><p>Kelley said the CTA was anticipating numbers to reach pre-Covid levels, and it looks like the show has pulled it off. The number of Chinese companies is more than the 1,000 that state-run tabloid Global Times reported for the 2020 show. CTA said the show has attracted around 4,000 exhibitors, although numbers are not final yet. Kelley said CES expects to see 130,000 attendees.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence">Artificial intelligence (AI)</a> is expected to be the major trend at the show this year, playing an even larger role since ChatGPT ignited a generative AI arms race over the past year. Smart homes, green tech and electric vehicles were other areas highlighted during the show’s opening remarks to the media.</p><p>Alibaba was highlighted as one of the exhibitors using machine learning platforms to “power e-commerce”.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1306" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/d1856897-2d66-43bf-b0ad-271970378ed9_da47af5a.jpg" title="Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shenzhen-based smart lighting company Govee is integrating generative AI to allow users to create specific moods. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even much smaller companies are touting their use of AI. Govee, a smart lighting maker from Shenzhen, is advertising the use of generative AI to help people create specific moods, like asking for a backdrop that is evocative of the Hong Kong skyline or Barbie Dreamhouse.</p><p>Some fabless chip design firms are also exhibiting, such as Fuzhou-based mobile chip maker Rockchip and Wuhan-based autonomous driving chip maker Black Sesame, which contracts with electric car companies Geely and BYD. Black Sesame chips are manufactured by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a>, it said.</p><p>Xpeng is among the major electric vehicle makers at the show, where it will be demonstrating its new “flying car”, the AeroHT.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1067" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/b8c16129-faf2-4eac-924a-4824d9f25c14_5368aac5.jpg" title="XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>XPeng is showcasing its AeroHT flying car at CES 2024. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>The return of Chinese tech giants comes even as geopolitical tensions have barely budged from where they were last year. US President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping may have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3241692/joe-biden-xi-jinping-meet-person-first-time-year-apec-sidelines" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3241692/joe-biden-xi-jinping-meet-person-first-time-year-apec-sidelines">met in November</a>, but there have been no major policy shifts around escalating restrictions on technology such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors">semiconductors</a> and AI.</p><p>TikTok and its Beijing-based owner ByteDance have been under intense political scrutiny in Washington over data privacy and national security concerns. This may not have deterred TikTok from showing up to the largest consumer electronics shows in its largest market.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3205947/ces-2023-number-chinese-companies-event-less-half-pre-pandemic-level-firms-shy-away-controversial" title="">Number of Chinese tech firms at CES 2023 less than half of pre-pandemic level</a></h3><p>Representatives from the company will join two panels at the show to discuss sports and entertainment. Beyond entertainment, though, ByteDance makes much of its money through advertising and has been trying to grow its e-commerce business.</p><p>Other Chinese companies cannot exhibit at the show even if they want to because they have been listed on Washington’s Entity List. This includes the world’s largest drone maker DJI and a number of semiconductor companies.</p><p>“From a show management perspective, we welcome participation from every company,” CTA’s Kelley said. “As a US-based trade association, we cannot allow participation if they are on some sort of Entity List. That’s really the only place where we will not allow participation.”</p><p>Still, CES may be more important for the many small firms that make up the bulk of the show’s exhibition floor. It remains the premier event of its kind.</p><p>“We like to make the case that the four days you spend in Las Vegas is some of the most efficient use of your time in the sense that you don’t have to necessarily travel the world to meet with individual business partners on six different continents,” said Kelley. “Instead, you can come to Las Vegas and meet everybody that you need to meet from the global technology industry over the course of a week.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung set for smallest profit drop in 6 quarters on chip rebound</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247610/samsung-set-smallest-profit-drop-6-quarters-chip-rebound</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  Samsung Electronics, the world's largest producer of memory chips, smartphones, and televisions, is estimated to report a 14% fall in its fourth-quarter profit due to losses in its chip division. However, the company's chip division loss is expected to be smaller compared to previous quarters as prices of DRAM and NAND flash chips rebounded in the December quarter. Samsung's mobile business also saw a decline in operating profit due to decreased shipments of its flagship foldable models.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung's expected profit decline in the fourth quarter reflects the impact of semiconductor market dynamics.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's chip division loss reduction and the recovery in chip prices.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of chip production in Samsung's overall performance; the effect of consumer demand on the semiconductor industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Forecasted profit fall; reduced chip division loss; rebounding prices of DRAM and NAND flash chips; decline in mobile business profit.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  三星电子作为全球最大的存储芯片、智能手机和电视制造商，预计在第四季度利润中将下跌14%，原因在于其芯片部门的亏损。然而，预计公司芯片部门的亏损将会比上个季度缩小，因为DRAM和NAND闪存芯片的价格在12月季度反弹。三星的移动业务也因其旗舰可折叠机型出货量减少而导致营业利润下降。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星预期中的第四季度利润下跌反映了半导体市场动态的影响。</li>    <li>主题：三星芯片部门亏损减少以及芯片价格回升。</li>    <li>观点：芯片生产在三星整体业绩中的重要性；消费者需求对半导体行业的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：预测的利润下降；芯片部门亏损减少；DRAM和NAND闪存芯片价格反弹；移动业务利润下降。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>semiconductor (n.) - /ˌsemɪkənˈdʌktə/ 半导体。    <p>原文例句：Samsung’s chip division likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由semi-（半）和conductor（导体）构成的，表示一种在导电性和绝缘性之间具有中间性质的物质。在这个例句中，它指的是三星的芯片部门。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rebound (v.) - /rɪˈbaʊnd/ 反弹，回升。    <p>原文例句：Samsung had reported chip division losses of 4.36 trillion won and 3.75 trillion won in the second and third quarters, respectively, as a semiconductor glut from slow demand for gadgets driven by inflation pressures on consumers caused the worst industry downturn in decades. However, prices of DRAM chips – used in various tech devices – and NAND flash chips – used to store data – rebounded in the December quarter, including for older chips, in a sign of an industry-wide recovery expected this year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，意思是“跳跃，回弹”。在这个例句中，它描述了DRAM芯片和NAND闪存芯片的价格在12月季度反弹。</p></li>  </ul>   </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>according to - 根据，按照。    <p>原文例句：Samsung’s chip division likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由acccord（协议，一致）和to（向，到）构成的，表示“按照，根据”。在这个例句中，它表示三星的芯片部门季度亏损可能减少到1.2万亿韩元左右，这是根据八项预测的平均值得出的。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in a sign of - 作为……的标志，作为……的迹象。    <p>原文例句：However, prices of DRAM chips – used in various tech devices – and NAND flash chips – used to store data – rebounded in the December quarter, including for older chips, in a sign of an industry-wide recovery expected this year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在，里面）和a sign（标志，信号）构成的，表示“作为……的标志，作为……的迹象”。在这个例句中，它表示DRAM芯片和NAND闪存芯片价格在12月季度反弹，包括旧芯片的价格上涨，这表明今年半导体行业将出现复苏。</p></li>  </ul>    </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters, analysts estimate, as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division. - 分析师估计，三星电子将报告其在六个季度中利润下降幅度最小，因为半导体价格的反弹减少了这家韩国企业集团的主要芯片部门的亏损。<p>句子分析：这是一个较长的复合句，由一个主句和两个并列的非限制性定语从句组成。主句是Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters，其中主语是Samsung Electronics，谓语是expected to report，宾语是its smallest profit drop in six quarters。第一个非限制性定语从句是as a rebound in semiconductor prices，其中as是连接词，表示原因，rebound in semiconductor prices是主语，shrinks是谓语，losses是宾语。第二个非限制性定语从句是in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division，其中in是介词，South Korean conglomerate's是形容词短语，修饰chip division，mainstay是形容词，修饰chip division，chip division是名词短语，作介词in的宾语。这个句子的意思是说，三星电子预计将报告其在六个季度中利润下降幅度最小，因为半导体价格的反弹减少了这家韩国企业集团的主要芯片部门的亏损。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Mobile DRAM chip prices rose an estimated 18 to 23 per cent during the fourth quarter, while mobile NAND flash chip prices rose 10 to 15 per cent, according to data provider TrendForce. - 根据数据提供商TrendForce的数据，第四季度移动DRAM芯片价格估计上涨了18%至23%，而移动NAND闪存芯片价格上涨了10%至15%。<p>句子分析：这是一个较长的简单句，有三个并列的句子成分。主语是Mobile DRAM chip prices，谓语是rose，宾语是an estimated 18 to 23 per cent。第二个句子成分的主语是mobile NAND flash chip prices，谓语是rose，宾语是10 to 15 per cent。第三个句子成分的主语是TrendForce，谓语是said，宾语是the percentage of increase。这个句子的意思是说，根据数据提供商TrendForce的数据，第四季度移动DRAM芯片价格估计上涨了18%至23%，而移动NAND闪存芯片价格上涨了10%至15%。</p></li>  </ul>            </div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters, analysts estimate, as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是由have/has和过去分词构成的，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个例句中，rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses是一个现在完成时态的句子，表示从过去某个时间开始，半导体价格的反弹一直持续到现在的动作或状态，从而减少了亏损。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示两个或多个事物之间的比较。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是形容词或副词的一种形式，表示两个或多个事物之间的比较。在这个例句中，smallest是形容词superlative的比较级，表示“最小的”。这个句子的意思是说，三星电子预计将报告其在六个季度中利润下降幅度最小。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The world’s biggest maker of memory chips, smartphones and televisions is expected to show a 14 per cent fall in fourth-quarter profit</li>
<li>Samsung’s chip division likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts</li>
</ul><p>Samsung Electronics is expected to report its smallest profit drop in six quarters, analysts estimate, as a rebound in semiconductor prices shrinks losses in the South Korean conglomerate's mainstay chip division.</p><p>The world’s biggest maker of memory chips, smartphones and televisions is expected to show a 14 per cent fall in fourth-quarter profit when it announces preliminary earnings on Tuesday.</p><p>Operating profit likely fell to 3.7 trillion won (US$2.82 billion) in the October-December quarter, according to the average of an LSEG SmartEstimate from 30 analysts, weighted toward those who are more consistently accurate.</p><p>That would compare with an operating profit of 4.31 trillion won in the December quarter of the previous year. Samsung last reported a year-on-year quarterly profit increase for the second quarter of 2022.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/article/3245933/us-gather-chips-supply-chain-intelligence-boost-national-security" title="">US to gather chip supply chain intelligence to boost national security</a></h3><p>A solid set of results would justify Samsung’s sharp stock market run-up in the fourth quarter, which has made it Asia’s second-most valuable listed company after chip foundry rival Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co, with a market capitalisation of about US$390 billion.</p><p>Samsung’s chip division – traditionally its biggest earner – likely reduced its quarterly loss to around 1.2 trillion won, according to an average of eight forecasts. Analysts said its dynamic random access memory (DRAM) chips business returned to a profit.</p><p>Samsung had reported chip division losses of 4.36 trillion won and 3.75 trillion won in the second and third quarters, respectively, as a semiconductor glut from slow demand for gadgets driven by inflation pressures on consumers caused the worst industry downturn in decades.</p><p>However, prices of DRAM chips – used in various tech devices – and NAND flash chips – used to store data – rebounded in the December quarter, including for older chips, in a sign of an industry-wide recovery expected this year.</p><p>Mobile DRAM chip prices rose an estimated 18 to 23 per cent during the fourth quarter, while mobile NAND flash chip prices rose 10 to 15 per cent, according to data provider TrendForce.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/8f2d3cfa-7d39-4dd6-b8f2-d7fda417159f_34f54c2a.jpg" title="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 smartphones at the Samsung Store in Seoul, January 7, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>While Samsung has repeatedly cut production since the first half of 2023 to cope with the downturn, analysts and sources said Samsung took in more supply of silicon wafers, the building blocks for semiconductors, in the fourth quarter, signalling it is gearing up to increase DRAM chip production.</p><p>Samsung was also more aggressive in selling memory chips than competitors, such as SK Hynix, in the fourth quarter in a bid to lower inventory, analysts said.</p><p>Rival Micron Technology forecast a quarterly revenue above market estimates last month, in a sign of a recovery in the memory chip market in 2024.</p><p>Samsung’s mobile business likely saw an operating profit of around 2.5 trillion won, according to an average of forecasts from eight analysts, as shipments of its two flagship foldable models were estimated to have fallen about 1 million units each versus the third quarter.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Podcasts gain popularity in China as one in five internet users tuned in last year, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247572/podcasts-gain-popularity-china-one-five-internet-users-tuned-last-year-says-report</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Chinese podcasts gained popularity in 2023, attracting over 220 million listeners from the country's vast internet user base. Younger professionals in China's higher-tier cities formed a significant portion of the audience, demonstrating a growing trend of podcast consumption among this demographic. The industry saw increased monetization with over 22,000 podcast hosts earning revenue from premium content and advertisements from global brands such as Coca-Cola and Cadillac. Despite China's strict online content censorship, podcasts thrived, with topics like health, lifestyle, Chinese history, and entertainment proving popular among listeners. The podcast industry embraces generative artificial intelligence (AI) to enhance efficiency and content creation.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese podcasts' rise in popularity attracts global brands and boosts monetization.</li>    <li>Theme: The growing popularity of Chinese podcasts and their impact on the industry, including audience demographics, monetization strategies, and content preferences.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The podcast industry's resilience amidst China's online content censorship and its adoption of AI-powered tools for content creation.</li>    <li>Main information: Statistics on podcast listeners, revenue generation, audience demographics, popular genres, and the impact of AI in the industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  2023年，中国播客吸引了超过2.2亿听众，成为互联网用户中广受欢迎的媒体形式。年轻的专业人士构成了中国播客受众的主力军，他们主要来自中国一二线城市。播客行业也呈现出越来越多的商业化趋势，超过22,000名播客主持人通过提供高级内容和来自全球品牌（如可口可乐和凯迪拉克）的广告获得了收入。尽管中国对在线内容进行严格审查，但播客行业却蓬勃发展，健康、生活方式、中国历史和娱乐等主题深受听众喜爱。播客行业还积极拥抱了人工智能（AI），利用AI驱动的音频工具提高了内容创作效率。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国播客的兴起吸引了全球品牌，促进了商业化。</li>    <li>主题：中国播客日益流行及其对行业的影响，包括受众群体、商业化策略和内容偏好。</li>    <li>观点：播客行业在面对中国在线内容审查时的韧性和其采用AI驱动的工具来进行内容创作。</li>    <li>主要信息：播客听众、收入生成、受众群体、热门类型以及AI在行业中的影响的统计数据。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>podcast (n.) - /ˈpɔːdˌkæst/ 播客，播客节目。    <p>原文例句：More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts on Ximalaya’s platform last year, across 31 genres.</p>    <p>例句讲解：播客是一种音频文件，通常由个人或团体定期制作并发布在网上，供用户下载或在线收听。它可以是访谈、讲座、新闻或其他主题的讨论。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>professional (n.) - /prəˈfɛʃ(ə)n(ə)l/ 专业人士，专家。    <p>原文例句：Young professionals helped Chinese podcasts attract ads from global brands such as drinks giant Coca-Cola and luxury carmaker Cadillac.</p>    <p>例句讲解：专业人士是指在某个领域或行业中具有专业知识和技能的人员。他们通常受过高等教育或专业培训，并具有丰富的实践经验。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>monetization (n.) - /ˌmʌnɪtʌɪˈzeɪʃən/ 使货币化，赚钱。    <p>原文例句：More than 22,000 podcast hosts earned a combined total of 70 million yuan (US$9.8 million) on Ximalaya last year, the company revealed in its research.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“使货币化”是指使某种东西能够产生经济价值或收益。在经济学中，它通常是指将非货币资产或资源转化为货币资产或资源的过程。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>censorship (n.) - /ˈsɛnsɔːrˌʃɪp/ 审查，检查制度。    <p>原文例句：Chinese podcast preferences were partially the result of the country’s strict censorship of online content.</p>    <p>例句讲解：审查制度是指政府或其他权力机构对信息的传播和流向进行控制和限制。它可以是通过法律法规、行政手段或技术手段等方式实现的。</li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>artificial intelligence (n.) - /ˌɑːrtɪˈfɪʃəl ˌɪntɛlɪˈdʒəns/ 人工智能。    <p>原文例句：The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence (AI), which increases efficiency and helps with content creation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：人工智能是指由计算机或其他机器模拟或实现人类智能的行为或决策过程。它是计算机科学的一个分支，也是近年来最热门的研究领域之一。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tune into - 调入，收听。    <P>原文例句：More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts on Ximalaya’s platform last year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：tune into是指收听或观看广播、电视或网络节目。它通常与介词into一起使用，表示进入或调入某个频道或节目。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>across the board - 全面，普遍。    <P>原文例句：More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts hosted by Ximalaya last year, across 31 genres of programmes.</p>    <p>例句讲解：across the board表示全面、普遍或不分彼此。它通常用于描述某种情况或趋势适用于所有人或所有情况。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>on the rise - 正在兴起，越来越受欢迎。    <P>原文例句：One in five internet users in China listened to a podcast last year, as the once niche sector gained popularity in 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：on the rise表示正在兴起、变得越来越受欢迎或流行。它通常用于描述事物或趋势的增长或发展。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>strict censorship - 严格审查制度。    <P>原文例句：Chinese podcast preferences were partially the result of the country’s strict censorship of online content.</p>    <p>例句讲解：strict censorship是指严格的审查制度或检查制度。这通常是指政府或其他权力机构对信息传播和流向进行严格的控制和限制。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>ride the wave - 顺应潮流，利用趋势。    <P>原文例句：The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence (AI), which increases efficiency and helps with content creation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：ride the wave是指顺应潮流或趋势，利用它们来获得优势或成功。它通常用于描述企业或个人利用新技术或新趋势来发展或壮大自己。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Young professionals also helped Chinese podcasts attract advertisements from global brands, from food and beverage giant Coca-Cola to luxury US carmaker Cadillac, providing an additional monetisation channel for the industry, according to a separate report by market consultancy iResearch.    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Young professionals also helped Chinese podcasts attract advertisements，其中主语是Young professionals，谓语是helped，宾语是advertisements。from food and beverage giant Coca-Cola to luxury US carmaker Cadillac是一个介词短语作定语，修饰advertisements，表示广告来自食品和饮料巨头可口可乐和豪华美国汽车制造商凯迪拉克。providing an additional monetisation channel for the industry是一个现在分词短语作目的状语，表示吸引广告的目的，即为行业提供额外的商业化渠道。根据市场咨询公司iResearch的另一份报告，前半句是young professionals helped Chinese podcasts attract advertisements from global brands，表示年轻的专业人士帮助中国播客吸引了来自全球品牌的广告。后  <ul><li>More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts on Ximalaya’s platform last year, across 31 genres</li>
<li>Young professionals helped Chinese podcasts attract ads from global brands such as drinks giant Coca-Cola and luxury carmaker Cadillac</li>
</ul><p>One in five internet users in China listened to a podcast last year, as the once niche sector gained popularity in 2023, according to a recently published research.</p><p>More than 220 million of the country’s nearly 1.1 billion internet users tuned into podcasts hosted by Ximalaya last year, across 31 genres of programmes, according to research published on Friday by the Chinese podcast service provider.</p><p>The audience for its podcasts skewed towards young Chinese professionals working in the country’s higher-tier cities, Ximalaya’s research showed.</p><p>The user group aged between 24 and 40 years represented more than 60 per cent of podcast listeners in China, while those from tier-one and tier-two cities accounted for more than 65 per cent of the total audience.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after" title="">China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech must end, party paper says</a></h3><p>Consumers in China are also increasingly more inclined to pay for quality podcast content, with more than half signing up for premium content. More than 22,000 podcast hosts earned a combined total of 70 million yuan (US$9.8 million) on Ximalaya last year, the company revealed in its research.</p><p>Young professionals also helped Chinese podcasts attract advertisements from global brands, from food and beverage giant Coca-Cola to luxury US carmaker Cadillac, providing an additional monetisation channel for the industry, according to a separate report by market consultancy iResearch.</p><p>Chinese users primarily tuned into podcasts during their daily commutes, with health and lifestyle, Chinese history, global politics, frontier technology, business and entertainment, as well as fantasy and thriller stories among the most popular genres on the Ximalaya platform.</p><p>Chinese podcast preferences were partially the result of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3244838/chinas-online-censors-target-short-videos-artificial-intelligence-and-pessimism-latest-crackdown" target="_self" title="">the country’s strict censorship of online content.</a> General news and politics, two of the most popular genres among podcast listeners in Western countries, were missing from the list in China, according to Ethan Cramer-Flood, a researcher at market consultancy Insider Intelligence.</p><p>“In the West, maybe news and politics rank relatively highly, whereas in China it’s just nowhere to be found because the censorship regime is so strict there,” Flood said in an online discussion last November. “So it’s [topics] like lifestyle, fashion, pet care … sports [that] are all at the top of the list because [they are] nothing remotely controversial.”</p><p>Still, Chinese podcasts are flourishing despite the country’s online content crackdown. In 2023, Ximalaya’s platform hosted 5.2 million more podcast episodes than the year before.</p><p>The podcast industry in China is also riding the wave of generative artificial intelligence (AI), which increases efficiency and helps with content creation, thanks to a suite of AI-powered audio tools Ximalaya launched last year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
