<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China unveils 3-year ‘data action plan’ as Beijing seeks to boost growth through tech</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247423/china-unveils-3-year-data-action-plan-beijing-seeks-boost-growth-through-tech</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  China's National Data Administration aims to harness the country's vast data resources to drive economic growth. The three-year plan includes building over 300 representative application scenarios, expanding the data industry by 20% annually, and promoting data trading. This initiative seeks to cultivate new economic drivers by leveraging China's market size, data reserves, and use cases. It involves supporting AI development, building high-quality datasets, and addressing challenges like low data quality, poor circulation, and untapped potential. The NDA, established in March 2022, is tasked with coordinating data infrastructure construction and promoting data integration, sharing, and utilization across various sectors.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's plan to utilize data for economic growth.</li>    <li>Theme: The establishment of the National Data Administration (NDA) and its three-year action plan to transform data into a driving force for China's economy.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of data as a production factor in stimulating economic development.</li>    <li>Main information: Building representative application scenarios, expanding the data industry, mobilizing data resources for AI development, addressing challenges in data quality, circulation, and applications, and promoting data utilization in various industries.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国的国家数据局旨在利用国家巨大的数据资源来推动经济增长。 这项为期三年的计划包括构建超过 300 个代表性应用场景，在未来三年内每年将数据行业扩展 20%，并促进数据交易。此项计划旨在通过利用中国广阔的市场规模、数据储备和使用案例来培育新的经济驱动力。它涉及支持人工智能发展，构建高质量的数据集，并应对诸如数据质量低下、流通不畅和潜在能力尚未开发等挑战。国家数据局于 2022 年 3 月成立，负责协调数据基础设施建设并促进跨不同行业的数据整合、共享和利用。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国利用数据实现经济增长的计划。</li>    <li>主题：国家数据局及其三年行动计划，将数据转变为中国经济的主要驱动力。</li>    <li>观点：数据作为刺激经济发展生产要素的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：构建代表性应用场景，扩大数据行业，调集数据资源以发展人工智能，应对数据质量、流通和应用中的挑战，促进数据在各个行业的利用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unleash (v.) - /ʌnˈliːʃ/ 释放，解开。    <p>原文例句：The goal was to unleash economic value while ensuring security and privacy. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由un-（不）和leash（皮带）组成，表示“释放，解开”。在这个例句中，它表示目标是释放经济价值，同时确保安全和隐私。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>circulate (v.) - /ˈsɜːkjʊˌleɪt/ 流通，循环。    <p>原文例句：China’s digital economy, having developed rapidly in recent years, still faces challenges including the low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped potential for applications, it said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由circum-（环绕）和late（携带）组成，表示“流转，循环，传播”。在这个例句中，它表示中国数字经济在近年迅速发展的同时，仍面临着数据供应质量低、流通不畅、应用潜力尚未开发等挑战。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>information technology (IT) - 信息技术。    <p>原文例句：The new administration, which officially began operations in October, is tasked with “coordinating and promoting the construction of data infrastructure, coordinating the integration, sharing, development and utilisation of data resources” across China’s economy and society, it said in March 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是information（信息）和technology（技术）的组合，表示“信息技术”。在这个例句中，它特指有关信息处理和传输的技术，通常包括计算机、软件、数据通信和数据系统等。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>national development and reform commission - 国家发展和改革委员会。    <p>原文例句：The agency, established under China’s top economic planner, the National Development and Reform Commission, is headed by information technology (IT) veteran Liu Liehong, former chairman of state-owned telecommunications network operator China Unicom. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是national（国家），development（发展），reform（改革）和commission（委员会）的组合，是中华人民共和国的一个重要组成部分，负责研究和拟订国民经济和社会发展计划，并监督和检查其执行情况。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China’s newly established data administration, an agency created by Beijing to make data an effective production factor, has unveiled a three-year action plan to use the country’s massive troves of information to boost its economy. - 中国新成立的数据管理局——国家数据局，为使数据成为有效的生产要素而创建，该机构已公布一项三年行动计划，计划利用国家大量的信息来提振经济。<p>句子分析：这是一个单句，主句是China’s newly established data administration has unveiled a three-year action plan，其中主语是China’s newly established data administration，谓语是has unveiled，宾语是a three-year action plan。an agency created by Beijing to make data an effective production factor是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰China’s newly established data administration，表示国家数据局是由北京创建的，目的是使数据成为有效的生产要素。to use the country’s massive troves of information to boost its economy是一个不定式作目的语，说明国家数据局公布三年的行动计划的目标，即利用国家大量的信息来提振经济。这个句子的意思是说，中国新成立的数据管理局——国家数据局，为使数据成为有效的生产要素而创建，该机构已公布一项三年行动计划，计划利用国家大量的信息来提振经济。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作定语 - 表示对先行词的限定或修饰。    <p>原文例句：According to the plan published by the National Data Administration (NDA) on Thursday, China aims to build more than 300 “representative” application scenarios by 2026. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中，published by the National Data Administration (NDA)是一个过去分词短语，作定语，修饰plan，表示这个计划是由国家数据管理局（NDA）发布的。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式作目的语 - 表示动作或状态的目的或意图。    <p>原文例句：The goal was to unleash economic value while ensuring security and privacy. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中，to unleash economic value while ensuring security and privacy是一个不定式作目的语，表示释放经济价值的目的是为了确保安全和隐私。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China aims to build more than 300 ‘representative’ application scenarios by 2026, and grow its data industry by 20 per cent every year</li>
<li>The digital economy still faces challenges including low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped applications potential</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/7195ef42-b909-415f-a96d-069d4c81cfa9_a08669f1.jpg" /><figcaption>A visitor shakes hands with a humanoid robot during the China International Digital Economy Expo 2023 in Hebei Province. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China’s newly established data administration, an agency created by Beijing to make data an effective production factor, has unveiled a three-year action plan to use the country’s massive troves of information to boost its economy.</p><p>According to the plan published by the National Data Administration (NDA) on Thursday, China aims to build more than 300 “representative” application scenarios by 2026, grow its data industry by 20 per cent every year, and multiply data trading volume.</p><p>The initiative is aimed at “cultivating” a new driving force for China’s economic development, leveraging the country’s advantages including a sizeable market, and abundant data resources and use cases, the NDA said.</p><p>The agency’s plan involves mobilising data resources to support development of China’s own artificial intelligence (AI) large language models - the technology used to train AI applications like ChatGPT. It will also increase efforts to have research institutions and leading enterprises build industry databases to create high quality datasets for training AI models.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246678/china-focus-finance-tech-and-farms-12-sector-digital-push-real-economy-2026" title="">China’s digital economy push for 12 sectors sets sights on finance, tech, farms</a></h3><p>The blueprint comes at a time when China’s digital economy, having developed rapidly in recent years, still faces challenges including the low quality of data supply, a poor circulation mechanism and untapped potential for applications, it said.</p><p>The NDA was announced in March last year as Beijing ramped up efforts in managing the country’s growing pool of data that is fragmented across different sectors and industries. The goal was to unleash economic value while ensuring security and privacy.</p><p>While the country’s internet watchdog, the Cyberspace Administration of China, has put in place laws and regulations governing data security, Beijing did not have a government body overseeing development policies for data until the establishment of the NDA.</p><p>The new administration, which officially began operations in October, is tasked with “coordinating and promoting the construction of data infrastructure, coordinating the integration, sharing, development and utilisation of data resources” across China’s economy and society, it said in March 2023.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246289/china-turns-spotlight-digital-economy-quest-common-prosperity-under-president-xi-jinping" title="">China’s focuses on digital economy to drive ‘common prosperity’ under Xi</a></h3><p>The agency, established under China’s top economic planner, the National Development and Reform Commission, is headed by information technology (IT) veteran Liu Liehong, former chairman of state-owned telecommunications network operator China Unicom.</p><p>The three-year plan will “guide and encourage” different types of private capital to invest in the data industry, and support data brokers in raising capital by going public.</p><p>The NDA also singled out 12 industries that should make better use of data, including manufacturing, agriculture, commerce, transport, finance and IT.</p><p>China’s new data strategies come as it seeks to catch up with the US in the development of AI, despite facing a host of challenges including restricted access to advanced chips.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong-listed Chinese miner CMOC takes Glencore’s cobalt crown as output jumps 170% in 2023</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247376/hong-kong-listed-chinese-miner-cmoc-takes-glencores-cobalt-crown-output-jumps-170-2023</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  China’s CMOC Group became the world’s leading producer of cobalt in 2023. The company's cobalt output surged by 170%, surpassing Glencore. CMOC produced 55,526 tonnes of cobalt, buoyed by its new Kisanfu mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo. The increased production contributed to a 30% drop in cobalt prices due to oversupply. CMOC's copper production also saw a significant 51% growth. Cobalt is a key material for EV batteries, and its demand is expected to grow with the increasing popularity of electric vehicles.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's CMOC Group becomes the world's largest cobalt producer, driving down prices.</li>    <li>Theme: CMOC's dominance in cobalt production, factors contributing to the price decline, and the growing demand for cobalt in the EV industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The role of CMOC in the global cobalt market, the impact of production increase on prices, and the potential market demand for cobalt in the future.</li>    <li>Main information: CMOC's production increase by 170%, surpassing Glencore; Kisanfu mine's contribution to the surge; cobalt price drop due to oversupply; CMOC's copper production growth; cobalt's significance in EV batteries; increasing demand for EVs.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  中国的五矿集团在2023年成为全球最大的钴生产商。该公司的钴产量激增了170%，超过了嘉能可。五矿集团生产了55,526吨钴，该公司在刚果民主共和国的新Kisanfu矿山产量激增。增产导致钴价因供应过剩而下降了30%。五矿集团的铜产量也大幅增长了51%。钴是电动汽车电池的关键材料，随着电动汽车的日益普及，对其需求有望增长。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国的五矿集团成为全球最大的钴生产商，从而压低了价格。</li>    <li>主题：五矿集团在钴产量中的主导地位、导致价格下跌的因素以及电动汽车行业对钴日益增长的需求。</li>    <li>观点：五矿集团在全球钴市场中的作用、产量增加对价格的影响以及未来钴的潜在市场需求。</li>    <li>主要信息：五矿集团产量增长170%，超过嘉能可；Kisanfu矿山对激增的贡献；钴价因供应过剩而下降；五矿集团的铜产量增长；钴在电动汽车电池中的重要性；对电动汽车的需求不断增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>surge (v.) - /sɜːrdʒ/ 激增，猛增。    <p>原文例句：CMOC’s copper output also jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes, establishing it as one of the world’s top producers at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语surgen（上升，冲高），表示“涌出，喷发，激增”。在这个例句中，它指的是五矿集团的铜产量大幅增长了51%，达到419,539吨，使该集团成为世界领先的铜生产商之一，特别是在许多矿企都在努力提高产量的情况下。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>slump (n.) - /slʌmp/ 暴跌，剧跌。    <p>原文例句：Soaring output at the US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year, alongside rising production in Indonesia and a rebound in exports from CMOC’s other operation in Congo, Tenke-Fungurume. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于中世纪英语slumpen（坠落，滑落），表示“突然而大幅的下跌”。在这个例句中，它指的是在美国18亿美元的Kisanfu矿山产量激增的情况下，钴价格去年大幅下跌，而印度尼西亚的产量增加和CMOC在刚果的另一个矿山Tenke-Fungurume的出口反弹也导致了这一跌势。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in a bid to - 为了，以……为目的。    <P>原文例句：The mismatch between supply and demand became so acute that by midyear Glencore had started to stockpile surplus at its operations in Congo in a bid to bring the market back into balance. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……中），a（一个），bid（出价，投标）和to（向……）构成的，表示“为了，以……为目的”。在这个例句中，它表示，由于供需之间的差距变得如此严重，嘉能可在年中时开始在其刚果的业务中囤积剩余的钴，目的是为了让市场恢复平衡。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>While investors and traders had been expecting a large increase at CMOC’s massive Kisanfu mine – which came online in the second quarter – the full-year result exceeded the company’s own production guidance by more than 20 per cent. - 虽然投资者和交易员们一直期待五矿集团规模庞大的Kisanfu矿山大幅增产——该矿山在第二季度投产——但全年产量超过了该公司自身生产目标的20%以上。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The full-year result exceeded the company’s own production guidance by more than 20 per cent，其中主语是The full-year result，谓语是exceeded，宾语是the company’s own production guidance by more than 20 per cent。While investors and traders had been expecting a large increase at CMOC’s massive Kisanfu mine – which came online in the second quarter –是一个独立结构作状语，表示虽然投资者和交易员们一直期待五矿集团规模庞大的Kisanfu矿山大幅增产——该矿山在第二季度投产——。这个句子的意思是说，虽然投资者和交易员们一直期待五矿集团规模庞大的Kisanfu矿山大幅增产——该矿山在第二季度投产——但全年产量超过了该公司自身生产目标的20%以上。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：CMOC’s copper output also jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes, establishing it as one of the world’s top producers at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示五矿集团的铜产量也大幅增长了51%，达到419,539吨，使该集团成为世界领先的铜生产商之一，特别是在许多矿企都在努力提高产量的情况下。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The company’s output of the key metal in EV batteries exceeded its own guidance by more than 20 per cent</li>
<li>Soaring output at CMOC’s US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/978ac785-70c2-47f2-8569-299b57f5feb3_f7bc69b7.jpg" /><figcaption>Excavators and drillers work in an open pit at Tenke Fungurume, a copper and cobalt mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>China’s CMOC Group boosted its cobalt output by more than 170 per cent last year, with surging production at a new mine in the Democratic Republic of Congo helping the company leapfrog Glencore as the world’s top producer of the key battery metal.</p><p>Hong Kong-listed CMOC produced 55,526 tonnes of cobalt in 2023, it said in a filing on Thursday. In October, Glencore forecast output of as much as 42,000 tonnes. While investors and traders had been expecting a large increase at CMOC’s massive Kisanfu mine – which came online in the second quarter – the full-year result exceeded the company’s own production guidance by more than 20 per cent.</p><p>Soaring output at the US$1.8 billion Kisanfu mine helped trigger a sharp slump in cobalt prices last year, alongside rising production in Indonesia and a rebound in exports from CMOC’s other operation in Congo, Tenke-Fungurume. The market was already in one of its biggest ever surpluses as 2023 began, and the additional output helped drive a 30 per cent slump in prices over the year.</p><p>The mismatch between supply and demand became so acute that by midyear Glencore had started to stockpile surplus at its operations in Congo in a bid to bring the market back into balance. Glencore is set to announce its full production results next month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/bc0491e6-2aee-4541-8141-aa5c1fb6228a_1126e908.jpg" title="An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>An electric vehicle (EV) chassis with battery is displayed at the booth of battery maker CATL during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing on November 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>CMOC’s copper output also jumped by 51 per cent to 419,539 tonnes, establishing it as one of the world’s top producers at a time when many miners are struggling to boost output.</p><p>Cobalt is a material used in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3234469/global-ev-transition-accelerates-falling-battery-costs-hasten-purchase-price-parity-further-blow" target="_self" title="">NCM (lithium, nickel, cobalt and manganese) batteries</a> powering electric cars, which offer vehicles a longer driving range than nickel-based LFP (lithium, iron and phosphate) counterparts.</p><p>Global consultancy AlixPartners forecast in a research report in July that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicles (EVs)</a> would account for 34 per cent of global sales by 2028 and make up 61 per cent of sales in 2035, compared to 14 per cent in 2022.</p><p>In China, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243806/li-auto-xpeng-pace-chinese-ev-makers-race-towards-2023-sales-record-amid-all-time-high-monthly" target="_self" title="">EV penetration rate</a> exceeded 40 per cent in 2023 amid motorists’ rising penchant for environmentally friendly cars featuring autonomous driving technology and digital cockpits.</p><p>Mainland China is now the world’s largest automotive and EV market, with sales of battery-powered cars accounting for about 60 per cent of the global total.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246699/chinese-battery-maker-gotion-starts-making-energy-storage-packs-fremont-plant-kicking-made-america" title="">Chinese EV battery maker Gotion starts making energy storage packs in US</a></h3><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3237220/chinese-ev-makers-course-smashing-85-million-2023-sales-target-mainland-industry-players-and" target="_self" title="">Electric vehicle (EV) sales on the mainland</a>, however, are seen growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from the projected 30 per cent increase in 2023.</p><p>Seoul-based consultancy SNE Research said in a report last February that electric cars with a driving range of more than 300 kilometres were sold at about US$30,000, on par with prices of petrol-powered vehicles, which helped EVs gain popularity around the globe.</p><p><em>Additional reporting by</em> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/author/daniel-ren" target="_self" title=""><em>Daniel Ren</em></a></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Qualcomm unveils chip for mixed reality to compete with Apple’s Vision Pro</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247367/qualcomm-unveils-chip-mixed-reality-compete-apples-vision-pro</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Qualcomm, a leading chip designer, introduces the Snapdragon XR2+ chip aimed at virtual and mixed-reality headsets, targeting to compete with Apple's upcoming Vision Pro.</li>    <li>This new chip boasts the capability of operating 12 or more high-resolution cameras, enhancing the user's experience in augmented and virtual reality applications.</li>    <li>Samsung and Google are among the first companies to adopt the Snapdragon XR2+ chip for their upcoming mixed-reality products.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>高通，作为领先的芯片设计公司，发布了骁龙XR2+芯片，专注于虚拟和混合现实头戴设备，目标是与苹果即将推出的Vision Pro竞争。</li>    <li>这款新的芯片功能强大，能够运行12个或更多高分辨率摄像头，增强用户在增强和虚拟现实应用中的体验。</li>    <li>三星和谷歌是首批采用骁龙XR2+芯片用于其即将推出的混合现实产品的公司。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>chip (n.) - /tʃɪp/ 芯片。    <p>原文例句：Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors, announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle English，意思是“切掉的小块”。在这个例句中，它指的是Qualcomm设计的一种用于虚拟和混合现实设备的芯片，这种芯片被称为骁龙 XR2+。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>headset (n.) - /ˈhɛdˌsɛt/ 头戴式设备。    <p>原文例句：The market for devices that project information onto the user’s view of the physical world was fired up last year by Apple’s announcement that it would sell a mixed-reality headset.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于head（头部）和set（设置），意思是“戴在头上的设备”。在这个例句中，它指的是一种可以让人们看到虚拟或增强现实内容的设备。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>at the heart of - 在……的核心，是……的核心。    <P>原文例句：Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由at（在），the（定冠词）和heart（心脏）组成的，表示“在……的核心，是……的核心”。在这个例句中，它表示高通的芯片一直是许多其他公司试图吸引消费者进入这一类别的核心，这一类别尚未流行起来。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Headsets with the XR2+ will use processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors to project 4K-resolution images on each lens, according to Qualcomm’s Said Bakadir, a senior director of product management. - 根据高通产品管理高级总监赛义德·巴卡迪尔的说法，配备XR2+的头戴设备将使用比上一代产品性能提升多达20%的处理器和图形组件，从而在每个镜片上投影出4K分辨率的图像。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Headsets with the XR2+ will use，其中主语是Headsets with the XR2+，谓语是will use。processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors to project 4K-resolution images on each lens是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰Headsets with the XR2+，表示这些头戴设备将使用比上一代产品性能提升多达20%的处理器和图形组件，从而在每个镜片上投影出4K分辨率的图像。according to Qualcomm’s Said Bakadir, a senior director of product management是一个插入语，提供有关信息的来源，即根据高通产品管理高级总监赛义德·巴卡迪尔的说法。这个句子的意思是说，配备XR2+的头戴设备将使用比上一代产品性能提升多达20%的处理器和图形组件，从而在每个镜片上投影出4K分辨率的图像，根据高通产品管理高级总监赛义德·巴卡迪尔的说法。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors, announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed或不规则变化形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示高通已经发布了骁龙XR2+芯片，这种芯片专为虚拟和混合现实头戴设备而设计，并将与苹果即将推出的Vision Pro竞争。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The chip design firm said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung and Google</li>
<li>Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off</li>
</ul><p>Qualcomm, the biggest maker of mobile phone processors, announced the Snapdragon XR2+ chip designed for virtual and mixed-reality headsets that will compete with Apple’s forthcoming Vision Pro.</p><p>The San Diego, California-based chip design firm said the new component, which can run 12 or more high-definition cameras, will be used by Samsung Electronics and Alphabet’s Google on products under development.</p><p>The market for devices that project information onto the user’s view of the physical world was fired up last year by Apple’s announcement that it would sell a mixed-reality headset. Qualcomm’s chips have been at the heart of many other companies’ attempts to lure consumers to the category, which has not yet taken off.</p><p>Augmented reality imposes graphics and written content on top of a person’s view of the world. Virtual reality places a consumer in a closed digital world. Apple’s coming Vision Pro and Meta Platforms' most-recent Quest 3 headset mix the technologies. Previous versions of Qualcomm’s XR chip have been featured in devices from Microsoft and Meta.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3240824/can-virtual-reality-ease-surgery-fears-patients-hong-kong-study-may-have-answer" title="">Virtual reality could be key to easing fears in surgical patients: study</a></h3><p>Headsets with the XR2+ will use processors and graphics components that are as much as 20 per cent better than their predecessors to project 4K-resolution images on each lens, according to Qualcomm’s Said Bakadir, a senior director of product management.</p><p>That improvement in quality will ease eye fatigue from reading text, reduce the potential for motion sickness and let device makers implement new features, he said. The chip’s ability to handle more cameras will aid in-depth perception and the eye tracking required to orient the user in the real world and recognise items.</p><p>“A lot of people want more juice to do more things,” Bakadir said. “People want to push the platform even higher.”</p><p>Qualcomm is working with a number of partners in addition to Google and Samsung, and announcements from customers may come as soon as next week’s CES show with products available as early as this year, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>OpenAI in talks with dozens of publishers to license content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  OpenAI与政治新闻媒体Politico的母公司Axel Springer签署了一项价值数千万美元的多年许可协议。作为培训其人工智能模型的一种更广泛的努力，OpenAI目前正在与数十家出版商谈判达成许可其文章的协议。这些协议对于OpenAI的未来至关重要，因为它需要平衡构建模型所需的最新、准确的数据与人们对其数据来源的日益严格审查。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: OpenAI and Politico's parent company sign a multi-year licensing deal.</li>    <li>Theme: OpenAI's efforts to license articles from publishers for training its AI models.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of updated, accurate data for OpenAI's AI models; the legal and ethical challenges surrounding the use of copyrighted content for training AI models.</li>    <li>Main information: OpenAI's negotiations with dozens of publishers; the lawsuit filed by The New York Times against OpenAI and Microsoft; the potential impact of the lawsuit on OpenAI's business.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  OpenAI 与政治新闻媒体 Politico 的母公司 Axel Springer 签署了一项价值数千万美元的多年许可协议。作为培训其人工智能模型的一种更广泛的努力，OpenAI 目前正在与数十家出版商谈判达成许可其文章的协议。这些协议对于 OpenAI 的未来至关重要，因为它需要平衡构建模型所需的最新、准确的数据与人们对其数据来源的日益严格审查。  <ul>    <li>摘要：OpenAI 与 Politico 的母公司签署了一项多年许可协议。</li>    <li>主题：OpenAI 为训练其人工智能模型而许可文章的努力。</li>    <li>观点：最新、准确的数据对于 OpenAI 的人工智能模型的重要性；围绕使用受版权保护的内容训练人工智能模型的法律和伦理挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：OpenAI 与数十家出版商的谈判；纽约时报对 OpenAI 和微软提起的诉讼；该诉讼对 OpenAI 业务的潜在影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ink (v.) - /ɪŋk/ 签订合同，达成协议。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由古英语单词“encan”演变而来的，意思是“使成为法律”。在这个例句中，它指的是OpenAI与Politico的母公司Axel Springer签订了一项价值数千万美元的多年许可协议。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>disclose (v.) - /dɪˈskloʊz/ 披露，公开。    <p>原文例句：In July, OpenAI announced an agreement with the Associated Press for an undisclosed amount.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语单词“discludere”，意思是“打开，分开”。在这个例句中，它涉及OpenAI与美联社达成了一项协议，但具体金额没有披露。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>strike a deal - 达成协议，达成交易。    <P>原文例句：OpenAI is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles, a broader effort than was previously known, as the start-up looks for content to train its artificial intelligence (AI) models.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由strike（罢工，打击）和deal（交易，协议）组成的，表示“达成协议，达成交易，达成合同”。在这个例句中，它指的是OpenAI正在与数十家出版商谈判，以达成许可其文章的协议，这是OpenAI为训练其人工智能模型而做出的更广泛的努力之一。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“We are in the middle of many negotiations and discussions with many publishers. They are active. They are very positive. They’re progressing well,” Tom Rubin, OpenAI’s chief of intellectual property and content, told Bloomberg News. - “我们正在与许多出版商进行许多谈判和讨论。他们很积极。他们非常积极。他们的进展很顺利，”OpenAI 的知识产权和内容主管汤姆·鲁宾告诉彭博新闻社。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是They are progressing well，其中主语是They，谓语是are progressing，宾语是well。we are in the middle of many negotiations and discussions with many publishers是一个现在进行时态的分词短语作状语，表示OpenAI目前正在进行许多谈判和讨论。They are active和They are very positive都是现在时态的分词短语作状语，表示出版商们很积极，他们非常积极。这个句子的意思是说，我们正在与许多出版商进行许多谈判和讨论，他们很积极，非常积极，他们的进展很顺利。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行或发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles, ...</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：be + 动词的现在分词（-ing形式）。其中be根据主语的人称和数进行变化，动词的现在分词表示动作或状态正在进行。这种时态用来表示正在进行或发生的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI正在与数十家出版商谈判，以达成许可其文章的协议。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：In July, OpenAI announced an agreement with the Associated Press for an undisclosed amount.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的过去式或过去分词形式。这种时态用来表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI在7月份宣布了一项与美联社达成的协议，但具体金额没有披露。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars</li>
<li>One of the companies it had been in talks with, The New York Times, sued OpenAI and Microsoft for using articles without permission</li>
</ul><p>OpenAI said it is talking to dozens of publishers about striking deals to license their articles, a broader effort than was previously known, as the start-up looks for content to train its artificial intelligence (AI) models.</p><p>“We are in the middle of many negotiations and discussions with many publishers. They are active. They are very positive. They’re progressing well,” Tom Rubin, OpenAI’s chief of intellectual property and content, told Bloomberg News. “You’ve seen deals announced, and there will be more in the future.”</p><p>OpenAI recently inked a multi-year licensing deal with Politico’s parent company Axel Springer for tens of millions of dollars, a person familiar with the matter previously told Bloomberg. In July, OpenAI announced an agreement with the Associated Press for an undisclosed amount. These deals are key to OpenAI’s future, as it is balancing the need for updated, accurate data to build its models with growing scrutiny about where that data is sourced from.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246524/chinese-ai-champion-sensetime-introduces-go-playing-robot-japan-south-korea" title="">Chinese AI champion SenseTime introduces Go playing robot to Japan, South Korea</a></h3><p>But last week, one of the companies it had been in talks with, The New York Times Co, sued OpenAI and Microsoft for using the publication’s articles without permission.</p><p>The suit poses an existential challenge to OpenAI’s business. If the Times wins the case, OpenAI may not only owe billions of dollars, but could also be forced to destroy any of its training data that includes work from the Times, a costly and complicated task. More immediately, however, the lawsuit complicates OpenAI’s deal-making efforts with the media industry.</p><p>“The current situation is vastly different than the situations that publishers faced in the past with search engines and social media,” Rubin said. “Here, the content is used for training a model. It’s not used to reproduce the content. It’s not used to replace the content.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246667/chinas-cloud-market-growth-plateaus-despite-big-ai-push" title="">China’s cloud market growth plateaus despite big AI push</a></h3><p>The Times, however, disagrees with OpenAI’s stance, arguing that ChatGPT is flat out copying its journalists’ work without paying for it.</p><p>In its lawsuit, the publisher showed examples in which ChatGPT spit out entire paragraphs of nearly verbatim text from The New York Times (although some have pointed out that in certain examples, it was specifically prompting ChatGPT to reproduce Times content). The publisher argues that is proof OpenAI used New York Times data.</p><p>“If Microsoft and OpenAI want to use our work for commercial purposes, the law requires that they first obtain our permission,” The New York Times said in a statement. “They have not done so.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong-based AI-driven company sells potential breast cancer drug in deal whose value could exceed US$500 million</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247263/hong-kong-based-ai-driven-company-sells-potential-breast-cancer-drug-deal-whose-value-could-exceed</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Insilico Medicine, an AI-driven drug discovery company, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group in a deal worth over US$500 million. The agreement grants Stemline, a subsidiary of Menarini, exclusive global rights to develop and commercialize a novel small molecule KAT6A inhibitor as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers. AI technology is playing an increasingly important role in drug discovery, with the AI-driven drug discovery market projected to reach an estimated value of US$7.1 billion by 2030. Insilico's founder and co-CEO, Dr. Alex Zhavoronkov, emphasizes the technology's ability to accelerate the identification of potential drugs. Breast cancer, the most common cancer worldwide, is expected to see a significant market growth in the coming years. Insilico has a diversified pipeline of 31 programs targeting various diseases, and recently announced plans for an IPO in Hong Kong to fund clinical trials of its AI-discovered drugs. The company has raised over $400 million in private markets.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Insilico sells its breast cancer drug candidate to Menarini Group, unlocking a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers.</li>    <li>Theme: AI technology drives drug discovery, leading to a multi-million dollar deal between Insilico and Menarini for a novel breast cancer treatment.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The promise of AI in revolutionizing drug discovery and the potential impact of this partnership on the development of cancer therapies.</li>    <li>Main information: Details of the agreement, including upfront payment, sales royalties, and development milestones; market size and growth projections for AI-driven drug discovery; Insilico's pipeline and plans for an IPO.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  Insilico Medicine，一家人工智能驱动的药物研发公司，以超过 5 亿美元的交易价格，将其用于治疗乳腺癌的临床前候选药物出售给了位于意大利的制药公司 Menarini 集团。该协议授予 Menarini 的子公司 Stemline 独家全球权利，以开发和商业化新型小分子 KAT6A 抑制剂，作为治疗激素敏感性癌症的潜在疗法。人工智能技术在药物研发中发挥着日益重要的作用，预计到 2030 年，人工智能驱动的药物研发市场将达到 71 亿美元的估值。Insilico 的创始人兼联合首席执行官 Alex Zhavoronkov 博士强调了该技术加速识别潜在药物的能力。乳腺癌是全球最常见的癌症，预计未来几年将迎来显着的市场增长。Insilico 拥有针对多种疾病的 31 个多元化项目，并最近宣布了在香港进行首次公开募股的计划，以资助其人工智能发现的药物的临床试验。该公司已在私人市场筹集了超过 4 亿美元。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Insilico 将其乳腺癌候选药物出售给 Menarini 集团，解锁了对激素敏感性癌症的潜在治疗方法。</li>    <li>主题：人工智能技术推动药物发现，促成 Insilico 与 Menarini 之间针对新型乳腺癌治疗药物的数百万美元交易。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能在药物发现领域变革的承诺，以及这种伙伴关系对癌症治疗方法开发的潜在影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：协议细节，包括预付款、销售提成和开发里程碑；人工智能驱动的药物发现的市场规模和增长预测；Insilico 的项目和首次公开募股计划。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>catalyst (n.) - /ˈkætəlɪst/ 催化剂。    <p>原文例句：AI has emerged as a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery by enhancing efficiency and accuracy while reducing the time-consuming aspects of research and development, experts say. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Catalyst 意思为“催化剂”，常用于化学领域，指能改变化学反应速度但不参与反应的物质。在引文中，Catalyst 比喻人工智能技术在药品发现中的促进作用。</p></li>    <li>clinical trial (n.) - /ˈklɪnɪkəl traɪəl/ 临床试验。    <p>原文例句：In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Clinical trial 指的是对药物或医疗器械在人体中的安全性、疗效等进行评估的研究。在这个句子中，Clinical trial 指的是对由人工智能发现和设计的药物进行的临床试验。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>play a role in - 起作用，发挥作用。    <p>原文例句：AI has emerged as a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery by enhancing efficiency and accuracy while reducing the time-consuming aspects of research and development, experts say.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“play a role in”的意思是“发挥作用，起作用”。在这个句子中，它表示人工智能技术在药品发现中发挥着关键的作用。</p></li>    <li>make a payment - 付款。    <p>原文例句：Stemline Therapeutics, a wholly owned unit of Menarini, will make a US$12 million upfront payment to Insilico under the agreement, which will be followed by sales royalties worth up to “double digits”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“make a payment”的意思是“付款”。在这个句子中，它表示Menarini的全资子公司Stemline Therapeutics将向Insilico支付1200万美元的预付款。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>AI has emerged as a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery by enhancing efficiency and accuracy while reducing the time-consuming aspects of research and development, experts say. - 专家表示，人工智能已成为革新药物发现的催化剂，它提高了效率和准确性，同时减少了耗时的研发环节。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂长句，主句是AI has emerged as a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery，其中主语是AI，谓语是has emerged，宾语是a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery。by enhancing efficiency and accuracy while reducing the time-consuming aspects of research and development是一个分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示人工智能技术通过提高效率和准确性，同时减少耗时的研发环节，成为革新药物发现的催化剂。这个句子的意思是说，专家表示，人工智能已成为革新药物发现的催化剂，它提高了效率和准确性，同时减少了耗时的研发环节。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间或动作发生之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence.</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去完成时是由had/has + 过去分词构成的，表示在过去某个时间或动作发生之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个句子中，revealed和shelving都是过去分词，表示这两个动作发生在fund之前已经完成。</p></li>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Insilico has raised more than US$400 million via private markets.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成进行时是由have/has been + 现在分词构成的，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个句子中，raised和been raising都是现在分词，表示Insilico从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态是筹集资金。</p></li>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：Menarini, an international pharmaceutical and diagnostics company with a turnover of more than US$4.4 billion and operations in 140 countries, sees the collaboration with Insilico as an opportunity to explore new treatment approaches and potentially unlock transformative cancer therapies, according to CEO Elcin Barker Ergun.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是由be + 过去分词构成的，表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。在这个句子中，sees和explore都是被动语态，表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语Menarini承受的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Insilico grants Italy’s Menarini Group, the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule inhibitor, as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers</li>
<li>Breast cancer, a hormone-sensitive cancer, is the most common cancer worldwide, and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the WHO</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/0aa273cd-964f-49d2-be3b-69223d5b9a88_d8bebbd1.jpg" /><figcaption>null</figcaption></figure><p>Insilico Medicine, a Hong Kong-based AI-driven drug discovery company that intends to list in Hong Kong after it unveiled an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3225736/hong-kong-based-biotech-insilico-medicine-shifts-ipo-plan-city-new-york" target="_self" title="">initial public offering plan</a> (IPO) last year, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group in a deal that could reach a value of over US$500 million.</p><p>Stemline Therapeutics, a wholly owned unit of Menarini, will make a US$12 million upfront payment to Insilico under the agreement, which will be followed by sales royalties worth up to “double digits”. The combined value of the deal includes all development, regulatory, and commercial milestones.</p><p>The agreement comes at a time when cutting-edge technology is playing a greater role in drug discovery. AI has emerged as a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery by enhancing efficiency and accuracy while reducing the time-consuming aspects of research and development, experts say.</p><p>The AI-driven drug discovery market is projected to grow at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 23.72 per cent from 2023 to 2030, reaching an estimated value of US$7.1 billion by 2030, according to US-based Vantage Market Research.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/8d6c5116-f305-4968-8ef3-f757c1373823_34f54c2a.jpg" title="An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The technology expedites the process of identifying potential drugs, according to Insilico’s founder and co-CEO, Dr Alex Zhavoronkov.</p><p>Under the exclusive licensing agreement, Insilico has granted Stemline the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule KAT6A inhibitor as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers and other oncology indications.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3199001/sanofi-signs-research-tie-hong-kongs-insilico-medicine-accelerate-ai-powered-drug-discovery" title="">Sanofi signs with Hong Kong biotech firm Insilico to spur AI drug discovery</a></h3><p>Breast cancer is the most common cancer worldwide and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the World Health Organization.</p><p>The global breast cancer market is projected to hit around US$73.68 billion by 2032 with a registered CAGR of 9.9 per cent, according to Precedence Research.</p><p>“The partnership at the early stage preclinical trial is truly optimal when the partner is very committed,” said Zhavoronkov.</p><p>Menarini, an international pharmaceutical and diagnostics company with a turnover of more than US$4.4 billion and operations in 140 countries, sees the collaboration with Insilico as an opportunity to explore new treatment approaches and potentially unlock transformative cancer therapies, according to CEO Elcin Barker Ergun.</p><p>Insilico, founded by Zhavoronkov in 2014, has a pipeline that consists of 31 programmes for 29 drug targets in cancer, fibrosis, immunity, central nervous system and ageing-related diseases.</p><p>In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence.</p><p>Zhavoronkov declined to reveal a timeline for its IPO but said market sentiment was a concern.</p><p>Insilico has a presence in the markets of the US, Greater China, Canada and the Middle East. It launched the Generative AI and Quantum Computing Research and Development Center in Abu Dhabi in February 2023.</p><p>To date, the company has raised more than US$400 million via private markets. In 2022, it secured series D financing of US$95 million from investors such as Prosperity7, a growth venture fund of Saudi Arabia’s Aramco, and others including B Capital Group, Warburg Pincus, and Hong Kong-based Qiming Ventures.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese EV maker Hozon predicts fivefold jump in overseas sales as growth slows in hyper-competitive domestic market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247305/chinese-ev-maker-hozon-predicts-fivefold-jump-overseas-sales-growth-slows-hyper-competitive-domestic</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese electric vehicle (EV) startup Hozon New Energy Automobile aims to increase its overseas sales five-fold in 2024, targeting 100,000 unit deliveries in 60 markets.</li>    <li>The company has started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand and plans to open a second assembly facility outside China in the second quarter.</li>    <li>Hozon's overseas expansion is driven by slowing growth in the domestic EV market and intense competition among 200 players.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国电动汽车 (EV) 初创公司合众新能源汽车计划在 2024 年将其海外销量提高五倍，目标在 60 个市场交付 100,000 辆汽车。</li>    <li>该公司已开始在泰国的第一家海外工厂组装汽车，并计划在第二季度在中国境外开设第二家组装工厂。</li>    <li>合众新能源汽车的海外扩张是由国内电动汽车市场增长放缓和 200 家参与者的激烈竞争推动的。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>count on - 依赖；指望。    <P>原文例句：Beijing-based Nio is also a top-tier electric car maker that many car buyers count on. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语由count（计算，计算）和on（在……上）构成，表示“依赖；指望”。在这个例句中，它指的是许多汽车买家依赖蔚来这个顶级电动汽车制造商。</p></li>    <li>crossover financing - 交叉融资。    <P>原文例句：In August, the company announced it had raised 7 billion yuan (US$986 million) in a crossover financing deal, without disclosing the names of the investors.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词由crossover（跨界，交叉）和financing（融资）构成，表示“交叉融资”。在这个例句中，它指的是合众新能源汽车在 8 月份宣布筹集了 70 亿元人民币（9.86 亿美元）的交叉融资，但没有透露投资者的姓名。</p></li>    <li>Middle East - 中东    <P>原文例句：Zhou said the carmaker targets total sales of 1 million EVs in 2026, including 400,000 outside mainland China. It also plans to build plants in markets like the Middle East, Africa and South America, he said. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示亚洲西南部、地中海东部和非洲东北部地区，包括巴林、埃及、伊朗、伊拉克、以色列、约旦、科威特、黎巴嫩、阿曼、卡塔尔、沙特阿拉伯、叙利亚、土耳其、阿拉伯联合酋长国和也门等国。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>budget EVs - 经济型电动汽车。    <P>原文例句：Neta is a variation of the name Nezha, a protection deity in Chinese mythology. The brand falls into the category of budget EVs in China, aimed at middle- and low-income drivers who prefer battery-powered vehicles to cars powered by petrol-guzzling internal combustion engines. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由budget（预算）和EVs（电动汽车）构成，表示“经济型电动汽车”。在这个例句中，它指的是合众新能源汽车旗下的哪吒汽车品牌，属于经济型电动汽车，目标客户是中低收入者，他们更喜欢电池驱动的汽车，而不是汽油驱动的内燃机汽车。</p></li>    <li>right-hand-drive versions - 右舵版本。    <P>原文例句：The plant, with an annual capacity of 20,000 units, produces right-hand-drive versions of Neta vehicles. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由right-hand-drive（右舵）和versions（版本）构成，表示“右舵版本”。在这个例句中，它指的是位于泰国的第一家海外工厂每年可以生产 20,000 辆右舵版本的哪吒汽车。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>At the end of November, Hozon, also known as Neta Auto, started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand, about two months ahead of schedule. - 11 月底，合众新能源汽车，也称为哪吒汽车，开始在其第一家海外工厂泰国工厂组装汽车，比原计划提前了大约两个月。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Hozon started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand，其中主语是Hozon，谓语是started assembling vehicles，宾语是at its first overseas factory in Thailand。At the end of November是一个时间状语，表示在 11 月底。about two months ahead of schedule是一个时间状语，表示比原计划提前了大约两个月。这个句子的意思是说，11 月底，合众新能源汽车开始在其第一家海外工厂泰国工厂组装汽车，比原计划提前了大约两个月。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>主动语态和被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由谁或什么发出的。    <p>原文例句：The carmaker aims to deliver a total 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia, as it starts operations of assembly plants in Thailand and Indonesia. </p>    <p>语法讲解：主动语态是指动作或状态是由主语发出的，被动语态是指动作或状态是由宾语发出的。在这个例句中，主语是carmaker，谓语是aims to deliver，表示汽车制造商的目标是交付。宾语是units，谓语是被动语态的deliver，表示汽车将被交付。这个句子的意思是说，这家汽车制造商的目标是今年在 60 个海外市场交付总计 100,000 辆汽车，主要在东南亚，因为它开始在泰国和印度尼西亚运营组装厂。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars aims to deliver 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia</li>
<li>Company started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand in November, about two months ahead of schedule</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/2f9a94ae-4006-4789-9e96-32506d8ef0a5_7020747c.jpg" /><figcaption>Performers present a Hozon NETA V during a launch ceremony in Bangkok, Thailand, on August 24, 2022. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> start-up Hozon New Energy Automobile expects its sales outside mainland China to jump five-fold in 2024 as the country’s increasingly confident carmakers look to international sales to counter slowing growth at home.</p><p>The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars, aims to deliver a total 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia, as it starts operations of assembly plants in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243541/chinese-ev-maker-hozon-kicks-operations-its-first-overseas-factory-thailand-it-steps-push-southeast" target="_self" title="">Thailand</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3230821/hozon-steps-plans-develop-right-hand-drive-neta-electric-cars-indonesia-it-pushes-ahead-its-hong" target="_self" title="">Indonesia</a>, according to vice-president Zhou Jiang.</p><p>At that level, overseas sales would account for a third of Hozon’s total deliveries in 2024, which are likely to hit 300,000 units, he said.</p><p>“Overall, Chinese-made electric cars are well received by customers around the world,” he said in a media briefing on Thursday. “Moreover, we are confident of our company’s global perspective with the goal of designing and manufacturing EVs for all the people.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo" class="image-inline caption" height="1328" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/338ee101-bc2d-48a2-8f3d-5ae81ace116c_515c76ff.jpg" title="Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo" width="2000" /><figcaption>Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo</figcaption></figure></div><p>At the end of November, Hozon, also known as Neta Auto, started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand, about two months ahead of schedule. The plant, with an annual capacity of 20,000 units, produces right-hand-drive versions of Neta vehicles.</p><p>Hozon’s second assembly facility outside China will be operational by the second quarter, Zhou said.</p><p>“Owing to a slowing domestic market, Chinese EV makers whose brands and vehicles can attract foreign buyers will step up their overseas expansion in the coming years,” said Eric Han, a ­senior ­manager at Suolei, an advisory firm in Shanghai. “Indeed, they enjoy a higher profit margin in other markets because of price competition at home.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247229/short-sellers-target-byd-worlds-top-ev-maker-rivalry-intensifies" title="">Short sellers target BYD, world’s top EV maker, as rivalry intensifies</a></h3><p>Neta is a variation of the name Nezha, a protection deity in Chinese mythology. The brand falls into the category of budget EVs in China, aimed at middle- and low-income drivers who prefer battery-powered vehicles to cars powered by petrol-guzzling internal combustion engines.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246896/chinese-ev-makers-face-day-reckoning-2024-competition-and-price-war-force-out-underperformers" target="_self" title="">EV sales in mainland China</a> are seen growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from the projected 30 per cent increase in 2023.</p><p>With the EV market crowded with 200 players, a new round of price cuts is in effect, with top players like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest maker</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3229066/xpeng-gets-volkswagens-us700-million-investment-jointly-develop-evs-worlds-largest-vehicle-market" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> offering discounts to lure buyers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/markets/article/3247151/china-evs-xpeng-and-li-auto-roll-out-x9-and-mega-mpvs-aimed-rich-buyers-bid-dominate-segment" title="">China EVs: Xpeng and Li Auto roll out minivan models with focus on rich buyers</a></h3><p>Hozon delivered a total of 127,496 vehicles to domestic and overseas customers in 2023, down 16 per cent year on year.</p><p>In August, the company announced it had <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3232811/chinese-ev-start-hozon-raises-us960-million-pre-ipo-financing-looks-expand-footprint-home-and-abroad" target="_self" title="">raised 7 billion yuan (US$986 million)</a> in a crossover financing deal, without disclosing the names of the investors.</p><p>Crossover financing typically gives a start-up more time and capital to develop its business before an initial public offering (IPO). Investors normally close cross-financing deals at a discounted price while gaining a foothold in the prospective IPO.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>Hozon reported a net loss of 6.9 billion yuan in 2022, 138 per cent wider than a 2.9 billion yuan loss in the previous year, according to the annual report of 360 Security Technology, one of the EV company’s investors.</p><p>Zhou said the carmaker targets total sales of 1 million EVs in 2026, including 400,000 outside mainland China. It also plans to build plants in markets like the Middle East, Africa and South America, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China is on track to be world AI leader by 2030, with Hong Kong’s help</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3247052/china-track-be-world-ai-leader-2030-hong-kongs-help</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China's AI market, firms, and tech are growing rapidly, while the regulatory environment is maturing.</li>    <li>Hong Kong can contribute by providing AI talent and funding.</li>    <li>China aims to become the world's leading AI innovation center by 2030.</li>    <li>China has the largest number of AI companies and large language models (LLMs) in the world.</li>    <li>China's AI market is expected to reach US$104.7 billion by 2030.</li>    <li>China's Global AI Governance Initiative calls for a "people-centered" approach to AI development and inclusiveness.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国的人工智能市场、企业和技术正在强劲增长，而监管环境也在不断成熟。</li>    <li>香港可以通过提供人工智能人才和资金来做出贡献。</li>    <li>中国的目标是到2030年成为世界领先的人工智能创新中心。</li>    <li>中国拥有全球数量最多的人工智能公司和大语言模型（LLM）。</li>    <li>预计到2030年，中国的人工智能市场将达到1047亿美元。</li>    <li>中国发起的全球人工智能治理倡议呼吁以“以人为本”的方式发展人工智能，并促进包容性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>undisputed (adj.) - 无争议的，公认的。    <P>原文例句：According to a recent Nikkei study, “China is the undisputed champion in artificial intelligence research papers … far surpassing the US in both quantity and quality”. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由un-（非）和disputed（争论，争议）构成的，表示“没有争议的，公认的”。在这个例句中，它表示根据最近的日经研究，中国在人工智能研究论文方面是“无争议的冠军……无论在数量还是质量上都远远超过美国”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>paramount (adj.) - 最重要的，至关重要的。    <P>原文例句：Furthermore, China has 975 million smartphone users, by far the highest in any country, meaning it generates a vast amount of digital information – and data plays a paramount role in developing AI.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由para-（在，旁边）和mons（山）组成，原本表示“最高的山”，后来引申为“最重要的是”。在这个例句中，它表示中国拥有9.75亿智能手机用户，是所有国家中最多的，这意味着中国产生了大量数字信息，而数据在人工智能的开发中发挥着至关重要的作用。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>play a role in - 在……中发挥作用。    <P>原文例句：Hong Kong has a key role to play in China’s AI development. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由play（玩，表演）和role（角色，作用）构成的，表示“在……中扮演角色，发挥作用”。在这个例句中，它表示香港在中国的AI发展中发挥着关键的作用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>come to - 发生，来临。    <P>原文例句：According to the 2023 AI Index Report by the Stanford Institute for Human-Centred Artificial Intelligence, global investment in AI has significantly increased over the last decade. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由come（来）和to（到）构成的，表示“发生，来临”。在这个例句中，它表示根据斯坦福人类中心人工智能研究所2023年人工智能指数报告，全球对人工智能的投资在过去十年里大幅增加。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>From a regulatory perspective, China has taken a further step towards digitalisation and innovation. - 从监管的角度来看，中国已经朝着数字化和创新迈出了新的一步。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是China has taken a further step towards digitalisation and innovation。其中主语是China，谓语是has taken，宾语是a further step towards digitalisation and innovation。From a regulatory perspective是一个介词短语作状语，表示从监管的角度来看。这个句子的意思是说，从监管的角度来看，中国已经朝着数字化和创新迈出了新的一步。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：According to a recent Nikkei study, “China is the undisputed champion in artificial intelligence research papers … far surpassing the US in both quantity and quality”.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示根据最近的日经研究，中国在人工智能研究论文方面是“无争议的冠军……无论在数量还是质量上都远远超过美国”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子的主语承受的。    <p>原文例句：Hong Kong can contribute by providing talent and funding.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语态，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。被动语态表示动作或状态是由句子的主语承受的，强调动作或状态的接受者。在这个例句中，它表示香港可以通过提供人才和资金来做出贡献。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China’s AI market, firms and tech are growing strongly, while the regulatory climate is maturing. Hong Kong can contribute by providing AI talent and funding</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/ccb3683c-5993-48ba-ab9c-122ea06719a8_5241b49e.jpg" /><figcaption>A woman stands in front of a poster during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai on July 6 last year. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>If we are in the midst of a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3236727/expect-chinas-regulators-help-ai-firms-race-against-us-european-peers" target="_self" title="">global race</a> for artificial intelligence (AI) breakthroughs, China is definitely a key player. While 2023 has been a year of AI hype – especially for generative AI, amid the popularity of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> – the industry has been of interest to most countries for years and will only become more important.</p><p>According to the 2023 AI Index Report by the Stanford Institute for Human-Centred Artificial Intelligence, global investment in AI has significantly increased over the last decade. By 2022, private investment in AI had grown to 18 times greater than in 2013.</p><p>Back in 2017, China made AI a national priority, stating its ambition to become “the world’s premier artificial intelligence innovation centre” by 2030.</p><p>According to the State Council’s 2017 guidelines, AI should be used to promote China’s technology, economy and social welfare, maintain national security and contribute to the world. The guidelines also said: “AI should be applied in the public service and social management to build a safer, more comfortable and convenient society.”</p><p>Why are nations racing to achieve AI dominance? One reason is that AI is a foundational technology with the capacity to increase productivity, boost competitiveness and help solve social challenges.</p><p>So what does the AI industry in China look like? According to a recent Nikkei study, “China is the undisputed champion in artificial intelligence research papers … far surpassing the US in both quantity and quality”.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>China’s AI market is projected to reach US$38.89 billion this year, and will grow by a compound annual rate of 18 per cent to reach US$104.7 billion by 2030. This is less than the US market, the world’s largest at a projected US$106.5 billion this year.</p><p>In addition, China has more than 4,300 AI enterprises and at least 238 <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241659/chinese-tech-companies-frenzy-over-ai-large-language-models-huge-waste-resources-baidu-ceo-says" target="_self" title="">large language models</a> (LLMs) – deep-learning AI algorithms based on very large data sets – with tech giants such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3239981/baidu-launches-paid-version-ernie-bot-chinese-firms-rush-make-money-their-generative-ai-chatbots" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3244693/alibaba-research-unit-unveils-llm-tailored-southeast-asia-e-commerce-giant-pushes-ai-fast-growth" target="_self" title="">Alibaba</a> (owner of the South China Morning Post) <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239432/tencent-using-hunyuan-ai-model-180-services-amid-competition-local-rivals-baidu-and-alibaba" target="_self" title="">Tencent</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238698/alibaba-tencent-and-other-major-chinese-backers-invest-us342-million-start-zhipu-ai-tech-sector-sees" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239031/iflytek-says-its-large-language-model-outperforms-chatgpt-chinese-ai-firm-vows-counter-us-chip-curbs" target="_self" title="">iFlyTek</a> all venturing into the field.</p><p>It is fair to say China can indeed become a world leader in AI by 2030. This is especially given its number of AI companies, number of people working in them, advanced AI infrastructure and supportive policies.</p><p>Furthermore, China has 975 million smartphone users, by far the highest in any country, meaning it generates a vast amount of digital information – and data plays a paramount role in developing AI.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>From a regulatory perspective, China has taken a further step towards digitalisation and innovation. At the third Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation, President Xi Jinping proposed the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238360/belt-and-road-forum-china-launches-ai-framework-urging-equal-rights-and-opportunities-all-nations" target="_self" title="">Global AI Governance Initiative</a> for countries participating in the Belt and Road Initiative.</p><p>The initiative calls for a “people-centred” approach to AI (i.e., developing AI for the good of humanity and its progress), more inclusiveness and fairness in AI development so countries can benefit regardless of their political or economic situation, testing and assessment systems based on AI risk levels, and regulation reform to protect privacy and data security.</p><p>Even though Global AI Governance Initiative is not the first multilateral forum on AI, it is undoubtedly one of the bigger ones, with potential implications for the AI regulatory scene across the globe.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3216079/how-hong-kong-can-play-role-preventing-ai-armageddon" title="">How Hong Kong can play a role in preventing AI Armageddon</a></h3><p>Meanwhile, Hong Kong has a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226804/hong-kongs-financial-secretary-tells-waic-city-has-key-role-play-chinas-ai-development" target="_self" title="">key role</a> to play in China’s AI development. Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po has said the city can contribute by providing talent and funding.</p><p>At the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai in July, Chan <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226804/hong-kongs-financial-secretary-tells-waic-city-has-key-role-play-chinas-ai-development" target="_self" title="">said</a> Hong Kong had advantages when it came to attracting talent in the current geopolitical landscape: “Our universities have brought together scientific researchers from the mainland and around the world, and the Hong Kong government has given a lot of policy and financial support in the past few years.”</p><p>Moreover, Chan added, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3241373/guangdong-authorities-unveil-new-data-transfer-guidelines-amid-push-build-greater-bay-area-ai-hub" target="_self" title="">Greater Bay Area</a> has formed “the whole industrial chain of AI from research to market application”.</p><p>To sum up, China will probably become the global AI leader and Hong Kong has a role to play in this. China’s AI industry is powerful and will keep on growing. While it is still too early to say if the Global AI Governance Initiative will be a success, it is relevant that China starts leveraging the Belt and Road Initiative.</p><p><strong>Dr Oriol Caudevilla is an honorary fellow at the Asian Institute of International Financial Law at the University of Hong Kong and a board director at the Global Impact FinTech Forum. The views do not necessarily reflect those of any of the organisations the author collaborates with</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba reduces stake in GoGoX amid Hong Kong logistics services firm’s mounting losses, as it faces cutthroat competition on the mainland</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247308/alibaba-reduces-stake-gogox-amid-hong-kong-logistics-services-firms-mounting-losses-it-faces</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba Group cut its stake in GoGoX Holdings for the fourth time in two months, reducing it from 12.23% to 8.89% due to intense competition and regulatory pressure in the mainland's intracity delivery market.</li>    <li>GoGoX, operating as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, faced stiff competition, reported losses since 2018, and experienced a 90% drop in market value after its Hong Kong debut in June 2022.</li>    <li>GoGoX's founder, Chen Xiaohua, resigned as chairman in December amid ongoing challenges and a major management reshuffle.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>阿里巴巴集团在过去两个月内第四次减持GoGoX控股，由于内地城市配送市场的激烈竞争和监管压力，其持股比例从12.23%降至8.89%。</li>    <li>GoGoX，在内地以“快狗打车”经营，面临激烈竞争，自2018年以来一直亏损，在2022年6月于香港上市后市值缩水超过90%。</li>    <li>GoGoX创始人陈小华在12月辞去董事长职务，公司进行了一次重大管理层改组。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stake (n.) - 股权，股份。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, leaving it with an 8.89 per cent equity holding as of December.</p>    <p>例句讲解：stake表示“股权，股份”，通常用作名词，指投资者在公司或企业中所拥有的份额和权益。在这个例句中，stake指的是阿里巴巴集团在GoGoX控股中的股权。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>divestment (n.) - 剥离，撤资。    <p>原文例句：Hangzhou-based Alibaba’s partial divestment initiative at GoGoX comes amid its preparations for the initial public offering (IPO) of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network.</p>    <p>例句讲解：divestment表示“剥离，撤资”，用作名词，指企业或组织出售或转让其资产、业务或股权的行为。在这个例句中，divestment指的是阿里巴巴集团对GoGoX控股的局部撤资。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>unicorn (n.) - 独角兽公司。    <p>原文例句：Founded as GoGoVan in Hong Kong in 2013, GoGoX became the city’s first unicorn in 2017 after its merger with short-distance freight service platform operator 58 Suyun.</p>    <p>例句讲解：unicorn表示“独角兽公司”，用作名词，指估值超过10亿美元的初创公司。在这个例句中，unicorn指的是GoGoX在2017年与58速运合并后成为香港首家独角兽公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stay in the red - 亏损。    <p>原文例句：The company – which expects to remain in the red this year, according to its 2022 prospectus – narrowed its losses to 642.9 million yuan (US$90.37 million) in the first half of 2023, from 1.05 billion yuan in the same period in 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：stay in the red表示“亏损”，用作动词短语，指企业或组织在一定时期内的收入小于支出。在这个例句中，stay in the red是指GoGoX预计在2023年继续亏损。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>raise capital - 筹集资金。    <p>原文例句：Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month.</p>    <p>例句讲解：raise capital表示“筹集资金”，用作动词短语，指企业或组织通过各种方式获得资金。在这个例句中，raise capital是指菜鸟网络计划筹集至少10亿美元作为资金。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>initial public offering (IPO) - 首次公开募股。    <p>原文例句：Hangzhou-based Alibaba’s partial divestment initiative at GoGoX comes amid its preparations for the initial public offering (IPO) of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network.</p>    <p>例句讲解：initial public offering (IPO)表示“首次公开募股”，用作名词，指企业或组织首次向公众出售股票，以筹集资金。在这个例句中，initial public offering (IPO)指的是阿里巴巴集团为菜鸟网络进行的首次公开募股。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022. - GoGoX，在内地以“快狗打车”经营，自2022年6月于香港上市后，市值缩水超过90%。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是GoGoX has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent，其中主语是GoGoX，谓语是has seen shrink，宾语是market value。since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示自2022年6月在香港上市以来。这个句子的意思是说，GoGoX自2022年6月在香港上市后，市值缩水超过90%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 用法多样，可作定语、状语或表语。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba’s partial divestment initiative at GoGoX comes amid its preparations for the initial public offering (IPO) of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network.</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语是指由分词和其修饰语组成的短语，它可以起到定语、状语或表语的作用。在这个例句中，partial divestment initiative是现在分词短语，作定语修饰Alibaba，表示阿里巴巴的局部撤资计划。for the initial public offering (IPO) of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network是现在分词短语，作状语修饰comes，表示阿里巴巴的局部撤资计划是为了菜鸟网络的首次公开募股。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Alibaba has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, leaving it with an 8.89 per cent equity holding as of December</li>
<li>GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/2c781207-f507-4907-bf84-a2425ae1e9fa_2a843a15.jpg" /><figcaption>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022. Image: GoGoX</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> has further reduced its stake in Hong Kong-listed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/transport-and-logistics" target="_self" title="">logistics</a> service provider <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/gogovan" target="_self" title="">GoGoX Holdings</a>, which is facing cutthroat competition and regulatory pressure in the mainland’s intracity delivery courier market.</p><p>Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, slashing its equity holding to 8.89 per cent as of late December from 12.23 per cent in mid-2023, according to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong-stock-market" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong stock exchange</a> records.</p><p>Following those moves, the biggest shareholder of GoGoX remains billionaire Yao Jinbo – the founder, chairman and chief executive of mainland Chinese online classifieds giant 58.com – with a 38.69 per cent share. GoGoX co-founder Chen Xiaohua, with a 5.95 per cent stake, retains his position as the company’s third-biggest shareholder.</p><p>Founded as GoGoVan in Hong Kong in 2013, GoGoX <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/china-tech/article/2108658/gogovan-become-hong-kongs-first-us1-billion-start-after-merger-58" target="_self" title="">became the city’s first unicorn in 2017</a> after its merger with short-distance freight service platform operator 58 Suyun. Still, GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/ab59b907-e9a0-49bd-b7d8-bd576851c04c_8a6158cb.jpg" title="GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX" width="2000" /><figcaption>GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX</figcaption></figure></div><p>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3182875/gogox-shares-rise-hkex-trading-debut-listing-hong-kongs" target="_self" title="">its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022</a>. Its share price closed up 6.8 per cent to HK$0.63 on Thursday.</p><p>The company – which expects to remain in the red this year, according to its 2022 prospectus – narrowed its losses to 642.9 million yuan (US$90.37 million) in the first half of 2023, from 1.05 billion yuan in the same period in 2022.</p><p>GoGoX also went through a major management reshuffle in December, as founder Chen resigned from his chairman role. The company tapped Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, another co-founder and the co-chief executive of GoGoX, as its new chairman.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hangzhou" target="_self" title="">Hangzhou</a>-based Alibaba’s partial divestment initiative at GoGoX comes amid its preparations for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3235860/alibabas-cainiao-files-us1-billion-ipo-helping-hong-kong-land-worlds-second-biggest-listing-2023" target="_self" title="">initial public offering (IPO) of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network</a>, which submitted its A1 filing to the Hong Kong stock exchange last September.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee" class="image-inline caption" height="1298" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/daae0416-e269-4485-a0b4-cb91724c76ec_051879a6.jpg" title="Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee" width="2000" /><figcaption>Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee</figcaption></figure></div><p>Alibaba is trying to stop the bleeding with its stake cut, as its initial goal with the GoGoX investment was to gain financial returns through the listing and create synergy with its own services, according to Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangdong-based consultancy iiMedia.</p><p>“This is still a market with huge demand and many opportunities even with the price wars, similar to those in the bike-sharing and ride-hailing sectors,” Zhang said. “So the bigger problem is more likely to lie within the operation of GoGoX, which will need revolutionary measures to reverse its losses.”</p><p>At present, GoGoX is competing in a crowded on-demand cargo delivery services market on the mainland, where its hometown rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246071/chinese-tech-ipos-watch-2024-global-fast-fashion-online-retailer-shein-leads-pack" target="_self" title="">Lalatech Holdings</a> operates Huolala. Competition has become more intense in recent years after traditional logistics firms and ride-hailing companies also set up similar app-based courier delivery operations.</p><p>Chinese ride-hailing giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/didi-chuxing" target="_self" title="">Didi Chuxing</a>, for example, started its own intracity freight service in 2020 and launched its autonomous trucking business Kargobot in April last year. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3137463/full-truck-chinas-uber-trucks-raise-us157-billion-us" target="_self" title="">Full Truck Alliance</a>, known as China’s “Uber for trucks” and focused on long-haul logistics services, in April launched its Sheng Sheng brand dedicated to same-city delivery.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240676/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-will-enhance-its-overseas-presence-proposed-buyout-local-rival-best" title="">Alibaba logistics spin-off Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout</a></h3><p>Huolala currently leads the mainland’s intracity courier delivery services market with a 61 per cent share, according to Frost &amp; Sullivan data cited in the prospectus of Lalatech, which is eyeing a Hong Kong IPO.</p><p>Similar to on-demand services like ride hailing, the early stage of competition in intracity freight services has relied heavily on subsidies for users.</p><p>That “cash-burning” business model, however, has faced increased scrutiny from regulators, who recently summoned Lalatech for talks regarding drivers’ rights and unfair price cuts.</p><p>GoGoX and other courier delivery services providers have also received “reminders” from regulators about their operations in the past year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Amid US tech war, Premier Li Qiang urges China to focus on application of core technologies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese Premier Li Qiang visited Hubei province to emphasize collaboration between academia and industry, and to promote self-reliance in technology.</li>    <li>Theme: Boosting innovation and economic development in China amid the ongoing tech war with the United States.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Improving collaboration between academia and industry is crucial for fostering innovation and economic growth.</li>    <li>Main information: Li visited various companies and institutions in Hubei, including universities, semiconductor manufacturers, and chemical companies. He stressed the need for market applications of core technologies, addressing obstacles to cooperation between academia and industry, and promoting sustainability through circular economy principles.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国总理李强访问湖北省，强调产学研合作，促进科技自立。</li>    <li>主题：在中美科技战持续的情况下，促进中国的创新和经济发展。</li>    <li>观点：产学研合作是推动创新和经济发展的关键。</li>    <li>主要信息：李强访问了湖北省的多个企业和机构，包括大学、半导体制造商和化工企业。他强调了核心技术市场应用的必要性，解决了产学研合作的障碍，并通过循环经济原则促进可持续发展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>core technology (n.) - /kɔːr ˈtɛknɑːlədʒi/ 核心技术    <p>原文例句：Premier Li Qiang pushed for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive during a two-day tour of Hubei province this week    <p>例句讲解：“核心技术”是指对国家安全和经济发展具有重大意义的关键技术，是国家科技发展的基础，也是国家竞争力的重要保障。在本文中，李强总理在参观湖北省期间，强调了核心技术的市场应用。</p></li>    <li>tackle (v.) - /ˈtækəl/ 处理，解决    <p>原文例句：Given the escalating containment efforts by the United States, Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology.     <p>例句讲解：“tackle”是指处理或解决问题，通常用于处理困难或具有挑战性的情况。在本文中，鉴于美国不断升级的遏制措施，北京正在努力用国产技术来解决关键问题。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>self-reliance drive - 自力更生运动    <p>原文例句：Premier Li Qiang pushed for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive during a two-day tour of Hubei province this week, with the world’s second-largest economy in urgent need of stabilisation to quell investor concerns and lift market confidence.    <p>例句讲解：“self-reliance drive”是指一个国家或地区努力减少对其他国家或地区的依赖，增加自主权和自给自足的能力。在本文中，李强总理在访问湖北省期间，强调了中国在核心技术上的自力更生运动。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China, though, has long suffered from loose cooperation between academia, including universities and research institutes, and enterprises focused on market applications.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是China has long suffered from loose cooperation，其中主语是China，谓语是has suffered，宾语是loose cooperation。though是一个连词，表示转折或对比。between academia, including universities and research institutes, and enterprises focused on market applications是一个介词短语，作状语，表示合作关系的主体。这个句子的意思是，中国长期以来一直受到学术界，包括大学和研究机构，与专注于市场应用的企业之间的合作松散的问题。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：Premier Li Qiang pushed for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive during a two-day tour of Hubei province this week, with the world’s second-largest economy in urgent need of stabilisation to quell investor concerns and lift market confidence.    <p>语法讲解：强调句型是指在句中使用某些结构来强调句子的某个成分，使之更加突出。在本文中，李强总理在访问湖北省期间，强调了核心技术市场应用的重要性。这句话使用了强调句型“Premier Li Qiang pushed for”，将“Premier Li Qiang”这个成分强调出来，突出李强总理在推动核心技术市场应用方面发挥的重要作用。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central province of Hubei this week</li>
<li>He called for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/3a8be64d-f864-409e-859c-0eef4d4f4ae3_9e966ee7.jpg" /><figcaption>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central Hubei province this week.</figcaption></figure><p>Premier Li Qiang pushed for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive during a two-day tour of Hubei province this week, with the world’s second-largest economy in urgent need of stabilisation to quell investor concerns and lift market confidence.</p><p>“We must expedite the development of productivity driven by emerging technology, and kick-start a robust economic start of the year,” he said in a statement following the tour of the central province on Tuesday and Wednesday, according to the official Xinhua News Agency.</p><p>Hubei is a key part of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3237870/xi-jinping-tells-chinas-biggest-economic-zone-balance-growth-and-security-and-no-more-mega-projects" target="_self" title="">Yangtze River Economic Belt,</a> which is one of President Xi Jinping’s key regional development strategies. It includes 11 provinces and municipalities, and accounts for over 40 per cent of China’s population and economic size.</p><p>“We need to improve collaboration between academia and business, by introducing more precise and supportive measures, thus fluidly turning scientific research into market production,” the premier said after visiting HGLaser Engineering and semiconductor manufacturer Yangtze Memory Technologies Corporation (YMTC) in the provincial capital of Wuhan.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245242/amid-us-tech-war-china-stuck-middle-technology-trap-it-time-open-its-doors-wider" title="">Time to open its doors wider, or will China fall into a middle-technology trap?</a></h3><p>Given the escalating <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245242/amid-us-tech-war-china-stuck-middle-technology-trap-it-time-open-its-doors-wider" target="_self" title="">containment efforts by the United States,</a> Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology.</p><p>Development was also mentioned as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3244856/chinas-development-biggest-political-priority-key-econ-meeting-leaders-vow-counter-risks-lift" target="_self" title="">China’s biggest priority</a> for 2024 at the tone-setting central economic work conference in mid-December.</p><p>HGLaser introduced China’s first fully domestically produced chip-cutting machine in July, according to the WeChat account of Donghu New Technology Development Zone in Wuhan.</p><p>But unlike China’s leading memory chip maker, YMTC, HGLaser has not been sanctioned by the US. YMTC was added to the US trade blacklist <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3203494/us-adds-36-chinese-companies-export-blacklist-including-countrys-top-flash-memory-chip-maker?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">in December 2022.</a></p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>During his two-day tour, Li also inspected Wuhan University’s laboratory on high-resolution Earth observation and the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3241788/chinas-gps-beidou-navigation-system-recognised-global-standard-commercial-aviation-important" target="_self" title="">BeiDou navigation system.</a></p><p>The home-grown BeiDou system, which is China’s equivalent to the US’ Global Positioning System (GPS), can be applied to agriculture, forestry and meteorology.</p><p>China, though, has long suffered from loose cooperation between academia, including universities and research institutes, and enterprises focused on market applications.</p><p>The cooperation issues include poor communication and insufficient resource sharing, which creates obstacles affecting the transformation of inventions in China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3241788/chinas-gps-beidou-navigation-system-recognised-global-standard-commercial-aviation-important" title="">‘Important milestone’: China’s GPS-like BeiDou navigation system hits new height</a></h3><p>As of the end of 2022, only 3.9 per cent of inventions at Chinese universities were industrialised, according to the latest data available by the China National Intellectual Property Administration, compared to around 50 per cent in the US.</p><p>Li also visited water conservancy projects and a chemical company focusing on green development in Yichang, as well as a battery industrial estate set up by Guangdong Brunp Recycling Technology, a subsidiary under China’s leading lithium battery maker, Contemporary Amperex Technology (CATL).</p><p>CATL is a supplier to several carmakers, including Tesla, BMW and Volkswagen.</p><p>The premier also encouraged companies to promote China’s sustainability by focusing on the circular economy to drive companies up the value chain.</p><p>The circular economy model seeks to minimise wasting resources and environmental impact by extending the life cycle of products.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>PDD halts development of local services offering to avoid head-on competition with Meituan and Ele.me, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247286/pdd-halts-development-local-services-offering-avoid-head-competition-meituan-and-eleme-report-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese e-commerce giant PDD has halted work on its local life services offering, avoiding direct competition with rivals Meituan, Alibaba, and ByteDance. The company's local services unit, Duoduo Maicai, focused on in-store orders, but faced challenges due to low profitability. Despite the halt in local services development, Duoduo Maicai will remain operational. PDD's decision comes amidst a competitive landscape in China's local services market, estimated to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025. Leading players like Meituan, Alibaba, and ByteDance offer various services, including food delivery, ride-hailing, and hotel reservations. PDD's expansion into overseas markets continues with its budget shopping app Temu, contributing to a significant increase in revenue.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: PDD halts local services offering in China amid stiff competition.</li>    <li>Theme: PDD's strategic shift in the face of a crowded local services market in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The challenges and opportunities for tech giants in capturing a share of China's rapidly growing local services market.</li>    <li>Main information: PDD's decision to halt local services development; Duoduo Maicai's focus on in-store orders and profitability challenges; PDD's continued expansion overseas with Temu.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国电子商务巨头拼多多已暂停其本地生活服务产品，避免与美团、阿里巴巴和字节跳动等竞争对手正面交锋。该公司的本地服务部门多多买菜专注于到店订单，但由于盈利能力低而面临挑战。尽管暂停了本地服务开发，但多多买菜仍将继续运营。拼多多的这一决定是在中国本地服务市场竞争激烈的背景下做出的，预计到2025年其市场规模将达到35万亿元。美团、阿里巴巴和字节跳动等领先企业提供各种服务，包括食品配送、叫车和酒店预订。拼多多继续通过其预算购物应用程序 Temu 拓展海外市场，这为其收入的显着增长做出了贡献。  <ul>    <li>摘要：拼多多在中国暂停本地生活服务，面临激烈竞争。</li>    <li>主题：拼多多在中国本地服务市场竞争激烈的背景下做出的战略调整。</li>    <li>观点：科技巨头在中国快速增长的本地服务市场中获取份额的挑战与机遇。</li>    <li>主要信息：拼多多决定暂停本地服务开发；多多买菜专注于到店订单以及盈利能力面临的挑战；拼多多通过 Temu 继续向海外扩张。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rivalry (n.) - /ˈraɪv(ə)lri/ 竞争， соперничество。    <p>原文例句：Chinese Big Tech firms have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025. Photo: AFP</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自法语，表示“競爭，對抗”。在这个例句中，它指在中国价值35万亿元人民币的本地服务市场上，中国大型科技公司的竞争。</p></li>    <li>profitability (n.) - /prɑːfɪˈtæbɪləti/ 利润性，profitability。    <p>原文例句：According to the LatePost report, which cited a PDD executive, although the unit has become an industry leader, it is not profitable due to low gross margins.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自法语，表示“利潤性，profitability”。在这个例句中，它指多多买菜由于低毛利率而没有盈利能力。</p></li>    </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make aggressive moves - 积极进取。    <P>原文例句：ByteDance’s Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has leveraged its more than 600 million daily active users to make aggressive moves in segments of on-demand e-commerce. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由make（使，制造），aggressive（积极的，侵略性的）和moves（动议，举措）组成，表示“积极进取，采取积极行动”。在这个例句中，它指抖音利用其超过6亿的日活跃用户，在按需电子商务领域积极进取。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese Big Tech firms have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025. - 中国大型科技公司为争夺到2025年估计价值35万亿元人民币的本地服务市场份额而激烈竞争。<p>句子分析：这是一个较长的句子，结构是：Chinese Big Tech firms have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025.。其中Chinese Big Tech firms是主语，have jostled for supremacy是谓语，supremacy是宾语，a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025.是一个介词短语作状语，表示竞争的市场。这个句子的意思是说，中国大型科技公司为争夺到2025年估计价值35万亿元人民币的本地服务市场份额而激烈竞争。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 分词短语是由分词、其所修饰的名词或代词以及其他成分构成的短语。    <p>原文例句：According to estimates by market intelligence firm iResearch. - 根据市场情报公司iResearch的估计。</p>    <p>语法讲解：According to是介词，estimates是名词，by market intelligence firm iResearch是一个分词短语作状语，表示根据市场情报公司iResearch的估计。这个句子的意思是说，根据市场情报公司iResearch的估计，到2025年，中国本地服务市场规模将达到35万亿元人民币。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Despite the halt in local services development, Duoduo Maicai is nevertheless expected to remain operational despite the halting of local life services, according to Chinese news portal Sina. - 尽管暂停了本地服务开发，但多多买菜仍将继续运营。</p>    <p>语法讲解：remain是及物动词，operational 是形容词，despite the halting of local life services是一个现在完成时从句，作原因状语，表示尽管暂停了本地服务开发。这个句子的意思是说，尽管暂停了本地服务开发，但多多买菜仍将继续运营。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>PDD had planned to launch local services offering in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, report says</li>
<li>Chinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in local services market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/416b82eb-4e16-46af-8cd9-c30d0a415c2f_5ba32be4.jpg" /><figcaption>Chinese Big Tech firms have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025. Photo: AFP </figcaption></figure><p>E-commerce giant PDD Holdings has halted work on its local life services offering, avoiding head-to-head rivalry with Meituan, Alibaba Group Holding and ByteDance, whose Douyin short video app has also dipped a toe into the sector.</p><p>PDD has “completely halted [development of] the local services business”, according to Chinese media outlet LatePost. PDD did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p>PDD, whose market cap overtook Alibaba in November after the firm beat revenue estimates, had planned to launch the service – which facilitates in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets – in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, LatePost reported. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>PDD had leveraged Duoduo Maicai’s business development team of around 3,000 people to sign up bricks-and-mortar outlets, such as restaurants and tourist attractions, the report said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244976/amazon-doubles-down-china-e-commerce-strategy-rivals-shein-temu-gain-traction" title="">Amazon doubles down on China e-commerce strategy as Shein, Temu gain traction</a></h3><p>However, PDD’s management has not been completely satisfied with the performance of Duoduo Maicai, which was established in 2020 in the midst of the Covid-19 pandemic. It enables residents in a community to purchase groceries and other daily essentials in bulk, bringing prices down.</p><p>Although the unit has become an industry leader, it is not profitable due to low gross margins, according to the LatePost report, which cited a PDD executive. Duoduo Maicai is nevertheless expected to remain operational despite the halting of local life services, according to Chinese news portal Sina.</p><p>Chinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan (US$4.9 trillion) by 2025, according to estimates by market intelligence firm iResearch.</p><p>Meituan, which merged with restaurant review site Dianping and bike-sharing start-up Mobike, currently leads the sector with a range of food delivery, taxi-ride and hotel reservation services.</p><p>Alibaba has been seeking to catch up with the merger of its Koubei restaurant rating service and navigation app Amap. Alibaba’s local services segment also runs food delivery unit <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3048045/chinas-eleme-deliver-food-100-restaurants-frontline-medical-staff?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Ele.me</a>, grocery delivery service Taoxianda, and online travel platform Fliggy.</p><p>ByteDance’s Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has leveraged its more than 600 million daily active users to make <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3207434/bytedance-primes-short-video-app-douyin-challenge-meituan-demand-local-services-amid-chinas-push?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">aggressive moves in segments of on-demand e-commerce</a>. The company set up a centre dedicated to developing local services in 2020.</p><p>Abandoning the local services market comes as PDD continues to expand aggressively overseas with its Temu app, now available in the United States, Japan and several other markets. The budget shopping platform helped drive an almost doubling of PDD’s third-quarter revenue to 68.8 billion yuan.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Microsoft to show off Copilot AI key for Windows keyboards at CES, in first change to layout since 1994</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247280/microsoft-show-copilot-ai-key-windows-keyboards-ces-first-change-layout-1994</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  微软将在Windows键盘上添加一个Copilot键，允许用户立即调用人工智能助手。这将成为Windows键盘布局的首次重大改变，自微软在1994年增加Windows/开始键以来，这是首次进行重大改变。微软将Copilot键视为迈向人工智能个人计算机的一步，并已投入大量资金重新调整其产品，以利用人工智能技术。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 微软将添加一个Copilot键来立即调用人工智能助手。</li>    <li>Theme: 微软致力于人工智能，将人工智能技术集成到Windows键盘中。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 人工智能对日常工作的影响；人工智能在Windows系统中的应用前景。</li>    <li>Main information: Copilot键的位置和功能；微软对人工智能的投资和布局；人工智能技术在Windows系统中的应用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  微软在 Windows 键盘上增加了一个 Copilot 键，允许用户立即调用人工智能助手。这是自微软于 1994 年增加 Windows/开始键以来，对 Windows 键盘布局的首次重大改动。微软将 Copilot 键视为迈向人工智能个人计算机的一步，并已投入大量资金重新调整其产品，以利用人工智能技术。  <ul>    <li>摘要：微软添加 Copilot 键用于立即调用人工智能助手。</li>    <li>主题：微软致力于人工智能，将人工智能技术集成到 Windows 键盘中。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能对日常工作的影响；人工智能在 Windows 系统中的应用前景。</li>    <li>主要信息：Copilot 键的位置和功能；微软对人工智能的投资和布局；人工智能技术在 Windows 系统中的应用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sport (v.) - /spɔːrt/ 炫耀，摆弄。    <p>原文例句：The first devices to sport the new key available this month.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语desporter，意思是“玩耍，嬉戏”，在现代英语中可以表示“炫耀，摆弄”。在这个例句中，它表示第一批带有新按键的设备本月上市。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>silicon (n.) - /ˈsɪlɪkɒn/ 硅，硅片。    <p>原文例句：“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语silex，意思是“燧石”，在现代英语中可以表示“硅，硅片”。在这个例句中，它是指计算机中的硅片，即半导体材料。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>over the coming days - 在未来几天内。    <P>原文例句：Microsoft’s hardware partners will show off Windows 11 computers with the Copilot button over the coming days at the CES technology conference </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由over（在……之上），the（限定词）和coming days（即将到来的日子）构成的，表示“在未来几天内”。在这个例句中，它表示微软的硬件合作伙伴将在未来几天内在 CES 技术大会上展示带有 Copilot 按钮的 Windows 11 电脑。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>to tout - /taʊt/ 吹嘘，夸耀。    <P>原文例句：Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves, but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语totir，意思是“拉，扯”，在现代英语中可以表示“吹嘘，夸耀”。在这个例句中，它指的是微软对人工智能技术的大肆宣传。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Microsoft is adding a button to the Windows keyboard to activate its AI Copilot service, with the first devices to sport the new key available this month.- 微软正在Windows键盘上增加一个按钮以激活其人工智能Copilot服务，第一批带有新密钥的设备将于本月上市。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Microsoft is adding a button to the Windows keyboard to activate its AI Copilot service，其中主语是Microsoft，谓语是is adding，宾语是a button。with the first devices to sport the new key available this month是一个分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示第一批带有新按键的设备本月上市。这个句子的意思是说，微软正在Windows键盘上增加一个按钮以激活其人工智能Copilot服务，第一批带有新按键的设备将于本月上市。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示现在正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft is adding a button to the Windows keyboard to activate its AI Copilot service</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态现在正在进行，强调动作或状态的进行性和暂时性。在这个例句中，it表示微软正在Windows键盘上增加一个按钮来激活其人工智能Copilot服务，强调这个动作正在进行中。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>倒装句型 - 把通常放在句尾的成分提到句首，以强调或突出这个成分。    <p>原文例句：Yusuf Mehdi, Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, said in a blog announcing the change.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，结构是：强调成分 + be + 主语 + 其他。其中强调成分可以是状语、宾语等，be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化。这种句型可以强调或突出强调成分，使句子更有气势或更生动。在这个例句中，Yusuf Mehdi, Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer是一个强调成分，提到句首是为了强调微软的消费者首席营销官Yusuf Mehdi作出了这一宣布。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Start key</li>
<li>The tech giant sees 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’ and has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/e31b152f-c194-4f64-8148-b14c9b1dd6e5_1adc5e70.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft said it is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to allow users to immediately call up its artificial intelligence assistant. Photo: YouTube / Windows</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft</a> is adding a button to the Windows keyboard to activate its AI Copilot service, with the first devices to sport the new key available this month.</p><p>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Windows/Start key in 1994, underscoring the company’s commitment to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a>. Microsoft’s hardware partners will show off Windows 11 computers with the Copilot button over the coming days at the CES technology conference and, over time, it will become a required feature.</p><p>The short cut will help users create images, write emails and summarise text with the help of AI.</p><p>“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234530/microsoft-sees-booming-enterprise-ai-demand-hong-kong-amid-us-china-tech-war-threatens-cloud" title="">Microsoft touts booming enterprise AI demand in Hong Kong amid cloud push</a></h3><p>The Redmond, Washington-based company sees 2024 as “the year of the AI PC”, according to Mehdi, mirroring the budding trend among smartphone makers to tout their latest models as “AI phones”. Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves, but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets. That list now includes Windows, Office, Bing search, security software and customer and finance products. The work heavily leverages the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">GPT-4 technology</a> from OpenAI, in which Microsoft has invested US$13 billion.</p><p>For device makers, Microsoft’s push into AI services has not yet translated into a boost for sales, as the novel Copilot features are being rolled out to new and existing devices alike. Mehdi’s promise of weaving AI into hardware and silicon may signal more pressure on consumers to upgrade as Microsoft evolves and improves its AI proposition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese search engine giant Baidu to donate quantum computing facility to state-backed lab in similar move to Alibaba</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247255/chinese-search-engine-giant-baidu-donate-quantum-computing-facility-state-backed-lab-similar-move</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  In an AI race with Chinese search engine giant Baidu donating its quantum computing facility to BAQIS, e-commerce giant Alibaba Group Holding donated its quantum lab to Zhejiang University last November. The donation aimed to focus on fundamental research in AI and its application in areas such as agriculture and healthcare.  Quantum computing can solve very complex statistical problems simultaneously, making it much faster than traditional computers. Although China and the US compete for supremacy in this field, the technology is still in its initial development stage. Recently, generative AI, including ChatGPT, is rapidly spreading worldwide, generating significant revenue.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Baidu and Alibaba, two Chinese tech giants, donate their quantum computing facilities to academic institutions to advance research in AI and quantum computing.</li>    <li>Theme: The competition between China and the US in quantum computing and AI technology, and the potential applications of quantum computing in various fields.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Encouraging collaboration and innovation in quantum computing research, while acknowledging the challenges and limitations of the technology.</li>    <li>Main information: Baidu's donation of its quantum computing facility to BAQIS; Alibaba's donation of its quantum lab to Zhejiang University; the potential of quantum computing in solving complex problems; the emergence of generative AI and its impact.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  在中国人工智能竞赛中，搜索引擎巨头百度将其量子计算设施捐赠给北大信息科学研究院（BAQIS），而电子商务巨头阿里巴巴集团于去年11月已将其量子实验室捐赠给浙江大学。捐赠目的是为了专注于人工智能的基础研究及其在农业、医疗保健等领域的应用。量子计算可以通过同时进行多次计算解决非常复杂的数据问题，使其速度大大快于传统计算机。尽管中国和美国在这个领域争夺霸权，但该技术仍处于初始发展阶段。最近，包括ChatGPT在内的生成式人工智能正在世界范围内迅速传播，产生了可观的收入。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国两大科技巨头百度和阿里巴巴将各自的量子计算设施捐赠给学术机构，以推进人工智能和量子计算领域的研究。</li>    <li>主题：中国和美国在量子计算和人工智能技术领域的竞争，以及量子计算在各个领域的潜在应用。</li>    <li>观点：鼓励在量子计算研究中进行合作和创新，同时认识到该技术的挑战和局限性。</li>    <li>主要信息：百度将其量子计算设施捐赠给北大信息科学研究院；阿里巴巴将其量子实验室捐赠给浙江大学；量子计算在解决复杂问题方面的潜力；生成式人工智能的兴起及其影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>quantum computing（量子计算）——利用量子力学原理进行计算。</li>    <li>fundamental research（基础研究）——旨在获得新知识或对已有知识的更深入理解的研究活动。</li>    <li>simultaneous（同时的）——在相同的时间或时期内发生。</li>    <li>generative AI（生成式人工智能）——一种能够生成新数据或内容的人工智能系统。</li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>revenue（收入）——企业或个人通过销售商品或提供服务而获得的资金。</li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>intellectual property (IP) alliance（知识产权联盟）——由多个组织或个人组成的联盟，旨在促进知识产权的共享和保护。</li>    <li>cross-licensing（交叉授权）——允许两个或多个专利持有人相互使用对方的专利技术。</li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>top-tier global（顶尖的全球）——在全球范围内处于领先地位的。</li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Beijing-based Baidu, which was an early Chinese investor in AI applications including autonomous driving, established its quantum computing facility in early 2018. - 总部位於北京的百度是一家早期投资自動駕駛等人工智能應用的中國企業，並於2018年初建立了自己的量子計算設施。      <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Beijing-based Baidu，谓语是established，宾语是its quantum computing facility。其中，Beijing-based是形容词短语，修饰Baidu，表示百度总部位于北京。which was an early Chinese investor in AI applications including autonomous driving是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰Baidu，提供有关百度的更多信息。established its quantum computing facility in early 2018是一个时间状语，表示百度在2018年初建立了自己的量子计算设施。这个句子的意思是说，百度于2018年初建立了自己的量子计算设施。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Quantum computing is an emerging field of science that harnesses the principles of fundamental physics to solve problems too complex for traditional computers. - 量子计算是一个新兴的科学领域，它利用基础物理学的原理来解决传统计算机无法解决的复杂问题。      <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Quantum computing is a emerging field of science，其中主语是Quantum computing，谓语是is。that harnesses the principles of fundamental physics to solve problems too complex for traditional computers是一个定语从句，修饰Quantum computing，表示量子计算利用基础物理学的原理来解决传统计算机无法解决的复杂问题。这个句子的意思是说，量子计算是一个新兴的科学领域，它利用基础物理学的原理来解决传统计算机无法解决的复杂问题。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物引起的或经历的。      <p>原文例句：Beijing did not define the area as a national priority until late 2020. </p>      <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，表示北京直到2020年末才将该领域定义为国家优先事项。在这个句子中，Beijing是动作的接受者，did not define是谓语动词的过去式，area是动作的对象。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示现在正在进行或发生的动作或状态。      <p>原文例句：This was launched with a mission to “become a top-tier global quantum computing research institution in five years”. </p>      <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在进行时的句子，表示这个任务现在正在进行或发生。在这个句子中，This是主语，was launched是谓语动词的过去式，with a mission to “become a top-tier global quantum computing research institution in five years”是一个不定式短语，表示这个任务的目的是“在五年内成为一个顶级全球量子计算研究机构”。这个句子的意思是说，这个任务现在正在进行或发生，它的目的是“在五年内成为一个顶级全球量子计算研究机构”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Last March, Baidu and BAQIS jointly launched the country’s first quantum computing intellectual property alliance, with the goal of facilitating easier IP cross-licensing</li>
<li>In 2023, Alibaba’s in-house research institution Damo Academy announced it was donating its own quantum lab to Zhejiang University</li>
</ul><p>Chinese search engine giant Baidu is donating its quantum computing research facility to the Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences (BAQIS), in a move similar to one made last year by e-commerce giant Alibaba Group Holding, as both firms lock horns in the country’s artificial intelligence (AI) race.</p><p>Baidu said on Thursday it would donate its Baidu Institute for Quantum Computing and associated experiment apparatus to BAQIS, a government-backed laboratory. The two parties are currently discussing details of the donation, according to a company statement.</p><p>Beijing-based Baidu, which was an early Chinese investor in AI applications including autonomous driving, established its quantum computing facility in early 2018.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3230671/tech-war-new-us-investment-curbs-have-limited-impact-chinas-targeted-semiconductors-quantum" title="">New US investment curbs to have limited impact on China’s targeted tech sectors</a></h3><p>It was launched with a mission to “become a top-tier global quantum computing research institution in five years”, with a focus on several areas including quantum AI, quantum algorithms and quantum architecture, according to local media the Paper.</p><p>In March last year, Baidu and BAQIS jointly launched the country’s first quantum computing intellectual property (IP) alliance, with the goal of facilitating easier IP cross-licensing and innovation in the industry.</p><p>Quantum computing is an emerging field of science that harnesses the principles of fundamental physics to solve problems too complex for traditional computers.</p><p>While quantum computers are not designed to replace traditional computers, they are able to solve very complex statistical problems via simultaneous multiple calculations, making them much faster.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3224737/chinese-scientists-use-quantum-computing-simulate-black-hole" title="">Chinese scientists use quantum computing to simulate black hole</a></h3><p>China and the US have been competing for supremacy in this field in recent years, although the technology is still in its early stage of development. Beijing did not define the area as a national priority until late 2020.</p><p>Last November, Alibaba’s in-house research institution Damo Academy announced it was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242956/alibaba-donates-its-quantum-lab-local-university-shifts-focus-ai-agriculture-healthcare" target="_self" title="">donating its own quantum lab to Zhejiang University.</a> Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Damo Academy said at the time that it would become more focused on fundamental research in AI and its application in areas such as agriculture and healthcare.</p><p>While quantum computing is still a long way from achieving large-scale commercialisation, the new trend of generative AI has been spreading rapidly around the world.</p><p>OpenAI, which unleashed a new era of AI with its conversational bot ChatGPT, was reported to be generating annual revenues of US$1.6 billion, according to US digital media outlet The Information. The San-Francisco-based start-up’s rival Anthropic was forecast to rake in over US$850 billion in annualised revenue by the end of 2024.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
