<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>TikTok owner ByteDance allows employees to cash in stock options earlier under new payroll policy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249073/tiktok-owner-bytedance-allows-employees-cash-stock-options-earlier-under-new-payroll-policy</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  ByteDance, the owner of TikTok and Douyin, has modified its payroll policy to enable workers to sell their stock options more quickly. This comes at a time when the company's initial public offering (IPO) remains uncertain. Under the new policy, employees will receive 20% of their total stock awards after their first year of service, up from 15% previously. The remaining shares will be vested over a four-year period. Furthermore, annual bonuses have been standardized to three months' worth of salary, with additional merit-based payments.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: ByteDance adjusts payroll policy to accelerate stock option sales for employees.</li>    <li>Theme: ByteDance's changing compensation structure amidst delayed IPO prospects.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Balancing employee retention with financial prudence during uncertain times.</li>    <li>Main information: New vesting schedule for stock awards; standardization of annual bonuses; mixed reactions among employees.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  字节跳动，此次调整主要包括三个方面：其一，针对公司11万名员工的股票激励政策。新规下，员工在第一年服务期满后即可获得20%的期权激励，剩余部分将在之后四年内分批授予。相较以往每年授予一次的节奏，新规将授予周期缩短至按季度进行，有助于员工提早兑现激励。其二，字节在年终奖方面也进行了调整。据报道，公司决定将年终奖发放标准调整为3个月基本工资，并以现金形式发放，之前员工可以自主选择年终奖以现金或股权的形式发放。其三，产品优化部门奖金最高可达6个月，现将以薪资上调的方式进行弥补。  <ul>    <li>摘要：字节跳动调整薪资政策以加速员工股票期权销售。</li>    <li>主题：字节跳动在IPO前景不确定之际，改变薪酬结构。</li>    <li>观点：在不确定时期平衡员工保留和财务稳健。</li>    <li>主要信息：股票奖励的新授予时间表；年度奖金标准化；员工反应不一。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>looming (adj.) - /ˈluːmɪŋ/ 即将到来的，迫在眉睫的。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance spent 2023 cutting the fat, but fresh challenges loom.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“looming”意为“即将到来，迫在眉睫”，形容即将到来的挑战，可能是当前正在做的事情还没结束，就会有新的挑战接踵而至。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>adjustment (n.) - /əˈdʒʌstmənt/ 调整，调解，适应。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance has adjusted its payroll policy to allow employees to sell their stock options faster.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“adjustment”意为“调整”，指字节跳动对薪资政策做出的改变，目的是为了让员工能够更快地出售他们的股票期权。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>time-based vesting - 基于时间授予。    <p>原文例句：The four-year time-based vesting schedule is commonly adopted by businesses to encourage staff to stay longer.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“time-based vesting”意为“基于时间授予”，是指一种常见的股票期权授予方式，根据员工在公司服务的时间长短来授予期权。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>cash in - 套现。    <p>原文例句：As ByteDance remains a private firm, the only way for staff to cash in their stock options is to sell to their employer.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“cash in”意为“套现”，指员工将股票期权出售给雇主以获得现金。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>A lights display by Douyin at a shopping centre in Beijing. - 在北京的购物中心，抖音的灯光秀。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是A lights display at a shopping centre in Beijing，其中主语是A lights display，谓语是at，宾语是a shopping centre in Beijing。Douyin by是一个介词短语作状语，修饰A lights display，表示灯光秀是由抖音制作的。in Beijing是一个介词短语作状语，修饰A lights display，表示灯光秀是在北京的购物中心举行的。这个句子的意思是说，在北京的购物中心，抖音的灯光秀。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>名词性从句 - 用作名词的句子成分。    <p>原文例句：The company’s share buy-back programme has taken place twice a year since 2017. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个名词性从句，用作主语，表示公司股票回购计划的发生。主句是The company’s share buy-back programme has taken place，其中主语是The company’s share buy-back programme，谓语是has taken place。twice a year since 2017是一个时间状语，表示从2017年开始，每年两次。这个句子的意思是说，公司的股票回购计划从2017年开始，每年两次。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 把句子中一个成分放在句首，以强调该成分。    <p>原文例句：In its latest reform, ByteDance also standardised its annual bonuses to three months worth of salary.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，把状语In its latest reform放在句首，以强调这个状语。主句是ByteDance also standardised its annual bonuses to three months worth of salary，其中主语是ByteDance，谓语是standardised，宾语是its annual bonuses。to three months worth of salary是一个介词短语作宾语补语，表示将年终奖标准化为三个月的工资。这个句子的意思是说，在最新的改革中，字节跳动还将年终奖标准化为了三个月的工资。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Under the new rule, staff will receive 20 per cent of their total stock awards after their first year of service, up from 15 per cent previously</li>
<li>Annual bonuses have been standardised to three months worth of salary, all granted in cash, with additional sums to be given on merit</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/6e2d688a-a5f7-4f1f-9db6-7f74a061f980_9463801a.jpg" /><figcaption>ByteDance’s logo is seen at the company’s office in Shanghai. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>ByteDance, owner of global short video hit TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin, has adjusted its payroll policy to allow employees to sell their stock options faster, as plans for an initial public offering (IPO) remain in limbo.</p><p>Under the new rule, applicable to ByteDance’s 110,000 employees worldwide, workers will receive 20 per cent of their total stock awards after their first year of service, up from 15 per cent previously, according to two people briefed on the matter on Thursday.</p><p>Thereafter, stock grants will be vested on a quarterly basis rather than annually, as was previously the case. Workers will get 25 per cent of their equity grants after the second year, and again in the third year, with all remaining shares to be vested after the fourth year.</p><p>ByteDance did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246294/after-tiktok-owner-bytedance-cuts-fat-focus-fundamentals-social-commerce-challenges-and-us-election" title="">TikTok owner ByteDance spent 2023 cutting the fat, but fresh challenges loom</a></h3><p>The four-year time-based vesting schedule is commonly adopted by businesses to encourage staff to stay longer. As ByteDance remains a private firm, the only way for staff to cash in their stock options is to sell to their employer.</p><p>The Beijing-based company’s share buy-back programme has taken place twice a year since 2017. The most recent one, in November, priced the stock at US$160 per share.</p><p>In its latest reform, ByteDance also standardised its annual bonuses to three months worth of salary, all granted in cash, with additional sums to be given on merit and in equity form. Previously, employees had been allowed to decide if they wanted their bonuses to be given entirely or partially in cash.</p><p>The change affects thousands of employees who are used to receiving higher bonuses, such as product design and optimisation staff whose bonuses had reached the level of six months’ salary. To offset the impact, the company has promised product managers pay rises.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A lights display by Douyin at a shopping centre in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/3078775a-24a5-417f-9719-ee6ae9394d11_1126e908.jpg" title="A lights display by Douyin at a shopping centre in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" width="2000" /><figcaption>A lights display by Douyin at a shopping centre in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure></div><p>The new policy has generated mixed reactions among employees at China’s most-valuable start-up.</p><p>One person said some staff may be happy to find more flexibility if they are considering a job change in the middle of the year. Another person said now that employees could not receive all bonuses as stock options, they could be charged higher income taxes.</p><p>Prospects for a ByteDance IPO remain uncertain amid intense scrutiny in the US over TikTok’s ties to China, as well as challenges in other overseas markets.</p><p>At home, ByteDance has retreated from the video gaming sector. It confirmed earlier this month that it was in talks with multiple potential buyers, including Tencent Holdings, to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations" target="_self" title="">sell its video-game operations</a>.</p><p>In December, the unicorn offered to buy back up to US$5 billion worth of shares from existing investors, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244025/tiktok-owner-bytedance-offers-buy-back-us5-billion-worth-investor-shares-ipo-prospects-remain-slim" target="_self" title="">valuing it at US$268 billion</a>, or about 10 per cent lower than a year earlier when ByteDance organised a US$3 billion share buy-back for earlier investors, the Post reported.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>World Economic Forum: CATL’s Robin Zeng calls for setting aside geopolitical tensions to address EV battery materials shortage</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3249090/world-economic-forum-catls-robin-zeng-calls-setting-aside-geopolitical-tensions-address-ev-battery</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Robin Zeng, the founder of CATL, the world's largest battery manufacturer, emphasized the need for collaboration to address the looming shortage of battery materials, urging countries to set aside geopolitical differences and work towards creating a resilient EV battery supply chain. He highlighted CATL's advanced battery recycling technologies, with a recycling rate of 99.6% for precious metals and 91% for lithium, far higher than Europe's capacity. Zeng expressed CATL's willingness to share technologies and assist overseas carmakers in tackling battery shortages, highlighting the company's expansion and partnerships in Europe and the US. He also emphasized the importance of technological innovation and sustainable supply chains in achieving the EV transition, including the development of sodium-ion batteries and cobalt-free cathode materials to reduce dependency on critical materials like lithium.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Addressing battery material shortages and geopolitical tensions to promote the EV transition.</li>    <li>Theme: Collaboration and innovation are crucial in securing a resilient EV battery supply chain and mitigating the impact of geopolitical issues.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: CATL's founder advocates for global cooperation, technology sharing, and sustainable practices to overcome battery material shortages and accelerate the EV transition.</li>    <li>Main information: CATL's advanced battery recycling technologies, willingness to share expertise, overseas expansion, and the need for alternative battery technologies to reduce dependency on critical materials.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  宁德时代创始人曾毓群强调说，为了应对即将到来的电池材料短缺问题，各国应搁置地缘政治分歧，共同努力构建弹性的电动汽车电池供应链，这一点非常必要。他高度评价了宁德时代的电池回收技术，该技术回收贵金属的比例高达 99.6%，锂的回收比例高达 91%，远高于欧洲 70% 到 80% 的回收率。曾毓群表示，宁德时代愿意与全球汽车制造商分享技术，帮助他们解决电池短缺问题，他重点介绍了公司在欧洲和美国的扩张和合作情况。他还强调，技术创新和可持续的供应链在实现电动汽车转型方面非常重要，其中包括开发钠离子电池和无钴正极材料，以减少对锂等关键材料的依赖。  <ul>    <li>摘要：解决电池材料短缺和地缘政治紧张局势，以促进电动汽车转型。</li>    <li>主题：合作和创新对于保护弹性的电动汽车电池供应链和减轻地缘政治问题的影响至关重要。</li>    <li>观点：宁德时代创始人呼吁全球合作、技术共享和可持续做法，以克服电池材料短缺并加速电动汽车转型。</li>    <li>主要信息：宁德时代先进的电池回收技术、分享专业知识的意愿、海外扩张以及对替代电池技术以减少对关键材料的依赖性的需求。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>transition (n.) - 转变。    <p>原文例句：The EV transition requires technological innovation, a sustainable and responsible supply chain and the concerted efforts of all stakeholders. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由trans-（通过，跨越）和-ition（动作或过程）构成的，表示“从一种状态或情况到另一种状态或情况的变化”。在这个例句中，它指的是向电动汽车的转变，即从传统的燃油汽车向电动汽车的转变。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>persistent (adj.) - 持久的。    <p>原文例句：Governments and carmakers are increasingly concerned about the persistent shortages of lithium, nickel and cobalt, which could put the net-zero transition under threat. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由per-（彻底地）和-sistent（坚持）组成的，表示“持续存在的，不消逝的”。在这个例句中，它指的是持续存在的锂、镍和钴的短缺，这种短缺可能会对实现净零排放的转型构成威胁。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>technological innovation - 技术创新。    <P>原文例句：As an essential part of decarbonising the automotive ecosystem, the EV transition requires technological innovation, a sustainable and responsible supply chain and the concerted efforts of all stakeholders. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由technological（技术的）和innovation（革新）构成的，表示“在技术上进行革新，创造新的技术”。在这个例句中，它是实现电动汽车转型的一个必要部分，即在技术上进行革新，创造新的技术，以支持电动汽车的发展。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sustainable and responsible supply chain - 可持续和负责任的供应链。    <P>原文例句：As an essential part of decarbonising the automotive ecosystem, the EV transition requires technological innovation, a sustainable and responsible supply chain and the concerted efforts of all stakeholders. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由sustainable（可持续的）和responsible（负责任的）以及supply chain（供应链）构成的，表示“一个既能满足当前的需求，又能确保未来的需求的可持续发展，并且对环境和社会负责的供应链”。在这个例句中，它是实现电动汽车转型的一个必要部分，即建立一个可持续和负责任的供应链，以支持电动汽车的发展。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>As sales of EVs continue to break records around the world, governments and carmakers are increasingly concerned about the persistent shortages of lithium, nickel and cobalt, which could put the net-zero transition under threat. 随着全球电动汽车销量不断创下新纪录，各国政府和汽车制造商越来越担心锂、镍和钴持续短缺的问题，这可能会威胁到实现净零排放的转型。<p>句子分析：这是一个复句，主句是Governments and carmakers are increasingly concerned about the persistent shortages of lithium, nickel and cobalt，其中主语是Governments and carmakers，谓语是are concerned，宾语是the persistent shortages of lithium, nickel and cobalt。As sales of EVs continue to break records around the world是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示随着全球电动汽车销量不断创下新纪录。which could put the net-zero transition under threat是一个结果状语从句，修饰主句，表示这可能会威胁到实现净零排放的转型。这个句子的意思是说，随着全球电动汽车销量不断创下新纪录，各国政府和汽车制造商越来越担心锂、镍和钴持续短缺的问题，这可能会威胁到实现净零排放的转型。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>非谓语动词 - 由动词转化而来的非谓语动词，包括不定式、动名词和分词。    <p>原文例句：Robin Zeng Yuqun, founder of Contemporary Amperex Technology Ltd (CATL), the world’s largest manufacturer of batteries for electric vehicles (EVs). </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，founder和manufacturer都是非谓语动词。founder是由动词found（创立）转化而来的名词，表示“创立者”。manufacturer是由动词manufacture（制造）转化而来的名词，表示“制造商”。它们在句子中分别作主语和宾语。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>关系从句 - 用以修饰先行词的句子。    <p>原文例句：He highlighted CATL's advanced battery recycling technologies, with a recycling rate of 99.6% for precious metals and 91% for lithium, far higher than Europe's capacity. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，with a recycling rate of 99.6% for precious metals and 91% for lithium是一个关系从句，修饰先行词CATL's advanced battery recycling technologies。这个关系从句表示CATL的先进电池回收技术具有很高的回收率，其中贵金属的回收率为99.6%，锂的回收率为91%。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>‘We are fighting climate change … so whatever the geopolitical issues are, we have to find a way,’ CATL founder tells Davos panel</li>
<li>By 2042, China will no longer need to mine new mineral materials because of its mature battery recycling market: Zeng</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/4d47a3f8-9ba6-43ca-a388-054f3db16628_c80f5359.jpg" /><figcaption>CATL showcases its ‘Superfast Charging Battery Shenxing’ at the 2023 International Motor Show in Munich, in this file photo from September last year. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>Geopolitical tensions must be set aside as the world faces shortages of critical battery materials such as lithium, nickel and cobalt due to surging demand, said Robin Zeng Yuqun, founder of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248522/china-evs-catl-worlds-top-battery-maker-plans-first-plant-beijing-supply-li-auto-and-xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Contemporary Amperex Technology Ltd (CATL)</a>, the world’s largest manufacturer of batteries for electric vehicles (EVs).</p><p>Countries – from government leaders to businesses and non-governmental organisations – must collaborate to accelerate innovation in the EV battery industry to ensure a resilient supply chain, reduce dependency on critical metals and decarbonise the transport sector to tackle the climate crisis, Zeng told the World Economic Forum meeting in Davos.</p><p>“We should really avoid any geopolitical issues in [battery] recycling technologies,” he said during a panel on Wednesday. “If we can provide these recycling technologies to Europe, to the US and to the rest of the world, it’d be very easy to manage mining issues.</p><p>“The demand for critical materials might increase by five times in the next 10 years, considering the fast growth of the industry. But at the end of the day, when we achieve 100 per cent electric cars, there will be very tiny amounts of new critical materials to be mined.”</p><p>China leads the world in battery recycling technologies, an important solution for addressing battery material shortages.</p><p>For instance, Zeng told the forum that CATL currently has the capacity to recycle as much as 99.6 per cent of precious metals such as nickel, cobalt and manganese, and up to 91 per cent of lithium, higher than Europe’s capacity of 70 per cent to 80 per cent. Last year, CATL recycled 100,000 tonnes of waste batteries through its subsidiary Brump to create 13,000 tonnes of lithium carbonate, he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3244015/chinese-ev-battery-giant-catl-will-set-research-and-development-centre-hong-kong-win-government" title="">EV battery giant CATL to open research and development centre in Hong Kong</a></h3><p>But CATL’s business has been affected by the fraught relations between Beijing and the West. In December, for instance, CATL was accused of posing a national security threat in the US and was banned from a US military base. The allegation was based on a letter from US lawmakers led by Republican senator Marco Rubio that said CATL enjoyed a close relationship with the Chinese leadership in Beijing.</p><p>“We are fighting climate change … so whatever the geopolitical issues are, we have to find a way,” Zeng said during the panel.</p><p>As sales of EVs continue to break records around the world, governments and carmakers are increasingly concerned about the persistent shortages of lithium, nickel and cobalt, which could put the net-zero transition under threat.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3231316/catl-produce-worlds-fastest-ev-battery-offers-400km-driving-range-just-10-minutes-charging-keep" title="">CATL to make battery offering 400km driving range from 10-minute charge</a></h3><p>S&amp;P Global forecast that a more than 270 per cent increase in lithium production levels is needed to meet the estimated demand from the EV battery sector by 2030. Nickel and cobalt are also expected to be critical, but to a lesser degree as the deployment of iron-based chemistries will remedy their potential shortage, it said.</p><p>The Fujian-based company is willing to share its technologies and help overseas carmakers address their battery shortages, Zeng said. By 2042, China will no longer need to mine new mineral materials because of its mature battery recycling market, he added.</p><p>CATL is increasingly <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3215488/tesla-talks-catl-chinas-leading-ev-battery-maker-building-plant-us" target="_self" title="">expanding its capacity overseas</a> with plants in Germany and Hungary. It is also partnering with Amsterdam-based multinational carmaker Stellantis and Ford Motor to build battery factories in Europe and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3210118/chinas-catl-provide-know-how-fords-new-us35-billion-electric-car-battery-plant-us" target="_self" title="">Michigan in the US</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>As an essential part of decarbonising the automotive ecosystem, the EV transition requires technological innovation, a sustainable and responsible supply chain and the concerted efforts of all stakeholders, Zeng said during another panel on Thursday.</p><p>Advancing mining and refinery technology helps to increase the supply of lithium and to alleviate shortages, he said. Increasing energy density helps improve material efficiency and therefore reduces the demand for raw materials.</p><p>Finding an alternative at lower costs, such as sodium-ion batteries or cobalt-free cathode materials, is also a solution for reducing dependency on critical materials such as lithium, he said.</p><p>According to Zeng, CATL introduced its first generation of sodium-ion batteries in 2021 and is currently working on its second generation, which will give cars a driving range of 400 to 500 kilometres per charge.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>How China is making its dream of flying cars, drones and sky cities come true</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3248760/how-china-making-its-dream-flying-cars-drones-and-sky-cities-come-true</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>China's "low altitude economy" is integrating advanced aerial technologies into daily life and urban planning, supported by government policies, financial and infrastructural support.</li>    <li>Electric vehicle (EV) industry in China, led by companies like Xpeng, is showcasing flying cars and other low-altitude aircraft.</li>    <li>The Chinese government's "green aviation" plan aims to support the innovation and deployment of flying cars through economic demonstration zones, test bases, and urban infrastructure development.</li>    <li>Close public-private collaboration and financial support enable Chinese EV makers to quickly transform concept vehicles into mass products.</li>    <li>China's low-altitude economy also includes drones, with Shenzhen aiming to build a "city in the sky" and leading the way in drone technology.</li>    <li>Shenzhen has announced China's first regulations over the low-altitude economy, covering infrastructure construction, airspace management, and safety standards.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国“低空经济”将先进航空技术融入日常生活和城市规划，受到政府政策、金融和基础设施支持。</li>    <li>中国由小鹏等企业引领的电动汽车（EV）产业，正在展示低空汽车和其他低空飞行器。</li>    <li>中国政府的“绿色航空”计划旨在通过经济示范区、测试基地和城市基础设施建设等，支持低空汽车的创新和部署。</li>    <li>紧密合作和金融支持使得中国电动汽车制造商能够快速将概念车转变为量产车。</li>    <li>中国的低空经济还包括无人机，深圳力争打造“空中之城”，并且走在无人机技术的前沿。</li>    <li>深圳宣布出台中国第一部低空经济管理办法，涵盖基础设施建设、空域管理和安全标准等方面。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>demonstration (n.) - 示范，演示。    <p>原文例句：An EHang autonomous aerial vehicle conducting a demonstration flight at the Baoan District Low-Altitude Economy Investment Promotion Conference in Shenzhen last year. - 去年，一辆亿航自主航空器在深圳宝安区低空经济投资促进会上进行了一次演示飞行。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词由demonstrate（示范，演绎）和-tion（行为，动作）构成，表示“示范，演示”。在这个例句中，它指亿航自主航空器在深圳宝安区低空经济投资促进会上进行了一次演示飞行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>conducive (adj.) - 有利的，有利环境的。    <p>原文例句：China’s low-altitude economy could serve as an inspirational model for the world, showing the potential for the integration of advanced aerial technologies into everyday life and urban planning. - 中国的低空经济可以成为世界的启发性典范，展示了将先进航空技术融入日常生活和城市规划的潜力。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词由con（一起）和duce（引导）构成，表示“有利的，有利环境的”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国的低空经济可以成为世界的启发性典范，展示了将先进航空技术融入日常生活和城市规划的潜力。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>low-altitude economy - 低空经济。    <P>原文例句：Policy, financial and infrastructural support is creating a conducive ecosystem for China’s ‘low altitude economy’, integrating advanced aerial tech into everyday life and urban planning. - 政策、财政和基础设施支持正在为中国的“低空经济”创造一个有利的生态系统，将先进的航空技术融入日常生活和城市规划。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由low（低）altitude（高度）和economy（经济）构成，表示“低空经济”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国正在发展低空经济，将先进的航空技术融入日常生活和城市规划。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>make leaps - 取得飞跃。    <P>原文例句：The Chinese government is keen for companies to continue making leaps in flying vehicle technology and last year announced a “green aviation” development plan, including for electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft, or eVTOL. - 中国政府渴望企业在飞行器技术上继续取得飞跃，去年宣布了一项“绿色航空”发展计划，包括电动垂直起降飞机或 eVTOL。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由make（做）leaps（飞跃）构成，表示“取得飞跃”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国政府渴望企业在飞行器技术上继续取得飞跃。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The plan includes the construction of infrastructure to integrate flying vehicles into urban transport and the daily commute. - 该计划包括建设基础设施，将飞行器融入到城市交通和日常通勤中。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The plan includes the construction of infrastructure，其中主语是The plan，谓语是includes，宾语是the construction of infrastructure。to integrate flying vehicles into urban transport and the daily commute是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示该计划的目的是将飞行器融入到城市交通和日常通勤中。这个句子的意思是说，该计划包括建设基础设施，将飞行器融入到城市交通和日常通勤中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成或发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The model, thought to be years away from broad use, completed a successful test flight in October 2022. - 据认为距离广泛使用还有好几年的这款机型在 2022 年 10 月完成了成功的试飞。</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间点之前已经完成或发生，强调动作或状态的完成或发生。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人对事件或情况的主观态度或看法。    <p>原文例句：It is thought to be years away from broad use. - 据认为距离广泛使用还有好几年的时间。</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语态，表示说话人对事件或情况的主观态度或看法。虚拟语气有两种形式：陈述语气和疑问语气。陈述语气用to be的过去时态或过去完成时态构成，常用于表示猜测、推测或假设。疑问语气用were、had或should来构成，常用于表示建议、愿望或请求。在这个例句中，it is thought to be years away from broad use这句话用了虚拟语气，表示说话人对这款机型距离广泛使用还有好几年的时间的猜测或推测。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Policy, financial and infrastructural support is creating a conducive ecosystem for China’s ‘low altitude economy’, integrating advanced aerial tech into everyday life and urban planning</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/95294f31-6a7b-449b-ae1b-5cb7ef61e7b8_e137b3d0.jpg" /><figcaption>An EHang autonomous aerial vehicle conducting a demonstration flight at the Baoan District Low-Altitude Economy Investment Promotion Conference in Shenzhen last year. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3247413/ai-will-be-spotlight-consumer-electronics-show-2024-glasses-blind-shoes-make-you-walk-faster-and" target="_self" title="">CES 2024</a> consumer electronics show in Las Vegas last week mesmerised tech observers from around the world with more than 4,000 exhibitors, from start-ups to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" target="_self" title="">tech giants</a>. Over 1,000 companies were <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248469/alibaba-tiktok-woo-us-ai-and-live-streaming-e-commerce-ces-trade-show-setting-tone-2024" target="_self" title="">from China</a>, demonstrating the country’s impressive contributions to global technology.</p><p>In particular spotlight was China’s electric vehicle (EV) industry, after China was recently crowned the world’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247833/china-solidify-its-position-worlds-top-car-exporter-2024-it-banks-manufacturing-heft-ubs" target="_self" title="">largest car exporter</a>, accounting for about half of global EV sales. At the tech showcase, Xpeng astonished with its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" target="_self" title="">“flying car”</a>, the AeroHT eVTOL.</p><p>Built sleekly in the shape of a sports car, with propellers that unfurl, the futuristic vehicle evoked visions of flying vehicles seen in films such as <em>Star Wars</em> and <em>The Fifth Element</em>. The model, thought to be years away from broad use, completed a successful test flight in October 2022.</p><p>At CES, Xpeng also showcased its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" target="_self" title="">Land Aircraft Carrier</a>, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car, for which the company will take pre-orders in the fourth quarter this year, with deliveries to start a year later.</p><p>The Chinese government is keen for companies to continue making leaps in flying vehicle technology and last year announced a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3237594/china-outlines-vision-green-aviation-nev-industry-c919-models" target="_self" title="">“green aviation” development plan</a>, including for electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft, or eVTOL. This is part of an official strategy to support a “<a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245769/chinas-low-altitude-economy-set-take-vast-potential-could-contribute-us700-billion-2025" target="_self" title="">low altitude economy</a>”.</p><p>The low-altitude economy refers to a comprehensive realm of industries centred around civil-manned and unmanned aerial vehicles, including manufacturing, low-altitude flight operations and integrated services.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Xpeng launched its modular Land Aircraft Carrier, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/bfdb3d00-6397-4d67-82cf-a01cf3c2ebc0_00d05c81.jpg" title="Xpeng launched its modular Land Aircraft Carrier, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Xpeng launched its modular Land Aircraft Carrier, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>China’s green aviation plan presented actionable items to boost the innovation and deployment of flying cars. Important measures include setting up economic demonstration zones and test bases for low-flying aircraft. The plan includes the construction of infrastructure to integrate flying vehicles into urban transport and the daily commute.</p><p>While US flying car companies such as Kittyhawk (backed by Google founder Larry Page) shut down in 2022 due to commercialising and scaling difficulties, China’s policy support is fostering a more conducive ecosystem for nascent technologies like this to advance and benefit society.</p><p>Xpeng’s AeroHT eVTOL, for instance, unlike other flying vehicles such as by German company Volocopter and Hyundai’s Supernal, which was showcased at CES 2024, can transform between terrestrial and aerial modes.</p><p>While the inventions by Volocopter and Supernal resemble personal helicopters, Xpeng’s AeroHT eVTOL has propellers that emerge in flying mode and fold into the car’s body after use. This allows it to navigate road traffic and fit into a standard car park space.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People view the XPeng AeroHT “modular flying car” at the CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada, on January 11. Photo: AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1202" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/c8aea417-015f-46e6-bfce-0a8c0a29a6fb_e4c01113.jpg" title="People view the XPeng AeroHT “modular flying car” at the CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada, on January 11. Photo: AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>People view the XPeng AeroHT “modular flying car” at the CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada, on January 11. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>Another factor that enhances the research and development of flying cars in China is close public-private collaboration. For instance, in 2021, the Guangdong government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3125538/china-electric-cars-xpeng-receives-us77-million-investment" target="_self" title="">invested 500 million yuan</a> (US$70 million) in Xpeng. Guangdong’s Zhaoqing city has also supported Xpeng’s expansion, last year signing an investment agreement for a project worth 2 billion yuan. This type of financial and infrastructural support creates a nurturing ecosystem that enables Chinese EV makers to quickly transform concept cars into mass products.</p><p>China has highlighted the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245769/chinas-low-altitude-economy-set-take-vast-potential-could-contribute-us700-billion-2025" target="_self" title="">low-altitude economy</a> as a core industry, deserving of special attention, at its annual <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3244856/chinas-development-biggest-political-priority-key-econ-meeting-leaders-vow-counter-risks-lift" target="_self" title="">central economic work conference</a> last month, together with artificial intelligence, the digital economy, green energy, biomedicine and private space flight. The vision is for China to address its economic challenges by investing in technology and industry, unlocking the country’s growth potential.</p><p>In addition to flying cars, drones are another area of China’s low-altitude economy that promises to revolutionise its agriculture, delivery services, emergency responses and more. Already, Shenzhen, China’s hi-tech hub, has <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246693/chinas-low-altitude-economy-takes-skies-unmanned-passenger-drone-completes-maiden-commercial-flight" target="_self" title="">declared plans</a> to build itself a “city in the sky”.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/2184687/how-dji-went-university-dorm-project-worlds-biggest-drone-company" target="_self" title="">China’s DJI</a> is the world’s largest drone manufacturer with 70 per cent of the global market share. Its drone technology has helped in the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/2183603/drone-maker-dji-eyes-enterprise-business-transformation-hardware-maker" target="_self" title="">automation of farming</a>, including planning, sowing, weeding, watering and monitoring crop growth. Food delivery platform Meituan, for example, has <a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3224049/how-chinese-tech-giant-meituan-cracked-food-delivery-drone-densely-built-shenzhen-and-implications" target="_self" title="">embraced drones</a>, speeding up its commercial transactions and slashing its labour cost. In 2022, the drone industry in Shenzhen alone generated a market value of 75 billion yuan.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Shenzhen is building a grid of over 600 landing/take-off stations for low-altitude aircraft from by 2025. This will facilitate their deployment and reduce operational costs for companies. Infrastructural support is essential in this industry, especially when the aim is to promote widespread public usage.</p><p>With more companies developing flying cars and other low-altitude aircraft in China, industry regulation is also maturing. This year, Shenzhen announced China’s first regulations over the low-altitude economy. Effective from February 1, these regulations aim to standardise the construction of low-altitude flight infrastructure, coordinate the management of low-altitude airspace and flight services, and set safety standards.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/travel-leisure/article/3227433/rise-shenzhen-chinas-silicon-valley-seaside-town-fast-moving-city-secret-pockets-tranquillity" title="">The rise of Shenzhen, from seaside town to China’s Silicon Valley</a></h3><p>They stipulate the construction of a low-altitude flight service platform, providing services like flight approval applications, intelligent flight monitoring and message alerts to units or individuals conducting low-altitude flight activities.</p><p>The fierce market competition in China’s EV industry has certainly contributed to the industry’s exponential growth. But China’s institutional support also plays a role in quickly making hi-tech advancements accessible to ordinary citizens, and not just a few privileged individuals.</p><p>Although there are still gaps between the big cities and the underdeveloped areas, China’s policy principle that new technologies should improve people’s lives and livelihoods makes for a promising future.</p><p>The development of China’s low-altitude economy could serve as an inspirational model for the world, showing the potential for the integration of advanced aerial technologies into everyday life and urban planning.</p><p><strong>Gerui Wang is a visiting scholar at Stanford University</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ChatGPT boosted user numbers and time spent on Microsoft’s Bing, but fails to dent Google’s search dominance</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249012/chatgpt-boosted-user-numbers-and-time-spent-microsofts-bing-fails-dent-googles-search-dominance</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Microsoft Bing's search engine market share has increased slightly since the integration of ChatGPT, but it still lags behind Google.</li>    <li>Microsoft believes generative AI will revolutionize search and advertising, but current gains suggest AI features alone won't make Bing a major player.</li>    <li>Bing's underdog status allows it to take risks and experiment with AI tools, while Google must balance innovation with protecting its brand.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>自 ChatGPT 集成以来，微软必应搜索引擎的市场份额略有增加，但仍落后于谷歌。</li>    <li>微软认为生成式人工智能将彻底改变搜索和广告，但目前的收益表明，仅靠 AI 功能不足以使必应成为主要参与者。</li>    <li>必应的“弱势”地位使它能够冒险并尝试人工智能工具，而谷歌则必须在创新与保护其品牌之间取得平衡。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>generative AI (n.) - 生成式人工智能。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft is betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending.</p>    <p>例句讲解：generative AI 由 generative（生成）和 AI（人工智能）组成，意为“生成式人工智能”。它是指能够生成新数据的 AI 系统，例如文本、图像或代码。</p></li>    <li>rewritten (v.) - 重写，改写。    <p>原文例句：The offering does nothing to enhance Bing’s search abilities. But its addition generated a spike in usage, according to Jordi Ribas, Microsoft’s corporate vice-president of search and AI.</p>    <p>例句讲解：rewritten 由 re（重新）和 write（写）组成，意为“重写，改写”。它指的是对已经存在的内容进行修改或更新。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>allocate their search spending - 分配他们的搜索支出。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft is betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending.</p>    <p>例句讲解：allocate their search spending 由 allocate（分配）, their（他们的）, search（搜索）, spending（支出）组成，意为“分配他们的搜索支出”。它指的是广告商如何将他们的预算分配给不同的搜索引擎。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>For Microsoft, the shift is an opportunity to propel Bing forward. But the incremental gains so far make clear that buzzy AI features alone probably will not transform it into a formidable search player.    <p>句子剖析：主语 For Microsoft；谓语 is an opportunity to propel Bing forward. But the incremental gains so far make clear that buzzy AI features alone probably will not transform it into a formidable search player；定语从句：the shift；状语：so far；宾语：it。</p>    <p>句子含义：对微软来说，这种转变是一个推动必应前进的机会。但到目前为止的渐进式增长表明，仅靠热门的人工智能功能可能不足以将其转变为强大的搜索参与者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The retooling of search by both technology giants reflects a shared conviction that generative AI will fundamentally change the way people seek and receive answers online.    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是由“have/has + been + 过去分词”构成，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在例句中，“has been + studying”表示“一直持续到现在的动作”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The market share of Microsoft’s search engine rose less than 1 percentage point since the ChatGPT announcement</li>
<li>Microsoft is betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/f958a4b4-35bc-43ff-923e-d785b6e45d9d_84591264.jpg" /><figcaption>The Microsoft Bing app. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>When Microsoft announced it was baking ChatGPT into its Bing search engine last February, bullish analysts declared the move an “iPhone moment” that could upend the search market and chip away at Google’s dominance.</p><p>“The entire search category is now going through a sea change,” chief executive officer Satya Nadella said at the time. “That opportunity comes very few times.”</p><p>Almost a year later, the sea has yet to change.</p><p>The new Bing – powered by OpenAI’s generative artificial intelligence (AI) technology – dazzled internet users with conversational replies to queries asked in a natural way.</p><p>But Microsoft’s search engine ended 2023 with just 3.4 per cent of the global search market, according to data analytics firm StatCounter, up less than 1 percentage point since the ChatGPT announcement.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1416" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/081a8c1b-b628-46e0-b984-6897c60d3a63_b10d85c3.jpg" title="Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>Bing has long struggled for relevance and attracted more mockery than recognition over the years as a serious alternative to Google. Multiple rebrandings and redesigns since its 2009 debut did little to boost Bing’s popularity.</p><p>A month before Microsoft infused the search engine with generative AI, people were spending 33 per cent less time using it than they had 12 months earlier, according to SensorTower.</p><p>The ChatGPT reboot at least helped reverse those declines. In the second quarter of 2023, US monthly active users more than doubled year over year to 3.1 million, according to a Bloomberg Intelligence analysis of SensorTower mobile app data.</p><p>Overall, users were spending 84 per cent more time on the search engine, the data show. By year-end, Bing’s monthly active users had increased steadily to 4.4 million, according to SensorTower.</p><p>To build on the momentum, Microsoft has been adding more AI tools to Bing. In October, the company integrated the latest version of OpenAI’s image-generating model, DALL-E 3. Visitors can use it to create realistic-looking images with simple text prompts.</p><p>The offering does nothing to enhance Bing’s search abilities. But its addition generated a spike in usage, according to Jordi Ribas, Microsoft’s corporate vice-president of search and AI.</p><p>“We noticed an increase in usage by 10 times and that took us by surprise because if you think about it, DALL-E 2 was already quite good,” he said in an interview. “It really made a difference in the engagement and the users that came to our product.”</p><p>Yusuf Mehdi, Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, declined to specify how many active users Bing has.</p><p>“Look, it’s still early days and new behaviours are being built,” he said. “We’re still learning new things, but have millions and millions of people using the new tools.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" class="image-inline caption" height="1257" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/751251ee-f99c-42e4-bf34-d1aa45378b12_882215d8.jpg" title="Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" width="2000" /><figcaption>Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even as the Bing team adds crowd-pleasers, Google has been racing to develop its own AI tools.</p><p>In May, it launched an experimental version of its search engine called the “search generative experience”, which delivers conversational responses atop the familiar list of links. Dubbed SGE for short, it is still not widely available. However, Google plans to embed its most powerful large language model, Gemini, into SGE sometime this year.</p><p>The Alphabet division also retains considerable advantages. It has more than 90 per cent of the market and is the default search engine on Apple hardware, including iPhones, giving Google crucial critical mass. The more people who use it, the more the search engine knows and the more Google can use that data to deliver and rank results in a way people find useful.</p><p>The retooling of search by both technology giants reflects a shared conviction that generative AI will fundamentally change the way people seek and receive answers online.</p><p>For Microsoft, the shift is an opportunity to propel Bing forward. But the incremental gains so far make clear that buzzy AI features alone probably will not transform it into a formidable search player.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>“We are at the gold rush moment when it comes to AI and search,” said Shane Greenstein, an economist and professor at Harvard Business School, who has studied the commercialisation of the internet.</p><p>“At the moment, I doubt AI will move the needle because, in search, you need a flywheel: the more searches you have, the better answers are. Google is the only firm who has this dynamic well-established.”</p><p>Still, Greenstein said Bing, being the underdog, has more latitude to experiment. “Google has to be careful not to hurt its brand and product when it comes to testing new AI tools,” he said. “Bing can afford to take the risk. It has nothing to lose.”</p><p>Microsoft is also betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending. The current ad model rests on costs-per-click, but AI-powered searches are getting consumers to answers faster and more directly without a litany of blue links, according to marketing chief Mehdi.</p><p>“We have advertisers telling us they’re getting better outcomes as a result of our AI efforts and are deeply interested in how this works,” he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Reddit aims to launch IPO in March, sources say, in first stock market debut of a social media firm since 2019</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248999/reddit-aims-launch-ipo-march-sources-say-first-stock-market-debut-social-media-firm-2019</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Reddit, a popular social media platform, plans to launch its initial public offering (IPO) in March 2023. The company, which generates revenue primarily through advertising, has yet to turn a profit, but hopes to attract investors interested in its user base and potential growth. This IPO would be the first major social media company to go public since Pinterest in 2019.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Reddit plans to conduct its IPO in March 2023.</li>    <li>Theme: Reddit's IPO amidst competition in the social media market and its efforts to attract investors.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of Reddit's IPO as a test of investor confidence in social media companies and the potential impact on Reddit's user base.</li>    <li>Main information: Reddit's IPO timeline and valuation, its advertising revenue growth, and the company's decision to charge for access to its application programming interface, which caused controversy among some users.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  社交媒体平台 Reddit 计划于 2023 年 3 月进行首次公开募股 (IPO)，该公司主要通过广告创收，目前尚未盈利，但希望吸引对用户群和潜在增长感兴趣的投资者。自 2019 年 Pinterest 上市以来，这将是第一家大型社交媒体公司公开上市。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Reddit 计划于 2023 年 3 月进行首次公开募股。</li>    <li>主题：Reddit 在社交媒体市场竞争中进行 IPO，以及吸引投资者的努力。</li>    <li>观点：Reddit 的 IPO 作为投资者对社交媒体公司信心考验的重要性，以及对 Reddit 用户群的潜在影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：Reddit 的 IPO 时间表和估值、广告收入增长，以及公司决定对访问其应用程序编程接口收费，这在一些用户中引发争议。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>niche (n.) - /niːʃ/ 市场细分，壁龛。    <p>原文例句：Reddit became best known for its niche discussion groups and its users voting “up” or “down” on the content posted by other members.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“niche”这个词源于法语，意思是“壁龛”，在英语中它被用来指“市场细分”，即针对特定消费者群体或需求而创建的市场。在这个例句中，它指的是Reddit的特色讨论小组，这些小组专注于不同的主题，吸引了有共同兴趣的用户。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev(j)əˌnuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：The company generates its revenue primarily through advertising and also offers premium access for US$5.99 per month. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“revenue”这个词源于古法语“revenu”，意思是“返回”，在英语中它被用来指“收入”或“收益”。在这个例句中，它指的是Reddit通过广告和高级访问获取的收入。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>go public - 上市。    <p>原文例句：Reddit is hoping to launch its IPO as soon as March, according to people familiar with the matter.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“go public”是一个动词短语，意思是“上市”，指公司通过首次公开募股的方式向公众出售股票，募集资金。在这个例句中，它指的是Reddit计划在3月份进行首次公开募股。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>pull the IPO trigger - 启动首次公开募股。    <p>原文例句：The company held back from pulling the IPO trigger until it came closer to profitability. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“pull the IPO trigger”是一个形象的比喻，意思是“启动首次公开募股”，指公司决定开始首次公开募股的过程。在这个例句中，它指的是Reddit在接近盈利时才决定启动首次公开募股。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Reddit said last year it would charge companies for access to its application programming interface, which is used by technology companies to train large-language models used in artificial intelligence. - Reddit 去年表示，它将向公司收取访问其应用程序编程接口的费用，该接口被科技公司用于训练人工智能中使用的大语言模型。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Reddit said it would charge companies for access to its application programming interface，其中主语是Reddit，谓语是said，宾语是it would charge companies for access to its application programming interface。which is used by technology companies to train large-language models used in artificial intelligence是一个定语从句，修饰application programming interface，表示这一接口被科技公司用于训练人工智能中使用的大语言模型。这个句子的意思是说，Reddit去年表示，它将向公司收取访问其应用程序编程接口的费用，该接口被科技公司用于训练人工智能中使用的大语言模型。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>一般过去时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Reddit held back from pulling the IPO trigger until it came closer to profitability. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，表示过去发生的动作或状态。结构是：主语 + 过去式动词。其中动词的过去式形式需要根据动词的词形变化规则来确定。在这个例句中，动词pull的过去式形式是pulled，表示Reddit在接近盈利时才决定启动首次公开募股。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Shares of Meta Platforms, which operates Facebook, have more than trebled in value over the past 12 months.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。在这个例句中，它表示Meta Platforms的股价在过去的12个月里上涨了两倍多，强调这一上涨趋势从过去持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Reddit is planning to make its public filing in February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March, sources say</li>
<li>The company, which generates its revenue primarily through advertising, has yet to turn a profit, co-founder Steve Huffman said last June</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/ceae1676-ec0a-453c-90b8-caa1d3c7da8a_ae468ee4.jpg" /><figcaption>Reddit is hoping to launch its IPO as soon as March, according to people familiar with the matter. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Social media platform Reddit has drawn up detailed plans to launch its initial public offering (IPO) in March, moving forward with a listing it has been eyeing for more than three years, according to people familiar with the matter.</p><p>It would be the first IPO of a major social media company since Pinterest’s debut in 2019, and would come as Reddit and its peers face stiff competition for advertising dollars from the likes of TikTok and Facebook.</p><p>The offering would also test the willingness of some Reddit users to back the company’s stock market debut. Many investors posting on the platform have helped fuel dozens of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3119536/gamestop-frenzy-how-reddit-nerds-sparked-wall" target="_self" title="">“meme” stock rallies</a> in the last three years, from retailer GameStop to movie operator AMC Entertainment Holdings.</p><p>Reddit, which filed confidentially for its IPO in December 2021, is planning to make its public filing in late February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March, two of the sources said.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP" class="image-inline caption" height="2581" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/a63256c8-0f58-4d2a-92c3-f97df71b18ee_a6b611e2.jpg" title="Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP" width="2000" /><figcaption>Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The San Francisco-based company, which was valued at about US$10 billion in a funding round in 2021, is seeking to sell about 10 per cent of its shares in the IPO, the sources added. It will decide on what IPO valuation it will pursue closer to the time of the listing, according to the sources.</p><p>The sources cautioned that Reddit’s IPO plans could be pushed back, as has happened in the past, and asked not to be identified discussing confidential deliberations.</p><p>A Reddit spokesperson declined to comment.</p><p>Founded in 2005 by web developer Steve Huffman and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3087871/reddit-co-founder-alexis-ohanian-resigns-urges-black-board" target="_self" title="">entrepreneur Alexis Ohanian</a>, Reddit became best known for its niche discussion groups and its users voting “up” or “down” on the content posted by other members.</p><p>The company, which generates its revenue primarily through advertising and also offers premium access for US$5.99 per month, has yet to turn a profit, Huffman said in a Reddit post last June.</p><p>In the past, the company has attributed its losses to investing in the platform and its users engaging less with advertising on its site than other social media.</p><p>The company held back from pulling the IPO trigger until it came closer to profitability. Bouts of market volatility that shut down the IPO market for much of the last two years also contributed to it delaying its plans.</p><p>Reddit expected to generate slightly over US$800 million in advertising revenue in 2023, up more than 20 per cent from a year earlier, The Information reported last month.</p><p>Reddit said last year it would charge companies for access to its application programming interface, which is used by technology companies to train <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">large-language models used in artificial intelligence</a>. The move upset some users who rely on third-party apps to access Reddit.</p><p>Large social media stocks have rebounded over the past year, driven mainly by a rally in technology stocks as interest rates peaked. Shares of Meta Platforms, which operates Facebook, have more than trebled in value over the past 12 months, while Snap’s shares rose 60 per cent over the same period.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China remains a tough market to stage a comeback for world’s former top smartphone vendor Samsung</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248969/china-remains-tough-market-stage-comeback-worlds-former-top-smartphone-vendor-samsung</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of China's smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets. </li>    <li>The company has closed various production bases in China, including its last smartphone plant in Huizhou and last personal computer factory in Suzhou. </li>    <li>Samsung's sharpened focus on the premium segment of China's smartphone market has managed to attract a growing number of new users.</li>    <li>Samsung's outlook in the world's second-largest economy is complicated by the ongoing US-China tech war and has been downsizing its production facilities in China. </li>    <li>The company is still ambitious to return to its former glory on the mainland, seeking to revive and bring change to the global smartphone market with the newly launched Galaxy 24 series featuring artificial intelligence technology. </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结</h2>  <ul>    <li>三星已将重点转向中国智能手机市场的高端领域，尤其是其可折叠手机。</li>    <li>该公司已关闭中国境内的多家生产基地，包括位于广东省惠州市的最后一处智能手机工厂和位于江苏省苏州市的最后一处个人电脑工厂。</li>    <li>三星对中国智能手机市场高端领域的关注吸引了越来越多的新用户。</li>    <li>三星在全球第二大经济体的市场前景受到持续的中美科技战的复杂影响，并已在中国缩小其生产设施和员工数量。</li>    <li>该公司仍有志于在中国重现昔日辉煌，寻求通过新推出的具有人工智能技术的 Galaxy 24 系列来重振并改变全球智能手机市场。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>foldable (adj.) - /ˈfoʊːldəbəl/ 可折叠的，可弯曲的。    <p>原文例句：Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland’s smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由fold（折叠）和-able（可……的）构成，表示“可折叠的，可弯曲的”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星的可折叠手机，这是一种可以使用铰链进行折叠的智能手机。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>consolidator (n.) - /kənˈsɑːlədeɪtər/ 巩固者，合并者。    <p>原文例句：Some analysts believe that companies like Lenovo and Xiaomi can become consolidators and eventually compete directly with Samsung and Apple.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由consolidate（巩固，合并）和-or（人）构成，表示“巩固者，合并者”。在这个例句中，它指的是联想和小米等公司，这些公司通过收购其他公司来扩大自己的市场份额和范围。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言。    <P>原文例句：Samsung is also a strong rival for Apple in terms of patent disputes.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示三星也是苹果在专利纠纷方面的一个强劲对手。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland’s smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets.<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Samsung，谓语是has shifted，宾语是its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland’s smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets。shifted是一个过去分词，表示一种完成或改变状态的动词，在这里表示三星已经将重点转向了中国大陆智能手机市场的高端领域，特别是可折叠手机。focus是一个名词，表示“焦点，重点”。segment是一个名词，表示“领域，部门”。mainland是一个名词，表示“大陆”。smartphone是一个名词，表示“智能手机”。market是一个名词，表示“市场”。particularly是一个副词，表示“特别地，尤其是”。foldable是一个形容词，表示“可折叠的，可弯曲的”。handset是一个名词，表示“手机”。这个句子的意思是说，三星已经将重点转向了中国大陆智能手机市场的高端领域，特别是可折叠手机。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland’s smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是指从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。其结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。在这个例句中，has shifted表示三星已经将重点转向了中国大陆智能手机市场的高端领域，这一动作从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调这一动作的持续性和未完成性。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland’s smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets</li>
<li>The company has closed various production bases in China, including its last smartphone plant in Huizhou and last personal computer factory in Suzhou</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/bf4f1a5f-c528-4f08-b9c2-588ca952e7dd_16946b13.jpg" /><figcaption>Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy Z Fold5 and Z Flip5 3D foldable smartphone displays are seen at the company’s flagship store in Shanghai on October 23, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>A resident of eastern Jiangsu province, 48-year-old Shen Ling used to own a number of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphones</a> in the 2010s, attracted by the devices’ well-designed appearance and popularity among consumers across mainland China.</p><p>“It was once an age of glory for Samsung in China, when so many of my friends were using the brand for its high-end market standing,” Shen said. “I also chose to buy a Samsung phone at that time for the same reason.”</p><p>But Samsung’s strong run in the world’s largest smartphone market took a disastrous turn in late 2016, when the company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/enterprises/article/2027114/samsung-permanently-shuts-note-7-production" target="_self" title="">permanently halted production of its Galaxy Note 7 handset</a> amid increased concerns about the device catching fire. That followed widespread criticism from Chinese consumers after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/2023711/samsung-insists-note-7-china-safe-after-6th-reported-battery-explosion" target="_self" title="">several incidents where the handset’s battery exploded</a>. In January 2017, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korean</a> electronics giant admitted that those incidents were <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/2064560/samsungs-galaxy-note-7-fires-caused-battery-design-manufacturing-issues" target="_self" title="">caused by battery manufacturing and design issues</a> after an internal investigation.</p><p>“The harm to Samsung’s image was devastating,” Shen said. “It made me unsure if I could trust the quality of its future handsets.” Shen finally decided to switch to a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> smartphone in 2020.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/08229e1a-0baf-487d-a0d0-871525d20f84_5b21820d.jpg" title="A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook</figcaption></figure></div><p>Samsung was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/social-gadgets/article/2134770/how-samsung-went-no-1-also-ran-chinas-smartphone-market-and-can" target="_self" title="">once the biggest smartphone vendor on the mainland</a>, with a market share of about 20 per cent in 2013. The Korean firm ranked dead last among the market’s major handset vendors by 2018, with just a 1 per cent share and has since remained around that level.</p><p>The company’s fall in mainland China’s smartphone market was partly due to “a combination of inappropriate operations leading to a damaged reputation”, said Ivan Lam, a senior analyst for Counterpoint Research. He also indicated that major Chinese vendors – including Huawei, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/vivo" target="_self" title="">Vivo</a> – rose to become strong domestic and international competitors.</p><p>But Samsung, which was unseated by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> in terms of annual smartphone shipments worldwide <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above?utm_source=rss_feed" target="_self" title="">for the first time in 2023</a>, still has ambitions to return to its former glory on the mainland.</p><p>While Huawei has largely retreated from the Korean market primarily because of local consumers’ loyalty to homegrown Android handsets, Samsung is slowly trying to stage a comeback in China. Still, Samsung’s mission has become more difficult amid the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248694/china-gdp-beijings-long-do-list-boost-economy-2024" target="_self" title="">shaky post-pandemic economic recovery</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>“Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end market in China, particularly with the introduction of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foldable-phones" target="_self" title="">foldable models</a>,” Counterpoint’s Lam said. “The current strategy for Samsung in China appears to be characterised by conservatism, stability and continuity.”</p><p>Over the past few years, Samsung continued to launch new smartphone models on the mainland. It has also been working with some Chinese Big Tech companies, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>, to help step up localisation of its smartphones’ content ecosystem.</p><p>The reason Samsung did not fully leave mainland China was obvious: the country remains the world’s largest computing, smartphone, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> market. Continued operation in the vast market has become more important for the Korean conglomerate, as its sales have been hit hard by sluggish global consumer electronics demand.</p><p>In its earnings guidance released last week, Samsung said it expected to post its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" target="_self" title="">sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit</a>. The company estimated that its operating earnings for 2023 plunged 84.9 per cent year on year to 6.54 trillion won (US$4.86 billion), while annual revenue was expected to drop 14.6 per cent to 258.16 trillion won.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" title="">Samsung profit tumbles 35% as chip weakness persists</a></h3><p>Samsung’s sharpened focus on the premium segment of China’s smartphone market has managed to attract a growing number of new users. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a> university student Cynthia Xia, for example, started using Samsung’s foldable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3192963/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-4-vs-motorola-razr-foldable-smartphones" target="_self" title="">Galaxy Z Flip 4</a> smartphone in 2022.</p><p>“I was totally attracted by the design and its flexibility to adopt customised settings,” Xia said. “I think no other brands are doing as well as Samsung in foldable phones.”</p><p>Still, Samsung’s outlook in the world’s second-largest economy is complicated by the ongoing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/us-china-tech-war-rivalry/news" target="_self" title="">US-China tech war</a>, which has cast a shadow over the Korean firm’s supply chain network on the mainland.</p><p>Although Samsung, along with memory chip rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3218776/south-korean-chip-maker-sk-hynix-denies-reports-it-selling-firms-dalian-flash-memory-fab-assuring" target="_self" title="">SK Hynix</a>, last year secured indefinite waivers from Washington to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3237485/tech-war-us-waiver-china-export-restrictions-advanced-semiconductor-equipment-south-koreas-samsung" target="_self" title="">ship advanced semiconductor-manufacturing equipment</a> for their China plants, the tech conglomerate has been downsizing its production facilities and number of employees in the country.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3014564/samsungs-last-china-smartphone-factory-closing-raising" title="">Will closing last Samsung smartphone factory hurt China’s role in global value chain?</a></h3><p>Over the past several years, Samsung has shut down multiple production bases on the mainland, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3014564/samsungs-last-china-smartphone-factory-closing-raising" target="_self" title="">its last smartphone plant</a> in Huizhou, a city in southern Guangdong province, and last personal computer factory in Suzhou, a bustling metropolis in Jiangsu. The company had 17,891 employees on the mainland in 2022, which was in stark contrast to its peak of 63,316 in 2013, according to Samsung’s Sustainability Report.</p><p>The relocation of Samsung’s factories from the mainland showed how the company “strategically deprioritised the Chinese market, resulting in reduced investment in brand and channel building”, Counterpoint’s Lam said.</p><p>With Samsung’s recently launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248863/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-smartphones-come-google-gemini-ai-technology-fight-apple-iphones" target="_self" title="">Galaxy 24 series, which features artificial intelligence technology</a>, all eyes are on how the company can help revive and bring change to the global smartphone market.</p><p>Still, that new handset is not expected to make a big splash on the mainland.</p><p>“None of my friends are using Samsung’s phones nowadays, so why wouldn’t I stick with domestic brands when they offer similar functionalities at lower prices?” Shen from Jiangsu said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei releases preview version of updated HarmonyOS Next as it accelerates shift away from Android</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248956/huawei-releases-preview-version-updated-harmonyos-next-it-accelerates-shift-away-android</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Huawei unveiled the developer preview version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS Next, marking a significant milestone in its rivalry with Android and iOS in the Chinese market. The company aims to create a robust ecosystem for HarmonyOS by collaborating with industry partners, educational institutions, and investing in innovation. With over 5,000 partners targeted by 2024, HarmonyOS is poised to surpass iOS as the second-largest operating system in China this year, according to TechInsights.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei introduces HarmonyOS Next, aiming to challenge Android and iOS in China.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's HarmonyOS Next targets software developers and aims to expand its ecosystem, with sights set on becoming the second-largest operating system in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: HarmonyOS Next's potential to disrupt the mobile operating system market in China.</li>    <li>Main information: Release of HarmonyOS Next developer preview version; partnership with 200+ companies and plans to involve 5,000 partners; investment of 7 billion yuan in app development and tools; collaboration with educational institutions to cultivate developers; projected growth to become China's second-largest operating system.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  华为发布了其自研移动操作系统 HarmonyOS Next 的开发者预览版本，标志着其在与 Android 和 iOS 的中国市场争夺战中迈出了重要的一步。该公司计划通过与行业合作伙伴、教育机构合作，投资创新等方式创建一个强大的 HarmonyOS 生态圈。根据 TechInsights 早些时候的报告，HarmonyOS 有望在今年超过 iOS 成为中国第二大操作系统，目标在 2024 年之前争取到 5000 个合作伙伴。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为推出 HarmonyOS Next，瞄准中国市场挑战安卓和 iOS。</li>    <li>主题：华为推出 HarmonyOS Next，面向软件开发者，旨在扩大其生态系统，目标成为中国第二大操作系统。</li>    <li>观点：HarmonyOS Next 有潜力颠覆中国移动操作系统市场。</li>    <li>主要信息：HarmonyOS Next 开发者预览版发布；与 200 多家公司合作，并计划吸引 5000 个合作伙伴；在应用开发和工具方面投资 70 亿元人民币；与教育机构合作培养开发者；预计将成为中国第二大操作系统。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sanction (v.) - /ˈsæŋ(k)ʃən/ 制裁，批准。    <p>原文例句：Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由sancio（神圣的）和sanctus（神圣的）组成，意为“使神圣，使合法，批准”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国政府禁止华为从没有华盛顿批准的供应商那里购买软件、芯片和其他美国原产技术的行为。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>robust (adj.) - /rəʊˈbʌst/ 强壮的，坚固的。    <p>原文例句：To encourage development of a more robust ecosystem for HarmonyOS, Huawei will also work with more than 280 companies and over 300 educational institutions to cultivate developers for the operating system, according to a company release. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由robur（橡树）和robur（橡树）组成，意为“橡树，橡树的，坚固的”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为努力与280多家公司和300多家教育机构合作，为其操作系统培养开发人员，以鼓励和发展更加健壮的HarmonyOS生态系统。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>native (adj.) - /ˈneɪtɪv/ 本地的，原生的。    <p>原文例句：Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native HarmonyOS apps, and the company aims to get 5,000 partners on board by the end of 2024, Zhu Yonggang, president of Huawei Consumer Business Cloud Services, said at the Thursday event. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由natus（出生，天然的）和natus（出生，天然的）组成，意为“天然的，本地的”。在这个例句中，它指的是200多家行业合作伙伴已经开始开发HarmonyOS原生应用程序，华为的目标是在2024年底之前吸引5000家合作伙伴加盟。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>at its developer conference - 在其开发者大会上。    <p>原文例句：The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday, and the operating system will be launched for commercial use in the fourth quarter of this year, Huawei said at its developer conference. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由at（在，于），its（它的），developer（开发者）和conference（会议）组成，表示“在它的开发者大会上”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为在其开发者大会上宣布，HarmonyOS Next的开发者预览版已于周四向编码人员开放，而该操作系统将于今年第四季度面向商用推出。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>HarmonyOS native apps - HarmonyOS原生应用程序。    <p>原文例句：Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native HarmonyOS apps, and the company aims to get 5,000 partners on board by the end of 2024, Zhu Yonggang, president of Huawei Consumer Business Cloud Services, said at the Thursday event. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由HarmonyOS（鸿蒙操作系统），native（本地的，原生的）和apps（应用程序）组成，表示“HarmonyOS原生应用程序”。在这个例句中，它指的是200多家行业合作伙伴已经开始开发HarmonyOS原生应用程序，华为的目标是在2024年底之前吸引5000家合作伙伴加盟。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>HarmonyOS’s official Weibo account - HarmonyOS官方微博账号。    <p>原文例句：Huawei will also invest 7 billion yuan (US$983 million) to support innovation in areas from HarmonyOS native apps to Software Development Kit (SDK), a toolset used to help developers build apps for a particular platform, according to posts published on HarmonyOS’s official Weibo account. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由HarmonyOS’s（HarmonyOS的），official（官方的）和Weibo account（微博账号）组成，表示“HarmonyOS官方微博账号”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为将在HarmonyOS原生应用程序到软件开发工具包（SDK）等领域投资70亿元人民币来支持创新，根据HarmonyOS官方微博账号发布的帖子。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment with its P60 Pro model, HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year, according to a report by TechInsights earlier this month.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year，其中主语是HarmonyOS，谓语是projected to surpass，宾语是Apple’s iOS。Driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment with its P60 Pro model是一个非谓语动词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示HarmonyOS的增长是由华为带着P60 Pro型号手机重返5G智能手机领域推动的。according to a report by TechInsights earlier this month是一个介词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示这个预测是根据TechInsights本月早些时候的一份报告得出的。这个句子的意思是说，根据TechInsights本月早些时候的一份报告，由于华为带着P60 Pro型号手机重返5G智能手机领域，HarmonyOS预计将超过苹果的iOS，成为今年中国第二大操作系统。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>主动语态和被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是主动或被动。    <p>原文例句：The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个主动语态的句子，表示动作或状态是由  <ul><li>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday</li>
<li>Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native apps for HarmonyOS</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/f12f9442-2dd3-4de3-a881-63405dd3a097_26cc2667.jpg" /><figcaption>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has unveiled the latest version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS for developers, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant takes on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p><p>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday, and the operating system will be launched for commercial use in the fourth quarter of this year, Huawei said at its developer conference.</p><p>HarmonyOS Next, billed as a major upgrade to Huawei’s mobile platform, will no longer support Android-based applications.</p><p>Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native HarmonyOS apps, and the company aims to get 5,000 partners on board by the end of 2024, Zhu Yonggang, president of Huawei Consumer Business Cloud Services, said at the Thursday event.</p><p>Meituan, the delivery services giant, has already finished the first version of its HarmonyOS app in the first batch of development partners, while other internet firms, such as lifestyle social media platform Xiaohongshu and online mapping service Amap, have also made progress.</p><p>Amap is backed by Alibaba Group Holding, the Post’s owner.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" title="">Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights</a></h3><p>To encourage development of a more robust ecosystem for HarmonyOS, Huawei will also work with more than 280 companies and over 300 educational institutions to cultivate developers for the operating system, according to a company release.</p><p>Huawei will also invest 7 billion yuan (US$983 million) to support innovation in areas from HarmonyOS native apps to Software Development Kit (SDK), a toolset used to help developers build apps for a particular platform, according to posts published on HarmonyOS’s official Weibo account.</p><p>The adoption of HarmonyOS has been growing. Since its launch in August 2019, HarmonyOS currently runs on over 800 million devices, according to Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group, speaking at the Thursday event.</p><p>HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List. Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>Driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment with its P60 Pro model, HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year, according to a report by TechInsights earlier this month.</p><p><em>Additional reporting by Ben Jiang</em></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sheryl Sandberg, who helped turn Facebook into digital advertising empire, to leave company board</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248977/sheryl-sandberg-who-helped-turn-facebook-digital-advertising-empire-leave-company-board</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Meta’s chief operating officer Sheryl Sandberg announced her resignation from the company’s board of directors, marking the end of her 14-and-a-half-year tenure at Facebook and Meta. Sandberg, who joined Facebook in 2008, played a crucial role in transforming the company from a tech startup to a digital advertising giant. During her time at Meta, she faced criticism for the company’s missteps, but she also implemented numerous initiatives to promote gender equality and empower women.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Sheryl Sandberg steps down from Meta's board, ending a transformative era at the social media giant.</li>    <li>Theme: Sandberg's departure from Meta signifies the end of an era marked by both successes and controversies, as well as her dedication to advancing women's leadership and empowerment.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Sandberg's resignation highlights the evolving landscape of Silicon Valley and the changing roles of tech executives in shaping the digital world.</li>    <li>Main information: Sandberg's decision to step down after 14 years at Meta; her contributions to the company's growth and transformation; her facing of criticism for the company’s missteps; her commitment to initiatives promoting gender equality.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Meta首席运营官谢丽尔·桑德伯格宣布辞去公司董事会职务，结束了她在Facebook和Meta长达14年半的任期。 桑德伯格于2008年加入Facebook，在将公司从一家科技初创公司转型为数字广告巨头方面发挥了至关重要的作用。在她任职Meta期间，她曾因公司的失误而受到批评，但她还实施了许多倡议来促进性别平等并赋予女性权力。  <ul>    <li>摘要：谢丽尔·桑德伯格辞去Meta董事会职务，标志着社交媒体巨头一个变革时代的结束。</li>    <li>主题：桑德伯格从Meta离职标志着一个既有成功也有争议的时代的结束，以及她致力于促进妇女领导力和赋权。</li>    <li>观点：桑德伯格的辞职凸显了硅谷不断变化的格局以及科技高管在塑造数字世界中的角色正在发生变化。</li>    <li>主要信息：桑德伯格决定在Meta工作14年后辞职；她为公司增长和转型做出的贡献；她因公司失误而面临批评；她致力于促进性别平等的举措。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>initiative (n.) - /ɪˈnɪʃətɪv/ ابتكار، مبادرة.    <p>原文例句：Sandberg announced that she was launching a girls’ leadership programme through her foundation to respond to what she calls stubborn gender inequities. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于initiate，意为“先导的，推动”。在这个例句中，它指的是桑德伯格通过她的基金会启动的旨在解决性别不平等的女孩领导力计划。</p></li>    <li>curriculum (n.) - 课程，课程表。    <p>原文例句：The programme includes a middle-school curriculum as well as resources for adults. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于currere，意为“奔跑”，表示“课程”。在这个例句中，它指的是这个项目包含的初中课程以及为成年人提供的资源。</p></li>    <li>foundation (n.) - /faʊnˈdeɪʃən/ مؤسسة، أساس.    <p>原文例句：Lean In is a project of the Sandberg Goldberg Bernthal Family Foundation, the private foundation Sandberg started with her late husband, Dave Goldberg. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于found，意为“奠基，基础”，表示“基础，基金会”。在这个例句中，它指的是桑德伯格和她的已故丈夫戴夫·戈德堡一起创建的私人基金会——桑德伯格戈德堡伯恩塔尔家族基金会。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>digital advertising empire - 数字广告帝国。    <p>原文例句：Sheryl Sandberg, who helped to transform Facebook from a tech start-up into a digital advertising empire, will step down from the board of Meta, Facebook’s parent company.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由digital（数字的），advertising（广告）和empire（帝国）组成，表示“数字广告帝国”。在这个例句中，它指的是桑德伯格帮助将Facebook从一家科技初创公司转型为一家数字广告帝国，从而使Facebook成为数字广告领域的主导者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>During her time at Meta, she faced criticism for the company’s missteps, but she also implemented numerous initiatives to promote gender equality and empower women. - 在她任职Meta期间，她曾因公司的失误而受到批评，但她还实施了许多倡议来促进性别平等并赋予女性权力。<p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，主句是she faced criticism for the company’s missteps，其中主语是she，谓语是faced，宾语是criticism for the company’s missteps。but she also implemented numerous initiatives to promote gender equality and empower women是一个并列连词but连接的并列句，其中主语是she，谓语是implemented，宾语是numerous initiatives to promote gender equality and empower women。这个句子的意思是说，在她在Meta任职期间，她因公司的失误而受到批评，但她还实施了许多倡议来促进性别平等并赋予女性权力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达假设、愿望、可能性等。    <p>原文例句：Sandberg said she will continue to serve as an adviser to the company. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种语言形式，用于表达与事实相反或不确定的情况。在这个例句中，虚拟语气用在will continue to serve as an adviser to the company中，表示桑德伯格将继续担任公司的顾问，尽管她已经辞去了董事会职务。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Sandberg left Google to join Facebook in 2008, 4 years before the company went public and was the number 2 executive at Meta under CEO Mark Zuckerberg</li>
<li>She stepped down as COO of Meta in 2022 but remained a member of the company board. Sandberg said she will continue to serve as an adviser to Meta</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/d30b61be-bbea-4726-8b0d-53c086bdcd8c_20c6fc3d.jpg" /><figcaption>Sheryl Sandberg on Thursday announced she is stepping down from the board of Meta. Photo: Reuters </figcaption></figure><p>Sheryl Sandberg, who helped to transform Facebook from a tech start-up into a digital advertising empire, will step down from the board of Meta, Facebook’s parent company.</p><p>“With a heart filled with gratitude and a mind filled with memories, I let the Meta board know that I will not stand for re-election this May,” Sandberg wrote in a Facebook post.</p><p>Sandberg left <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/google" target="_self" title="">Google</a> to join <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/facebook" target="_self" title="">Facebook</a> in 2008, four years before the company went public. As the number two executive at Meta under CEO <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mark-zuckerberg" target="_self" title="">Mark Zuckerberg</a>, Sandberg also took a lot of heat for some of its biggest missteps.</p><p>She stepped down as chief operating officer of Meta in 2022 but remained a member of the company board. She had served as COO of Facebook, and then Meta, for 14-and-a-half years and as a board member for 12 years.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3180106/key-facebook-force-sheryl-sandberg-stepping-down" title="">Key Facebook force Sheryl Sandberg stepping down</a></h3><p>“Under Mark’s leadership, Javi Olivan, Justin Osofsky, Nicola Mendelsohn and their teams have proven beyond a doubt that the Meta business is strong and well-positioned for the future, so this feels like the right time to step away,” Sandberg wrote.</p><p>Sandberg said she will continue to serve as an adviser to the company.</p><p>Last year Sandberg announced that she was launching a girls’ leadership programme through her foundation to respond to what she calls stubborn gender inequities. The programme includes a middle-school curriculum as well as resources for adults.</p><p>Lean In is a project of the Sandberg Goldberg Bernthal Family Foundation, the private foundation Sandberg started with her late husband, Dave Goldberg.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese state media calls for crackdown on deceptive pricing in live-streaming e-commerce</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248938/chinese-state-media-calls-crackdown-deceptive-pricing-live-streaming-e-commerce</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2><ul><li>China's state media Economic Daily calls for stricter scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live-streaming e-commerce.</li><li>Misleading practices like fake price comparisons and exaggerations are seen as price fraud and have hurt consumers' rights and damaged the reputation of the live-streaming industry.</li><li>The government is urged to improve regulations, clarify responsibilities, and increase penalties for price fraud in this sector.</li><li>E-commerce platforms need to take the initiative to crack down on dubious live-streaming practices and impose harsher penalties.</li><li>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen rapid growth in China, accounting for 18.1% of all online shopping in the first 10 months of 2023.</li></ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>  <li>中国国内媒体《经济日报》呼吁对直播带货中存在的虚假定价等欺骗性行为加强监管。</li>  <li>伪造价格对比、夸大宣传等误导行为被视为价格欺诈，损害了消费者的权益，也破坏了直播电商行业的声誉。</li>  <li>文章呼吁政府完善相关法规，明确电子商务平台、商家、主播等主体的责任，加大对价格欺诈行为的处罚力度。</li>  <li>针对电商直播中存在的乱象，电子商务平台应主动作为，加大对违规行为的处罚力度，甚至可以禁止多次违规的商家。</li>  <li>近年来直播电商发展迅速，2023年前10个月，直播电商销售额同比增长58.9%，达到2.2万亿元，占我国网络购物总额的18.1%。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>scrutiny (n.) - /ˈskruːtɪni/ 审查，仔细检查。      <P>原文例句：In an opinion piece on Thursday, the official media blasted some live streamers for misleading consumers with tactics such as fake price comparisons and exaggerations, adding that more than 5,000 broadcasters were penalised last year for price manipulation.</P>      <p>例句讲解：解释：scrutiny表示“仔细检查，审查”。在这个例句中，它描述了官方媒体对一些直播主播使用虚假价格比较和夸大宣传等误导消费者的行为进行了批评，并指出去年有超过5000名主播因价格操纵而受到处罚。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fraudulent (adj.) - /frɔːdʒ.jʊ.lənt/ 欺诈的，骗人的。    <P>原文例句：The paper said misconduct in the live-streaming industry, from fraudulent advertising to misleading pricing, should be addressed and punished for the sake of the sector’s healthy and sustained growth.</P>    <p>例句讲解：解释：fraudulent表示“欺诈的，骗人的”。在这个例句中，它描述了《人民日报》指出了直播行业中存在的问题，包括欺诈性广告和虚假定价等行为，并认为应该解决和惩罚这些问题，以确保该行业健康和可持续地发展。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>crack down on - 打击，取缔。    <P>原文例句：E-commerce platforms need to take the initiative to crack down on dubious live-streaming practices, the article urged, and they should impose harsher penalties and even ban those that repeatedly commit violations.</P>    <p>例句讲解：解释：“crack down on”是一个动词词组，意思是“打击，取缔”。在这个例句中，它表示电子商务平台需要主动打击可疑的直播行为，并且应该对多次违规的行为者处以更严厉的惩罚，甚至可以禁止其直播。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In an opinion piece on Thursday, the official media blasted some live streamers for misleading consumers with tactics such as fake price comparisons and exaggerations, adding that more than 5,000 broadcasters were penalised last year for price manipulation. - 在周四的一篇评论文章中，官方媒体批评了一些使用虚假价格比较和夸大宣传等手段误导消费者的主播，并补充说去年有超过5000名主播因价格操纵而受到处罚。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The official media blasted some live streamers for misleading consumers，其中主语是The official media，谓语是blasted，宾语是some live streamers。with tactics such as fake price comparisons and exaggerations是一个介词短语作状语，表示使用虚假价格比较和夸大宣传等手段。adding that more than 5,000 broadcasters were penalised last year for price manipulation是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示补充说明，即去年有超过5000名主播因价格操纵而受到处罚。这个句子的意思是说，在周四的一篇评论文章中，官方媒体批评了一些使用虚假价格比较和夸大宣传等手段误导消费者的主播，并补充说去年有超过5000名主播因价格操纵而受到处罚。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态发生在主句谓语动作或状态之前。    <p>原文例句：Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去分词短语作状语，由Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts组成，表示在文章所说的价格欺诈行为发生之前，商家伪造或抬高了原价并提供虚假折扣。这个分词短语作状语是为了说明价格欺诈行为是如何发生的。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态发生在主句谓语动作或状态的同时。    <p>原文例句：The government is urged to improve regulations, clarify responsibilities, and increase penalties for price fraud in this sector.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在分词短语作状语，由improve regulations, clarify responsibilities, and increase penalties组成，表示在政府被敦促改进法规、明确责任和增加对价格欺诈的处罚的同时，这些动作或状态也在发生。这个分词短语作状语是为了说明政府在改进法规、明确责任和增加处罚时应该同时做的事情。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission</li>
<li>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years, with sales jumping 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/da9d4337-120c-49ea-b242-d1f49b587f18_9b05dbbb.jpg" /><figcaption>TikTok Shop and an online influencer prepare for a live-streaming session of selling goods from the Consumer Electronics Show (CES), Las Vegas, January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese state media Economic Daily has called for tighter regulatory scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming, as the country’s e-commerce players increasingly turn to these campaigns to lure customers and drive sales amid fierce competition and macro-economic headwinds.</p><p>In an opinion piece on Thursday, the official media blasted some live streamers for misleading consumers with tactics such as fake price comparisons and exaggerations, adding that more than 5,000 broadcasters were penalised last year for price manipulation.</p><p>Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247160/bytedances-douyin-makes-instant-refunds-mandatory-following-pdd-taobao-and-jdcom-amid-fierce-e" title="">Chinese version of TikTok makes instant refunds mandatory amid e-commerce rivalry</a></h3><p>“Live-streaming e-commerce has become an important part of the digital economy, but price fraud and other chaotic practices have hindered the high-quality development of the economy,” the article said. These tactics not only hurt consumers’ rights but also damaged the reputation of the live-streaming industry, it added.</p><p>The Economic Daily urged the government to improve regulations for the sector and increase the penalties for price fraud. The responsibilities of e-commerce platforms, merchants and broadcasters should be clarified in these cases, the media outlet said.</p><p>E-commerce platforms need to take the initiative to crack down on dubious live-streaming practices, the article urged, and they should impose harsher penalties and even ban those that repeatedly commit violations.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above" title="">Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with broad iPhone discounts</a></h3><p>The call for stricter oversight comes as e-commerce platforms are increasingly relying on live streaming to attract consumers amid fierce domestic competition and weaker consumer spending.</p><p>Key players in the field include traditional e-commerce platforms such as Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao, as well as short video apps like ByteDance’s Douyin and Kuaishou Technology. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years. Sales in the sector jumped 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023, reaching 2.2 trillion yuan (US$311 billion), accounting for 18.1 per cent of all online shopping in China, according to data from the Ministry of Commerce.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1309" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/754d97a1-4883-40b6-b755-d027eb815bcf_113d2948.jpg" title="A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>However, the rapid growth has invited increasing regulatory attention. In April 2021, the Cyberspace Administration of China and six other regulators jointly released rules aimed at curbing malpractice such as selling fake products, falsifying view numbers and promoting pyramid schemes.</p><p>Last month People’s Daily, the chief mouthpiece of the Chinese Communist Party, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3243239/peoples-daily-calls-tighter-control-live-streaming-e-commerce-china-controversies-mount" target="_self" title="">called for tighter oversight of live-streaming e-commerce</a>. The paper said misconduct in the live-streaming industry, from fraudulent advertising to misleading pricing, should be addressed and punished for the sake of the sector’s healthy and sustained growth.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TikTok owner ByteDance looks to expand in US, Canada and Australia amid rising competition and political headwinds</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248932/tiktok-owner-bytedance-looks-expand-us-canada-and-australia-amid-rising-competition-and-political</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance is expanding its operations in the US, Canada, and Australia by opening new offices and hiring talent to work on TikTok and other apps. </li>    <li>The company is also transferring employees from other regions to its new locations to support the expansion. </li>    <li>ByteDance is doing this to maintain its business momentum amid rising competition and political headwinds.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>字节跳动在美国、加拿大和澳大利亚扩张业务，开设新办事处并招聘人才，以开发包括抖音在内的应用程序。</li>    <li>公司还将其他地区的部分员工调往新办事处，以支持扩张计划。</li>    <li>字节跳动这样做是为了在日益激烈的竞争和政治逆风中保持业务发展势头。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>subsidiary (n.) - /sʌbˈsɪdɪərɪ/ 子公司。    <p>原文例句：TikTok owner ByteDance looks to expand in Silicon Valley in the United States, and also in Canada and Australia as the sector continues to boom and amid rising competition. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词表示“子公司，附属公司”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok的所有者字节跳动公司。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>headwind (n.) - /ˈhɛdwɪnd/ 逆风。    <p>原文例句：The expansion comes as ByteDance seeks to maintain its business momentum amid rising competition and political headwinds.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词表示“逆风，阻力”。在这个例句中，它指的是字节跳动在业务发展中遇到的竞争和政治阻力。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>maintain momentum - 保持势头。    <P>原文例句：The expansion comes as ByteDance seeks to maintain its business momentum amid rising competition and political headwinds.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由maintain（保持）和momentum（势头）组成，表示“保持势头”。在这个例句中，它表示字节跳动希望在竞争和政治逆风中保持业务发展的势头。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance did not immediately respond to a request for comment. - 字节跳动没有立即回复置评请求。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的否定句，主语是ByteDance，谓语是did not respond，宾语是一个不定代词a request for comment。immediately是一个修饰语，表示“立即，立刻”。在这个例句中，did not respond是一个过去时态，表示“没有回复”。not是否定助动词。整个句子的意思是说，字节跳动没有立即回复置评请求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>介词短语 - 表示动作或状态发生的时间、地点、方式等。    <p>原文例句：The company is in talks to sublease a large office building on Coleman Avenue in San Jose, California.</p>    <p>语法讲解：介词短语是由介词和名词或代词组成的，表示动作或状态发生的时间、地点、方式等。介词有in、on、at、by、from、to、with等。在这个例句中，in San Jose, California是一个介词短语，表示“在加利福尼亚州圣何塞”。介词in表示地点，名词短语San Jose, California表示地点。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>动名词短语 - 由动名词加修饰语构成的短语，可以作主语、宾语、表语等。    <p>原文例句：For example, it has relocated 120 people working across product, operations, and research and development from China to Canada and Australia.</p>    <p>语法讲解：动名词短语是由动名词加修饰语构成的短语。动名词是由动词加-ing构成的，表示动作或状态，可以用作名词。在这个例句中，working across product, operations, and research and development是一个动名词短语，表示“从事产品、运营和研发工作”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In addition to US, ByteDance is looking for talent to join its expanded operations in Canada and Australia to work on apps including TikTok</li>
<li>ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/6f1c2685-a484-454c-8ac6-1cbb7274395c_40276094.jpg" /><figcaption>TikTok owner ByteDance looks to expand in US, Canada and Australia. Photo: AFP  </figcaption></figure><p>ByteDance, which owns global short video hit TikTok, is looking to expand in Silicon Valley in the United States, and also in Canada and Australia as the sector continues to boom and amid rising competition.</p><p>The company is in talks to sublease a large office building on Coleman Avenue in San Jose, California, according to a report by the Bay Area News Group last week.</p><p>Meanwhile, it is looking for talent – mainly computer engineers – to join its expanded operations in Canada and Australia to work on apps including TikTok, video editor CapCut and social media and lifestyle app Lemon8, according to a report on Thursday by Chinese media outlet Jiemian.</p><p>In addition to hiring new staff, ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations. For example, it has relocated 120 people working across product, operations, and research and development from China to Canada and Australia, according to the Jiemian report.</p><p>ByteDance did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>The expansion comes as ByteDance seeks to maintain its business momentum amid rising competition and political headwinds.</p><p>Its flagship app TikTok said in 2021 that its monthly active users (MAU) surpassed 1 billion. CapCut’s MAU has hit 200 million, according to a March report by Baijing, a blog that covers Chinese companies doing business overseas.</p><p>Although ByteDance has retreated in video gaming, it is doubling down on e-commerce by leveraging the popularity of TikTok. It has set an ambitious target for its US shopping operation to increase tenfold to US$17.5 billion in gross merchandise volume this year, according to a Bloomberg report.</p><p>The company’s overall revenue expanded around 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing projected growth at Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings, according to a December Bloomberg report.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance’s Douyin steps up oversight of live-streaming hosts, closing 290,000 accounts last year for ‘harmful’ content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248921/bytedances-douyin-steps-oversight-live-streaming-hosts-closing-290000-accounts-last-year-harmful</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  China's live-streaming sector faces more regulations due to vulgar language and harassment by hosts during live sessions. In 2023, Douyin cracked down on inappropriate practices by shutting down over 290,000 host accounts, including top influencers, in a move to weed out harmful activities like vulgar content, improper challenges, and enticing viewers to spend more. The crackdown also targeted scams, gambling, and pornography, with nearly two-thirds of banned hosts involved in such activities. Concerns over improper challenge games and enticed spending were also raised by Chinese authorities. Meanwhile, Douyin has introduced measures to improve host management, including a host rating system and support for verified hosts generating positive content. The rising trend of using AI-powered virtual hosts has also prompted the platform to implement stricter rules for transparency. To protect vulnerable demographics, Douyin has restricted minors from hosting live sessions and tipping other hosts, while it intervenes when elderly users are susceptible to online scams.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese authorities take action to regulate the live-streaming sector, curbing harmful practices and promoting responsible online behavior.</li>    <li>Theme: Douyin's live-streaming crackdown tackles vulgar language, harassment, inappropriate challenges, and enticed spending in live sessions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of regulating online content to protect users from scams, gambling, and pornography.</li>    <li>Main information: The shutdown of over 290,000 host accounts for inappropriate practices; focus on weeding out harmful activities such as vulgar content and improper challenges; nearly two-thirds of banned hosts involved in scams, gambling, and pornography; Douyin's efforts in improving host management and protecting vulnerable users.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  中国加强直播行业监管整顿，制止直播过程中主播存在低俗语言及骚扰行为。2023年，抖音为根除低俗内容、不当挑战、诱导观众消费等有害行为，对平台主播及直播行为采取进一步管控，全年共处罚超过29万个主播账号，其中包括部分头部账号。同时对以诈骗、赌博、色情为目的的违规直播行为重拳出击，近三分之二的封禁账号都与这些违规行为有关。中国网信办在过去两年也多次提及不当挑战游戏、诱导消费等问题，开展专项活动整治网络恶意内容。此外，抖音的整治还针对平台内推广诈骗、赌博、色情内容的主播账号，其中近三成的账号，多达19万人，涉及上述行为。经过与警方联动协作，目前已有超过300名违法嫌疑人被抓获。以安徽籍女主播为例，她本人对于抖音的整治行动表示认可，但同时也指出，打击违规成本过高，一些老主播很容易被误伤，封禁一个经营多年的主播账号，代价太大。至于如何避免误伤，实现精细化运营，抖音暂时还没有给出回复。今年9月，抖音开始对所有主播进行信用分评级管理，违规严重程度、主播的影响力大小、历史违规情况等因素都会被考虑；同时对于直播过程中产生优质内容的主播，抖音将给予相应扶持，配合主播打造“健康、积极”的直播氛围。抖音也关注到虚拟主播的崛起，为虚拟主播相关账号增设了更多的身份审核机制，要求虚拟主播背后的个人信息更加透明。去年6月，有超7.65亿中国网民访问了各种直播服务，占全国10.79亿网民的约70%，直播服务已覆盖全年龄段人群，其中未成年人和老年人是抖音特别关注的群体。抖音对未成年人直播打赏等行为进行了限制，并针对老年人在抖音上遭遇网络诈骗行为提供了干预手段。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国加强对直播行业的监管，打击低俗语言、骚扰等行为，维护健康积极的直播生态。</li>    <li>主题：抖音整治直播中的低俗语言、骚扰、不当挑战、诱导消费行为。</li>    <li>观点：加强网络内容监管，保护用户免受诈骗、赌博、色情等危害。</li>    <li>主要信息：整治超过29万个主播账号；重点根除低俗内容、不当挑战等有害行为；近三分之二的封禁账号涉及诈骗、赌博、色情行为；抖音对主播精细化管理，保护弱势群体。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>crack down on (v.) - 严厉打击。    <p>原文例句：Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was worth US$98.2 billion in 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：crack down on是固定搭配，意为“严厉打击”。在这个例句中，it表示中国监管机构对价值982亿美元的直播行业进行了严厉打击。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>harmful (adj.) - 有害的，有害的。    <p>原文例句：The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts, including some top influencers, as the platform sought to weed out practices it deemed harmful, such as outdoor live-streaming containing vulgar content, improper challenge games among hosts, as well as enticing viewers to spend more money, the company said in a post published to its official WeChat account on Tuesday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：harmful是形容词，意为“有害的”。在这个例句中，it表示该公司在2023年开展的直播监管行动关闭了29万多个主播账户，其中包括一些顶级名流，因为该平台试图消除它认为有害的做法，例如包含低俗内容的户外直播、主播之间的不当挑战游戏以及诱使观众花费更多钱。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>incentive (n.) - 激励，鼓励。    <p>原文例句：That included a plant that will make mechanical enclosures for iPhones and a semiconductor equipment manufacturing plant it will operate with Applied Materials, the government said at the time. </p>    <p>例句讲解：incentive是名词，意为“动机”。在这个例句中，it表示该政府声称该土地的一部分将用来建造一个为iPhone生产机械外壳的工厂，以及一个与应用材料公司合作运营的半导体设备制造工厂。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Firefox is also very competitive in terms of performance and speed. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示Firefox在性能和速度方面也很有竞争力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The announcement, made in an exchange filing in Taiwan late Monday, did not give any further details, saying only that the investment was for “operational needs”. - 这一消息是在周一晚间台湾的一份交易文件中公布的，没有透露任何进一步的细节，只是说这笔投资是为了“运营需求”。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The announcement did not give any further details，其中主语是The announcement，谓语是did not give，宾语是any further details。made in an exchange filing in Taiwan late Monday是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰The announcement，表示这一消息是在周一晚间台湾的一份交易文件中公布的。saying only that the investment was for “operational needs”是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示这一消息的内容或方式，即只是说这笔投资是为了“运营需求”。这个句子的意思是说，这一消息没有透露任何进一步的细节，只是说这笔投资是为了“运营需求”，这一消息是在周一晚间台湾的一份交易文件中公布的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式 - 表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：In a joint effort with local authorities in Changsha, the capital of central Hunan province, Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year.</p>    <p>语法讲解：动词不定式是由to加动词原形构成的，表示动作或状态。在这个例句中，to remove表示删除。to remove the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts是一个动词不定式作目的语，表示删除10  <ul><li>Some outdoor live streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions</li>
<li>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was worth US$98.2 billion in 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/9a28fd60-8832-4f14-b4c3-01657424e7b0_5660f465.jpg" /><figcaption>An advertisement for Douyin seen at a bus stop in China. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure><p>Douyin, the sibling app of ByteDance’s global short video hit TikTok, said it imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023 to rein in inappropriate practices.</p><p>The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts, including some top influencers, as the platform sought to weed out practices it deemed harmful, such as outdoor live-streaming containing vulgar content, improper challenge games among hosts, as well as enticing viewers to spend more money, the company said in a post published to its official WeChat account on Tuesday.</p><p>Some outdoor live-streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions, according to the post.</p><p>In a joint effort with local authorities in Changsha, the capital of central Hunan province, Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>The banned hosts had engaged in “harmful” outdoor live-streaming activities in Changsha, a major tourist spot which attracted live-streamers who wanted to broadcast its bustling nightlife.</p><p>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was forecast to have made 700 billion yuan (US$98.2 billion) in 2023, according to Statista.</p><p>Improper challenge games and enticed spending were also issues raised by the Cyberspace Administration of China over the past two years, as part of the top Chinese internet watchdog’s campaigns to root out malicious online content.</p><p>Douyin’s live-streaming clampdown also targeted live streamers who were promoting scams, gambling and pornographic content on the platform. Nearly two-thirds, or 190,000, of the hosts banned last year were involved in such activities.</p><p>Through efforts with the Chinese police, more than 300 criminal suspects have been arrested, Douyin said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3247755/watched-strangers-china-mother-live-streams-son-9-doing-homework-says-he-works-3-times-faster" title="">Chinese mother live-streams son, 9, doing homework so he is not distracted</a></h3><p>However, the crackdown is taking a toll on some hosts, who said they were incidentally banned as part of the measures. One host, based in the central province of Anhui, who requested anonymity for fear of retribution by the platform, told the South China Morning Post on Thursday that while she agreed with Douyin’s efforts, it was easy for some veteran hosts to get caught up, adding that losing access to accounts that took years to build up is a high cost.</p><p>Douyin did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Thursday.</p><p>The platform has also been improving the way it manages live streamers. Last September, it introduced a revamped host rating system to take into account multiple factors such as the severity of the alleged malpractice, and the hosts’ level of influence and popularity.</p><p>Meanwhile, verified hosts generating “good” content would be rewarded with support from Douyin to create a “healthy and positive” environment for live-streaming activities.</p><p>The rising trend of using artificial intelligence (AI)-powered virtual hosts has also caught Douyin’s attention. The short video app has put in place rules to require more transparency, with additional identity checks required for the individuals behind such virtual hosts.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1332" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0141f38e-3a8c-4a47-84ce-4ce5fdc448a3_3366798b.jpg" title="In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>More than 765 million Chinese internet users had tuned into live sessions across various online services as of last June, according to data from the China Internet Network Information Centre, representing around 70 per cent of the country’s total 1.079 billion netizens.</p><p>The widespread adoption of live-streaming services has included people of all ages, including minors and seniors, two groups which Douyin said it was paying special attention to.</p><p>Douyin has introduced restrictions that prevent minors from hosting live sessions or tipping other hosts. It also has safeguards that intervene when its system determines an elderly user is falling prey to online scams on its app.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Private-equity investors to return to China in search of M&amp;A deals in 2024, Bain &amp; Co says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248937/private-equity-investors-return-china-search-ma-deals-2024-bain-co-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>   <li>Global and domestic private-equity investors are making a comeback to the Chinese mergers and acquisitions (M&A) market amid hopes of economic recovery.</li>    <li>Despite declining deal volumes in 2023, mainland China still accounted for 41% of deals in the Asia-Pacific region.</li>    <li>Private-equity investors are shifting their focus to improving profitability and revenue rather than chasing high valuations.</li>    <li>New talks on potential deals have resurfaced since the second half of 2023, but deal conclusions may take longer.</li>    <li>China's M&A activity is expected to rebound in 2024, driven by government stimulus and a recovering economy.</li>    <li>Middle Eastern countries are showing interest in inbound M&A deals in China, particularly in new energy and electric vehicles.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>全球和国内私募股权投资者重返中国并购市场，寄希望于经济复苏。</li>    <li>尽管 2023 年交易量下降，中国内地仍占亚太地区交易量的 41%。</li>    <li>私募股权投资者正在将重点从追逐高估值转向提高盈利能力和收入。</li>    <li>自 2023 年下半年以来，关于潜在交易的新谈判已重新浮出水面，但达成交易可能需要更长时间。</li>    <li>在政府刺激措施和经济复苏的推动下，预计中国并购活动将在 2024 年反弹。</li>    <li>中东国家对中国入境并购交易表现出兴趣，尤其是在新能源和电动汽车领域。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>mergers and acquisitions (M&A) - 并购。    <p>原文例句：Global and domestic private-equity investors are making a comeback to the Chinese mergers and acquisitions (M&A) market following three straight years of decline, as they look to profit from an economic recovery, global consultancy Bain & Co said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由mergers（合并）和acquisitions（收购）构成的，表示“并购”。在这个例句中，它指的是全球和国内私募股权投资者重返中国并购市场，他们希望从经济复苏中获利。</p></li>    <li>frothy valuations - 浮沫估值。    <p>原文例句：Private-equity investors will focus on improving profitability and bolstering revenue from their portfolio firms, rather than potential frothy valuations, when they are making investment decisions, said Zhou Hao, head of the firm’s Greater China private equity and M&A practice.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由frothy（泡沫状的，浮沫的）和 valuations（估值）构成的，表示“浮沫估值”。在这个例句中，它指的是一些私募股权投资者的潜在投资决策，即他们将专注于提高投资组合公司的盈利能力和收入，而不是追求泡沫估值。</p></li>    </ul>  <ul>    <li>stable and sustainable returns - 稳定和可持续的回报。    <p>原文例句：Most investors with massive amounts of dry powder prefer large-scale businesses to small, high-growth firms, as they chase stable and sustainable returns in a fast-changing market, Bain said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由stable（稳定的）和sustainable（可持续的）以及returns（回报）构成的，表示“稳定和可持续的回报”。在这个例句中，它指的是大多数拥有大量闲置资金的投资者更青睐大型企业，而不是小型、高增长的企业，因为他们在快速变化的市场中追求稳定和可持续的回报。</p></li>    <li>dry powder - 未投资资本。    <p>原文例句：Private-equity dry powder soared to an unprecedented US$2.59 trillion globally as of December 1 last year, an 8% increase over December 2022’s total of US$2.39 trillion, data by S&P Global and Preqin shows.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由dry（干燥的，闲置的）和powder（粉末，资本）构成的，表示“未投资资本”。在这个例句中，它指的是截至去年 12 月 1 日，全球私募股权未投资资本激增至前所未有的 2.59 万亿美元，比 2022 年 12 月的总额 2.39 万亿美元增加了 8%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>economic recovery - 经济复苏。    <p>原文例句：Global and domestic private-equity investors are making a comeback to the Chinese mergers and acquisitions (M&A) market following three straight years of decline, as they look to profit from an economic recovery, global consultancy Bain & Co said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由economic（经济的）和recovery（复苏）构成的，表示“经济复苏”。在这个例句中，它指的是全球和国内私募股权投资者重返中国并购市场，他们希望从经济复苏中获利。</p></li>    <li>deal volumes - 交易量。    <p>原文例句：Mainland China reported 5,156 M&A deals in 2023, with a combined value of US$301 billion, according to Refinitiv data. This was a nine-year low and a third straight year of declines, in terms of deal volumes.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由deal（交易）和volumes（量）构成的，表示“交易量”。在这个例句中，它指的是根据 Refinitiv 的数据，2023 年中国内地报告了 5,156 笔并购交易，总价值为 3,010 亿美元。就交易量而言，这是九年来的最低水平，也是连续第三年下降。</p></li>    </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Despite a drop in deal volumes, mainland China still accounted for 41 per cent of deals in the Asia-Pacific region in the first half of 2023, according to S&P Global Market Intelligence. - 尽管交易量下降，但根据标准普尔环球市场情报的数据，2023 年上半年中国内地仍占亚太地区交易量的 41%。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是China still accounted for 41 per cent of deals，其中主语是China，谓语是still accounted for，宾语是41 per cent of deals。Despite a drop in deal volumes是一个介词短语，作状语，表示尽管交易量下降。in the Asia-Pacific region是一个介词短语，作地点状语，表示在亚太地区。in the first half of 2023是一个时间状语，表示在 2023 年上半年。整个句子的意思是，尽管交易量下降，但根据标准普尔环球市场情报的数据，2023 年上半年中国内地仍占亚太地区交易量的 41%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：“New talks on deal making [have] resurfaced since the second half of 2023,” he said.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在进行时态的句子，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be用的是are，表示现在时态，分词是making，表示正在进行的动作。have resurfaced是一个现在完成时态的动词，表示在某个时间点之前已经发生的动作或状态，并且一直持续到现在。这个句子的意思是，他表示，自 2023 年下半年以来，关于达成交易的新谈判已经重新浮出水面。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>条件句 - 表示假设或条件。    <p>原文例句：It may take longer to conclude the deals, but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted this year.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个条件句，结构是：if + 现在时态，主句 + will + 动词原形。其中if表示如果，主句是it is certain that more transactions will be conducted this year，表示可以肯定今年将进行更多交易。will take longer to conclude the deals是一个现在时态的句子，表示需要更长时间才能达成交易。这个句子的意思是，达成交易  <ul><li>It may take longer to conclude deals, ‘but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted’ in 2024, Bain executive says</li>
<li>Mainland China M&amp;A deals dropped to a nine-year low last year amid a third straight year of declines, Refinitiv data shows</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/3af570e6-afc9-4398-8253-c7bffe73cf71_6190bf99.jpg" /><figcaption>The Liuiazui financial hub in Shanghai. Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for GDP, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, at the National People’s Congress. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Global and domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3246654/china-ma-activity-set-rebound-2024-amid-renewed-overseas-interest-it-wont-be-business-usual-heres" target="_self" title="">private-equity investors</a> are making a comeback to the Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mergers-acquisitions" target="_self" title="">mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;A)</a> market following three straight years of decline, as they look to profit from an economic recovery, global consultancy Bain &amp; Co said.</p><p>Private-equity investors will focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247667/chinese-stocks-darkest-days-may-be-over-earnings-rebound-property-recovery-seen-lifting-gloom-2024" target="_self" title="">improving profitability and bolstering revenue</a> from their portfolio firms, rather than potential frothy valuations, when they are making investment decisions, said Zhou Hao, head of the firm’s Greater China private equity and M&amp;A practice.</p><p>“New talks on deal making [have] resurfaced since the second half of 2023,” he said. “It may take longer to conclude the deals, but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted this year.”</p><p>Bain’s statement is significant because, despite a drop in deal volumes, mainland China still accounted for 41 per cent of deals in the Asia-Pacific region in the first half of 2023, according to S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence.</p><p>Mainland China reported 5,156 M&amp;A deals in 2023, with a combined value of US$301 billion, according to Refinitiv data. This was a nine-year low and a third straight year of declines, in terms of deal volumes.</p><p>US dollar-denominated private-equity funds that have at least half their capital invested in China raised US$1.4 billion in the first half of last year, down about 90 per cent from a year earlier, according to Preqin data.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3248558/asset-manager-blackstone-expand-private-equity-headcount-singapore-southeast-asia-push" title="">Asset manager Blackstone to expand private-equity headcount in Singapore</a></h3><p>However, earlier this month, UBS forecast that profit growth for Chinese listed companies will jump to 8 per cent in 2024 from 3 per cent last year, buoyed by a recovery in the world’s second-largest economy.</p><p>Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for gross domestic product, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, when the annual session of the National People’s Congress is held.</p><p>Moreover, Kang Yi, head of China’s National Bureau of Statistics, said during a press conference on Wednesday that some incentives Beijing rolled out last year – such as the plan to issue 1 trillion yuan (US$139 billion) worth of special treasury bonds – will take effect in 2024. The central government will also prepare new supportive policies to spur the mainland’s economy, he added.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3246654/china-ma-activity-set-rebound-2024-amid-renewed-overseas-interest-it-wont-be-business-usual-heres" title="">China M&amp;A activity set for rebound but 2024 won’t be business as usual</a></h3><p>Most investors with massive amounts of dry powder prefer large-scale businesses to small, high-growth firms, as they chase stable and sustainable returns in a fast-changing market, Bain said.</p><p>Private-equity dry powder soared to an unprecedented US$2.59 trillion globally as of December 1 last year, an 8 per cent increase over December 2022’s total of US$2.39 trillion, data by S&amp;P Global and Preqin shows.</p><p>Bain said in a research report released on Thursday that buyout funds mainly benefited from higher valuations of portfolio firms in China amid increasing price-to-earnings multiples, because investors in new rounds of financing were convinced of their future growth potential.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3245604/global-ma-deal-makers-miss-us3-trillion-mark-first-time-10-years" title="">Global M&amp;A: deal makers to miss US$3 trillion mark for first time in 10 years</a></h3><p>Higher valuations contributed to 55 per cent of the total returns private-equity funds reaped in China from 2012 to 2022, Bain said. Revenue increases contributed to 37 per cent of total returns while only 8 per cent of the returns were derived from profit rises.</p><p>Middle Eastern countries that are eager to shift from fossil fuel-based economies are pursuing opportunities for China inbound M&amp;A deals, particularly in the new energy and electric-vehicles (EV) sectors.</p><p>In October, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3239304/chinese-self-driving-technology-start-ponyai-gets-us100-million-investment-saudi-arabias-smart-city" target="_self" title="">Saudi Arabian smart city developer Neom</a> invested US$100 million in Chinese autonomous driving technology start-up Pony.ai to help fund its research and development and finance its operations.</p><p>On December 18, Chinese EV maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3242863/chinese-ev-maker-nio-sees-ai-robots-replacing-30-cent-workforce-2027-improve-efficiency-cut-costs" target="_self" title="">Nio</a> announced it had raised US$2.2 billion from CYVN Holdings, a fund backed by the Abu Dhabi government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s lottery players bet on AI chatbots to give winning numbers, but none are millionaires yet</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248909/chinas-lottery-players-bet-ai-chatbots-give-winning-numbers-none-are-millionaires-yet</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Chinese social media users have been sharing their experiences using generative AI to generate lottery numbers. While some have won small sums of money, others have had no luck. Experts warn that lotteries are designed to be random and that AI has no special edge over humans when it comes to predicting winning numbers.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese social media users experiment with generative AI to generate lottery numbers, with mixed results.</li>    <li>Theme: The use of generative AI for lottery number generation in China and its outcomes.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The role of generative AI in lottery number selection; the randomness of lotteries and the lack of a clear advantage for AI over humans in predicting winning numbers.</li>    <li>Main information: Sharing experiences on social media platforms; lottery number generation using AI chatbots like Gemini-Pro and ChatGPT; varying results, including small wins and no wins; expert opinions on the randomness of lotteries and the limitations of AI.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  中国社交媒体用户分享了他们使用生成式人工智能挑选彩票号码的经历。虽然有些人赢了小额奖金，但其他人却一无所获。专家警告说，彩票的设计是随机的，人工智能在预测中奖号码方面并没有比人类有什么特殊的优势。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国社交媒体用户尝试使用生成式人工智能生成彩票号码，结果好坏参半。</li>    <li>主题：中国使用生成式人工智能生成彩票号码及其结果。</li>    <li>观点：生成式人工智能在彩票号码选择中的作用；彩票的随机性以及人工智能在预测中奖号码方面相对于人类缺乏明显的优势。</li>    <li>主要信息：在社交媒体平台上分享经验；使用像双子座专业版和聊天机器人GPT这样的生成式人工智能聊天机器人生成彩票号码；结果不一，包括小赢和小输；专家对彩票随机性和人工智能局限性的看法。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>generative (adj.) - /ˈdʒenərətɪv/ 生成性的，创造性的。    <p>原文例句：Chinese social media users share their experiences using generative AI to pick lottery numbers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语generare（产生，创造），表示“产生，创造，生成性的”。在这个例句中，它描述了中国社交媒体用户使用生成式人工智能来挑选彩票号码的经历。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>chatbot (n.) - /ˈtʃætbɒt/ 聊天机器人，对话机器人。    <p>原文例句：The country is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由chat（聊天）和bot（机器人）组成，表示“聊天机器人，对话机器人”。在这个例句中，它指的是使用人工智能来模拟人类对话的计算机程序。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>turn into - 变为，变成，成为。    <P>原文例句：ChatGPT and its peers are known for giving smart answers to a variety of questions, but some internet users in China recently found that lottery numbers generated by artificial intelligence (AI) chatbots have yet to turn them into millionaires.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由turn（转动，转向）和into（进入，变成）构成的，表示“转变为，变为，成为”。在这个例句中，它表示由人工智能聊天机器人生成的彩票号码还没有使中国互联网用户成为百万富翁。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>pick by - 挑选，选择。    <P>原文例句：Gu first fed the chatbot with two years’ worth of historical data from Super Lotto, one of the most popular of its kind in China that asks players to select five numbers from a set of 35 balls and two bonus numbers from another set of 12 balls.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由pick（挑选，选择）和by（通过，由……来）构成的，表示“通过……来挑选，选择”。在这个例句中，它表示Gu首先向聊天机器人输入了两年的超级乐透历史数据，超级乐透是中国最受欢迎的彩票之一，要求玩家从一组35个球中选择五个数字，从另一组12个球中选择两个奖金号码。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>While sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers, it has not stopped people from using AI to try to boost their chances. - 虽然复杂的AI算法在预测幸运数字方面没有特别的优势，但这并没有阻止人们使用AI来提高自己的中奖机会。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是AI algorithms have no particular edge，其中主语是AI algorithms，谓语是have no particular edge，宾语是over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers。状语从句是While sophisticated AI algorithms，其中主语是While，谓语是sophisticated AI algorithms，宾语是no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers。分词短语try to boost their chances作状语，表示提高中奖机会的目的或方式。这个句子的意思是说，虽然复杂的AI算法在预测幸运数字方面没有特别的优势，但这并没有阻止人们使用AI来提高自己的中奖机会。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>In the case of Gu, the Xiaohongshu user, Gemini explained to her that it tried to predict lottery results by picking recent lucky numbers that also won more frequently in the past. - 在用户Gu的案例中，双子座向她解释说，它尝试通过挑选最近的幸运号码来预测彩票结果，这些幸运号码在过去也更频繁地中奖。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Gemini explained to her，其中主语是Gemini，谓语是explained，宾语是to her。状语从句是In the case of Gu, the Xiaohongshu user，其中主语是In the case of Gu, the Xiaohongshu user，谓语是tried to predict lottery results by picking recent lucky numbers that also won more frequently in the past。这个句子的意思是说，在用户Gu的案例中，双子座向她解释说，它尝试通过挑选最近的幸运号码来预测彩票结果，这些幸运号码在过去也更频繁地中奖。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间之前已经发生或完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Gu also said she previously spent 20 yuan (US$2.8) betting on Union Lotto, another popular lottery in China, using the same approach, winning 5 yuan in total.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间之前已经发生或完成，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示Gu之前也曾使用相同的方法在另一个中国受欢迎的彩票大联盟乐透上花了20元（合2.8美元）进行投注，总共赢得了5元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示一种假设、愿望或可能性。    <p>原文例句：“Treat lottery as a recreational activity, not a way to invest or make money. Good luck,” it said.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语态，结构是：should/could/would/may + 原形。其中should/could/would/may要根据语境和说话人的意图进行选择，原形是动词的-ing形式。这种语态表示一种假设、愿望或可能性，在这个例句中，双子座说：“把彩票当作一种娱乐活动，而不是一种投资或赚钱的方式。祝你好运！”，其中虚拟语气Good luck表示祝愿或希望。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Chinese social media users share their experiences using generative AI to pick lottery numbers</li>
<li>The country is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/ef431a3d-68c7-4027-852b-cc9d3567841e_0b6e9536.jpg" /><figcaption>A lottery shop in Beijing. Photo: SCMP/Simon Song</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT and its peers</a> are known for giving smart answers to a variety of questions, but some internet users in China recently found that lottery numbers generated by artificial intelligence (AI) chatbots have yet to turn them into millionaires.</p><p>In one post that went viral on the Instagram-like platform Xiaohongshu, user Gu Xiangnan from eastern Anhui province shared her experience buying lottery tickets using numbers generated by Google’s Gemini-Pro.</p><p>She first fed the chatbot with two years’ worth of historical data from Super Lotto, one of the most popular of its kind in China that asks players to select five numbers from a set of 35 balls and two bonus numbers from another set of 12 balls.</p><p>Among the five combinations picked by Gemini, two of them each contained two winning numbers, while another two each had one correct bonus number. Gu won no money.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Gu also said she previously spent 20 yuan (US$2.8) betting on Union Lotto, another popular lottery in China, using the same approach, winning 5 yuan in total.</p><p>“Although it was just for fun, there is something worth looking into,” she said.</p><p>Lotteries are designed to be random, meaning that picking the right numbers from millions of possible combinations depends entirely on luck. While sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers, it has not stopped people from using AI to try to boost their chances.</p><p>The Xiaohongshu post was liked by more than 5,000 users, with some commenting that they also won small sums using numbers suggested by generative AI. Gemini-Pro and OpenAI’s ChatGPT are officially unavailable in China, although they can be accessed using a virtual private network.</p><p>China, which logged annual lottery sales of around 600 billion yuan last year, is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets.</p><p>People in other parts of the world have also been turning to generative AI for lottery number suggestions.</p><p>In April, Thai man Patthawikorn Boonrin claimed on TikTok that he won 2,000 baht (US$56) using ChatGPT, according to digital media Mashable. A month later, Singaporean man Aaron Tan won a US$40 cash prize with ChatGPT-generated numbers, according to news portal Yahoo.</p><p>Also in May, Paris-based data scientist Rohith Teja bought a 2.5 euro (US$2.7) lottery ticket using random numbers given by ChatGPT, winning 6 euros. Another ticket that he purchased using numbers generated by ChatGPT through analysing historical data contained no winning numbers at all.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3243129/how-chinas-lottery-boom-reflects-long-and-challenging-road-its-economic-recovery" title="">How China’s lottery boom reflects a ‘long and challenging’ economic recovery</a></h3><p>“The lottery is a highly randomised event that cannot be predicted by any predictive model,” Teja concluded in his blog.</p><p>In the case of Gu, the Xiaohongshu user, Gemini explained to her that it tried to predict lottery results by picking recent lucky numbers that also won more frequently in the past.</p><p>While the chatbot said its selection “had a certain degree of randomness as well as a certain degree of regularity”, it advised against taking the lottery too seriously.</p><p>“Treat lottery as a recreational activity, not a way to invest or make money. Good luck,” it said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple chip supplier TSMC expects a return to ‘healthy growth’, backing hopes for global tech recovery in 2024</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248918/apple-chip-supplier-tsmc-expects-return-healthy-growth-backing-hopes-global-tech-recovery-2024</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC) expects a return to solid growth this quarter and gave itself room to raise capital spending this year.</li>    <li>The company projected revenue growth of at least 8 per cent to US$18.8 billion in the March quarter, versus expectations for around US$18.2 billion.</li>    <li>TSMC's revenue should grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year, marking a rebound from the modest decline of last year.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>台积电预计本季度将恢复强劲增长，并给自己留出了今年增加资本支出的空间。</li>    <li>该公司预计3月份的收入增长至少8%，达到188亿美元，而预期约为182亿美元。</li>    <li>台积电今年的收入预计将增长20%至25%左右，这标志着去年小幅下滑后的反弹。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.njuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co expects revenue to grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于French，由re-（重新）和venir（来，发生）组成，表示“重新来过，重新发生”，引申为“收益，收入”。在这个例句中，它表示台积电预计今年的收入将增长20%至25%左右。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>anticipate (v.) - /ænˈtɪs.ɪ.peɪt/ 预期，预料。    <p>原文例句：The world’s most valuable chip maker anticipates a recovery in smartphone and computing demand. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由anti-（在……之前，相反）和capere（抓住）组成，表示“抓住之前，预计，预料”。在这个例句中，它表示全球最有价值的芯片制造商预计智能手机和计算需求将复苏。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>return to solid growth - 回归稳健增长。    <p>原文例句：Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co expects a return to solid growth this quarter. </p>    <p>词组讲解：这个词组是由return（返回），to（到），solid（坚固）和growth（增长）构成的，表示“回归稳健增长”。在这个例句中，它表示台积电预计本季度将回归稳健增长。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company’s outlook, while not quite surpassing the most bullish estimates, comes after a years-long slump in tech demand. - 该公司的展望虽然没有完全超过最乐观的估计，但它是在科技需求多年低迷之后做出的。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company’s outlook comes after a years-long slump in tech demand，其中主语是The company’s outlook，谓语是comes，宾语是after a years-long slump in tech demand。while not quite surpassing the most bullish estimates是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰The company’s outlook，表示该公司的展望虽然没有完全超过最乐观的估计。这个句子的意思是说，该公司的展望虽然没有完全超过最乐观的估计，但它是在科技需求多年低迷之后做出的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TSMC, which also counts Android chip design firm Qualcomm among its biggest customers, got a boost from frenzied demand for Nvidia’s artificial intelligence (AI) processors in 2023. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，但不强调动作或状态的持续性，而强调动作或状态的结果或影响。在这个例句中，它表示台积电在2023年从英伟达的人工智能（AI）处理器中获得了狂热的追捧。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>TSMC, the world’s largest contract chip manufacturer, projected revenue growth of at least 8 per cent to US$18.8 billion in the March quarter</li>
<li>The Taiwanese company’s outlook comes after a years-long slump in tech demand</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/1ba9ec97-57a0-404c-8f10-74bfd74536c6_76fe20b5.jpg" /><figcaption>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co expects revenue to grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year. Image: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc" target="_self" title="">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a> (TSMC) expects a return to solid growth this quarter and gave itself room to raise capital spending this year, suggesting the world’s most valuable chip maker anticipates a recovery in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> and computing demand.</p><p>The main <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> supplier to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/nvidia" target="_self" title="">Nvidia Corp</a> projected revenue growth of at least 8 per cent to US$18.8 billion in the March quarter, versus expectations for around US$18.2 billion. It is also budgeting capital expenditure of US$28 billion to US$32 billion, potentially up from US$30 billion in 2023.</p><p>The Taiwanese company’s outlook, while not quite surpassing the most bullish estimates, comes after a years-long slump in tech demand. But signs of a recovery for the chip-making sector have emerged in recent weeks. The Semiconductor Industry Association estimated chip sales increased in November after more than a year of declines.</p><p>TSMC chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3206603/apple-supplier-tsmc-worlds-biggest-contract-chip-maker-keep-spending-check-amid-weak-global" target="_self" title="">C C Wei</a> reiterated that he expects a return to “healthy growth” this year.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co logo seen atop a building at the Hsinchu Science Park in Hsinchu, Taiwan, on January 9, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1332" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/fa4428f2-8ef6-41b6-af8b-803745c49428_6c52fb99.jpg" title="The Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co logo seen atop a building at the Hsinchu Science Park in Hsinchu, Taiwan, on January 9, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co logo seen atop a building at the Hsinchu Science Park in Hsinchu, Taiwan, on January 9, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>TSMC, which also counts Android chip design firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/qualcomm" target="_self" title="">Qualcomm</a> among its biggest customers, got a boost from frenzied demand for Nvidia’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) processors in 2023.</p><p>It reported net income for the fourth quarter of NT$238.7 billion (US$7.6 billion), beating the average analyst estimate. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247936/tsmc-halts-revenue-drop-beats-expectations-brisk-demand-ai-chips-nvidia-advanced-micro-devices" target="_self" title="">Revenue was US$625.5 billion</a>, TSMC reported earlier, matching the previous holiday quarter and arresting a series of falls.</p><p>“Our business has bottomed out on a year-over-year basis, and we expect 2024 to be a healthy growth year for TSMC,” Wei said.</p><p>TSMC’s revenue should grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year, he said. That marks a rebound from the modest decline of last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247936/tsmc-halts-revenue-drop-beats-expectations-brisk-demand-ai-chips-nvidia-advanced-micro-devices" title="">Chip-making giant TSMC halts revenue drop on brisk AI demand</a></h3><p>“TSMC could lead global chip foundries through 2023-24 industry headwinds, thanks to growing AI chip demand and migration to next-gen process nodes such as N3 in second half of 2023 and N2 by 2025,” Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Charles Shum said in a research note.</p><p>“Although the smartphone and PC chip market remains stagnant, TSMC’s advanced packaging tech, both 2.5D and 3D, fortifies its position in the contract-chip making market, allowing a potential return to a 53 per cent gross margin following a brief second-half downturn.”</p><p>Over the course of 2023, TSMC moderated its capital expenditure plans as the consumer electronics industry grappled with a glut of unsold inventory.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246852/competitive-pay-tsmc-plant-may-ripple-across-japan-beat-inflation" title="">Competitive pay at TSMC plant may ripple across Japan, beat inflation</a></h3><p>But uncertainty persists. This month, fellow contract semiconductor maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> posted its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" target="_self" title="">sixth successive quarter of declining operating profit</a>, as it weathered the impact of muted consumer demand in its own smartphone and memory chip businesses.</p><p>Questions also overshadow mainland China, the world’s largest computing, smartphone, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> and semiconductor market.</p><p>Apple – long one of TSMC’s most important customers – faced headwinds with its latest generation of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhones</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" target="_self" title="">Several analysts downgraded Apple</a> on expectations of soft demand, and Jefferies has said the iPhone sales slump in China is likely to deepen. The US company has also been hit by a widening <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3233603/china-orders-government-workers-stop-using-iphones-amid-heightened-tensions-us" target="_self" title="">ban on foreign-device use among Chinese government agencies</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/state-owned-enterprises" target="_self" title="">state-owned enterprises</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong’s green tech hub goal: nurture start-ups, identify advantages and create talent pool, fintech body says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3248875/hong-kongs-green-tech-hub-goal-nurture-start-ups-identify-advantages-and-create-talent-pool-fintech</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Hong Kong aims to become a prominent green tech and finance center by leveraging China's expertise in electric vehicles, renewable energy, and hydrogen, while fostering start-ups and attracting talent. Collaborations between the government and the private sector will provide funding, attract and develop talent, and promote a risk-taking mindset.   <ul>    <li>Objective: Hong Kong's ambition to become a green tech and green finance hub.</li>    <li>Collaboration: Government and private sector partnership to support start-ups, nurture talent, and promote a risk-taking mindset.</li>    <li>Leveraging China's Expertise: Utilize China's dominance in electric vehicles and renewable energy to Hong Kong's advantage.</li>    <li>Talent Development: Importance of attracting and nurturing a skilled workforce in green tech and finance.</li>    <li>Funding: Creation of funding structures to support green start-ups and encourage investment.</li>    <li>Challenges: Fostering a risk-taking mindset and expanding the talent pool.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  香港旨在成为重要的绿色科技和金融中心，方法是利用中国在电动汽车、可再生能源和氢能方面的专业知识，同时培育初创企业并吸引人才。政府与私营部门之间的合作将提供资金、吸引和培养人才，并促进冒险精神。  <ul>    <li>目标：香港成为绿色科技和绿色金融中心。</li>    <li>合作：政府和私营部门合作，以支持初创企业、培养人才并促进冒险精神。</li>    <li>利用中国专业知识：充分利用中国在电动汽车和可再生能源上的优势。</li>    <li>人才发展：吸引和培养称职的绿色科技和金融领域劳动力。</li>    <li>资金：建立资助结构以支持绿色初创企业并鼓励投资。</li>    <li>挑战：培育风险承担意识和扩大人才库。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>dominance (n.) - /ˈdɑːmənəns/ 优势，支配地位。    <p>原文例句：Given China’s leadership position in electric vehicles, renewable energy and hydrogen, these sectors can be initial targets for collaborations, he added.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由dominate（支配，控制）和-nce（状态，性质）构成的，表示“统治，支配，优势地位”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国在电动汽车、可再生能源和氢能领域的领导地位，他补充说，这些领域可以作为合作的初期目标。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>collaborative (adj.) - /kəˈlæbərətɪv/ 合作的，协作的。    <p>原文例句：“Public-private collaborative funding can help.” Sethi said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由collaborate（合作，协作）和-ive（有……性质的）构成的，表示“合作的，协作的，联合的”。在这个例句中，Sethi说，“公私合作的资金可以帮助。”，他补充说，这些领域可以作为合作的初期目标。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>put the flag up - 宣布，宣称。    <P>原文例句：“We feel it is important for Hong Kong to put that flag up and say we are the leading green tech centre.” Sethi said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由put（放置，放入），the flag（旗帜，国旗）和up（向上，升起）构成的，表示“升旗，宣布，宣称”。在这个例句中，Sethi说，“我们认为香港有必要宣布并说我们是领先的绿色科技中心。”，他补充说，这些领域可以作为合作的初期目标。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in crucial technologies - 在关键技术方面。    <P>原文例句：“leverage China’s expertise in crucial technologies”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），crucial（关键的，重要的）和technologies（技术，技术学）构成的，表示“在关键的技术方面”。在这个例句中，它指的是利用中国的专业知识，特别是在关键技术方面，如电动汽车、可再生能源和氢能等。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>be involved in - 涉及，参与。    <P>原文例句：“involved in areas such as low-carbon energy products, greenhouse gas emissions and tools for collecting and analysing data on physical climate risks,”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由be（是，存在）和involved in（参与，卷入）构成的，表示“参与，涉及，卷入”。在这个例句中，它指的是涉及的领域，如，低碳能源产品、温室气体排放和收集和分析有关物理气候风险数据的工具。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong’s aim of becoming a green technology and finance centre can become a reality if efforts are concentrated on supporting start-ups and leveraging China’s expertise in crucial technologies, according to the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. - 根据香港金融科技协会的说法，如果将精力集中在支持初创企业和利用中国在关键技术方面的专业知识上，香港成为绿色技术和金融中心的目标就可以成为现实。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Hong Kong’s aim can become a reality，其中主语是Hong Kong’s aim，谓语是can become a reality。if efforts are concentrated on supporting start-ups and leveraging China’s expertise in crucial technologies是一个条件状语从句，表示如果将精力集中在支持初创企业和利用中国在关键技术方面的专业知识上。根据香港金融科技协会的说法是一个状语，表示这是香港金融科技协会的观点。这个句子的意思是说，根据香港金融科技协会的说法，如果将精力集中在支持初创企业和利用中国在关键技术方面的专业知识上，香港成为绿色技术和金融中心的目标就可以成为现实。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset, said Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee. - 政府和私营部门应该加强合作，建立资助结构来支持绿色初创企业，吸引和培养人才库，并促进冒险精神，绿色技术和ESG委员会的联席主席Sandeep Sethi说。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The government and the private sector should step up collaboration，其中主语是The government and the private sector，谓语是should step up collaboration。to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset是一个目的状语从句，表示为了建立资助结构来支持绿色初创企业，吸引和培养人才库，并促进冒险精神。Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee是一个状语，表示这是Sandeep Sethi的观点。这个句子的意思是说，政府和私营部门应该加强合作，建立资助结构来支持绿色初创企业，吸引和培养人才库，并促进冒险精神，绿色技术和ESG委员会的联席主席Sandeep Sethi说。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示现在之前发生的行为或状态一直持续到现在。    <p>原文例句：Some 80 per cent of senior finance executives in the city, surveyed late last year by the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, said recruiting green and sustainable finance professionals was more difficult compared with other job functions.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的延续性和完成性。在这个例句中，它表示香港大学科技学院的调查显示，去年晚些时候对该市的80%高级金融主管进行调查时，他们表示，与其他职位相比，招聘绿色和可持续金融专业人士更加困难。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>动词不定式 - 表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：  <ul><li>Public-private collaboration to fund start-ups, attracting and nurturing talent can help city achieve green tech, finance hub goal: FinTech Association of Hong Kong</li>
<li>City must leverage China’s dominance in fields such as electric vehicles and renewable energy to its advantage, non-profit’s Sandeep Sethi says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/a4b626bb-229f-49f8-979e-4aaf7649c6cd_f97275b3.jpg" /><figcaption>The Hong Kong government has stated its ambition to become a leading green tech and green finance hub. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>Hong Kong’s aim of becoming a green technology and finance centre can become a reality if efforts are concentrated on supporting start-ups and leveraging China’s expertise in crucial technologies, according to the FinTech Association of Hong Kong.</p><p>The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset, said Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee.</p><p>“Various cities are trying to promote themselves as green tech centres” said Sethi, who is also an independent consultant and a former executive at Deutsche Bank. “We feel it is important for Hong Kong to put that flag up and say we are the leading green tech centre. We need to identify sub-sectors where we feel Hong Kong has certain advantages.”</p><p>Given China’s leadership position in electric vehicles, renewable energy and hydrogen, these sectors can be initial targets for collaborations, he added.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/90970213-f607-4ca0-9991-68a291db888d_798e21ed.jpg" title="FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung" width="2000" /><figcaption>FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung</figcaption></figure></div><p>Hong Kong’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3211122/budget-2023-hong-kong-launches-initiatives-become-global-green-innovation-finance-centre" target="_self" title="">ambition</a> to become an international centre for both green tech and green finance was highlighted by Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po in his budget speech last February. Previously, the focus was on building the city into a leading green and sustainable finance hub in Asia.</p><p>The government followed up its intention by setting up a green technology and finance development committee, comprising leaders from the finance, technology, academic and professional services sectors in June.</p><p>Next month, the government is hosting the Hong Kong GreenTech Week, which aims to bring together green tech businesses and investors from around the world, according to co-organiser Green Development Institute.</p><p>On a more basic level, Hong Kong can do better by providing early-stage funding for start-ups involved in areas such as low-carbon energy products, greenhouse gas emissions and tools for collecting and analysing data on physical climate risks, said Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/78343ebc-5f85-4434-9186-b91134e46289_798e21ed.jpg" title="Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung" width="2000" /><figcaption>Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Some green tech start-ups that have done well after getting seed funding of HK$10 million (US$1.3 million) to HK$20 million have struggled to raise additional financing to fund expansion,” said Barford, who is also the Hong Kong financial services consulting data and analytics lead at consultancy EY.</p><p>The government should consider expanding its financial assistance programmes, which would encourage family offices and institutional investors to take part in fundraising by start-ups, he added.</p><p>Towards that end the Hong Kong government is providing assistance. The different research and development funding schemes overseen by the Innovation and Technology Commission had provided total funding of some HK$400 million to about 130 green tech R&amp;D projects as of last June, according to the Environment and Ecology Bureau.</p><p>The bureau also administers a HK$400 million Green Tech Fund that supports R&amp;D projects in net-zero electricity generation, energy savings, green buildings, green transport and waste reduction. Some 30 projects have received HK$132.5 million since the fund was set up in 2020.</p><p>The government’s Hong Kong Science and Technology Parks Corporation and Cyberport have also set up separate funds to co-invest with angel investors and venture capital funds in start-ups at their respective industry parks.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3244092/hong-kong-regains-appeal-among-global-financial-talent-opportunities-open-fintech-esg-and-markets" title="">Hong Kong regains appeal among global talent amid demand in fintech, ESG</a></h3><p>“There is a gap between the intention and the actual projects that get financed,” said Sethi. “A lot of these are new technology projects where it is hard to prove the business case and profitability. This is where public-private collaborative funding can help.”</p><p>Other difficulties facing the government and industries include growing the talent pool, Sethi said.</p><p>Some 80 per cent of senior finance executives in the city, surveyed late last year by the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, said recruiting green and sustainable finance professionals was more difficult compared with other job functions. Talent retention and acquisition was the second most pressing issue after disclosure regulations.</p><p>Fostering a risk-taking mindset is another challenge, according to Sethi.</p><p>“In a lot of Asian countries, the education systems are focused on preparing students to get stable jobs, but in tech we need entrepreneurs who are willing to take risks,” he said. “It takes years and perhaps generations to change the mindset.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s Vision Pro headset will be missing a Netflix app at launch in February</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248870/apples-vision-pro-headset-will-be-missing-netflix-app-launch-february</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Netflix宣布不打算为苹果即将推出的Vision Pro头显开发应用程序，这意味着用户无法下载Netflix内容以供离线观看。Netflix解释说，用户可以通过网络浏览器在设备上观看其内容。这种方法对于售价3499美元的Vision Pro头显来说是一个重大遗漏，因为苹果正押注娱乐内容来帮助销售这项新技术。Netflix还为苹果的其他设备（包括iPhone和iPad）提供应用程序，但并未参与苹果的TV应用程序。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Netflix不会为Apple的Vision Pro头显开发应用程序，用户将无法下载内容以供离线观看。</li>    <li>Theme: Netflix的决定对Vision Pro用户的影响，以及公司对新技术的看法。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 用户在Vision Pro头显上访问Netflix内容的挑战；Netflix与Apple在流媒体行业的竞争。</li>    <li>Main information: Netflix用户可以通过网络浏览器在Vision Pro上观看内容；Netflix没有计划为头显的专属操作系统VisionOS发布软件；Netflix此前曾表示将在Vision Pro上支持其iPad应用程序，但现在改变了决定。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Netflix宣布不打算为苹果即将推出的Vision Pro头显开发应用程序，这意味着用户无法下载Netflix内容以供离线观看。Netflix解释说，用户可以通过网络浏览器在设备上观看其内容。这种方法对于售价3499美元的Vision Pro头显来说是一个重大遗漏，因为苹果正押注娱乐内容来帮助销售这项新技术。Netflix还为苹果的其他设备（包括iPhone和iPad）提供应用程序，但并未参与苹果的TV应用程序。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Netflix不会为Apple的Vision Pro头显开发应用程序，用户将无法下载内容以供离线观看。</li>    <li>主题：Netflix的决定对Vision Pro用户的影响，以及公司对新技术的看法。</li>    <li>观点：用户在Vision Pro头显上访问Netflix内容的挑战；Netflix与Apple在流媒体行业的竞争。</li>    <li>主要信息：Netflix用户可以通过网络浏览器在Vision Pro上观看内容；Netflix没有计划为头显的专属操作系统VisionOS发布软件；Netflix此前曾表示将在Vision Pro上支持其iPad应用程序，但现在改变了决定。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>headsets (n.) - /ˈhɛdsɛt/ 耳机，头戴式耳机。    <p>原文例句：Netflix is not planning to launch an app for Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset, marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world’s biggest video subscription service.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“耳机”一词由head（头）和set（装置）组成，意为“头戴式耳机”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果即将推出的Vision Pro头显，这是一种虚拟现实耳机。</p></li>    <li>pass (n.) - /pæs/ 通行证，许可证，通行证。    <p>原文例句：Rather than designing a Vision Pro app – or even just supporting its existing iPad app on the platform – Netflix is essentially taking a pass.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“通行证”一词由pass（通过）和age（后缀）组成，意为“通行证，许可证，通行证”。在这个例句中，它表示Netflix基本上正在放弃为Vision Pro头显开发应用程序，甚至不支持其现有的iPad应用程序在该平台上运行。</p></li>    <li>interface (n.) - /ˈɪntərfis/ 界面，接口。    <p>原文例句：The Vision Pro will run two main types of apps: new software written specifically for the device’s interface or existing iPad applications.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“界面”一词由inter（之间）和face（面孔）组成，意为“界面，接口”。在这个例句中，它指的是Vision Pro头显的界面，即用户与设备交互的方式。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>mark a snub - 表示拒绝，不屑。    <p>原文例句：Netflix is not planning to launch an app for Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset, marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world’s biggest video subscription service.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由mark（标记）和snub（蔑视）组成，表示“表示拒绝，不屑”。在这个例句中，它表示Netflix不打算为苹果即将推出的Vision Pro头显发布应用程序，这标志着世界上最大的视频订阅服务对这项新技术不屑一顾。</p></li>    <li>gather awards - 获得奖项。    <p>原文例句：Apple is a small player in this category, with less than 10 per cent of the US market. But it has been gathering award wins in the space, and the two companies compete over talent and production deals.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由gather（收集）和awards（奖项）组成，表示“获得奖项”。在这个例句中，它表示苹果在流媒体领域获得了奖项，尽管它在这个类别中是一个小玩家，只占美国市场不到10%的份额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In contrast with its Vision Pro strategy, Netflix did develop an app for Meta Platforms’ Quest headsets, though it has not been updated in years. - 相比之下，Netflix为Meta Platform的Quest头显开发了一款应用程序，尽管它已经很多年没有更新了。    <p>句子分析：这个句子使用了一个对比连词“in contrast with”，表示“相比之下”。它将Netflix为Meta Platform的Quest头显开发应用程序与它为Vision Pro头显开发应用程序的情况进行对比。句子中的“though”表示“尽管”，表示Netflix为Quest头显开发的应用程序已经很多年没有更新了。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Netflix is not planning to launch an app for Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset... The Vision Pro will run two main types of apps: new software written specifically for the device’s interface or existing iPad applications.</p>    <p>语法讲解：“现在完成时”表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。它是由have/has been + 过去分词构成的。在这个例句中，“is not planning”和“will run”都用了现在完成时态，表示Netflix不打算为Vision Pro头显发布应用程序，以及Vision Pro头显将运行两种主要类型的应用程序。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、愿望或不真实的情况。    <p>原文例句：It is also a bit of a reversal for the company, which said in July that it would support its iPad app on the Vision Pro. </p>    <p>语法讲解：“虚拟语气”表示假设、愿望或不真实的情况。它通常使用would或could来表示。在这个例句中，“would support”表示Netflix之前说它会支持其iPad应用程序在Vision Pro上运行，但现在改变了决定。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Rather than designing a Vision Pro app or supporting its existing iPad app on the platform, Netflix says users can watch its content on a web browser</li>
<li>The approach means Vision Pro users will not be able to download Netflix content to watch offline on an aeroplane</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0daed4bb-8aac-444e-9863-2f6975c1c780_21ab5745.jpg" /><figcaption>The Apple Vision Pro headset seen at an unveiling event in Cupertino, California last June. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netflix" target="_self" title="">Netflix</a> is not planning to launch an app for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3223224/apples-vision-pro-best-ar-and-vr-mixed-reality-headset-market-and-represents-future-computing-even" target="_self" title="">Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset</a>, marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world’s biggest video subscription service.</p><p>Rather than designing a Vision Pro app – or even just supporting its existing iPad app on the platform – Netflix is essentially taking a pass. The company, which competes with Apple in streaming, said in a statement that users interested in watching its content on the device can do so from the web.</p><p>It is a sizeable omission for the US$3,499 headset, which debuts on February 2. Apple is banking on entertainment content to help market the nascent and pricey technology, and Netflix is a must-have streaming service for many consumers.</p><p>Netflix also offers apps for Apple’s other devices, including the iPhone and iPad, though it does not participate in the company’s TV app.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1329" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/27470cf7-0ad7-471c-936b-45ab61159d8c_ce1fbea2.jpg" title="The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Vision Pro will run two main types of apps: new software written specifically for the device’s interface or existing iPad applications. Apple has sought to make it easy to transfer developers’ current iPad apps over to the new platform, aiming to quickly amass a wide range of Vision Pro software.</p><p>The fact that Netflix is not even willing to support the iPad approach suggests that it is taking a wait-and-see stance with the headset. It is also a bit of a reversal for the company, which said in July that it would support its iPad app on the Vision Pro. Even then, though, Netflix did not plan to release software specifically for the headset’s operating system, visionOS.</p><p>“Our members will be able to enjoy Netflix on the web browser on the Vision Pro, similar to how our members can enjoy Netflix on Macs,” Los Gatos, California-based Netflix said in the statement. Apple declined to comment.</p><p>In contrast with its Vision Pro strategy, Netflix did develop an app for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236053/meta-launches-quest-3-vr-and-ar-headset-just-ahead-apples-vision-pro" target="_self" title="">Meta Platforms’ Quest headsets</a>, though it has not been updated in years.</p><p>The approach means it will be harder for users to access Netflix on the Vision Pro. And they will not be able to download Netflix content to watch offline, potentially making it more of a pain to use on an aeroplane.</p><p>The lack of an app also means Netflix watchers will not have access to custom environments for streaming. That means Netflix cannot create specialised immersive backdrops for its users to watch videos in.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="998" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/946981d0-f40f-4bc7-b1f9-bd435067d043_6ca422b1.jpg" title="An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>While Netflix and Apple do not compete in TV hardware, they are both currently vying for subscribers in the streaming industry.</p><p>Apple is a small player in this category, with less than 10 per cent of the US market. But it has been gathering award wins in the space, and the two companies compete over talent and production deals. It is plausible Netflix does not want to help boost a rival by giving it a key app for its upcoming launch.</p><p>Apple has been marketing the Vision Pro as an entertainment device in the run-up to pre-orders beginning on Friday.</p><p>The Cupertino, California-based company said earlier this week that the headset would have many entertainment options beyond its own TV+ service. That includes programming from Disney+, Max, Peacock, ESPN and Amazon Prime Video, among others.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
