<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Huawei’s HarmonyOS to beat Apple’s IOS as the No. 2 smartphone operating system in China in 2024: TechInsights report</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>HarmonyOS is expected to surpass Apple's iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year.</li>    <li>Huawei's comeback in the 5G smartphone segment will drive the adoption of HarmonyOS.</li>    <li>HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps, is expected to be launched in 2024.</li>    <li>Major Chinese companies, including Ant Group, JD.com, NetEase, and Meituan, are developing native apps for HarmonyOS.</li>    <li>McDonald's China has adopted HarmonyOS Next for its mobile payment app Alipay.</li>    <li>Over 700 million devices currently run on HarmonyOS, with over 2.2 million third-party developers creating apps for the platform.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>HarmonyOS预计将在今年超过苹果的iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。</li>    <li>华为重回5G智能手机领域将推动HarmonyOS的采用。</li>    <li>HarmonyOS Next预计将在2024年发布，该系统将不支持基于Android的应用程序。</li>    <li>包括蚂蚁集团、京东、网易和美团在内的中国主要公司正在为HarmonyOS开发原生应用程序。</li>    <li>麦当劳中国已为其移动支付应用程序支付宝采用HarmonyOS Next。</li>    <li>目前有超过7亿台设备运行HarmonyOS，有超过220万第三方开发人员为该平台创建应用程序。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>surpass (v.) - /sərˈpæs/ 超过，超越。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s IOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词的意思是超过，超越。在这个例句中，它表示华为的移动平台HarmonyOS预计将在今年超过苹果的iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sanction (v.) - /ˈsæŋkʃən/ 制裁，惩罚。    <p>原文例句：While Google’s Android and Apple’s IOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, Canadian research firm TechInsights said in a report released on Wednesday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词的意思是制裁，惩罚。在这个例句中，它表示华为的自研操作系统HarmonyOS将从谷歌的Android和苹果的iOS这两大美国巨头手中抢占一些中国市场份额。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>home-grown (adj.) - /ˌhoʊm ˈɡrəʊn/ 国产的，本地的。    <p>原文例句：Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment, which started with the surprise launch in late August of its Mate 60 Pro, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词的意思是国产的，本地的。在这个例句中，它表示华为Mate 60 Pro智能手机搭载了国产的5G芯片，尽管美国的技术制裁旨在阻止对其获取此类技术。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make a solid recovery - 强劲复苏。    <p>原文例句：TechInsights also expects Huawei to make a solid recovery in 2024, according to the report.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组的意思是强劲复苏。在这个例句中，它表示TechInsights预计华为将在2024年强劲复苏。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps. - HarmonyOS预计还将在2024年实现一个里程碑，届时将发布HarmonyOS Next，该系统将不支持基于Android的应用程序。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是HarmonyOS is projected to reach a milestone in 2024，其中主语是HarmonyOS，谓语是is projected to reach，宾语是a milestone。with the launch of HarmonyOS Next是一个介词短语作状语，表示HarmonyOS预计将在2024年发布HarmonyOS Next时实现一个里程碑。which will not support Android-based apps是一个定语从句，修饰HarmonyOS Next，表示HarmonyOS Next将不支持基于Android的应用程序。这个句子的意思是说，HarmonyOS预计还将在2024年实现一个里程碑，届时将发布HarmonyOS Next，该系统将不支持基于Android的应用程序。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词结构 - 分词结构由分词和其宾语、状语等成分组成，在句中可作定语、状语或表语。    <p>原文例句：Despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个分词结构，由分词intended和其宾语access to such technology组成，在句中作状语，表示尽管美国的技术制裁旨在阻止对其获取此类技术。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>倒装结构 - 倒装结构是指句子中主谓语的顺序颠倒，一般用于强调句子的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：More than 700 million devices currently run on HarmonyOS, with more than 2.2 million third-party developers creating apps for the platform, according to Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group, speaking at the company’s annual developer conference in August.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装结构，把More than 700 million devices currently run on HarmonyOS放在句子开头，强调了目前有超过7亿台设备运行HarmonyOS。with more than 2.2 million third-party developers creating apps for the platform是一个介词短语作状语，表示有超过220万第三方开发人员为该平台创建应用程序。这个句子的意思是说，目前有超过7亿台设备运行HarmonyOS，有超过220万第三方开发人员为该平台创建应用程序。这些数据是由华为消费者业务集团首席执行官余承东在该公司8月份举行的年度开发者大会上公布的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Increased HarmonyOS adoption is expected to be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment</li>
<li>TechInsights also expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/83c4b156-87f3-4acb-b3f4-8cb885281387_c0009114.jpg" /><figcaption>Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s IOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year driven by the US-sanctioned firm’s comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to a report by TechInsights.</p><p>While Google’s Android and Apple’s IOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, Canadian research firm TechInsights said in a report released on Wednesday.</p><p>Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment, which started with the surprise launch in late August of its Mate 60 Pro, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology.</p><p>TechInsights also expects Huawei to make a solid recovery in 2024, according to the report.</p><p>Huawei’s smartphones are all powered by HarmonyOS, its self-developed Android alternative launched in August 2019, three months after the US government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">added the firm to its Entity List</a>. Under this trade blacklist, Huawei is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>On its release, the Mate 60 Pro inspired <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">a wave of patriotic fervour</a> among Chinese consumers, and the Shenzhen-based firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241541/huawei-has-big-problem-popular-mate-60-5g-smartphones-theres-not-enough-supply-meet-growing-demand" target="_self" title="">faced supply issues as it scrambled to crank up production to meet demand</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" title="">Huawei sees 9 per cent sales growth in 2023, boosted by Mate 60 Pro 5G comeback</a></h3><p>TechInsights expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months. Huawei’s product portfolio further expanded last week when it launched new smartphone models under its mid-range Nova series.</p><p>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p><p>Huawei is expected to launch a developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next in the first quarter of 2024, and is already working with China’s major companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p><p>Last month, Chinese financial technology giant Ant Group, the fintech affiliate of South China Morning Post owner <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, said it is building a new version of mobile payment app Alipay based on HarmonyOS, after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242703/alibaba-develops-native-dingtalk-app-harmonyos-huawei-aims-end-support-android-apps?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba started development on a new version of DingTalk</a>, its workplace collaboration app, for the platform.</p><p>Other major Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> companies – including e-commerce firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>, video gaming giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netease?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">NetEase</a> and food delivery market leader <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> – in November already started to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241371/chinese-big-tech-firms-jdcom-netease-and-meituan-rush-hire-harmonyos-based-app-developers-huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">recruit developers to build native apps for HarmonyOS</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mcdonalds?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">McDonald’s</a> China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year – became <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244236/mcdonalds-china-pushes-development-native-apps-based-harmonyos-adoption-huaweis-mobile-operating?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239589/xiaomi-launches-home-grown-cross-device-system-hyperos-us-sanctioned-huawei-moves-further-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS Next</a>.</p><p>It remains to be seen whether these efforts will have a halo effect on other smartphone makers and make HarmonyOS a default operating system for not just smartphones but also laptops and cars in China, TechInsights said.</p><p>More than 700 million devices currently run on HarmonyOS, with more than 2.2 million third-party developers creating apps for the platform, according to Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group, speaking at the company’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230293/tech-war-huawei-revive-smartphone-business-back-fresh-ai-powered-operating-system-even-us-sanctions?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">annual developer conference in August</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple dominates global premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground on the back of its new 5G handsets</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Apple remained the leading supplier of premium smartphones worldwide in 2023, but its market share decreased due to the resurgence of Huawei's 5G phones and Samsung's foldable phones. Apple's share dropped from 75% in 2022 to 71% in 2023, while Huawei gained ground with a 5% share, up from 3% the previous year. Samsung maintained its second position with a 17% share, while Xiaomi and Oppo ranked fourth and fifth, respectively. The premium segment showed resilience despite the projected decline in the overall global smartphone market, accounting for nearly a quarter of global sales and 60% of industry revenue. The ultra-premium segment, with smartphones priced above $1,000, accounted for one-third of total premium handset sales. Consumers are increasingly willing to spend more on high-quality devices that last longer, and emerging markets like India are driving growth in the premium smartphone segment.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's dominance in the premium smartphone market waned in 2023 due to competition from Huawei and Samsung.</li>    <li>Theme: Changing dynamics in the premium smartphone market, with Apple facing strong competition from Huawei and Samsung.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The resilience of the premium segment despite the overall decline in the smartphone market; the growing importance of high-quality devices and the impact of emerging markets.</li>    <li>Main information: Apple's market share decline; Huawei's resurgence with its 5G phones; Samsung's gains with foldable phones; Xiaomi and Oppo's positions in the premium segment; resilience of the premium segment; consumer preferences for high-quality devices; growth in emerging markets.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  苹果公司在2023年仍然是全球最大的高端智能手机供应商，其市场份额为71%，位居第一。然而，由于华为5G手机的强势回归和三星折叠手机的强势表现，苹果公司的领先地位出现了下滑。从2022年的75%下降至2023年的71%，而华为则从2022年的3%上升至现在的5%，占据了更多的市场份额。三星以17%的市场份额位居第二，小米和oppo分别位居第四和第五。高端智能手机市场表现出了韧性，尽管2023年全球智能手机市场的整体出货量预计将达到近十年来的最低水平，下降5%。高端智能手机市场预计将占全球智能手机市场销售额的四分之一，占行业收入的60%。而售价超过1000美元的超高端智能手机市场占到了高端智能手机总销售额的三分之一。在过去几年中，高端智能手机市场已经成为全球疲软的智能手机市场的一个增长点。Counterpoint预测，高端智能手机的销量份额将从2016年的6%增长到2023年的24%。  <ul>    <li>摘要：2023年，苹果公司在高端智能手机市场的主导地位因华为和三星的竞争而减弱。</li>    <li>主题：高端智能手机市场格局的变化，苹果公司面临华为和三星的激烈竞争。</li>    <li>观点：高端智能手机市场在整体智能手机市场下滑情况下的表现坚韧；消费者对高质量设备的日益重视以及新兴市场的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果公司市场份额下滑；华为5G手机强势回归；三星折叠手机表现强劲；小米和oppo在高端智能手机市场中的地位；高端智能手机市场的韧性；消费者对高质量设备的偏好；新兴市场的增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>resurgence (n.) - /rɪˈsɜːrджəns/ 再现，复兴。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei, which released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由re-（再次）和surge（上升，激增）组成，表示“再次出现，复兴”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为的5G手机的强势回归。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>resilience (n.) - /rɪˈzɪlɪəns/ 韧性，复原力。    <p>原文例句：The latest market data shows the resilience of the premium segment, despite the projected decrease in the overall global smartphone market in 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语resilire（跳回），表示“恢复原状的能力，韧性”。在这个例句中，它指的是高端智能手机市场在整体智能手机市场预计下降的情况下表现出的韧性。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>from...to - 从……到……    <P>原文例句：Over the past few years, the premium segment has emerged as a growth area in the otherwise weak worldwide smartphone market. Counterpoint projected the premium segment sales share to triple to 24 per cent in 2023, compared to 6 per cent in 2016.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“从……到……”，用于表示时间范围、数量范围、程度范围等。在这个例句中，它表示从2016年的6%到2023年的24%，即高端智能手机市场销售份额预计将从2016年的6%增长到2023年的24%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Much of the global premium segment’s growth last year was driven by China, western Europe, India, and the Middle East-and-Africa regions, according to Counterpoint.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价，就……而言”。在这个例句中，它表示从地区角度来看，全球高端智能手机市场去年的大部分增长是由中国、西欧、印度和中东及非洲地区推动的。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The US firm’s lead, however, declined year on year amid Huawei’s 5G comeback with its Mate 60 series and the gains made by Samsung’s foldable phones. - 然而，这家美国公司的领先地位逐年下降，因为华为带着Mate 60系列的5G手机强势回归，三星的折叠手机也取得了进展。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是The US firm’s lead declined year on year，其中主语是The US firm’s lead，谓语是declined，宾语是year on year。amid Huawei’s 5G comeback with its Mate 60 series and the gains made by Samsung’s foldable phones是一个介词短语作状语，表示在华为Mate 60系列的5G手机强势回归和三星折叠手机取得进展的情况下。这个句子的意思是说，然而，这家美国公司的领先地位逐年下降，因为华为带着Mate 60系列的5G手机强势回归，三星的折叠手机也取得了进展。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei, which released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示苹果公司的市场份额从2022年的75%下降到2023年的71%，这是一个持续性的过程，强调这种下降的持续性和未完成性。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式短语 - 表示动作或状态，通常作名词、形容词或副词。    <p>原文例句：The latest market data  <ul><li>Apple remained the world’s top vendor of premium smartphones in 2023, with a 71 per cent market share, according to research firm Counterpoint</li>
<li>The US firm’s lead, however, declined year on year amid Huawei’s 5G comeback with its Mate 60 series and the gains made by Samsung’s foldable phones</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/64d88f21-13d4-47d7-a021-0a71facc64d7_e98ebaba.jpg" /><figcaption>Apple’s iPhone 15 Pro and Pro Max models are seen on display at a store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 22, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> continued to lead the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> industry’s premium segment in 2023, but saw its worldwide share decline mainly because of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-sanctioned</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>’ strong <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/5g/news" target="_self" title="">5G</a> handset market comeback with its Mate 60 series.</p><p>The global premium smartphone market, where handsets are priced from US$600, saw Apple remain the “undisputed leader” last year with a dominant 71 per cent share, according to the latest industry report released on Tuesday by Counterpoint Research.</p><p>Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei, which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020</a>, as well as the gains made by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a>’ Galaxy S23 series and its latest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foldable-phones" target="_self" title="">foldable phones</a>.</p><p>Samsung retained the global No 2 spot in the premium segment with a share of 17 per cent, compared to 16 per cent in 2022. Still, No 3 Huawei captured more new ground year on year with a 5 per cent share, up from 3 per cent in 2022, according to the Counterpoint report.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/cb3a9a4b-0ce5-45f4-91e6-798c2c4c40f0_5babf532.jpg" title="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> last year took the fourth and fifth spots in the premium smartphone segment with a 2 per cent and 1 per cent share, respectively.</p><p>The latest market data shows the resilience of the premium segment, despite the projected decrease in the overall global smartphone market in 2023 – global handset shipments are forecast to hit their lowest level in almost a decade with a 5 per cent decline, according to an earlier Counterpoint report.</p><p>The premium segment, meanwhile, was expected to account for nearly one-fourth of global smartphone market sales and 60 per cent of the industry’s revenue in 2023. Counterpoint data shows that the so-called ultra-premium segment, where smartphones cost more than US$1,000, accounted for one-third of total premium handset sales last year.</p><p>Over the past few years, the premium segment has emerged as a growth area in the otherwise weak worldwide smartphone market. Counterpoint projected the premium segment sales share to triple to 24 per cent in 2023, compared to 6 per cent in 2016.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3246457/ranked-top-5-smartphones-2023-iphone-15-pro-max-and-google-pixel-8-pro-two-foldable-phones-and-best" title="">Top 5 smartphones of 2023, from iPhone 15 Pro Max to the best camera phone</a></h3><p>“There has been a shift in consumer buying patterns in the smartphone market,” Counterpoint senior analyst Varun Mishra said in the premium segment report. “Considering the importance a smartphone holds, consumers are willing to spend more to get a high-quality device that they can use for a longer period.”</p><p>Much of the global premium segment’s growth last year was driven by China, western Europe, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/india" target="_self" title="">India</a>, and the Middle East-and-Africa regions, according to Counterpoint.</p><p>India is already the world’s fastest-growing market for premium smartphones, the Counterpoint report said. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217435/apple-opens-first-retail-store-india-us-tech-giant-sharpens-focus-south-asian-nation-major-market" target="_self" title="">Apple opened its first retail store in India</a> last April, underscoring the US tech titan’s increasing focus on the South Asian nation as a key sales market and alternative manufacturing hub to China.</p><p>“Owning the latest and greatest flagships has also become a status symbol for many consumers, especially in emerging markets where they are jumping directly from the mid-price band to the premium band,” Mishra said. “Further, these devices are increasingly becoming more affordable due to promotion seasons and financing options.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance’s Douyin makes instant refunds mandatory, following PDD, Taobao and JD.com amid fierce e-commerce competition</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247160/bytedances-douyin-makes-instant-refunds-mandatory-following-pdd-taobao-and-jdcom-amid-fierce-e</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has made its "express refund" policy mandatory for merchants, requiring them to immediately refund customers upon request.</li>    <li>E-commerce platforms in China are adopting "refund without returning the cargo" or "refund without reason" policies to attract consumers and stay competitive.</li>    <li>Pinduoduo introduced a similar policy in 2021, allowing users to get refunds without returning non-conforming goods, which helped it gain market share.</li>    <li>Alibaba's Taobao and JD.com have recently implemented their own "refund only" policies to match Pinduoduo's strategy.</li>    <li>Douyin's refund service excludes customized products and non-tangible goods, with a limit of 1,500 yuan (US$211) per transaction.</li>    <li>Alibaba has reorganized its e-commerce business unit and promoted young managers to regain market share from Pinduoduo.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>抖音，中国的TikTok版本，已强制要求商家采用“快速退款”政策，要求商家在收到退货商品前立即向消费者退款。</li>    <li>中国的电子商务平台正在采用“无理由退款”或“无条件退款”的政策来吸引消费者，提升竞争力。</li>    <li>拼多多在 2021 年推出了一项类似的政策，允许用户在不退还货物的条件下获得退款，这帮助拼多多从竞争平台手中赢得了对价格敏感的中国消费者。</li>    <li>阿里巴巴的淘宝和京东最近也已实施了自己的“仅退款”政策，以匹配拼多多的策略。</li>    <li>抖音的退款服务不适用于定制产品和非实物商品，如会员资格。即时退款也限制在 1500 元（211 美元）以内。</li>    <li>阿里巴巴对电子商务业务部门进行了重组，并提升年轻管理人员，以期从拼多多手中夺回市场份额。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Woo (v.) - /wʊː/ 引诱，招揽。      <p>原文例句：The company hopes to woo consumers away from Facebook and Twitter.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Woo 源自古英语，意为“吸引，招揽”。在这个例句中，它表示该公司希望从 Facebook 和 Twitter 吸引用户。</p>    </li>    <li>Intensify (v.) - /ɪnˈtɛnsɪfaɪ/ 加强。      <p>原文例句：The political situation in the country has intensified in recent months.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Intensify 源自拉丁语，意为“增强，增加”。在这个例句中，它表示国家的政治局势在最近几个月有所加剧。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>At the expense of - 以……为代价。      <p>原文例句：The company's profits have increased at the expense of its employees.</p>      <p>例句讲解：At the expense of 是一个介词短语，意为“以……为代价”。在这个例句中，它表示公司的利润是以员工的利益为代价而增加的。</p>    </li>    <li>Gain favor - 得到支持或赞同。      <p>原文例句：The policy has gained favor with voters.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Gain favor 是一个动词短语，意为“得到支持或赞同”。在这个例句中，它表示这项政策得到了选民的支持。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>E-commerce platforms are turning to policies known as “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason” as part of a push to be more consumer-friendly at the expense of merchants amid intensified competition. - 电子商务平台正在转向“无理由退款”或“无条件退款”等政策，作为在激烈的竞争中增加对消费者的友好程度、牺牲商家的利益的一个举措。      <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是E-commerce platforms are turning to policies known as “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason”，其中主语是E-commerce platforms，谓语是are turning to policies，宾语是known as “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason”。as part of a push to be more consumer-friendly at the expense of merchants amid intensified competition是一个介词短语作状语，修饰E-commerce platforms are turning to policies，说明电子商务平台转向这些政策是为了在激烈的竞争中增加对消费者的友好程度、牺牲商家的利益。这个句子的意思是说，电子商务平台正在转向“无理由退款”或“无条件退款”等政策，作为在激烈的竞争中增加对消费者的友好程度、牺牲商家的利益的一个举措。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词的用法 - 分词可以用来修饰名词、代词或整个句子。      <p>原文例句：The company has been sued by customers for allegedly selling defective products.</p>      <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，selling defective products 是一个现在分词短语，作allegedly的状语，表示该公司被客户起诉的原因是据称销售有缺陷的产品。</p>    </li>    <li>动词的时态 - 动词的时态用于表示动作或状态发生的时间。      <p>原文例句：The company was fined for violating environmental regulations.</p>      <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，was fined是过去式被动语态，表示该公司因为违反环保规定而被罚款。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Merchants selling on the short video app Douyin can no longer opt out of the option to instantly refund up to US$211 before receiving returned goods</li>
<li>Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com recently started offering refunds without returns to woo consumers away from rising budget e-commerce champion Pinduoduo</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/3ce8d4ad-d4c8-4569-8e73-e028869c8250_11da8613.jpg" /><figcaption>The logo of Douyin displayed next to a mobile phone displaying an e-commerce site on the app in an illustration picture taken on October 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Douyin, the Chinese version of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a> that is betting big on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce">e-commerce</a>, has made its “express refund” policy mandatory, forcing merchants to immediately return money to consumers upon request to compete with similar offerings on Taobao and Pinduoduo.</p><p>The platform operated by Beijing-based <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance">ByteDance</a>, which added a shopping channel in 2019, allows users to get a refund as soon as they mail back the returned parcel, rather than when the merchant receives it. A recent policy update regarding the service introduced in 2021 denies merchants the option of turning it off.</p><p>E-commerce platforms are turning to policies known as “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason” as part of a push to be more consumer-friendly at the expense of merchants amid intensified competition. Online retail sales of tangible goods in China increased 8.3 per cent in the first 11 months of 2023, according to the National Bureau of Statistics.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>Budget shopping app <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo">Pinduoduo</a>, owned by PDD Holdings, was the first major e-commerce site to introduce a similar refunds policy in 2021 allowing users to get their money back without returning goods found to not match merchant descriptions. This was seen as a major factor in helping Pinduoduo woo price-sensitive Chinese consumers away from competing platforms.</p><p>The policy of allowing refunds without returns has started to gain favour as platforms look for any possible edge over rivals.</p><p>Taobao, the e-commerce platform from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom">JD.com</a> last week rolled out their own <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating">“refund only” policies</a>, finally matching the option from Pinduoduo. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Douyin has offered refunds without returns since September.</p><p>Douyin’s new refund service is not available for customised products or non-tangible goods such as memberships. Instant refunds are also limited to 1,500 yuan (US$211).</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Alibaba has been facing a new sense of urgency to win back consumers after PDD overtook China’s e-commerce king in market capitalisation. Alibaba was valued at US$190.2 billion on the New York Stock Exchange on Tuesday, lower than PDD’s US$193.5 billion on the Nasdaq.</p><p>In December, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals">Alibaba promoted six young managers</a> to run its core e-commerce business unit in an attempt to “reignite their entrepreneurial spirit” and “secure and win their future”, according to an internal letter penned by the conglomerate’s CEO Eddie Wu Yongming, two days after he became the head of the unit.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech firms must end, says communist party newspaper after video gaming stock rout</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese Communist Party mouthpiece calls for an end to excessive regulation of the platform economy.</li>    <li>The article argues that such regulation has harmed the country's internet titans and made them less competitive globally.</li>    <li>It also suggests that the erratic behavior of regulators has created uncertainty and risk for businesses.</li>    <li>The author proposes that regulators should work together to avoid duplication and consider the views of regulated parties.</li>    <li>The article suggests that Chinese internet companies should be allowed to self-govern with minimal interference from the state.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中共党校机关报呼吁结束对平台经济的过度监管。</li>    <li>文章认为，这种监管损害了该国互联网巨头，使其在全球竞争力下降。</li>    <li>还指出监管机构的反复无常行为给企业带来了不确定性和风险。</li>    <li>作者建议监管机构应协同合作，避免重复执法，并考虑被监管方的意见。</li>    <li>文章建议应允许中国互联网企业以最小的国家干预进行自我治理。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>erratic（adj.） - 不规则的，不稳定的。    <p>原文例句：China’s disciplinary enforcers add ‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于Latin，由e-（出，离）和ragare（游荡）组成，意为“游荡，漂泊”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国纪检部门将“坏”书籍、性、毒品等添加到严重犯罪中。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sharpen one’s teeth（习语） - 磨快牙齿，准备攻击或战斗。    <p>原文例句：A long list of Chinese ministries has been sharpening their teeth when it comes to disciplining internet firms. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是一个习语，比喻某人或某个组织准备采取行动或行动。在这个例句中，它指的是中国多个部委磨刀霍霍，准备整顿互联网公司。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>economic slowdown（名词） - 经济放缓。    <p>原文例句：Beijing’s pursuit of market control, along with China’s economic slowdown and rising geopolitical tensions with the US, have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由economic（经济的）和slowdown（放缓）组成，表示经济增长速度放慢。在这个例句中，它指的是中国经济放缓以及与美国不断加剧的地缘政治紧张局势，导致中国互联网股票在过去三年表现不佳。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>regulatory crackdown（名词） - 监管打压。    <p>原文例句：Beijing’s regulatory crackdown on the internet sector officially came to an end a year ago, when the Chinese leadership said the country’s platform enterprises would be encouraged to “fully display their capabilities” in growth, job creation and international competition. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由regulatory（监管的）和crackdown（镇压）组成，表示政府或监管机构对某个行业或领域进行严厉管制。在这个例句中，它指的是北京方面对互联网行业的监管打压，该打压于一年前正式结束，中国领导层表示该国的平台企业将被鼓励在增长、创造就业和国际竞争中“充分发挥其能力”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rationality and necessity（名词） - 合理性与必要性。    <P>原文例句：It is important to respect the rationality and necessity of platform self-governance to guide and encourage the formation of self-regulatory mechanisms. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由rationality（合理性）和necessity（必要性）组成，表示某件事或行为的合理性和必要性。在这个例句中，它指的是尊重平台自我治理的合理性和必要性，以指导和鼓励自我监管机制的形成。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>According to the Study Times opinion piece, the erratic regulatory behaviour is “a risk and a challenge” for China as its leading internet firms are left further behind their global peers in terms of competitiveness and growth potential. - 根据学习时报的评论文章，不稳定的监管行为对中国来说是“一个风险和挑战”，因为其领先的互联网公司在竞争力和增长潜力方面落后于全球同行。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The erratic regulatory behaviour is “a risk and a challenge” for China，其中主语是The erratic regulatory behaviour，谓语是is，宾语是“a risk and a challenge”。as its leading internet firms are left further behind their global peers in terms of competitiveness and growth potential是一个as引导的状语从句，修饰主句，表示中国领先互联网公司在竞争力和增长潜力方面进一步落后于全球同行的原因。这个句子的意思是说，根据学习时报的评论文章，不稳定的监管行为对中国来说是“一个风险和挑战”，因为其领先的互联网公司在竞争力和增长潜力方面落后于全球同行。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>将来时 - 表示将来发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：China’s disciplinary enforcers add ‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences</p>    <p>语法讲解：将来时态是用will或shall加上动词原形构成的。在这个例句中，add是动词原形，will是将来时态助动词，表示中国纪检部门将来会将“坏”书籍、性、毒品等添加到严重犯罪中。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设或愿望的情况。    <p>原文例句：Beijing’s pursuit of market control, along with China’s economic slowdown and rising geopolitical tensions with the US, have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是在句子中使用虚拟语气动词形式来表示假设或愿望的情况。在这个例句中，have turned是虚拟语气动词形式，表示北京追求市场控制、中国经济放缓以及与美国不断加剧的地缘政治紧张局势，导致中国互联网股票在过去三年表现不佳这一情况是假设或愿望的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The mouthpiece of the Central Party School argued that regulators must stop the practice of swinging between extremes of lax oversight and ‘overly strict’ regulation</li>
<li>The opinion came days after the NPPA wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with draft regulation to restrict spending on video games</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/3319e698-c70a-4b75-a5c4-b17164272de6_6b557a93.jpg" /><figcaption>Tencent’s Game for Peace is seen on a mobile phone in this illustration picture taken May 13, 2019.  Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>A Chinese Communist Party newspaper has urged the country’s regulators to end their erratic moves against the platform economy, in a sign of growing concern over policy damage to the health of the country’s ailing internet titans.</p><p>A front page opinion piece published by the Study Times, the mouthpiece of the Central Party School, on Wednesday argued that regulators must stop the practice of swinging between extremes of lax oversight and “overly strict” regulation so that China’s Big Tech firms can have room to grow.</p><p>The article, which did not name any specific company or regulator, came days after the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" target="_self" title="">proposed regulation to restrict spending on video games.</a> The South China Morning Post reported on Tuesday that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes" target="_self" title="">a key gaming official has left his job following the debacle,</a> as the Chinese government tries to allay market fears.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246511/chinas-disciplinary-enforcers-add-bad-books-sex-drugs-serious-offences" title="">China’s disciplinary enforcers add ‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences</a></h3><p>The draft proposal is the latest example of regulatory hostility, after Beijing’s campaign of “curbing irrational expansion of capital” in 2020 unleashed a race among different ministries and watchdogs to claim authority in checking and approving internet businesses.</p><p>A long list of Chinese ministries has been sharpening their teeth when it comes to disciplining internet firms. The Cyberspace Administration of China, the country’s internet watchdog, for instance, has articulated Beijing’s demand for data security into intrusive requirements that have made it increasingly difficult and costly to comply with.</p><p>Beijing’s pursuit of market control, along with China’s economic slowdown and rising geopolitical tensions with the US, have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years. Tencent Holdings, the country’s most valuable player that once eyed being Asia’s first US$1 trillion company, fell out of the global top 10 after losing 60 per cent of its market capitalisation, while Post owner Alibaba Group Holding, which exceeded Amazon.com in market value in 2014, is now worth an eighth of the US e-commerce titan.</p><p>According to the Study Times opinion piece, the erratic regulatory behaviour is “a risk and a challenge” for China as its leading internet firms are left further behind their global peers in terms of competitiveness and growth potential.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/643c0e52-aced-4b9f-a2cf-0f56737ce2f0_bd901af2.jpg" title="People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" width="2000" /><figcaption>People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song</figcaption></figure></div><p>China must improve “cross-departmental coordination” to avoid duplicated enforcement and checks, while regulatory acts and policy adjustments must factor in “the views of all parties, especially those being regulated” to avoid interrupting normal business activities or causing unexpected risks, it said.</p><p>Chinese regulators should loosen their grip and allow “self-governance” by Chinese internet companies, it added. “It is important to respect the rationality and necessity of platform self-governance to guide and encourage the formation of self-regulatory mechanisms,” the article said.</p><p>It remains unknown whether China’s different regulators will heed the advice. Beijing’s regulatory crackdown on the internet sector officially came to an end a year ago, when the Chinese leadership said the country’s platform enterprises would be encouraged to “fully display their capabilities” in growth, job creation and international competition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung to kick off year of AI phones with new launch this month</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247104/samsung-kick-year-ai-phones-new-launch-month</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  In recent years, Samsung and other smartphone manufacturers have focused on camera technology and flexible displays to stand out. In 2024, AI capabilities will take center stage, with Samsung's Galaxy S24 launch emphasizing "Galaxy AI." Artificial intelligence is expected to be integrated into smartphones, with more than a billion AI-powered smartphones projected to be shipped by 2027. OpenAI's ChatGPT and Dall-E have generated excitement, contributing to Nvidia's rise. Samsung and Qualcomm are poised to lead the market, with Samsung expected to capture a significant share followed by Chinese manufacturers.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: AI capabilities will be a key focus for smartphone manufacturers in 2024.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's launch of the Galaxy S24 highlights the integration of AI into smartphones.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Generative AI tools like ChatGPT and Dall-E are driving the trend towards AI-powered smartphones.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's launch event on January 17th; projected shipment of over a billion AI-powered smartphones by 2027; OpenAI's contribution to Nvidia's success; Samsung and Qualcomm's leadership in AI-related smartphone products.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary：</h2>  近年来，三星等智能手机厂商一直依靠相机技术和柔性屏的进步来脱颖而出。2024年，人工智能功能将占据中心舞台，三星Galaxy S24发布强调“Galaxy AI”。人工智能有望被集成到智能手机中，预计到2027年将出货超过10亿部搭载人工智能的智能手机。OpenAI的ChatGPT和Dall-E引起了轰动，促成了英伟达的崛起。三星和高通有望引领市场，预计三星将占据相当大的份额，其次是中国制造商如小米、vivo、荣耀和OPPO。  <ul>    <li>摘要：2024年人工智能功能将成为智能手机制造商的主要关注点。</li>    <li>主题：三星发布Galaxy S24，强调人工智能与智能手机的融合。</li>    <li>观点：ChatGPT和Dall-E等生成式人工智能工具正在推动人工智能智能手机的发展潮流。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星1月17日的发布会；预计到2027年出货超过10亿部人工智能智能手机；OpenAI对英伟达成功的贡献；三星和高通在人工智能相关智能手机产品中的领先地位。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>generative (adj.) - 产生性的，有创造性的。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词来源于Latin，意思是“产生，创造”。在这个例句中，它指的是使用人工智能来生成内容或数据的能力，而不是只存储和处理信息。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>accelerator (n.) - 加速器。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Dall-E tools, which generate text or visual responses to users’ queries, are at the forefront of a generative-AI wave that is swept across the tech industry – and helped make Nvidia a trillion-dollar company by providing the key AI-training accelerators. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词是由ad-（向）和celer（快）组成的，意为“使更快，加速器”。在这个例句中，它指的是一种硬件或软件，用于提高人工智能模型的训练速度。</p> </li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stand out - 脱颖而出，引人注目。    <p>原文例句：In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语的意思是“从人群中脱颖而出，引人注目”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星和其他智能手机制造商依赖相机技术和柔性显示屏的改进，以便在市场上脱颖而出。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>key to unlocking - 解开锁定的钥匙，打开局面的关键。    <p>原文例句：The world’s most prolific smartphone maker is leaning into artificial intelligence (AI) as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语的意思是“打开局面的关键，解开锁定的钥匙”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星将人工智能视为打开今年销量大增局面的关键。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei launches new Nova smartphones without giving details on chip - 华为发布新款Nova智能手机，并未提供关于芯片的详细信息。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Huawei，谓语是launches，宾语是new Nova smartphones。without giving details on chip是一个介词短语作状语，表示华为发布新款Nova智能手机时，并未提供关于芯片的详细信息。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices, as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year. - 推进该技术的下一步是将其集成到设备中，正如美国芯片制造商高通过去一年一直在吹捧的那样。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices，其中主语是The next step in advancing the technology，谓语是is，宾语是to integrate it into devices。as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year是一个时间状语从句，表示美国芯片制造商高通过去一年一直在吹捧这一技术。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 一种想象或不现实的情况下的情态语态。    <p>原文例句：Samsung and Qualcomm are immediate leaders as current product offerings and capabilities position them as first movers."</p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是在一个句子中表示说话者态度或看法的陈述或请求。例如，有人说：“我希望我是一只鸟”，这句话使用了虚拟语气，因为这是一个不可能发生的情况。在这个例句中，虚拟语气被用来表示三星和高通是当前市场上的即时领导者，这是因为他们目前的产品和能力使他们成为第一批进入者。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>连词 - 两种或多种语法单位（如词、短语或句子）之间的连接符。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p>    <p>语法讲解：连词是连接词或词组的词，用以表示说话者或作家的态度或观点。例如，有人说：“我爱你”，这句话使用了连词“爱”，因为这表达了说话者对另一个人的感情。在这个例句中，连词“according to”被用来表示根据Counterpoint Research的估计，预计到2027年底将出货超过10亿部内置生成式人工智能的智能手机。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out</li>
<li>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates</li>
</ul><p>The world’s most prolific smartphone maker is leaning into artificial intelligence (AI) as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.</p><p>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – on January 17 in San Jose, California, with a live-streamed event. The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming”.</p><p>In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out, but 2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246310/huawei-launches-new-nova-smartphones-without-giving-details-chip-attention-remains-fixed-its" title="">Huawei launches new Nova smartphones without giving details on chip</a></h3><p>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p><p>OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Dall-E tools, which generate text or visual responses to users’ queries, are at the forefront of a generative-AI wave that is swept across the tech industry – and helped make Nvidia a trillion-dollar company by providing the key AI-training accelerators. The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices, as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year.</p><p>“Samsung and Qualcomm are immediate leaders as current product offerings and capabilities position them as first movers,” the Counterpoint researchers wrote in December. “Similar to what it did with foldables, Samsung is likely to capture almost 50 per cent share for the next two years, followed by key Chinese OEMs like Xiaomi, Vivo, Honor and Oppo.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok use</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247089/montana-appealing-ruling-blocked-state-barring-tiktok-use</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Montana's attorney general is appealing a court ruling that blocked a state law banning the use of the Chinese-owned video sharing app TikTok. Judge Donald Molloy had granted a preliminary injunction against the ban, ruling that it violates the Constitution and oversteps state power. TikTok has denied sharing US user data with the Chinese government and taken measures to protect user privacy.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Montana appeals court ruling against TikTok ban.</li>    <li>Theme: Legal challenge to Montana's ban on TikTok over concerns about data privacy and national security.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The state's authority to regulate technology and the federal government's role in foreign policy.</li>    <li>Main information: Montana's ban on TikTok, preliminary injunction issued by Judge Molloy, TikTok's response and legal arguments, efforts to restrict TikTok at the federal level.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  蒙大拿州总检察长就法院裁决对该州禁止使用中国短视频分享应用 TikTok 的法律提出上诉。唐纳德·莫洛伊法官已对该禁令颁布了初步禁令，裁定该禁令违反宪法，越权执法。TikTok 否认与中国政府分享美国用户数据，并采取措施保护用户隐私。  <ul>    <li>摘要：蒙大拿州就法院裁决反对 TikTok 禁令提出上诉。</li>    <li>主题：针对蒙大拿州禁止 TikTok 的法律挑战，原因是担心数据隐私和国家安全。</li>    <li>观点：该州监管技术和联邦政府在外交政策中的作用的权力。</li>    <li>主要信息：蒙大拿州禁止 TikTok、莫洛伊法官发布的初步禁令、TikTok 的回应和法律论据、联邦层面限制 TikTok 的努力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>preliminary injunction (n.) - /prɪˈlɪmɪnəri ɪnˈdʒʌŋkʃən/ 初步禁令。    <p>原文例句：US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词是由preliminary（初步的）和injunction（禁令）组成的，表示“法院在诉讼过程中为保护当事人的合法权益而作出的临时性强制措施”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国地方法院唐纳德·莫洛伊法官于11月30日发布的初步禁令，该禁令阻止了蒙大拿州禁止TikTok的法律。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>violate (v.) - /ˈvaɪ.ə.leɪt/ 违反，侵犯。    <p>原文例句：Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government and the state’s action was too sweeping.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个动词来源于拉丁语violare，意思是“破坏，侵犯”。在这个例句中，它表示莫洛伊法官认为蒙大拿州试图行使由联邦政府掌握的外交政策权力，并且该州的行动过于广泛。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>sweeping (adj.) - /ˈswiː.pɪŋ/ 广泛的，全面的。    <p>原文例句：Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government and the state’s action was too sweeping.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词是由sweep（扫，掠过）派生而来的，意思是“广泛的，全面的”。在这个例句中，它表示莫洛伊法官认为蒙大拿州试图行使由联邦政府掌握的外交政策权力，并且该州的行动过于广泛。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take effect - 生效，起作用。    <p>原文例句：Montana’s ban had been set to take effect on January 1.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，取）和effect（效果）组成的，表示“生效，起作用”。在这个例句中，它指的是蒙大拿州的禁令原定于1月1日生效。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TikTok users in Montana also had filed suit last year to block the ban approved by the state legislature, which cited concerns about the personal data of Montana users and potential Chinese spying.</li><p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是TikTok users in Montana had filed suit last year to block the ban，其中主语是TikTok users in Montana，谓语是had filed suit，宾语是the ban。从句是which cited concerns about the personal data of Montana users and potential Chinese spying，其中主语是which，谓语是cited，宾语是concerns about the personal data of Montana users and potential Chinese spying。这个句子的意思是说，去年，蒙大拿州的 TikTok 用户也提起诉讼，阻止州议会批准的禁令，该禁令提到了对蒙大拿州用户个人数据以及潜在的中国间谍活动的担忧。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成或发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Molloy had previously said preliminary pretrial statements were due by January 16. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的过去式或过去分词。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间点之前已经完成或发生。在这个例句中，它表示莫洛伊法官之前说过，初步的审前陈述应在1月16日之前提交。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice that the state is appealing the ruling to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals</li>
<li>US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’</li>
</ul><p>Montana said on Tuesday it was appealing a decision by a US judge in November to block the state's first-of-its kind ban on the use of short-video sharing app TikTok.</p><p>Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice that the state is appealing the ruling to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals.</p><p>Montana’s ban had been set to take effect on January 1, but US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban on the Chinese-owned app, saying Montana’s law “violates the Constitution in more ways than one” and “oversteps state power”.</p><p>TikTok and Knudsen’s office did not immediately comment. Molloy had previously said preliminary pretrial statements were due by January 16.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246313/taiwan-elections-tiktok-teams-fact-checkers-stop-disinformation-site" title="">TikTok teams up with fact checkers to stop election disinformation on site</a></h3><p>TikTok users in Montana also had filed suit last year to block the ban approved by the state legislature, which cited concerns about the personal data of Montana users and potential Chinese spying.</p><p>In earlier court filings, TikTok said it “has not shared, and would not share, US user data with the Chinese government, and has taken substantial measures to protect the privacy and security of TikTok users”. Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government and the state’s action was too sweeping.</p><p>TikTok has faced efforts by some in Congress to ban the app or give the Biden administration's powers to impose restrictions or bar foreign-owned apps, but those efforts have stalled.</p><p>Many states and the US government have barred TikTok on government-owned devices, but only Montana has sought to completely bar the app’s use.</p><p>Former President Donald Trump in 2020 sought to bar new downloads of TikTok and Chinese-owned WeChat, but a series of court decisions blocked the effective ban from taking effect.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple hits 7-week low after Barclays downgrade on demand concerns</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In 2023, Apple saw a significant surge in its stock value, reaching an all-time high in mid-December. However, the company faces challenges, including a demand slowdown and concerns over its devices' weak demand in 2024, leading to a recent stock decline. Apple's performance in China, competition from Huawei, and scrutiny of its app store practices further contribute to its current situation.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's stock rise in 2023 is contrasted with its current challenges.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's stock performance, challenges, and outlook for 2024.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Concerns about Apple's demand slowdown, competition, and app store practices, leading to a bearish outlook.</li>    <li>Main information: Apple's stock rise in 2023; demand slowdown; weak demand forecast for 2024; China's impact; Huawei's competition; app store scrutiny.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023 年，苹果的股票价值大幅上涨，于 12 月中旬达到历史最高点。然而，该公司也面临挑战，包括需求放缓以及对 2024 年设备需求疲软的担忧，导致股价近期下跌。苹果在中国的表现不佳、华为的竞争以及其应用商店做法的审查进一步加剧了其当前的困境。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果 2023 年的股价上涨与其目前面临的挑战形成鲜明对比。</li>    <li>主题：苹果的股票表现、挑战和 2024 年的前景。</li>    <li>观点：对苹果需求放缓、竞争和应用商店做法的担忧，导致看跌的前景。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果 2023 年的股价上涨；需求放缓；预测 2024 年的需求疲软；中国的冲击；华为的竞争；对应用商店的审查。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>grapple (v.) - /ˈgræpəl/ 努力应付。    <p>原文例句：The company has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词的意思是“努力应对，努力应付”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司一直在努力应对需求放缓，并预计假日季度的销售额低于华尔街的预期。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>below Wall Street estimates - 低于华尔街预期。    <p>原文例句：The company has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组的意思是“低于华尔街预期”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司预计假日季度的销售额低于华尔街的预期。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Analysts, on average, rate the iPhone maker “buy”, with a median price target of US$200. - 分析师平均认为iPhone制造商“买入”，目标价中值为200美元。</p>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Analysts rate the iPhone maker “buy”，其中主语是Analysts，谓语是rate，宾语是the iPhone maker “buy”。on average, with a median price target of US$200是一个独立的状语，表示分析师平均认为iPhone制造商“买入”，目标价中值为200美元。这个句子的意思是说，分析师平均认为iPhone制造商“买入”，目标价中值为200美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。在这个例句中，它表示苹果公司一直在努力应对需求放缓，从去年的年初开始一直持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple’s shares rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech firms led the markets</li>
<li>The company has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates</li>
</ul><p>Apple on Tuesday fell nearly 3.6 per cent to a seven-week low after Barclays downgraded the shares of the world’s most valuable company on concerns that demand for its devices, from the iPhone to the Mac, will remain weak in 2024.</p><p>Barclays is the second brokerage to have the equivalent of a “sell” rating on the stock, which now has its most number of bearish recommendations in at least two years, according to LSEG data.</p><p>The stock accounts for a hefty 7 per cent of the S&amp;P 500’s market weight – the broader index was dragged 0.56 per cent lower on Tuesday.</p><p>Apple rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech companies led the markets.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245817/apple-ramps-vision-pro-production-aiming-launch-february" title="">Apple ramps up Vision Pro production, aiming for launch by February</a></h3><p>Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates. Its performance in China has also been a worry after the revival of local rival Huawei Technologies.</p><p>“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long said in a client note, pointing to the China weakness as well as subdued demand in developed markets.</p><p>Long is rated four out of five stars for his recommendation accuracy on Apple, according to LSEG data.</p><p>The brokerage also warned risks were mounting for Apple’s services business, which has come under the scanner in countries including the United States over app store practices.</p><p>The business has often outpaced growth in Apple’s hardware segment in recent years and now accounts for nearly a quarter of the company’s total revenue.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3246322/us-import-ban-certain-apple-watch-models-takes-effect-over-patent-clash" title="">Apple to appeal US watch ban in patent dispute</a></h3><p>The stock rout on Tuesday erased more than US$100 billion of Apple’s market capitalisation, as its shares closed at US$185.64.</p><p>Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral” and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160. Before Tuesday, Itau BBA’s “sell” was the only bearish rating on Apple since July 2022.</p><p>Analysts, on average, rate the iPhone maker “buy”, with a median price target of US$200. The company trades at about 28.7 times its 12-month forward earnings estimates, much higher than the S&amp;P 500’s 19.8.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese video gaming official steps down after market rout linked to proposed rule changes, sources say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Feng Shixin, a prominent official in China's video game industry, has stepped down from his role at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department.</li>    <li>This move follows the release of draft rules by the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) that proposed restrictions on consumer spending in video games, leading to a sell-off of Chinese gaming stocks.</li>    <li>Feng's departure may indicate a potential rollback of some of the proposed restrictions in an effort to reduce the negative impact on the video game industry and financial markets.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国共产党中央宣传部出版局局长冯士新因视频游戏行业监督管理产生影响，导致相关股票大幅下跌，被迫离职。</li>    <li>国家新闻出版署发布的视频游戏消费限额等新规引发中国游戏股下跌，冯士新的离职可能预示着一些限制可能被取消，以减轻对视频游戏行业和金融市场的负面影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>whipsaw (v.) - 猛烈摇摆，使剧烈振动。    <p>原文例句：The departure also underscored the importance of shielding financial markets from being whipsawed by haphazard government policies. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于英语的动词whip（鞭打，抽打），有“猛烈摇摆，使剧烈振动”的意思。在这个例句中，它表示金融市场受到政府政策的猛烈摇摆。</p></li>    <li>quota (n.) - 配额，限额。    <p>原文例句：Video game developers would have to implement measures to cap user spending, with bans on “excessive” rewards for activity such as daily logins and top-ups for fresh spending by consumers. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语的quotus（多少），有“配额，限额”的意思。在这个例句中，它表示视频游戏开发商必须采取措施来限制用户支出，禁止对用户行为（例如每日登录和充值）给予“过多的”奖励。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>a significant impact on - 对……有重大影响。    <p>原文例句：Any regulation that could have “a significant impact on capital markets” must be coordinated with financial management departments in advance. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由a（一个），significant（重要的），impact（影响）和on（在……上面）组成，表示“对……有重大影响”。在这个例句中，它表示任何可能对资本市场产生“重大影响”的监管政策都必须事先与金融管理部门协调。</p></li>    <li>subject to - 受到……的支配，受……的影响。    <p>原文例句：previously subject to a harsh crackdown – and broad efforts by the government to stabilise stock market sentiment and support the country’s private sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由subject（主题，对象）和to（对，朝向）组成，表示“受到……的支配，受……的影响”。在这个例句中，它表示视频游戏行业之前受到严厉打击，而政府正在努力稳定股市情绪并支持该国的私营部门。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Feng’s departure comes as Beijing attempts to limit the damage from the NPPA’s disclosure on December 23 of draft rules aimed at reining back spending on video games, which triggered a global sell-off of China gaming stocks, including leading players such as Tencent Holdings and NetEase.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Feng’s departure comes as Beijing attempts to limit the damage，其中主语是Feng’s departure，谓语是comes，宾语是Beijing attempts to limit the damage。the NPPA’s disclosure on December 23 of draft rules aimed at reining back spending on video games是一个过去分词短语作时间状语，表示在12月23日，NPPA公布了旨在控制视频游戏支出的新规。which triggered a global sell-off of China gaming stocks, including leading players such as Tencent Holdings and NetEase是一个定语从句，修饰new rules，表示新规引发了中国游戏股的大幅抛售，包括腾讯控股和网易等龙头企业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 为了强调或突出句子的某个成分，而将句子中某些成分的正常语序颠倒过来。    <p>原文例句：In an attempt at damage control, the NPPA subsequently said the proposed regulation changes were aimed at “healthy development” of the gaming industry and that it would “revise and improve” the rules.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，正常语序应该是The NPPA subsequently said in an attempt at damage control that the proposed regulation changes were aimed at “healthy development” of the gaming industry and that it would “revise and improve” the rules。将in an attempt at damage control置于句首，是为了强调NPPA在试图控制损失。这个句子的意思是说，为了控制损失，NPPA随后表示，拟议的监管变更旨在“健康发展”游戏产业，并将“修改和完善”相关规则。</p></li>    <li>并列句 - 由两个或两个以上结构相同或相似的句子并列组合而成的句子。    <p>原文例句：The timing and severity of the proposed rule changes dealt a fresh blow to already-fragile investor confidence in Chinese stocks. NetEase, the country’s No. 2 gaming operator, fell by nearly a quarter in a single trading day, with Tencent dropping over 12 per cent.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个并列句，由两个简单句组成：The timing and severity of the proposed rule changes dealt a fresh blow to already-fragile investor confidence in Chinese stocks。NetEase, the country’s No. 2 gaming operator, fell by nearly a quarter in a single trading day, with Tencent dropping over 12 per cent。这两个简单句之间用逗号隔开，表示并列关系。这个句子的意思是说，拟议规则变更的时间和严厉程度对中国股市的脆弱投资者信心造成新的打击。网易，该国第二大游戏运营商，在单个交易日内下跌了近四分之一，腾讯下跌超过12%。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Feng Shixin has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, people say</li>
<li>Move comes as Beijing attempts to limit the damage from draft rules from watchdog aimed at reining back spending on video games</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/c1897329-2f24-429e-bd01-4e017c08984b_8dd3a965.jpg" /><figcaption>Feng Shixin has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, people say. Photo: Xinhua </figcaption></figure><p>A key Chinese official involved in oversight of the country’s video gaming industry has stepped down after proposed regulation last month wiped out billions of dollars of value from Chinese gaming stocks, according to people familiar with the situation.</p><p>Feng Shixin, a long-serving official, has left his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, one person told the South China Morning Post, asking not to be identified due to the sensitivity of the matter.</p><p>A second person, who also asked for anonymity, said Feng’s departure was a sign that China may walk back some of last month’s proposed restrictions on consumer spending in video games, which surprised the market due to their severity.</p><p>The National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA), the agency that answers directly to the propaganda authority in overseeing China’s video gaming industry, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246161/chinas-video-gaming-watchdog-speaks-out-after-draft-spending-rules-roil-market" title="">China’s video gaming watchdog speaks out after spending rules roil market</a></h3><p>Feng’s departure comes as Beijing attempts to limit the damage from the NPPA’s disclosure on December 23 of draft rules aimed at reining back spending on video games, which triggered a global sell-off of China gaming stocks, including leading players such as Tencent Holdings and NetEase.</p><p>The departure also underscored the importance of shielding financial markets from being whipsawed by haphazard government policies. Any regulation that could have “a significant impact on capital markets” <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3170664/chinas-vice-premier-liu-he-vows-support-economic-growth" target="_self" title="">must be coordinated</a> with financial management departments in advance, the Xinhua news agency reported in March 2022, quoting then Vice-Premier Liu He.</p><p>According to the published proposals, which are open to public feedback until January 22, video game developers would have to implement measures to cap user spending, with bans on “excessive” rewards for activity such as daily logins and top-ups for fresh spending by consumers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3170664/chinas-vice-premier-liu-he-vows-support-economic-growth" title="">China vows ‘substantial measures’ to shore up economy as headwinds grow</a></h3><p>The timing and severity of the proposed rule changes dealt a fresh blow to already-fragile investor confidence in Chinese stocks. NetEase, the country’s No. 2 gaming operator, fell by nearly a quarter in a single trading day, with Tencent dropping over 12 per cent.</p><p>The new rules appeared to be at odds with a recent change in Beijing’s tone towards the video gaming industry – previously subject to a harsh crackdown – and broad efforts by the government to stabilise stock market sentiment and support the country’s private sector.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>In an attempt at damage control, the NPPA subsequently said the proposed regulation changes were aimed at “healthy development” of the gaming industry and that it would “revise and improve” the rules.</p><p>Meanwhile, the regulator approved 105 new <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">video games</a> for sale in China for December, the most in 17 months, in a supportive gesture to an industry with combined annual sales of 300 billion yuan (US$40 billion) in 2023.</p><p>Feng is a veteran regulator. He delivered keynote speeches at the China Gaming Industry Annual Conference, the yearly gathering of officials and executives for three consecutive years in 2018, 2019 and 2020 as a deputy publication bureau chief.</p><p>In December 2020, Feng urged China’s gaming companies to be vigilant about gaming content and not to “provide channels for any harmful content”.</p><p>At the latest annual conference in December 2023, Yang Fang, an official from the NPPA, delivered the keynote speech after Feng delegated the task to her.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/markets/article/3246336/hong-kong-stocks-recover-tencent-netease-recoup-part-us63-billion-sell-while-new-china-report-aids" title="">Hong Kong stocks rebound as Tencent, NetEase rally, China data aids sentiment</a></h3><p>China has developed a sophisticated regulatory system for video gaming since the propaganda department took over the regulatory authority in 2018 from other ministries.</p><p>All online video games must go through rigorous screening to obtain licences before being released to the public and monetised, and all players are required to have real-name registration.</p><p>Prior to a recent easing, Chinese authorities had deemed video gaming as “spiritual opium” and implemented several rules to avoid addiction among minors and to promote healthy growth of the industry.</p><p>In the summer of 2021, China imposed a play time ceiling of three hours per week – from 8pm to 9pm on Fridays, Saturdays and Sundays – for players under the age of 18.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chip industry giant ASML blocked by US, Netherlands from shipping equipment to China ahead of export deadline</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247042/chip-industry-giant-asml-blocked-us-netherlands-shipping-equipment-china-ahead-export-deadline</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ASML, a significant maker of lithography machines, has faced export license revocations for certain machines to China.</li>    <li>The Chinese Foreign Ministry criticizes this action as hegemonic and bullying, urging the Netherlands to support market principles.</li>    <li>The US has put pressure on ASML, limiting China's access to advanced EUV lithography systems.</li>    <li>China has recently applied for licenses to ship DUV systems before new limitations, obtaining three such licenses.</li>    <li>Dutch restrictions follow US restrictions on DUV machines, leading Chinese manufacturers to stockpile chip-making equipment.</li>    <li>ASML clarifies its commitment to complying with export control regulations, maintaining its financial outlook despite the situation.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>   <li>阿斯麦公司作为制造光刻机的重要公司，其向中国出口的部分机器许可证遭到部分撤销。</li>    <li>中国外交部谴责此举是霸权主义和霸凌行为，敦促荷兰方面坚持公平市场原则。</li>    <li>美国方面对阿斯麦施压，限制中国获得先进的 EUV 光刻机系统。</li>    <li>中国方面近期申请了在新的限制生效前向中国出口 DUV 系统的许可证，并获得了三个这样的许可证。</li>    <li>荷兰的限制措施是继美国对 DUV 机器采取限制措施之后，导致中国制造商开始大量储备芯片制造设备。</li>    <li>阿斯麦公司明确了其遵守出口管制法规的承诺，尽管面临这种情况，但仍在维持其财务前景。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>lithography (n.) - /lɪˈθɒɡrəfi/ 石版印刷术，光刻术。    <p>原文例句：A licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government, impacting a small number of customers in China,” the company said in a statement on Monday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由litho-（石头）和graphy（书写）构成，表示“石版印刷术，光刻术”。在这个例句中，它指的是一种可以将设计图案转移到半导体晶圆上的技术，是制造集成电路的重要步骤。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>revocation (n.) - /rɛvəʊˈkeɪʃən/ 撤销，废除。    <p>原文例句：A licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government, impacting a small number of customers in China,” the company said in a statement on Monday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由re-（重新）和vocation（呼唤）构成，表示“撤销，废除”。在这个例句中，它指的是荷兰政府部分撤销了阿斯麦公司向中国出口某些光刻机系统的许可证。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fair market principles - 公平的市场原则。<P>原文例句：On Tuesday, Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesman Wang Wenbin condemned the “hegemonic and bullying behaviour” from the US, urging the Netherlands to uphold fair market principles and honour its contractual obligations.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由fair（公平的），market（市场）和principles（原则）构成，表示“公平的市场原则”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国外交部敦促荷兰遵守公平的市场原则。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>A licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government, impacting a small number of customers in China,” the company said in a statement on Monday. - 荷兰政府最近部分撤销了2023年向中国出口NXT:2050i和NXT:2100i[深紫外(DUV)]光刻系统的许可证，影响了中国少数客户。<p>句子分析：这是一个主动语态的句子，主语是The Dutch government，谓语是has revoked，宾语是a licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023，状语是impacting a small number of customers in China，时间状语是recently。这个句子的意思是说，荷兰政府最近部分撤销了2023年向中国出口NXT:2050i和NXT:2100i[深紫外(DUV)]光刻系统的许可证，影响了中国少数客户。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作的承受者。    <p>原文例句：The logo of chip equipment maker ASML seen at its booth during Semicon China, a trade fair for the semiconductor industry, in Shanghai on June 29, 2023. </p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是用来表示动作的承受者。被动语态的结构是：be+过去分词。在这个例句中，seen是see的过去分词，表示看到了。be是is，表示现在时态。所以，这个句子的意思是，2023年6月29日，在上海举行的半导体行业贸易展Semicon China上，人们在ASML公司的展位上看到了这家芯片设备制造商的标志。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示比较。    <p>原文例句：ASML is the biggest exporter of lithography machines, almost all of which come from ASML – though the company does not have the same hold on the DUV market as on EUV.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是用来表示比较的。比较级的结构是：more + 形容词/副词 + than。在这个例句中，more是比较级的前缀，形容词是big，than是比较级连词，ASML是比较的对象。所以，这个句子的意思是，ASML是最大的光刻机出口商，几乎所有的光刻机都来自ASML，尽管该公司在DUV市场上的占有率不如在EUV市场上那么大。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The maker of critical lithography systems said a licence to export some machines to China was partially revoked, but does not expect an impact on bottom line</li>
<li>The Chinese Foreign Ministry slammed the ‘hegemonic and bullying behaviour’ of the US and urged the Netherlands to uphold fair market principles</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/04ce0805-1869-40cf-9ab0-deeaa9b9e4ca_60c0c0ac.jpg" /><figcaption>The logo of chip equipment maker ASML seen at its booth during Semicon China, a trade fair for the semiconductor industry, in Shanghai on June 29, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Dutch chip-making equipment manufacturer ASML was forced to cancel some shipments to China after having licences partially revoked, in a blow to the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls">apparent efforts to stockpile</a> related technology ahead of new restrictions.</p><p>“A licence for the shipment of NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i [deep ultraviolet (DUV)] lithography systems in 2023 has recently been partially revoked by the Dutch government, impacting a small number of customers in China,” the company said in a statement on Monday.</p><p>On Tuesday, Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesman Wang Wenbin condemned the “hegemonic and bullying behaviour” from the US, urging the Netherlands to uphold fair market principles and honour its contractual obligations.</p><p>Under US pressure, ASML already restricts Chinese clients from buying its more advanced extreme ultraviolet (EUV) lithography systems, which are used to produce the world’s most cutting-edge chips. ASML has a near monopoly on the machines.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Wang Wenbin, gestures during a press conference in Beijing on January 2, 2024, where he discussed the suspension on some exports of Dutch company ASML to China. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/608cf9f2-a296-426f-8d3a-a814ac9f96ea_5af09944.jpg" title="China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Wang Wenbin, gestures during a press conference in Beijing on January 2, 2024, where he discussed the suspension on some exports of Dutch company ASML to China. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Wang Wenbin, gestures during a press conference in Beijing on January 2, 2024, where he discussed the suspension on some exports of Dutch company ASML to China. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>However, from September, the Dutch equipment maker had been able to apply for licences to ship some of its less advanced DUV systems to China ahead of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3240707/chinas-soaring-dutch-imports-signal-stockpiling-asml-kit-ahead-us-backed-export-controls">new restrictions</a> that came into effect on January 1. The Dutch manufacturer received three such licences.</p><p>Lithography tools are complex projection systems that are considered the most important equipment needed in the process of producing integrated circuits. China is considered years behind in this tech, and has so far struggled to close the gap with leading firms despite heavy government investment.</p><p>Ahead of the Dutch restrictions, and following the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy">expanded US export restrictions</a> on DUV machines in October, Chinese manufacturers have been importing and stockpiling <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened">record numbers</a> of chip-making equipment from abroad.</p><p>China imported 42 lithography systems in November for US$816.8 million, with companies in the Netherlands and Japan accounting for nearly the entire amount spent on such imports.</p><p>China’s imports of critical chip-making lithography systems from the Netherlands, in particular, surged 1,050 per cent in value that month. The Netherlands is the biggest exporter of lithography machines, almost all of which come from ASML – though the company does not have the same hold on the DUV market as on EUV.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened" title="">China’s imports of Dutch chip-making equipment surged tenfold in November</a></h3><p>After a teardown of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a>’ latest 5G smartphone, the Mate 60 Pro, concluded that Chinese chip maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductor-manufacturing-international-corporation-smic" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductor-manufacturing-international-corporation-smic">Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC)</a> produced the device’s advanced 7-nanometre chip using DUV lithography machines, some <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain">experts predicted</a> more would be done to restrict China’s access to such technology.</p><p>Citing anonymous sources, Bloomberg reported on Tuesday that US President <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/people/joe-biden" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/people/joe-biden">Joe Biden</a>’s administration had requested that ASML cancel several shipments of DUV systems to China weeks ahead of new rules coming into force this month.</p><p>A spokeswoman from ASML declined to comment on that timeline, but noted that it was unlikely that the company would receive new licences for the NXT:2050i and NXT:2100i DUV machines in 2024.</p><p>“In recent discussions with the US government, ASML has obtained further clarification of the scope and impact of the US export control regulations,” the equipment maker said in its Monday statement.</p><p>“ASML is fully committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations, including export control legislation in the countries in which we operate,” it added.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>In recent years, China has been ASML’s third-largest market after Taiwan and South Korea, but it jumped to first place in the third quarter of 2023, accounting for 46 per cent of sales. This was up from 24 per cent in the previous quarter and 8 per cent in the first quarter.</p><p>In November, Shen Bo, senior vice-president of ASML and president of its China arm, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240290/dutch-chip-equipment-giant-asml-looks-speed-delivery-mature-lithography-machines-china-clients" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240290/dutch-chip-equipment-giant-asml-looks-speed-delivery-mature-lithography-machines-china-clients">reportedly signalled</a> that the company was working to speed up deliveries to China to meet demand for DUV machines. At the time, the company had a backlog of €35 billion (US$37 billion) from orders made in 2021 and 2022, which included orders from China, he added.</p><p>In an investor call the previous month, ASML CEO Peter Wennink said the company had fulfilled less than 50 per cent of Chinese clients’ orders in the previous two years, but shifting demand from other customers created an opportunity to fulfil more orders in the country.</p><p>In its most recent statement, ASML said it did not expect the licence revocation or the latest US export controls to have a material impact on its 2023 financial outlook, echoing similar sentiments expressed in its latest financial report.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Baidu’s move to cancel YY Live acquisition amid fierce market competition, tougher regulation a boon to firm’s AI business expansion, analysts say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247038/baidus-move-cancel-yy-live-acquisition-amid-fierce-market-competition-tougher-regulation-boon-firms</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  - Baidu's decision to terminate its acquisition of Joyy's live-streaming business reflects its sharpened focus on developing artificial intelligence (AI) technologies and products. This move is aligned with China's broader efforts to leverage AI for economic growth.  - The company aims to integrate AI into all its products and services, as exemplified by its Ernie Bot chatbot, which has gained significant user traction since its launch.  - However, the fate of the YY Live deal remains uncertain as Joyy intends to seek legal consultation and consider various options. The termination could impact Joyy's future strategy in the live-streaming industry amidst increasing competition and tighter regulations.</div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  - 百度取消收购欢聚集团旗下YY Live直播业务的决定，表明了百度正加紧布局人工智能（AI）发展战略，致力于将AI技术融入到各款产品与服务中，推动公司实现长远、可持续的业绩增长。  - 百度去年11月推出的类ChatGPT服务“文心一言”，已经迅速赢得了大量用户，在人工智能领域占据领先地位。  - 但是目前YY Live的交易却面临着不确定的命运，因为欢聚集团准备咨询法律意见并考虑各种应对策略。在不断加剧的竞争和严格的监管措施下，YY Live的终止交易可能会对其未来的发展战略产生影响。</div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>race (v.) - /reɪs/ 竞赛，比赛；竞争。    <p>原文例句：Chinese companies race to cash in on the technology and help boost the country’s economic recovery. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由race（比赛，竞争）构成的，表示“竞赛，比赛；竞争”。在这个例句中，它描述了中国公司竞相利用这项技术来帮助提升中国经济复苏的能力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>chatbot (n.) - /ˈtʃætbɑːt/ 聊天机器人。    <p>原文例句：The company’s more basic artificial intelligence chatbot, Ernie 3.5 remains free of charge to the public. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由chat（聊天）和bot（机器人）构成的，表示“聊天机器人”。在这个例句中，它描述了该公司更基础的人工智能聊天机器人Ernie 3.5仍然对公众免费。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take a deep breath - 深呼吸。    <P>原文例句：Take a deep breath and think step by step. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿），a（一个），deep（深的），breath（呼吸）构成的，表示“深呼吸”。在这个例句中，它表示要深呼吸，然后一步一步地思考。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>construction (n.) - /kənˈstrʌkʃən/ 建设，建造；构造，结构。    <P>原文例句：Zachary Salzwedel, the company’s construction manager, knows what his project deadlines are and is happy to meet them. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由construct（建设），ion（ion）构成的，表示“建设，建造；构造，结构”。在这个例句中，它是指一个项目经理知道他项目的最后期限并且很高兴能够满足它们。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Baidu’s decision to terminate its acquisition of social media firm Joyy’s live-streaming business shows the internet search giant’s sharpened focus on artificial intelligence (AI) development initiatives, according to analysts, as Chinese companies race to cash in on the technology and help boost the country’s economic recovery. - 根据分析师的说法，百度决定终止收购社交媒体公司欢聚集团的直播业务，表明这家互联网搜索巨头更加关注人工智能 (AI) 开发计划，因为中国公司竞相利用这项技术来帮助提振国家的经济复苏。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Baidu’s decision to terminate its acquisition of social media firm Joyy’s live-streaming business shows the internet search giant’s sharpened focus on artificial intelligence (AI) development initiatives，其中主语是Baidu’s decision to terminate its acquisition of social media firm Joyy’s live-streaming business，谓语是shows，宾语是the internet search giant’s sharpened focus on artificial intelligence (AI) development initiatives。as Chinese companies race to cash in on the technology and help boost the country’s economic recovery是一个时间状语，表示当中国公司竞相利用这项技术来帮助提振国家的经济复苏时。这个句子的意思是说，根据分析师的说法，百度决定终止收购社交媒体公司欢聚集团的直播业务，表明这家互联网搜索巨头更加关注人工智能 (AI) 开发计划，因为中国公司竞相利用这项技术来帮助提振国家的经济复苏。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>省句 - 只保留句子中必要的成分，其他成分省略。    <p>原文例句：He rarely left the house, just worked, slept. - 他很少离开家，只是工作，睡觉。</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，主语He，谓语left，宾语house都被省略了，只保留了必要的成分，即worked和slept，这样的句子称为省句。省句通常用于口语中，以使语言更加简洁、轻松。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>绝对比较句 - 表示两种情况的绝对比较。    <p>原文例句：It is not a hotel, more a kind of house-museum. - 它不是一家酒店，更像一种住宅博物馆。</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，It is not a hotel是第一个比较句，more a kind of house-museum是第二个比较句，not是程度副词，表示否定，more表示更多，a kind of house-museum是名词短语，表示一种住宅博物馆。这个句子使用了绝对比较句的句式，表示It is not a hotel和more a kind of house-museum这两种情况的绝对比较。绝对比较句通常用于比较两种情况的程度或数量，以强调其中一种情况更胜一筹。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Cancelling the YY Live acquisition is expected to help Baidu put more teeth into its artificial intelligence-centric business and product strategy</li>
<li>That move was ‘not totally unexpected’ amid changes in China’s internet sector, where the growing focus has been on generative AI, analysts said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/0c0aab40-f9c0-4f96-af99-649dd4a00b3d_8d4efc03.jpg" /><figcaption>Internet search giant Baidu has been sharpening its focus on artificial intelligence development initiatives. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>’s decision to terminate its acquisition of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> firm Joyy’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/live-streaming" target="_self" title="">live-streaming</a> business shows the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> search giant’s sharpened focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) development initiatives, according to analysts, as Chinese companies <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3239981/baidu-launches-paid-version-ernie-bot-chinese-firms-rush-make-money-their-generative-ai-chatbots" target="_self" title="">race to cash in on the technology</a> and help <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3224050/can-ai-give-china-upper-hand-surpass-us-and-become-worlds-top-economy-after-chatgpt-changed-game" target="_self" title="">boost the country’s economic recovery</a>.</p><p>In a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong-stock-market" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong stock exchange</a> filing on Monday, Baidu said its affiliate Moon SPV exercised the right to terminate the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3110190/baidu-buys-live-streaming-service-yy-it-seeks-catch-rivals-such" target="_self" title="">US$3.6 billion acquisition of YY Live</a> from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/singapore" target="_self" title="">Singapore</a>-based Joyy because the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246921/baidus-live-streaming-ambitions-dealt-blow-lapse-us36-billion-deal-buy-joyys-yy-live" target="_self" title="">deal lapsed, as it failed to meet certain conditions</a> that include obtaining the necessary regulatory approvals from government authorities as of December 31.</p><p>This move was “not totally unexpected, given investors have been waiting for more details in past years”, Jefferies equity analysts Thomas Chong and Zoey Zong said in a research note on Monday following Baidu’s announcement. They indicated that China’s internet sector “has been undergoing changes”, which reflects Baidu’s focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">generative AI</a>.</p><p>“For Baidu, Ernie Bot [has already] achieved a milestone in user base and [helps] reconstruct all [of the company’s] products with AI,” the Jefferies analysts said in their report, citing an announcement made during the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238197/baidu-says-ai-chatbot-ernie-now-matches-openais-gpt-4-unveils-new-enterprise-tools" target="_self" title="">Baidu World 2023 conference in Beijing</a> last October.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours. The company’s more basic artificial intelligence chatbot, Ernie 3.5 remains free of charge to the public. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1192" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/02/efbd36b2-fd43-498a-9fc7-a6ca3fe68665_3190cbb8.jpg" title="Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours. The company’s more basic artificial intelligence chatbot, Ernie 3.5 remains free of charge to the public. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Baidu last November launched the paid version of its ChatGPT-like service, Ernie Bot, enabling subscribers to make 100 inquiries every three hours. The company’s more basic artificial intelligence chatbot, Ernie 3.5 remains free of charge to the public. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>By cancelling the YY Live deal, Baidu could put more teeth into its AI-centric business and product strategy, which co-founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3211124/baidu-beats-fourth-quarter-estimates-internet-search-giant-bets-future-developing-chinas-answer?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Robin Li Yanhong</a> said in the firm’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242461/baidu-forecasts-ai-revenue-growth-and-limited-short-term-impact-us-chip-curbs" target="_self" title="">third-quarter earnings report</a> was setting “the stage for sustained multi-year revenue and profit expansion within our Ernie and Ernie Bot ecosystem”.</p><p>In the company’s earnings call in November, Li said Ernie Bot was handling tens of millions of queries daily three months into its public roll-out, while thousands of enterprises have adopted Baidu’s AI services. As of December 28, Ernie Bot already amassed more than 100 million users, according to Baidu.</p><p>Still, Baidu aims to discuss with Joyy the next steps after the termination of the YY Live share purchase agreement. Baidu’s Hong Kong-listed shares edged down 0.7 per cent to HK$115.3 (US$14.76) on Tuesday.</p><p>Joyy, however, “is seeking legal advice” and “will consider all options at its disposal”. The company claims that the deal, which was entered into in November 2020, was “substantially completed” in February 2021, with certain matters to be completed in future.</p><p>The market cap of Nasdaq-listed Joyy has shrunk by a third over the past three years. The firm’s shares closed at US$39.7 on December 29, which was lower than its November 2020 level of around US$60.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246921/baidus-live-streaming-ambitions-dealt-blow-lapse-us36-billion-deal-buy-joyys-yy-live" title="">Baidu’s bid to buy Joyy’s live-streaming business lapses</a></h3><p>On microblogging service <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/weibo" target="_self" title="">Weibo</a>, Beijing-based angel investor Timothy Guo Tao said in a post that “fierce competition and tougher regulation on live streaming” services on the mainland could have also played a part in Baidu’s decision to bring the YY Live deal to an end.</p><p>In November, YY Live’s monthly active users totalled 16 million, lower than <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/douyu" target="_self" title="">Douyu International</a>’s 31 million and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/huya" target="_self" title="">Huya</a>’s 23 million, according to market intelligence firm Analysys. In July 2021, the Chinese government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3140625/chinas-antitrust-regulator-blocks-tencents-us53-billion-merger-game" target="_self" title="">blocked the US$5.3 billion merger</a> of video game streamers Douyu and Huya.</p><p>Even though YY Live is a pioneer of China’s live-streaming sector, it has been overtaken by younger market players like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243683/douyin-chinese-version-tiktok-testing-paid-videos-again-some-users-push-back" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Kuaishou Technology</a>, which are China’s top two short video platforms that also provide live- streaming features.</p><p>Joyy’s YY Live had also been the target of criticism from US hedge fund Muddy Waters, which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3110485/muddy-waters-targets-chinese-social-media-company-joyy-days-after" target="_self" title="">labelled Joyy “a multibillion-dollar fraud”</a> in a report just days after Baidu entered the deal to buy YY Live. The American short seller claimed that up to 90 per cent of YY Live’s live-streaming revenue was fraudulent. Joyy refuted the report, asserting that it “contained numerous errors, unsubstantiated statements and misleading conclusions”.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>With Baidu’s deal cancelled, YY Live must now “rethink its competition strategy”, said Chen Yuxin, analyst at LeadLeo Research Institute.</p><p>YY Live, according to Chen, has become a laggard in the live-streaming industry, where it has neither expanded into e-commerce nor transformed into a strong social media platform in China.</p><p>Tighter scrutiny by mainland regulators on live-streaming services could also be more challenging for YY Live to compete. Chen said <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242432/video-game-streamer-douyu-confirms-ceos-arrest-china-after-weeks-speculation-about-gambling-content" target="_self" title="">the arrest of Douyu chief executive Chen Shaojie</a> in November on suspicion of opening a casino “rang a bell to the entire industry that the authority will further strengthen regulation of the live-streaming industry”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
