<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Apple supplier BOE, one of the world’s top display makers, forges US$9 billion deal to build next-generation plant in southwestern China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248092/apple-supplier-boe-one-worlds-top-display-makers-forges-us9-billion-deal-build-next-generation-plant</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>BOE Technology Group is investing in a new 63 billion yuan production facility in Chengdu, Sichuan province, China.</li>    <li>The Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex is expected to start mass production in Q4 2026 and meet global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets.</li>    <li>The production facility will position Chengdu as the largest manufacturing base for advanced flexible panels in the display industry.</li>    <li>BOE's investment underscores efforts by Chinese local governments to increase collaboration with Big Tech companies in the private sector to restore business confidence and drive economic recovery.</li>    <li>OLED displays for mobile devices and information technology are expected to grow rapidly, with a forecasted CAGR of 7.3% from 2022 to 2027.</li>    <li>China is expected to dominate global display manufacturing capacity, with a 72% market share from 2026 to 2027.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>京东方科技集团将在中国四川省成都市投资建设一个630亿元人民币的生产基地。</li>    <li>该Gen-8.6 AMOLED生产综合体预计将于2026年第四季度开始量产，以满足全球对用于笔记本电脑和平板电脑的高端显示器的需求。</li>    <li>该生产基地将使成都成为显示行业先进柔性面板的最大制造基地。</li>    <li>京东方此次投资凸显了中国地方政府与私营部门的大型科技公司加强合作的努力，以恢复商业信心和推动经济复苏。</li>    <li>用于移动设备和信息技术设备的OLED显示屏预计将快速增长，据预测，2022年至2027年的复合年增长率为7.3%。</li>    <li>中国预计将主导全球显示器制造能力，2026年至2027年的市场份额将达到72%。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li><strong>complex (n.)</strong> - /ˈkɒmpleks/ 复杂的，复合的；一个复杂的或复合的东西。    <p>原文例句：The deal represents the largest single industrial project in terms of investment in Chengdu, the capital of southwestern Sichuan province.</p>    <p>例句讲解：此句中，“complex”用作名词，表示“综合体”，指代京东方科技集团在成都市投资建设的生产基地。</p></li>    <li><strong>soaring (adj.)</strong> - /ˈsɔːrɪŋ/ 高耸的，飞翔的；急剧上升的。    <p>原文例句：BOE Technology Group’s new production complex is expected to start mass production by the fourth quarter of 2026.</p>    <p>例句讲解：此句中，“soaring”用作形容词，表示“急剧上升的”，指代京东方科技集团新生产基地的产量。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li><strong>production complex</strong> - 生产综合体。    <p>原文例句：The deal represents the largest single industrial project in terms of investment in Chengdu, the capital of southwestern Sichuan province.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“production complex”是一个固定词组，表示“生产综合体”，指代京东方科技集团在成都市投资建设的生产基地。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li><strong>BOE’s so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex is expected to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets.</strong>    <p>句子分析：这是个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是“BOE’s so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex”，谓语是“is expected to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets”。句子大意是：京东方科技集团的Gen-8.6 AMOLED生产综合体预计将满足全球对用于笔记本电脑和平板电脑的高端显示器的需求。</p></li>    <li><strong>BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada.</strong>    <p>句子分析：这是个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是“BOE Technology Group”，谓语是“shows its latest flexible notebook display”。句子大意是：京东方科技集团在本周拉斯维加斯举行的CES贸易展上展示了其最新的柔性笔记本电脑显示器。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li><strong>Present perfect tense</strong> - 现在完成时。    <p>原文例句：BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line.</p>    <p>语法讲解：“previously established”是一个现在完成时的动词结构，表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态，并一直持续到现在。在此句中，“previously established”表示京东方科技集团过去已经建立了中国大陆第一条第六代柔性OLED生产线，并一直持续到现在。</p></li>    <li><strong>Comparative and superlative adjectives</strong> - 比较级和最高级形容词。    <p>原文例句：China is forecast to dominate global display manufacturing capacity, with a 72 per cent market share from 2026 to 2027.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在此句中，“dominate”是一个比较级形容词，表示“主导”；“largest”是一个最高级形容词，表示“最大的”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>BOE’s so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex is expected to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets</li>
<li>The deal represents the largest single industrial project in terms of investment in Chengdu, the capital of southwestern Sichuan province</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/f510ed59-cdd2-46ae-9e74-0cdf88c294bd_6e2e158b.jpg" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group’s new production complex for advanced displays in Chengdu, capital of southwestern Sichuan province, is expected to start mass production by the fourth quarter of 2026. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> supplier <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/3024664/how-chinese-accountant-turned-dying-state-owned-factory-worlds-no-1?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">BOE Technology Group</a>, one of the world’s largest display makers, will set up a 63-billion yuan (US$9 billion) next-generation production complex in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chengdu" target="_self" title="">Chengdu</a>, capital of southwestern Sichuan province, that is expected to bolster mainland China’s lead in display manufacturing capacity over the next few years.</p><p>The Chengdu municipal government on Wednesday said in a statement that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/beijing" target="_self" title="">Beijing</a>-based BOE and the city’s Hi-Tech Industrial Development Zone have signed the contract to build the plant, representing the largest single industrial project in the capital in terms of investment.</p><p>BOE, which initially announced the project last December, will build its so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED – for active-matrix organic light-emitting diode – production facility to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets, according to the firm.</p><p>Shares of BOE in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shenzhen" target="_self" title="">Shenzhen</a> closed up 1.07 per cent to 3.76 yuan on Thursday.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/81c3e4de-5983-4500-9e40-24c9b7f0441d_edd804f5.jpg" title="BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>The deal underscores efforts by Chinese local governments to increase collaboration with Big Tech companies in the private sector, which is in line with the mainland’s efforts to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3210306/chinas-key-private-sector-needs-continuity-stability-support-economic-recovery-doubts-remain" target="_self" title="">restore business confidence and drive economic recovery</a>.</p><p>The new BOE production facility is expected to position Chengdu as the display industry’s largest manufacturing base for advanced flexible panels.</p><p>Construction of the new plant is estimated to take 34 months, according to BOE, and mass production is projected to start by the fourth quarter of 2026. The next-generation plant is designed to produce 32,000 glass substrates – each measuring 2,290 millimetres by 2,620mm – every month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/73fdd8a8-8b16-4d68-8c5f-e654e2a0eacf_1126e908.jpg" title="BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Apart from accommodating larger substrates, BOE said its Gen-8.6 AMOLED production line will be able to enhance panel-cutting efficiency for mid-size displays, reduce production costs, lower power consumption and achieve an extended lifespan.</p><p>OLED displays for mobile and other information technology devices are expected to enjoy rapid expansion between 2022 and 2027, with a compound annual growth rate of 7.3 per cent, according to a recent report by Display Supply Chain Consultants (DSCC).</p><p>China is forecast to dominate global display manufacturing capacity, with a 72 per cent market share from 2026 to 2027, the DSCC report said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/3024664/how-chinese-accountant-turned-dying-state-owned-factory-worlds-no-1" title="">How Chinese accountant turned dying factory into No 1 display maker</a></h3><p>By comparison, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>’s market shares are expected to reach 8 per cent and 17 per cent, respectively, in 2027.</p><p>The global OLED market is predicted to generate US$64 billion in revenue in 2026, driven by demand for panels used in laptops, computers monitors and tablets, according to DSCC.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei secures JD.com as HarmonyOS partner as home-grown software emerges as alternative for Apple iOS, Android in China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248044/huawei-secures-jdcom-harmonyos-partner-home-grown-software-emerges-alternative-apple-ios-android</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In order to compete with Google's Android and Apple's iOS in the Chinese market, Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of its home-grown HarmonyOS. Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com will develop an app for HarmonyOS Next, which is expected to surpass Apple's iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year. HarmonyOS Next, scheduled for launch in 2024, will not support Android-based apps. Huawei has secured partnerships with several Chinese companies, including JD.com, NetEase, and Meituan, to develop native apps for HarmonyOS.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei partners with JD.com to expand HarmonyOS ecosystem and challenge Android and iOS dominance in China.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's efforts to promote HarmonyOS as a viable alternative to Android and iOS in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The potential of HarmonyOS to capture a significant market share in China and compete with global players.</li>    <li>Main information: JD.com's commitment to build an app for HarmonyOS Next; HarmonyOS Next's projected launch in 2024 without Android app compatibility; Huawei's collaborations with Chinese companies to develop native HarmonyOS apps.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  为了与谷歌的安卓和苹果的iOS在中国市场竞争，华为正推动旗下自主研发的鸿蒙操作系统HarmonyOS的广泛采用。中国电商巨头京东将为HarmonyOS Next构建应用，HarmonyOS Next有望在今年成为中国第二大操作系统，超过苹果的iOS。HarmonyOS Next计划于2024年推出，将不再支持基于安卓的应用。华为已与京东、网易和美团等多家中国公司达成合作，为HarmonyOS开发原生应用。拥有5500多家门店和20多万名员工的麦当劳中国成为首批采用HarmonyOS Next的跨国餐饮企业之一。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为携手京东，壮大鸿蒙生态，挑战安卓和iOS在中国的主导地位。</li>    <li>主题：华为努力推广鸿蒙，将其打造为安卓和iOS在中国的可行替代品。</li>    <li>观点：鸿蒙操作系统在中国赢得重要市场份额并与全球巨头竞争的潜力。</li>    <li>主要信息：京东承诺为HarmonyOS Next开发应用；HarmonyOS Next预计于2024年推出，但不兼容安卓应用；华为与中国企业合作开发鸿蒙原生应用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>secure (v.) - /sɪˈkjʊər/ 得到，确保。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies has secured another partner to promote use of HarmonyOS, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant continues to take on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由se（分开）和cura（照顾）组成，意为“关心，照顾”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为又争取到一个合作伙伴来推广HarmonyOS的使用，这是这家美国制裁的电信设备巨头继续在中国的市场上与谷歌的安卓和苹果的iOS竞争。这个词作为动词时基本意思是“确保”，即“使牢固，稳固；使安全，可靠”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>iteration (n.) - /ˌɪtəˈreɪʃən/ 重复，迭代。    <p>原文例句：JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由iter（再次）和-ation（名词后缀）组成，意为“重复，迭代”。在这个例句中，它指的是京东将为HarmonyOS Next构建一个应用程序，该应用程序基于华为移动平台的下一版本中的智能创新，这使得它能够在多种场景之间进行切换。这个词作为名词时基本意思是“重复，迭代”，即“重复，再度”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>heavyweight partner - 至关重要的合作伙伴。    <P>原文例句：Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”, Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由heavyweight（重量级）和partner（合作伙伴）组成，表示“至关重要的合作伙伴”。在这个例句中，余承东称京东为“重量级合作伙伴”，他说，这种合作伙伴关系标志着HarmonyOS在社交媒体平台微博上发布的新里程碑。这个词组常用来形容在某特定领域或活动中占主导地位的合作伙伴，其重要性不言而喻。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative in August 2019, three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List. - 华为自研的鸿蒙操作系统于2019年8月推出，作为安卓的替代品，就在美国政府将华为列入实体清单三个月之后。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative，其中主语是Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS，谓语是was launched，宾语是as an Android alternative。in August 2019, three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List是一个过去分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示华为自研的鸿蒙操作系统于2019年8月推出，就在美国政府将华为列入实体清单三个月之后。这个句子的意思是说，华为自研的鸿蒙操作系统于2019年8月推出，作为安卓的替代品，就在美国政府将华为列入实体清单三个月之后。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of HarmonyOS, which is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS in China this year.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句型，强调的是HarmonyOS。结构是：It + be + 被强调成分 + that/who + 其他。在这个例句中，be用的是is，被强调成分是HarmonyOS，that/who后面的句子是对HarmonyOS的进一步描述。这个句子的意思是说，华为正在推动HarmonyOS的广泛采用，预计今年将超过苹果的iOS成为中国第二大操作系统。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>宾语从句 - 用于修饰或补充宾语。    <p>原文例句：JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform and its ability to support transitions between multiple scenarios.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个宾语从句，修饰宾语an app。结构是：that/who + 主语 + 谓语 + 其他。在这个例句中，that后的句子是对an app的进一步描述，说明了这个应用程序将基于华为移动平台的下一版本中的智能创新，并且能够在多种场景之间进行切换。这个句子的意思是说，京东将为HarmonyOS Next构建一个应用程序，该应用程序将基于华为移动平台的下一版本中的智能创新，并且能够在多种场景之间进行切换。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform</li>
<li>Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of HarmonyOS, which is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS in China this year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/5435c70a-132e-4030-86c0-5a8e160d23ce_92ca8b90.jpg" /><figcaption>A billboard advertising Huawei’s Harmony OS at the Smart China Expo in Chongqing, Sept. 4, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has secured another partner to promote use of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3136017/will-huaweis-harmony-operating-system-end-global-duopoly-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS</a>, as the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">US-sanctioned</a> telecommunications equipment giant continues to take on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p><p>Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform and its ability to support transitions between multiple scenarios, Richard Yu Chengdong, chief executive of Huawei’s consumer business group, said on Wednesday.</p><p>Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”, Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo.</p><p>Joining with a growing number of Chinese internet companies, Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of its home-grown HarmonyOS, which is projected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" target="_self" title="">surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China</a> this year, according to Canadian research firm TechInsights.</p><p>While Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, driven by the firm’s smartphone comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to TechInsights.</p><p>The self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative in August 2019, three months after the US government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">added Huawei to its Entity List</a>. Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p><p>A developer preview of HarmonyOS Next is expected to be launched in the first quarter of 2024. Huawei is already working with major Chinese companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p><p>Ant Group, the fintech affiliate of South China Morning Post owner <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, said last month that it was building a new version of mobile payment app Alipay based on HarmonyOS, after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242703/alibaba-develops-native-dingtalk-app-harmonyos-huawei-aims-end-support-android-apps?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba started development on a new version of DingTalk</a>, its workplace collaboration app.</p><p>Other major Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> companies – including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>, video gaming giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netease?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">NetEase</a> and food delivery market leader <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> – in November started to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241371/chinese-big-tech-firms-jdcom-netease-and-meituan-rush-hire-harmonyos-based-app-developers-huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">recruit developers to build native apps for HarmonyOS</a>.</p><p>McDonald’s China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees – became <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244236/mcdonalds-china-pushes-development-native-apps-based-harmonyos-adoption-huaweis-mobile-operating?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239589/xiaomi-launches-home-grown-cross-device-system-hyperos-us-sanctioned-huawei-moves-further-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS Next</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Elon Musk’s X tells watchdog it has shed 1,000 ‘safety’ staff</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248024/elon-musks-x-tells-watchdog-it-has-shed-1000-safety-staff</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Australia's eSafety Commission criticizes Twitter's recent layoffs and reinstatement of banned accounts, claiming it creates a conducive environment for the spread of harmful content.</li>    <li>Twitter, now known as X under Elon Musk's ownership, has lost over 1,000 employees involved in content moderation, leading to a surge in "toxicity and hate" on the platform.</li>    <li>The eSafety Commission obtained detailed data revealing the departure of 1,213 specialist "trust and safety staff," including 80% of software engineers focused on safety issues.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>澳大利亚电子安全委员会批评推特最近的裁员和恢复禁令账户的行为，声称这为有害内容的传播创造了有利的环境。</li>    <li>在埃隆·马斯克的所有权下，现在称为 X 的 Twitter 已经失去了 1,000 多名参与内容审核的员工，导致平台上的“毒性和仇恨”激增。</li>    <li>电子安全委员会获得的详细数据显示，1,213 名专家“信任和安全人员”离职，其中包括 80% 专注于安全问题的软件工程师。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>reinstate (v.) - /,riːɪnˈsteɪt/ 恢复，重新任命。    <p>原文例句：Musk’s X has shed more than 1,000 staff globally from teams responsible for stopping abusive content online, according to new figures released Thursday by Australia’s online watchdog. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由re-（重新）和state（状态，条件）构成，表示“重新任命，恢复”。在这个例句中，它指的是马斯克的 X 公司从全球范围内裁掉了 1,000 多名负责阻止网络滥用内容的员工。</p></li>    <li>prevail (v.) - /prɪˈveɪl/ 普遍存在，占优势。    <p>原文例句：But attempts to exercise these powers have occasionally been met with indifference.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由prae-（之前）和valere（力量，价值）组成，表示“普遍存在，占优势”。在这个例句中，它指的是行使这些权力有时会遭到漠视。</p></li>    </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>perfect storm - 完美风暴。    <P>原文例句：Australia’s eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由perfect（完美的）和storm（风暴）构成的，形象地表示“极其不利或危险的情况”。在这个例句中，它指的是澳大利亚电子安全委员会表示这些“大幅削减”和数千个被禁账户的恢复为有害内容的传播创造了“完美风暴”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>The eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content. - 澳大利亚电子安全委员会表示，这些“大幅削减”和数千个被禁账户的恢复为有害内容的传播创造了“完美风暴”。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The eSafety Commission said，其中主语是The eSafety Commission，谓语是said，宾语是these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content。had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content是一个过去完成时态的分词短语作结果状语，表示“为有害内容的传播创造了完美的风暴”。在这个句子的意思是说，澳大利亚电子安全委员会表示，这些“大幅削减”和数千个被禁账户的恢复为有害内容的传播创造了“完美风暴”。 </p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态在另一个过去时间之前已经完成    <p>原文例句：Commissioner Julie Inman Grant, a former Twitter employee, said it was the first time these figures had been made public. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：had + been + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词。这种时态表示过去发生的动作或状态在另一个过去时间之前已经完成。在这个例句中，它表示朱莉·因曼·格兰特专员说这是这些数据第一次被公开。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The eSafety Commission said the ‘deep cuts’ and reinstatement of banned accounts created a ‘perfect storm’ for the spread of harmful content</li>
<li>Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing firms to outline how they are tackling hate speech and child sexual abuse</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/194a6a33-50f8-40c7-89c1-765fdcb76853_d3339bb6.jpg" /><figcaption>In a photo illustration, the Twitter X logo is displayed on the screen of a smartphone. Photo: SOPA Images/Zuma Press/TNS</figcaption></figure><p>Elon Musk’s X has shed more than 1,000 staff globally from teams responsible for stopping abusive content online, according to new figures released Thursday by Australia’s online watchdog.</p><p>Australia’s eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content.</p><p>The regulator has in recent months zeroed in on X – formerly known as Twitter – previously saying Musk’s takeover coincided with a spike in “toxicity and hate” on the platform.</p><p>Using Australia’s groundbreaking Online Safety Act, the eSafety Commission has obtained a detailed breakdown of software engineers, content moderators and other safety staff working at X.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247497/tech-trade-group-representing-tiktok-snapchat-and-meta-sues-ohio-over-states-new-law-limiting" title="">Tech group with TikTok and Meta sues Ohio over law curbing children’s social media use</a></h3><p>Commissioner Julie Inman Grant, a former Twitter employee, said it was the first time these figures had been made public.</p><p>They showed 1,213 specialist “trust and safety staff”, including contractors, had left X since it was acquired by Musk in October 2022.</p><p>This included 80 per cent of the software engineers focused on “trust and safety issues”, said Inman Grant.</p><p>“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away, it would be like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers,” she told AFP.</p><p>“You’ve got a perfect storm. You’re drastically decreasing your defences, and you’re introducing repeat offenders back onto the platform.”</p><p>Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing tech companies to outline how they are tackling issues such as hate speech and child sexual abuse.</p><p>But attempts to exercise these powers have occasionally been met with indifference. In October last year, the eSafety Commission slapped X with an A$610,500 (US$388,000) fine, saying it had failed to show how it was cracking down on child pornography.</p><p>But X ignored the deadline to pay the fine, before launching ongoing legal action to have it overturned.</p><p>X did not reply to AFP’s request for comment, instead sending an automated response that read “busy now, please check back later”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei ends US lobbying operations after years of fighting ban</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3248018/huawei-ends-us-lobbying-operations-after-years-fighting-ban</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei, once a dominant player in the US telecommunications market, has closed its lobbying office in Washington, DC, ending years of efforts to influence US policymakers.</li>    <li>The move comes as the Chinese tech giant continues to face a US ban on its products and technology over concerns about national security.</li>    <li>Huawei's lobbying efforts, which included hiring lobbyists and spending millions of dollars on public relations, failed to prevent the US government from blacklisting the company.</li>    <li>The closure of Huawei's lobbying office marks a significant retreat for the company and highlights the challenges Chinese companies face in operating in the United States.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>曾经在美国电信市场占据主导地位的华为公司，已经关闭了其位于华盛顿特区的游说办公室，结束多年来试图影响美国决策者的努力。</li>    <li>此举正值这家中国科技巨头继续面临美国对其实施的产品和技术禁令之际，原因是国家安全问题。</li>    <li>华为的游说努力，包括聘请游说者和花费数百万美元进行公关活动，未能阻止美国政府将该公司列入黑名单。</li>    <li>华为游说办公室的关闭标志着该公司的一次回归，突显出中国公司在美国运营所面临的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Exodus: (n.) - 大量外出的行为，大批人的离去。    <p>原文例句：The departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, after a years-long effort to maintain a presence in North America.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古希腊语，意为“离开”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为美国业务人员的大量外流。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Blacklist: (v.) - 将（人或组织）列入黑名单，禁止与之打交道。    <p>原文例句：The company pushed back on those claims, saying its products posed no threat, but American regulators by 2022 had barred the company from selling products in the US and moved to starve it of access to cutting-edge technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由black（黑）和list（清单）构成的，意为“黑名单”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国监管机构禁止华为在美国销售产品。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>A small army of: 形容数量多或规模很大的群体。    <P>原文例句：At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语是由a small（小的）和army of（军队）构成的，意为“一支小军队”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为曾经拥有的庞大的公关团队。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Cut-through: (n.) - 跨越、突破。    <P>原文例句：The US market isn’t a likely place for a breakthrough for Huawei in the near future, said Chris Pereira, a former Huawei public relations executive and founder of the consultancy iMpact.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由cut（切）和through（通过）构成的，意为“跨越、突破”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为不太可能在美国市场取得突破。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The lobbyists’ recent departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, and marks a quiet end to the company’s costly, years-long effort to maintain presence in the North American market. - 游说者最近的离开是继华为美国业务人员外流之后，也标志着该公司多年来维持北美市场地位的昂贵努力的悄然结束。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是marks a quiet end to the company’s costly, years-long effort to maintain presence in the North American market，其中主语是marks，谓语是a quiet end，宾语是the company’s costly, years-long effort to maintain presence in the North American market。The lobbyists’ recent departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations是一个过去分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示这个动作发生在主句动作之前，即游说者最近的离开是继华为美国业务人员外流之后。这个句子的意思是说，游说者最近的离开是继华为美国业务人员外流之后，也标志着该公司多年来维持北美市场地位的昂贵努力的悄然结束。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语 - 由过去分词和修饰语构成的短语，可以作定语、状语等。    <p>原文例句：The lobbyists’ recent departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, and marks a quiet end to the company’s costly, years-long effort to maintain presence in the North American market. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去分词短语，由past participle（过去分词）和修饰语departures构成的，作状语，表示游说者的离开发生在主句的动作之前。在这个例句中，它表示游说者最近的离开是继华为美国业务人员外流之后。</p>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>并列句 - 由两个或多个分句并列构成的句子，分句之间用逗号、分号或and连接。    <p>原文例句：The company spent more than US$13 million lobbying in the past 10 years, according to federal filings.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个并列句，由两个分句并列构成的，分句之间用逗号连接。这两个分句分别是对公司游说支出的描述，在意义上是并列的。这个句子的意思是说，该公司在过去10年中游说了超过1300万美元，根据联邦档案。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, after a years-long effort to maintain a presence in North America</li>
<li>At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/61065c57-e9bf-4bb0-a892-196dc21024cd_6e1ed843.jpg" /><figcaption>The Huawei logo is seen during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai, July 6, 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies, the Chinese wireless equipment maker that spent tens of millions of dollars trying to win over US policymakers only to eventually be blacklisted, has shuttered its in-house lobbying operations in Washington.</p><p>Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists there – Jeff Hogg and Donald Morrissey – left in recent months, Bloomberg News found. The Shenzhen, China-based firm did not respond to multiple requests for comment.</p><p>The lobbyists’ recent departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, and marks a quiet end to the company’s costly, years-long effort to maintain presence in the North American market. The firm reached its peak by supplying small mobile firms across the US even as major carriers shunned it. Rising tensions with Beijing eventually all but banned it.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" title="">Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets</a></h3><p>More than a decade ago, Washington officials began warning of Huawei’s ability to embed spying capabilities in its gear, which was present in thousands of cell towers and other network equipment in the US. The company pushed back on those claims, saying its products posed no threat, but American regulators by 2022 had barred the company from selling products in the US and moved to starve it of access to cutting-edge technology.</p><p>At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives. Executives were known to regularly arrange briefings with congressional offices and major newsrooms. The company spent more than US$13 million lobbying in the past 10 years, according to federal filings.</p><p>In a single quarter of 2019, Huawei’s federal lobbying spending totaled US$1.8 million, a six-fold increase from the previous year. It spent US$3.6 million on lobbying in the US in 2021, according to the filings. Some of that went to glitzy parties populated by high-profile hired guns including veteran Democratic lobbyist Tony Podesta, who made US$1 million from Huawei that year, according to disclosures with the US Senate. Podesta said in a filing that his work for Huawei ended on December 30, 2022.</p><p>With a ban firmly in place and its US business scant, Huawei has little reason to keep burning through lobbying cash in Washington. “The US market isn’t a likely place for a breakthrough for Huawei in the near future,” said Chris Pereira, a former Huawei public relations executive and founder of the consultancy iMpact.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/e55aff24-0f6a-4156-9c60-9d12d7c1fc31_ac707f82.jpg" title="A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Morrissey, who lobbied for both Huawei and Futurewei, confirmed in a LinkedIn message that he left the company in December. He said he is now the senior director of government affairs at the battery technology company Gotion. Hogg, who had served as Huawei’s head of government relations since 2020, left the company in November, according to his LinkedIn profile. He did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p>The company has lost outside lobbying firms as well. Imperium Global Advisors and LeMunyon Group terminated their contracts with Futurewei, Huawei’s US-based research arm, in November 2023, according to filings with the Senate. And Squire Patton Boggs, a global law firm, has not reported lobbying activity to Congress on Futurewei’s behalf since the beginning of 2023. Former US Representative Lee Terry, Republican of Nebraska, terminated his lobbying contract with Huawei at the end of 2022. according to filings with the Senate.</p><p>By October, the only firm registered as working on Huawei’s behalf was Sidley Austin, which did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p>Huawei itself has filed its own notice that it was terminating lobbying efforts at the Capitol. The company has also ceased operations at offices in Plano, Texas, Trey Smith, executive vice-president at CBRE, a real estate services firm that handles leases for the building, said in an email.</p><p>In response to Huawei’s ban, China’s government has accused the US of abusing state power to hobble Chinese companies. Huawei in recent months offered its own de facto response, producing a new phone using highly advanced technology the US has been trying to keep out of China’s hands. The company says revenue surged 9 per cent in 2023, in part thanks to the new phone.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s Taobao and Tmall Group pushes new AI tools to boost merchants’ service to consumers in first major move after leadership reshuffle</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247985/alibabas-taobao-and-tmall-group-pushes-new-ai-tools-boost-merchants-service-consumers-first-major</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Alibaba's Taobao and Tmall Group are introducing AI tools to enhance seller services and attract new customers. This move aims to strengthen their position amid market competition.  The newly developed customer service chatbot, Dianxiaomi, will be updated with AI capabilities to improve seller-consumer engagement and assist with tasks like pre- and post-sales services. Alibaba's efforts to implement AI reflect the company's commitment to staying competitive against rivals like JD.com and emerging platforms.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Alibaba's Taobao and Tmall Group introduce AI tools to improve their services and attract new customers.</li>    <li>Theme: AI integration in e-commerce for enhancing seller services and gaining a competitive advantage against rival platforms.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: E-commerce platforms using AI to enhance customer experience and boost sales.</li>    <li>Main information: TTG's launch of AI-powered features for sellers, Dianxiaomi chatbot's upgrade, and TTG's focus on providing enhanced exposure to quality merchants.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  阿里巴巴旗下的淘宝和天猫集团正在引入人工智能工具，旨在提升商家服务并吸引新客户。此举旨在巩固其在市场竞争中的地位。最新开发的客服聊天机器人-点小蜜将以人工智能能力进行更新，以改善卖家和消费者的互动，并协助处理售前和售后服务等任务。阿里巴巴致力于实施人工智能，反映了该公司致力于保持竞争力，以对抗京东、抖音等竞争对手和新兴平台。  <ul>    <li>摘要：阿里巴巴旗下的淘宝和天猫集团引入人工智能工具，旨在提升卖家服务并吸引新客户。</li>    <li>主题：在电子商务中集成人工智能，以提升卖家服务，并在与竞争平台的竞争中获得竞争优势。</li>    <li>观点：电子商务平台使用人工智能来提升客户体验并促进销售。</li>    <li>主要信息：TTG 为卖家推出人工智能支持的功能、点小蜜聊天机器人的升级以及 TTG 注重为优质商家提供更好的展示。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>chatbot (n.) - 聊天机器人，一种可以模拟人类对话的计算机程序。    <p>原文例句：TTG said AI models would be employed to transform Dianxiaomi, a customer service chatbot, to enhance seller-consumer interaction.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由chat（聊天）和bot（机器人）组成的，表示一种可以聊天、提供信息或帮助人们完成任务的计算机程序。在这个例句中，它指的是天猫和淘宝集团将人工智能模型应用于客服聊天机器人点小蜜，以增强卖家与消费者之间的互动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>intervention (n.) - 干预，介入。    <p>原文例句：These indicators include the “rejection rate of refund request” and “platform intervention rate”, which weigh on consumers’ purchasing decisions.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由inter-（在……之间）和venire（来）组成，表示“介入，干预”。在这个例句中，它指的是退货请求拒绝率和平台干预率，这些指标会影响消费者的购买决定。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>repurchase rate - 复购率。    <P>原文例句：TTG said internal statistics showed that five-star-rated sellers enjoy a significantly higher repurchase rate than certain 3-star stores on its platform.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由repurchase（回购，再次购买）和rate（比率）构成的，表示某一产品或服务的回购率，即消费者再次购买该产品的比例。在这个例句中，它指的是淘宝和天猫集团的内部统计数据显示，五星级卖家的复购率明显高于平台上某些三星级店铺。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The updated Dianxiaomi, which is currently undergoing tests with a select group of sellers, will be made available to all merchants by June, according to TTG. - 经过改进的点小蜜目前正在一组精选卖家中进行测试，TTG 表示，将在 6 月份向所有卖家开放。<p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是The updated Dianxiaomi will be made available to all merchants by June，其中主语是The updated Dianxiaomi，谓语是will be made available，宾语是to all merchants。by June是一个时间状语，表示在六月之前。从句which is currently undergoing tests with a select group of sellers是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰点小蜜，表示点小蜜目前正在一组精选卖家中进行测试。这个句子的意思是说，经过改进的点小蜜目前正在一群精选的卖家中进行测试，根据 TTG 的说法，它将在 6 月份向所有卖家开放。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、期望、愿望、可能性等不真实的情况。    <p>原文例句：TTG said it will launch a new rating system for online shops, focusing on indicators related to consumer services. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语态，结构是：will/would/might/could + 原形动词（或be + 过去分词）。其中will/would表示将来，might/could表示可能性。虚拟语气可以用来表示假设、期望、愿望、可能性等不真实的情况。在这个例句中，它表示淘宝和天猫集团将推出一个新的在线商店评级系统，重点关注与消费者服务相关的指标。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。现在完成时表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示天猫应用程序是一个受欢迎的市场，国际和主要中国企业向国内消费者销售品牌商品。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Taobao and Tmall Group’s AI initiative is geared towards helping merchants improve their services and attract new customers</li>
<li>An AI-upgraded customer service chatbot, Dianxiaomi, is expected to be available to all Taobao and Tmall sellers by June</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/a64d09cb-4f09-4901-b140-db8cdc3ed1d4_a2cf7620.jpg" /><figcaption>Taobao and Tmall Group’s adoption of artificial intelligence tools shows the Alibaba Group Holding unit’s effort to fend off increased competition in China’s e-commerce market. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>’s main <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> unit is now beta testing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) tools and functions for merchants on its Chinese online shopping sites, marking the first major move at the enterprise since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245680/alibaba-names-new-taobao-and-tmall-ceo-major-move-fend-competition" target="_self" title="">a leadership reshuffle in December</a>.</p><p>The Taobao and Tmall Group (TTG) unveiled the new AI features, which are designed to improve services and attract new customers, at its “sellers’ conference” held on Tuesday in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hangzhou" target="_self" title="">Hangzhou</a>, capital of eastern Zhejiang province and home base of South China Morning Post owner Alibaba.</p><p>TTG said AI models would be employed to transform Dianxiaomi, a customer service chatbot, to enhance seller-consumer interaction. That will include tasks such as pre- and post-sales service, data analysis and other online sales activities.</p><p>The updated Dianxiaomi, which is currently undergoing tests with a select group of sellers, will be made available to all merchants by June, according to TTG. It said the accuracy rate of Dianxiaomi’s response time has so far improved to 85 per cent.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/342c70b0-1832-40c4-bff8-11fa840de980_6cb4cf92.jpg" title="The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>TTG also vowed to provide “quality merchants” more exposure to consumers, from the homepage to advertised search results, TTG announced at the event.</p><p>TTG’s adoption of AI tools shows the effort being made by the Alibaba unit to fend off increased competition from main domestic rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> and the challenge from younger platforms, such as PDD Holdings’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="">Pinduoduo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>.</p><p>The move comes weeks after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245680/alibaba-names-new-taobao-and-tmall-ceo-major-move-fend-competition" target="_self" title="">Eddie Wu Yongming</a> was named the new chief executive at TTG, replacing Trudy Dai Shan. TTG subsequently <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals" target="_self" title="">promoted six millennial executives</a> to lead key departments.</p><p>Before TTG’s latest initiative, Alibaba’s international business-to-business wholesale marketplace <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" target="_self" title="">Alibaba.com in November announced a new AI tool</a> to help the platform’s merchants automate their client-facing operations, including writing emails, to entice more customers overseas.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" title="">Alibaba pushes new AI tool to help wholesale merchants manage overseas clients</a></h3><p>At the seller’s event in Hangzhou, TTG said internal statistics showed that five-star-rated sellers enjoy a significantly higher repurchase rate than certain 3-star stores on its platform. The repurchase rate at five-star pet supply stores, for example, is about 127 per cent higher than those of 3-star peers.</p><p>TTG on Tuesday also said it will launch a new rating system for online shops, focusing on indicators related to consumer services. These indicators include the “rejection rate of refund request” and “platform intervention rate”, which weigh on consumers’ purchasing decisions.</p><p>Late in December, both JD.com and Taobao said they will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" target="_self" title="">offer a “refund only” policy</a> so consumers can keep the goods they had bought but complained about – matching an option that budget online retailer Pinduoduo has had in place since 2021.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US regulator SEC authorises bitcoin-spot ETFs in cryptocurrency breakthrough</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The SEC finally approved the first US bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs). </li>    <li>It marks a significant shift in the SEC's stance on bitcoin and digital assets.</li>    <li>Three major asset management firms, BlackRock, Invesco, and Fidelity, are among the first to launch bitcoin ETFs.</li>    <li>The decision came after years of opposition from the SEC, which was concerned about the risks associated with bitcoin.</li>    <li>SEC Chair Gary Gensler emphasized the need for investor caution and highlighted the risks associated with bitcoin and crypto products.</li>    <li>The approval of bitcoin ETFs is seen as a milestone for the digital asset industry and could lead to broader adoption of bitcoin among retail and institutional investors.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>美国证券交易委员会（SEC）终于批准了首批比特币交易所交易基金（ETF）。</li>    <li>这标志着 SEC 对比特币和数字资产立场的重大转变。</li>    <li>首批推出比特币 ETF 的资产管理公司包括贝莱德、Invesco 和富达这三家巨头。</li>    <li>该决定是在 SEC 多年反对后做出的，SEC 一直以来都对与比特币相关的风险表示担忧。</li>    <li>SEC 主席加里·根斯勒强调了投资者保持谨慎的必要性，并强调了与比特币和加密产品相关的风险。</li>    <li>比特币 ETF 的获批被视为数字资产行业的一个里程碑，并可能导致比特币在散户和机构投资者中得到更广泛的采用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>capitulation (n.) - /kəˌpɪtʃʊˈleɪʃən/ 投降,屈服    <p>原文例句：The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade.</p>    <p>例句讲解：capitulation 在这里表示“屈服、投降”。SEC 在十多年的反对之后终于批准了比特币 ETF，这标志着 SEC 的屈服。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>heralded (v.) - /ˈherəld/ 宣布,预告    <p>原文例句：The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs.</p>    <p>例句讲解：heralded 在这里表示“宣布”。SEC 在 X 账户上发布的虚假帖子声称该机构已批准 ETF，这引发了轰动。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>correlation (n.) - /ˌkɒrɪˈleɪʃən/ 相关性    <p>原文例句：Cathie Wood’s Ark Investments, among others, which provided data showing a high correlation between cash trading and the futures contracts that trade on CME Group’s platform.</p>    <p>例句讲解：correlation 在这里表示“相关性”。凯茜·伍德的方舟投资和其他机构提供了数据，显示现货交易与在芝商所平台上交易的期货合约之间存在很高的相关性。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>exchange-traded funds (ETFs) - 交易所交易基金    <p>原文例句：US regulators for the first time approved exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that invest directly in bitcoin, a move heralded as a landmark event for the roughly US$1.7 trillion digital-asset sector that will broaden access to the largest cryptocurrency on Wall Street and beyond.</p>    <p>例句讲解：exchange-traded funds (ETFs) 在这里表示“交易所交易基金”。美国监管机构首次批准了直接投资于比特币的交易所交易基金 (ETF)，此举被认为是价值约 1.7 万亿美元的数字资产行业的一个里程碑事件，将扩大华尔街及其他地区对最大加密货币的投资渠道。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>securities and exchange commission (SEC) - 美国证券交易委员会    <p>原文例句：The approvals also mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade, ever since Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss first proposed a bitcoin ETF in 2013.</p>    <p>例句讲解：securities and exchange commission (SEC) 在这里表示“美国证券交易委员会”。SEC 批准比特币 ETF 标志着该机构在持续十多年的反对之后做出的罕见让步，早在 2013 年，泰勒和卡梅伦·温克莱沃斯兄弟首次提议推出比特币 ETF。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade. - SEC 批准比特币 ETF 标志着该机构在持续十多年的反对之后做出的罕见让步。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的复合句，由两个独立分句组成，用 and 连接。主句是 SEC批准比特币 ETF 标志着该机构在持续十多年的反对之后做出的罕见让步，宾语是罕见让步。第一个分句是 SEC 批准比特币 ETF，主语是 SEC，谓语是批准比特币 ETF。第二个分句是持续十多年的反对之后，主语是持续十多年的反对，谓语是做出的罕见让步。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作定语 - 用于修饰名词或代词。    <p>原文例句：The landmark decision comes after Grayscale Investments won a key victory over the SEC. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，won a key victory over the SEC 是一个过去分词短语，作定语，修饰名词decision。该短语表示 Grayscale Investments 在对 SEC 的关键胜利之后做出了具有里程碑意义的决定。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>连接词 and 的用法 - 用于连接词、词组或句子。    <p>原文例句：Gensler voted along side the agency’s two Republicans to back exchanges’ plans to list the products, the SEC’s website showed.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，and 用于连接词组Gensler voted along side the agency’s two Republicans 和to back exchanges’ plans to list the products，表示Gensler 与该机构的两位共和党人一起投票支持交易所列出这些产品的计划。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade</li>
<li>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/df6929be-b19f-4119-85e5-a531ae26273d_52ea2e34.jpg" /><figcaption>A bitcoin is seen in an illustration picture taken in Paris, France, June 23, 2017. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>US regulators for the first time approved exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that invest directly in bitcoin, a move heralded as a landmark event for the roughly US$1.7 trillion digital-asset sector that will broaden access to the largest cryptocurrency on Wall Street and beyond.</p><p>The Securities and Exchange Commission, whose three-part mandate includes investor protection, authorised funds from industry heavyweights BlackRock, Invesco and Fidelity to smaller competitors including Valkyrie to begin trading Thursday.</p><p>The approvals also mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade, ever since Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss first proposed a bitcoin ETF in 2013. BlackRock’s surprise application last June, followed by an appeals court ruling that called the denial of a different application “arbitrary and capricious,” triggered a blistering rally in the cryptocurrency as speculation that US regulators would finally give their blessing to the structure.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239953/hong-kongs-hashkey-launches-first-crypto-trading-app-retail-investors-gives-away-new-token" title="">Hong Kong gets first crypto trading app for retail investors</a></h3><p>“While we approved the listing and trading of certain spot bitcoin ETP shares today, we did not approve or endorse bitcoin,” SEC Chair Gary Gensler said in a statement. “Investors should remain cautious about the myriad risks associated with bitcoin and products whose value is tied to crypto.”</p><p>At the crux of the SEC’s previous rulings against a spot ETF was the argument that no regulated exchange was able to adequately monitor bitcoin trading in a way that would reliably detect fraud and manipulation. That contention was opposed by Cathie Wood’s Ark Investments, among others, which provided data showing a high correlation between cash trading and the futures contracts that trade on CME Group’s platform.</p><p>In reviewing the latest set of proposals, the SEC said it examined the correlation between spot and futures trading at a variety of time intervals and concluded prices moved in such a way that irregularities on exchanges such as Kraken and Coinbase were likely to show up in the futures.</p><p>“Because the CME’s surveillance can assist in detecting those impacts on CME bitcoin futures prices, the exchanges’ comprehensive surveillance-sharing agreement with the CME – a US regulated market whose bitcoin futures market is consistently highly correlated to spot bitcoin, albeit not of ‘significant size’ related to spot bitcoin – can be reasonably expected to assist in surveilling for fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices in the specific context of the proposals,” the order said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246909/crypto-services-firm-linked-huobi-sees-losses-expand-40-cent-ftx-funds-still-out-reach" title="">Losses mount at Huobi-linked crypto firm while FTX funds still out of reach</a></h3><p>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs. The regulator subsequently said that the account had been compromised, causing the price of bitcoin to fluctuate widely.</p><p>Gensler voted along side the agency’s two Republicans to back exchanges’ plans to list the products, the SEC’s website showed. The regulator’s two other Democrats voted against the proposals.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/9a0bebf2-048a-459e-9a2e-2dd720360177_a66cec46.jpg" title="The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Bitcoin rose about 3.4 per cent to US$47,500 following the approvals. The original cryptocurrency, which sank 64 per cent in 2022, more than doubled in 2023 in large part because of speculation that the SEC would eventually approve ETFs that will allow investors to get exposure to the token in their traditional brokerage accounts instead of one of the crypto-native start-ups that have come under increasing government scrutiny following a series of sector scandals and bankruptcies.</p><p>“The approval means that both retail and institutional investors now have the ability to diversify their portfolio with crypto exposure without worrying about the complicated issues of custody,” said Campbell Harvey, finance professor at Duke University. “The ETF makes it easy to add to your portfolio.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246538/china-calls-tougher-crackdown-use-crypto-illegal-forex-trading" title="">China calls for tougher crackdown on use of crypto for illegal forex trading</a></h3><p>Crypto proponents have for years argued that a so-called spot fund that invests directly in bitcoin would be beneficial to investors and would help bring the industry closer to the more highly regulated world of traditional finance. It also suggests a sort of milestone of maturity for the relatively nascent industry, where skirmishes with regulators came to a climax after the collapse of Sam Bankman-Fried’s FTX empire highlighted risks lurking in the industry.</p><p>The landmark decision comes after Grayscale Investments won a key victory over the SEC. A federal appeals court had overturned the rejection of Grayscale’s application to convert its bitcoin trust into an ETF. The court called the denial “arbitrary and capricious” because the commission failed to explain its different treatment of similar products. ETFs that hold bitcoin futures were approved in 2021.</p><p>The SEC’s loss to Grayscale was one of the reasons why the SEC approved the applications, Gensler said in Tuesday’s statement.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China rich list compiler Hurun clarifies Tsinghua graduate Zhang Zetian’s ranking to quell online controversy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247956/china-rich-list-compiler-hurun-clarifies-tsinghua-graduate-zhang-zetians-ranking-quell-online</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  According to Hurun's ranking, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University in China have produced the most graduates who became billionaires. Zhang Zetian, wife of tech billionaire Richard Liu, was ranked as the third richest graduate from Tsinghua, but her wealth is jointly owned with her husband. The ranking sparked controversy online, leading Hurun to clarify its methodology.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Hurun's ranking of Tsinghua and Zhejiang University graduates as billionaires.</li>    <li>Theme: Zhang Zetian's wealth and ranking as the third richest graduate from Tsinghua.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Hurun's clarification of its methodology for ranking wealthy Chinese alumni.</li>    <li>Main information: Zhang's wealth is jointly owned with her husband; scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China; the ranking of other universities based on the number of alumni on the Hurun China Rich List.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  根据胡润研究院的排名，中国清华大学和浙江大学培养了最多的毕业生成为亿万富翁。刘强东的妻子张泽天被排在清华第三富有的毕业生，但她与丈夫共同拥有这份财富。该排名引发了网络争议，导致胡润澄清了其对中国富有的校友进行排名的评判方法。  <ul>    <li>摘要：胡润对清华和浙江大学毕业生亿万富翁的排名。</li>    <li>主题：张泽天作为清华大学第三富有的毕业生的财富和排名。</li>    <li>观点：胡润关于中国富有的校友排名的评判方法的澄清。</li>    <li>主要信息：张的财富与她的丈夫共同拥有；对中国个人财富和收入不平等的审查；根据胡润中国富豪榜上校友人数对其他大学的排名。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>breakthrough (n.) - /ˈbreɪkθruː/ 突破，创新。    <p>原文例句：It's a breakthrough in physics, something scientists have been searching for decades, said Ghoniem, assistant professor of mechanical engineering at Johns Hopkins University.</p>    <p>例句讲解：breakthrough 意为“突破”，可以指科学上的重大发现，也可以指在困难或阻碍中取得的进展。在这个例句中，它指的是物理学上的重大发现，即科学家们多年来一直在寻找的东西。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>prospective (adj.) - /prəˈspɛktɪv/ 预计的，潜在的。    <p>原文例句：Demand for the metal is expected to rise strongly in the coming years due to the growing number of prospective electric vehicles on the roads.</p>    <p>例句讲解：prospective 意为“预计的，潜在的”，可以指未来可能发生的事情或情况。在这个例句中，它指的是未来潜在的电动汽车数量的增长。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>controversy (n.) - /ˈkɑːntrəvərsi/ 争论，争议。    <p>原文例句：The comments sparked controversy among some readers, who accused the author of being insensitive and biased.</p>    <p>例句讲解：controversy 意为“争论，争议”，可以指人们对某个问题或情况的不同意见或看法。在这个例句中，它指的是作者发表的评论引起了部分读者的争议，指责作者麻木不仁，存在偏见。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>come amid - 在……期间发生。    <p>原文例句：The controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：come amid 意为“在……期间发生”，表示某事发生在某个背景或环境中。在这个例句中，它指的是个人财富和收入不平等在中国受到更加严格的审查期间，争议发生了。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fall under - 属于，归类于。    <p>原文例句：In the case of Tsinghua’s Zhang, her 60 billion yuan worth falls under her and [husband] Liu jointly.”    <p>例句讲解：fall under 意为“属于，归类于”，表示某事物属于某个类别或范围。在这个例句中，它指的是张在清华的600亿元财富属于她和她丈夫共同拥有。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online. - 胡润研究院，一个由鲁伯特·胡格沃夫运营的富豪榜编制机构，澄清了其决定，将中国科技亿万富翁刘强东的妻子张泽天列为清华大学毕业生中第三富有的人，此前该排名引发了网络争议。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是The Hurun Research Institute has clarified its decision，其中主语是The Hurun Research Institute，谓语是has clarified，宾语是its decision。a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰The Hurun Research Institute，表示胡润研究院是一个由鲁伯特·胡格沃夫运营的富豪榜编制机构。to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University是一个不定式短语作目的语，表示胡润研究院澄清其决定将张泽天列为清华大学毕业生中第三富有的人。after the ranking stirred controversy online是一个时间状语从句，表示在该排名引发网络争议之后。这个句子的意思是说，胡润研究院，一个由鲁伯特·胡格沃夫运营的富豪榜编制机构，澄清了其决定，将中国科技亿万富翁刘强东的妻子张泽天列为清华大学毕业生中第三富有的人，此前该排名引发了网络争议。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作定语 - 表示对名词或代词的修饰和限定。    <p>原文例句：The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online. - 胡润研究院，一个由鲁伯特·胡格沃夫运营的富豪榜编制机构，澄清了其决定，将中国科技亿万富翁刘强东的妻子张泽天列为清华大学毕业生中第三富有的人，此前该排名引发了网络争议。</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf是一个现在分词短语，作定语，修饰The Hurun Research Institute，表示胡润研究院是一个由鲁伯特·胡格沃夫运营的富豪榜编制机构。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>不定式短语作目的语 - 表示动作或状态的目的或意图。    <p>原文例句：The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online. - 胡润研究院，一个由鲁伯特·胡格沃夫运营的富豪榜编制机构，澄清了其决定，将中国科技亿万富翁刘强东的妻子张泽天列为清华大学毕业生中第三富有的人，此前该排名引发了网络争议。</p><p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University是一个不定式短语，作目的语，表示胡润研究院澄清其决定将张泽天列为清华大学毕业生中第三富有的人。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>According to Hurun, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China</li>
<li>Zhang ranked behind Meituan founder Wang Xing and Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/22f80ee8-51eb-4f11-94d0-38c9096e305d_32c40a21.jpg" /><figcaption>JD.com chairman Richard Liu Qiangdong and wife Zhang Zetian at Princess Eugenie’s wedding. Photo: YouTube </figcaption></figure><p>The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.</p><p>According to a list published by Hurun last Friday, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China. And 30-year-old Zhang was ranked as the third-richest graduate from Tsinghua, with a net worth of 60 billion yuan (US$8.4 billion).</p><p>Zhang ranked behind 44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan and 62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group. However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p><p>Hurun issued a statement on Monday to clarify its methodology for the ranking of rich Chinese alumni. “In the case of Tsinghua’s Zhang, her 60 billion yuan worth falls under her and [husband] Liu jointly.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239156/chinese-tech-founders-bounce-back-huruns-2023-rich-list-number-and-overall-wealth-billionaires-drop" title="">Chinese tech billionaires move up Hurun 2023 Rich List amid internet rebound</a></h3><p>The controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China. According to a separate rich list published by Forbes in November 2023, the net worth of Liu, founder and chairman of e-commerce giant JD.com, was US$4.7 billion, ranking No. 69 in China’s top 100 rich list.</p><p>Liu’s celebrity-style marriage to Zhang is also rare among Chinese tech billionaires, with many maintaining a low profile when it comes to family matters.</p><p>The Tsinghua alumni rich list was part of a Hurun Most Successful University Alumni 2023 ranking the research firm released. Hurun defined the “most successful alumni” to include former full-time undergraduates, postgraduates and those entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</p><p>A total of 58 universities, 45 Chinese and 13 overseas, have at least three alumni on the Hurun China Rich List 2023. Tsinghua and Zhejiang University topped the list, each with 32 alumni on the list.</p><p>Peking University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, and Wuhan University came in third, fourth and fifth with 22, 21, and 17 alumni respectively on the list.</p><p>Robin Li Yanhong, founder, chairman and CEO of Baidu, and Xiaomi chairman and CEO Lei Jun are two of the most high-profile and richest graduates to have come from Peking University and Wuhan University, respectively, according to the list.</p><p>Outside China, Stanford University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, University of California, Yale University and Harvard University from the US were the top five institutions with the most Hurun China Rich listers.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China augmented reality start-up Rokid gets US$70 million in new funding round led by Hefei government</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247968/china-augmented-reality-start-rokid-gets-us70-million-new-funding-round-led-hefei-government</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Rokid, a Chinese augmented reality (AR) technology firm, has secured a substantial investment of 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round. The municipal government of Hefei, the capital of Anhui province, served as the lead investor in this round, signaling the growing support from authorities for technology start-ups in China. The funding will facilitate Rokid's establishment of its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub, and R&D center in Hefei's New Station Hi-Tech Zone. This move aligns with Hefei's strategy to foster innovation in metaverse applications and technologies.  <ul>    <li>Abstract:Rokid raises 500 million yuan in funding round, backed by Hefei municipal government.</li>    <li>Theme: Hefei's support for tech start-ups and Rokid's commitment to advancing the metaverse industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Local governments' role in promoting local development strategies through investment in start-ups; importance of collaboration between tech companies and local authorities.</li>    <li>Main information: Rokid's funding amount and lead investor; establishment of industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub, and R&D center in Hefei; focus on cutting-edge R&D and user experience; shared vision between Rokid and Hefei to cultivate the XR/metaverse industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Rokid，一家中国增强现实（AR）技术公司，在其最新一轮融资中获得了 5 亿元人民币（7000 万美元）的巨额投资。安徽省省会合肥市政府担任本轮融资的牵头投资方，这表明中国政府对科技初创企业的支持力度不断加大。这笔资金将促进 Rokid 在合肥新站高新区建立其工业元宇宙总部、生态系统中心和研发中心。此举符合合肥市培育元宇宙应用和技术创新的战略。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Rokid 在由合肥市政府支持的融资轮次中筹集到 5 亿元人民币。</li>    <li>主题：合肥对科技创业企业的支持和 Rokid 推动元宇宙产业发展的承诺。</li>    <li>观点：地方政府通过对初创企业投资促进地方发展战略的作用；科技公司与地方政府合作的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：Rokid 的融资金额和牵头投资者；在合肥建立工业元宇宙总部、生态系统中心和研发中心；专注于尖端研发和用户体验；Rokid 与合肥培育 XR/元宇宙产业的共同愿景。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>extended reality (XR) - 扩展现实。    <p>原文例句： XR is an overarching term that includes AR, virtual reality, and mixed reality technologies that seek to combine or mirror the physical and digital worlds to allow consumers, equipped with XR equipment, to traverse between and interact with them.</p>    <p>例句讲解： XR 是一个涵盖 AR、虚拟现实和混合现实技术的总称，这些技术旨在组合或镜像物理世界和数字世界，使配备 XR 设备的消费者能够在两者之间穿梭和互动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>foster - 培养，促进。    <p>原文例句： The cooperation between Rokid and Hefei builds on a shared vision to cultivate extended reality [XR]/metaverse industry development, ” Hong said.</p>    <p>例句讲解： cultivate 的意思是“培育、促进”，在这个例句中，它表示 Rokid 和合肥之间的合作建立在共同愿景的基础上，旨在培育扩展现实 [XR]/元宇宙产业的发展。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>drive innovation - 推动创新。    <P>原文例句： Hong Fan, chairman of Hefei New Venture Investment Control, an investment vehicle under the Hefei government, added that the cooperation aligns with Rokid and the city’s efforts to drive innovation on metaverse applications and technologies.</P>    <p>例句讲解： drive innovation 的意思是“推动创新”，在这个例句中，它表示合肥新兴创业投资控制有限公司董事长洪帆补充说，此次合作与 Rokid 和该市在元宇宙应用和技术领域推动创新的努力相一致。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Rokid said in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor. - Rokid 在周三的一份声明中表示，已在最新一轮融资中筹集到 5 亿元人民币（7000 万美元），由安徽省省会合肥市政府作为牵头投资者。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是 Rokid，谓语是 has raised，宾语是 500 million yuan (US$70 million)。with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor 是一个介词短语作状语，表示以合肥市政府为牵头投资者的身份。这个句子的意思是说，Rokid 在周三的一份声明中表示，已在最新一轮融资中筹集到 5 亿元人民币（7000 万美元），由安徽省省会合肥市政府作为牵头投资者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句： Rokid has made AR equipment for a variety of consumer, travel, and industrial uses, counting companies such as the State Grid Corporation of China and home appliance giant Midea among its clients.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。其结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。在这个例句中，has made 表示 Rokid 一直在做 AR 设备，counting 表示 Rokid 一直在计算公司数量。这个句子的意思是说，Rokid 为各种消费者、旅游和工业用途制造 AR 设备，其中包括中国国家电网公司和家电巨头美的等客户。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物承受。    <p>原文例句：The funding will facilitate Rokid's establishment of its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub, and research and development (R&D) centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone, tapping into the Chinese city’s emerging ecosystem including micro-displays, the metaverse and other areas.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是一种语态，表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物承受。其结构是：be + 过去分词。在这个例句中，be facilitated 表示 Rokid 的建立受到资助的促进，tapping into 表示 Rokid 利用了中国城市的生态系统。这个句子的意思是说，这笔资金将促进 Rokid 在合肥新站高新区建立其工业元宇宙总部、生态系统中心和研发中心，利用中国城市的包括微显示器、元宇宙和其他领域的新兴生态系统。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Rokid said it has raised 500 million yuan in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei as a lead investor</li>
<li>Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and R&amp;D centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/f677fbfd-346b-4b28-a3ab-89b2e076e79f_2f7ce20d.jpg" /><figcaption>Rokid Glass, augmented reality glasses, at the Rokid booth during CES 2018, Las Vegas. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese augmented reality (AR) technology firm Rokid has raised nearly half a billion yuan in its latest round of funding led by a local Chinese government, in a fresh indication of the backing from authorities for tech start-ups.</p><p>Rokid said in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor. As part of the deal, Rokid signed an investment and cooperation agreement with Hefei to advance the local metaverse industry.</p><p>Chinese authorities have increasingly stepped up as private equity investors in projects in line with local development strategies. As a quid pro quo for funding, local governments generally require these start-ups to make local investments.</p><p>Under the Hefei deal, Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and research and development (R&amp;D) centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone, tapping into the Chinese city’s emerging ecosystem including micro-displays, the metaverse and other areas.</p><p>“We are honoured to contribute to advancements in science/technology … through our innovations,” said Misa Zhu, founder and CEO of Rokid, adding that the company will focus on cutting-edge R&amp;D and user experience optimisation.</p><p>“Looking ahead, we will maintain a focus on achieving technological milestones and enriching our ecosystem to empower developers and deliver superior products that benefit consumers and enterprises globally”, Zhu said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3233933/china-wants-metaverse-firms-global-influence-and-plans-five-industrial-clusters-2025" title="">China wants up to 5 metaverse companies with ‘global influence’ by 2025</a></h3><p>Hong Fan, chairman of Hefei New Venture Investment Control, an investment vehicle under the Hefei government, added that the cooperation aligns with Rokid and the city’s efforts to drive innovation on metaverse applications and technologies.</p><p>“The cooperation between Rokid and Hefei builds on a shared vision to cultivate extended reality [XR]/metaverse industry development, ” Hong said.</p><p>XR is an overarching term that includes AR, virtual reality, and mixed reality technologies that seek to combine or mirror the physical and digital worlds to allow consumers, equipped with XR equipment, to traverse between and interact with them.</p><p>Founded in 2014, Rokid has made AR equipment for a variety of consumer, travel, and industrial uses, counting companies such as the State Grid Corporation of China and home appliance giant Midea among its clients.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Can Beethoven, Bach and Mozart help iPhone sales in China? Apple to launch classical music app on mainland amid sluggish demand for its flagship produ...</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247961/can-beethoven-bach-and-mozart-help-iphone-sales-china-apple-launch-classical-music-app-mainland-amid</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Apple Music Classical, launched in most markets globally in March 2022, will enter mainland China on January 24, along with five other East Asian markets. This move aims to boost Apple's digital services revenue in China, its largest market in terms of App Store revenue. Despite facing weak consumption and competition from Chinese smartphone rivals, Apple remains optimistic about its long-term prospects in China.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple Music Classical app to launch in China, targeting the world's largest smartphone market.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's expansion of its digital services in China, particularly focusing on the classical music market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Apple's strategy to address weak iPhone sales in China and maintain its strong position in the App Store market.</li>    <li>Main information: Launch date of Apple Music Classical app in China and other markets; China's contribution to App Store revenue; iPhone sales decline in China; Apple's reassurance to investors despite sales challenges.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  苹果音乐古典应用程序于去年 3 月在全球大多数市场推出，将于 1 月 24 日在中国内地首次亮相。在同一天，该应用程序还将在包括中国香港、澳门、台湾、日本和韩国在内的其他五个东亚市场推出。苹果音乐古典应用程序在中国推出可能会提振该公司在这个国家的主要数字服务业务，因为这是其在 App Store 相关收入方面最大的市场。照片：Shutterstock  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果音乐古典应用程序将在中国推出，目标是全球最大的智能手机市场。</li>    <li>主题：苹果在中国扩张其数字服务，特别是专注于古典音乐市场。</li>    <li>观点：苹果解决中国 iPhone 销量疲软并保持其在 App Store 市场上强劲地位的策略。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果音乐古典应用程序在中国和其他市场推出的日期；中国对 App Store 收入的贡献；中国 iPhone 销量下降；苹果向投资者保证，尽管面临销售挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.nuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，意为“返回”，在经济学中，它指的是企业或个人的收入或收益。在这个例句中，它指的是中国在 2022 年为苹果 App Store 生态系统贡献的总计费和销售额。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>decline (v.) - /dɪˈklaɪn/ 减少，下降。    <p>原文例句：In the first week of the year, iPhone sales on the mainland were down 30 per cent year year, according to a Jefferies research note published on Sunday. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，意为“倾斜，下降”，表示“减少，下降”。在这个例句中，它指的是 iPhone 在中国大陆的销量在今年第一周同比下降了 30%。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：China is its largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示中国是苹果在 App Store 相关收入方面最大的市场。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company’s online China App Store shows that the app – touted by Apple as the world’s largest classical music catalogue, with more than five million tracks – can now be pre-ordered by iPhone users in the country. - 从该公司在线中国应用商店可以看到，这款应用程序——据苹果宣称是全球最大的古典音乐目录，拥有超过 500 万首曲目——现在可以被国内的 iPhone 用户预订。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The app can now be pre-ordered by iPhone users in the country，其中主语是The app，谓语是can be pre-ordered，宾语是by iPhone users in the country。从该公司在线中国应用商店可以看到，是一个介词短语作状语，修饰主语The app，表示从该公司在线中国应用商店可以看到这个信息。这款应用程序——据苹果宣称是全球最大的古典音乐目录，拥有超过 500 万首曲目——是一个长定语作主语The app的定语，提供了关于这个应用程序的更多信息。现在可以被国内的 iPhone 用户预订是一个现在时被动语态的动词短语作谓语，表示这个应用程序现在可以被国内的 iPhone 用户预订。</p><li>Apple’s major digital services business in China, which remains the company’s largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue, is likely to be bolstered by the app’s launch. - 苹果在中国的主要数字服务业务可能会因这款应用程序的推出而提振，因为中国仍然是该公司在 App Store 相关收入方面最大的市场。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Apple’s major digital services business in China is likely to be bolstered by the app’s launch，其中主语是Apple’s major digital services business in China，谓语是is likely to be bolstered，宾语是by the app’s launch。which remains the company’s largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue是一个定语从句，作主语Apple’s major digital services business in China的定语，表示中国仍然是该公司在 App Store 相关收入方面最大的市场。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple has continued to reassure investors even though iPhone sales have been slowing. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示尽管 iPhone 的销量一直在下降，但 Apple 一直持续向投资者保证。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、愿望或可能性。    <p>原文例句：Whether the classical music app’s local release would somehow help lift iPhone sales on the mainland remains to be seen. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种语气，用来表示假设、愿望或可能性。在英语中，虚拟语气有两种形式：虚拟语气现在时和虚拟语气过去时。虚拟语气现在时用在现在时或将来时的主句中，表示假设或可能性。虚拟语气过去时用在过去时或过去完成时的主句中，表示假设或愿望。在这个例句中，它表示古典音乐应用程序的本地发布是否会以某种方式帮助提振中国大陆的 iPhone 销量还有待观察。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Apple Music Classical app, which was launched in most markets globally in March last year, will make its mainland debut on January 24</li>
<li>On the same date, the app will also be available in five other East Asian markets that include Hong Kong, Macau, Taiwan, Japan and South Korea</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/5bfc68e8-e24d-446d-84dd-b98d8c4fe639_56cadcbe.jpg" /><figcaption>The Apple Music Classical app’s launch in China is likely to bolster the firm’s major digital services business in the country, which is its largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> will soon make its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/classical-music" target="_self" title="">classical music</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">app</a> available in mainland China, expanding the US tech giant’s digital services offering in the world’s largest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> market where sales of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> are seeing a deepening decline.</p><p>The Apple Music Classical app, which was launched in most markets globally in March last year, will make its mainland debut on January 24, according to the company’s online China App Store. The app – touted by Apple as the world’s largest classical music catalogue, with more than five million tracks – can now be pre-ordered by iPhone users in the country.</p><p>On the same date, the stand-alone app will also be available in five other East Asian markets that include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/macau-0" target="_self" title="">Macau</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a>, according to a post on Tuesday by Apple on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/twitter-x" target="_self" title="">X, formerly Twitter</a>.</p><p>The app’s launch is likely to bolster Apple’s major digital services business in China, which remains the company’s largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse" class="image-inline caption" height="1330" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/8163ba04-0fe9-402a-937d-975263f7c4ad_f67d3284.jpg" title="China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse" width="2000" /><figcaption>China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse</figcaption></figure></div><p>China accounted for US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of the total US$1.1 trillion in billings and sales facilitated by the App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published on Apple’s website in May last year.</p><p>By comparison, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> generated US$273 billion, or almost 25 per cent, of the App Store ecosystem’s overall billings and sales in 2022. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/europe" target="_self" title="">Europe</a> accounted for US$119 billion, or 11 per cent, of that year’s total.</p><p>Whether the classical music app’s local release would somehow help lift iPhone sales on the mainland remains to be seen, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247712/chinas-retail-sales-weaken-year-falling-home-prices-jobs-outlook-feed-consumer-insecurity-ubs" target="_self" title="">consumption remains weak</a> across the country and Apple faces stiff competition from major Chinese smartphone rivals.</p><p>In the first week of the year, iPhone sales on the mainland were down 30 per cent year on year, according to a Jefferies research note published on Sunday. The brokerage indicated that there was “a big rise in discounts” for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3192215/apples-iphone-14-sees-surging-pre-orders-china-enthusiastic-consumers" target="_self" title="">iPhone 14</a> and 14 Plus models, while the newer <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3235981/apple-iphone-15-review-faster-cheaper-new-standard-models-are-big-jump-over-their-predecessors" target="_self" title="">iPhone 15</a> and 15 Plus models saw “a moderate rise” in discounts.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics" title="">Apple supplier Foxconn sees sales decline in first quarter of 2024 amid weak demand</a></h3><p>Chinese smartphone vendors, with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honor" target="_self" title="">Honor</a> leading the pack, had “much stronger” momentum during the period, with sales delivering “flattish growth” year on year, Jefferies analysts led by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/enterprises/article/2113581/chinas-chance-lead-global-innovation-may-lie-5g-mobile-technology" target="_self" title="">Edison Lee</a> wrote in the note.</p><p>The iPhone’s total sales volume last year on the mainland was down 3 per cent from 2022, which translated to a 0.4 per cent decline in Apple’s market share, according to Jefferies. It estimated that rival Huawei saw its mainland market share in the December quarter gain 2 per cent from the previous quarter, and 6 per cent year on year.</p><p>Apple is expected to see “even higher revenue pressure” on the mainland in 2024, according to Jefferies.</p><p>Still, Apple has continued to reassure investors even though iPhone sales have been slowing. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240278/apples-ceo-cook-sees-china-bright-spot-after-record-iphone-sales-country-despite-overall-revenue" target="_self" title="">In the firm’s earnings call in November</a>, Apple chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tim-cook" target="_self" title="">Tim Cook</a> said: “Over the long term, I view China as an incredibly important market, and I’m very optimistic about it.”</p><p>Cook made two visits to the mainland last year, meeting senior government officials, Chinese developers and Apple’s contract manufacturing partners.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Foxconn pushes into electric vehicle production near its biggest iPhone plant amid slow smartphone sales</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247941/foxconn-pushes-electric-vehicle-production-near-its-biggest-iphone-plant-amid-slow-smartphone-sales</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Foxconn, a major Apple supplier, has established a new venture in Zhengzhou, China, called Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co, to advance its presence in the electric vehicle (EV) sector amid declining smartphone sales.</li>    <li>The new company will focus on car component manufacturing, motor production, and NEV sales, tapping into the growing demand for electric vehicles.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>富士康，苹果的主要供应商，在中国郑州成立了一家新的合资企业，名为富士康新能源汽车产业发展（河南）有限公司，旨在增强其在电动汽车（EV）领域的 Präsenz，原因是智能手机销量有所下降。</li>    <li>新公司将专注于汽车零部件制造、电机生产和新能源汽车销售，以满足不断增长的对电动汽车的需求。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>venture (n.) - /ˈven.tʃər/ 冒险，投机事业。    <p>原文例句：The new project will involve car component manufacturing and development, motor production and car sales.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Venture是一个名词，意思是“冒险，投机事业”。它源于拉丁语“ventura”，意为“将发生的事情”，隐含着一种不确定性和风险。在这个例句中，它指的是富士康在郑州成立的新合资企业，旨在增强其在电动汽车领域的Präsenz。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>accelerate (v.) - /əkˈsel.ə.reɪt/ 加速，加快。    <p>原文例句：The world’s largest contract electronics manufacturer is accelerating its move into the automobile industry amid weakening demand for smartphones and consumer gadgets.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Accelerate是一个动词，意思是“加速，加快”。它源于拉丁语“accelerare”，意为“增加速度”。在这个例句中，它指的是富士康正在加速向汽车行业转型，以应对智能手机和消费电子产品需求疲软的局面。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make Apple products - 制造苹果产品。    <p>原文例句：Foxconn plans to invest at least US$2.6 billion in a plant it is building in India to make Apple products.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Make Apple products是一个动词词组，意思是“制造苹果产品”。它是由动词“make”和名词“Apple products”组成的。在这个例句中，它指的是富士康计划在印度投资至少26亿美元，用于建设新工厂来制造苹果产品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co, was established on January 4 with a registered capital of 500 million yuan (US$70 million), according to public records in the National Enterprise Credit Information Publicity System. - 富士康新能源汽车产业发展（河南）有限公司于1月4日成立，注册资本5亿元人民币（7000万美元），根据国家企业信用信息公示系统中的公开记录。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co, was established，其中主语是Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co,，谓语是was established，宾语是on January 4 with a registered capital of 500 million yuan (US$70 million)。according to public records in the National Enterprise Credit Information Publicity System是一个介词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示成立的信息来源于国家企业信用信息公示系统中的公开记录。这个句子的意思是说，富士康新能源汽车产业发展（河南）有限公司于1月4日成立，注册资本5亿元人民币（7000万美元），根据国家企业信用信息公示系统中的公开记录。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company is accelerating its move into the automobile industry amid weakening demand for smartphones and consumer gadgets. - 富士康正在加速向汽车行业转型，以应对智能手机和消费电子产品需求疲软的局面。</p>    <p>语法讲解：本句使用了现在进行时态，结构为：主语 + be + 动词的ing形式。现在进行时态表示正在进行的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性。在示例句子中，"is accelerating"表示富士康正在加速向汽车行业转型，强调这一转型正在进行中。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：The new project will involve car component manufacturing and development, motor production and car sales. - 新项目将涉及汽车零部件制造和开发、电机生产和汽车销售。</p>    <p>语法讲解：本句使用了被动语态，结构为：be + 动词的过去分词 + by + 动词的过去分词。被动语态表示动作或状态是由句子的宾语承受的，强调动作或状态的承受者。在示例句子中，"will involve"表示新项目将涉及汽车零部件制造和开发、电机生产和汽车销售，强调这些活动是由新项目承受的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Apple supplier has set up a new venture in Zhengzhou to sharpen its focus on the electric vehicle industry</li>
<li>The new project will involve car component manufacturing and development, motor production and car sales</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/aad49844-fb12-4001-aa76-72cbfe6b99d4_f04766b4.jpg" /><figcaption>A Foxconn building in Taipei. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foxconn" target="_self" title="">Foxconn Technology Group</a> has set up a new car venture in Zhengzhou city, capital of central China’s Henan province and home to the world’s largest iPhone factory, as the Apple supplier steps up its efforts in the new energy vehicle (NEV) sector amid declining smartphone sales.</p><p>The new firm, named Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co, was established on January 4 with a registered capital of 500 million yuan (US$70 million), according to public records in the National Enterprise Credit Information Publicity System.</p><p>Its business covers car component manufacturing and development, motor production and NEV sales, among other areas.</p><p>Foxconn, known formally as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hon-hai-precision-industry" target="_self" title="">Hon Hai Precision Industry</a>, said the new venture belongs to Foxconn Innovation Industry Development Group Co and aims to sharpen the company’s focus on the electric vehicle industry, according to a report by the Securities Times on Tuesday.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Foxconn confirmed the report, adding that the Henan subsidiary was disclosed in December 2023 to the Taiwan Stock Exchange.</p><p>The world’s largest contract electronics manufacturer is accelerating its move into the automobile industry amid weakening demand for smartphones and consumer gadgets.</p><p>The Taiwanese giant last week reported US$198.9 billion in preliminary revenue for 2023, down 7 per cent from 2022. It blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, while <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics" target="_self" title="">expecting continuing decline in the first quarter of this year</a>.</p><p>In October, Foxconn <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238352/apple-supplier-foxconn-build-ai-factories-using-nvidias-chips-and-software-range-applications" target="_self" title="">announced a new electric cargo van called Model N</a> and announced plans to mass produce its compact SUV Model B. Jun Seki, its chief strategy officer for electric vehicles, said the company was in touch with about 14 potential customers and saw India and Japan as promising countries for EV development.</p><p>To help push the company towards its new direction, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3218313/apple-supplier-foxconn-sets-global-business-base-iphone-city-show-commitment-china" target="_self" title="">Foxconn opened a new global business base in Zhengzhou</a> last April and reaffirmed its commitment to the Chinese market, even as the firm and other Apple suppliers move to diversify their supply chain.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/853102cf-b84f-499d-9b72-8c24ea357fde_a66cec46.jpg" title="A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Foxconn plans to start building new factories for smartphones and electronics goods in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of major construction projects in 2024 released last week by the provincial Development and Reform Commission.</p><p>The company, which was put under <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239113/china-says-investigation-apple-supplier-foxconns-operations-mainland-normal-law-enforcement" target="_self" title="">a tax and land use investigation</a> in October by mainland authorities, employs 200,000 workers in its Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p><p>In 2022, that facility was rocked by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3200747/violence-erupts-foxconn-zhengzhou-plant-workers-protest-over-benefits-and-covid-19-controls-worlds?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">violent workers’ protests</a> and an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3197909/coronavirus-iphone-factory-exodus-shows-how-chinas-covid-narrative-still-strikes-fear-public?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">exodus of tens of thousands of employees</a> that Apple CEO Tim Cook later <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3208974/apples-tim-cook-blames-supply-disruption-chinas-pandemic-controls-revenue-drop" target="_self" title="">blamed for a decline in the US company’s quarterly revenue</a>.</p><p>Separately, Foxconn plans to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">invest at least US$2.6 billion in a plant</a> it is building in India to make Apple products, according to a report by Bloomberg last month.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China EV maker Xpeng accepts pre-orders for flying car but notes urban use is far off</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese electric vehicle maker Xpeng unveils two types of flying cars at CES, targeting a consumer market with the modular Land Aircraft Carrier and the sportier AeroHT eVTOL.</li>    <li>The Land Aircraft Carrier will start taking pre-orders in Q4 2024, with deliveries to begin a year later.</li>    <li>The AeroHT eVTOL made its international debut at CES, having previously conducted flying tests in China, but pricing and availability information are not yet available.</li>    <li>Xpeng aims to launch the flying cars before regulations are in place for city use, targeting areas where aircraft operation is not regulated.</li>    <li>While pricing is expected to be similar to luxury performance cars, Xpeng distances itself from comparisons to EHang, emphasizing different target markets and capabilities.</li>    <li>Xpeng is in talks with regulators in China but acknowledges that international expansion will take time, especially considering geopolitical tensions.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国电动汽车制造商小鹏汽车在 CES 上推出两款飞行汽车，瞄准消费者市场，包括模块化陆地航空母舰和运动型 AeroHT eVTOL。</li>    <li>陆地航空母舰将于 2024 年第四季度开始接受预订，交付将于一年后开始。</li>    <li>AeroHT eVTOL 在 CES 上首次亮相，此前已在中国进行过试飞，但定价和可用性信息尚未公布。</li>    <li>小鹏汽车的目标是在城市使用法规到位之前推出飞行汽车，目标是在飞机运营不受监管的地区。</li>    <li>虽然预计定价将与豪华性能汽车相似，但小鹏汽车与大疆的比较保持距离，强调不同的目标市场和功能。</li>    <li>小鹏汽车正在与中国监管机构进行谈判，但承认国际扩张需要时间，特别是考虑到地缘政治紧张局势。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>debut (v.) - /ˈdeɪbjuː/ 首次公开亮相，首次登场。    <p>原文例句：The company’s subsidiary AeroHT presented two types of flying cars at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Tuesday. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语debutare（开始），表示“首次公开亮相，首次登场”。在这个例句中，它描述了小鹏汽车的子公司 AeroHT 在 2024 年拉斯维加斯举行的 CES 上首次推出了两种类型的飞行汽车。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>propeller (n.) - /prəˈpɛlə/ 螺旋桨。    <p>原文例句：There is no information on pricing or availability for the AeroHT, which has propellers that pop out of the back.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由pro-（向前）和pellere（驱动）组成的，表示“螺旋桨”。在这个例句中，它描述了 AeroHT 的螺旋桨是从后部弹出出来的。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>separate aircraft - 单独的飞机。    <P>原文例句：AeroHT’s modular Land Aircraft Carrier comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由separate（分开的）和aircraft（飞机）组成，表示“单独的飞机”。在这个例句中，它指的是 AeroHT 的模块化陆地航空母舰配备了单独的飞机，可以从汽车上发射。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Xpeng’s ambitions could face some challenges with current geopolitical tensions, though. Chinese drone tech has been caught in the cross hairs before. - 尽管如此，小鹏汽车的雄心壮志可能会面临当前地缘政治紧张局势的一些挑战。此前，中国无人机技术已经陷入困境。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Xpeng’s ambitions could face some challenges，其中主语是Xpeng’s ambitions，谓语是could face，宾语是some challenges。though是一个连接词，表示转折，将两个句子连接起来。current geopolitical tensions是一个形容词短语，作状语，修饰challenges，表示挑战来自当前的地缘政治紧张局势。Chinese drone tech has been caught in the cross hairs before是一个过去完成时态的句子，作状语，表示中国无人机技术在此之前就已经陷入困境。这个句子的意思是说，尽管如此，小鹏汽车的雄心壮志可能会面临当前地缘政治紧张局势的一些挑战，因为在此之前，中国无人机技术已经陷入困境。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>介词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态发生的方式、时间、地点、原因、目的等。    <p>原文例句：Xpeng distanced itself from the EHang comparison, saying its products are different and target different buyers. </p>    <p>语法讲解：介词短语作状语是介词短语在句中作状语，表示动作或状态发生的方式、时间、地点、原因、目的等。介词短语由介词和介词宾语组成，介词宾语可以是名词、代词、动词不定式或其他介词短语。在这个例句中，Xpeng distanced itself from the EHang comparison是一个介词短语作状语，表示小鹏汽车与大疆的比较保持距离的原因，即小鹏汽车表示其产品与大疆的产品不同，目标客户也不同。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去完成时态 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：When asked whether this could present some hurdles, Gu said, “I’m not even thinking about that right now … This business is purely focused on the China market right now.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去完成时态是表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态的时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。在这个例句中，had not even thinking about that right now是一个过去完成时态，表示顾并未在谈话中考虑这个问题。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The company’s subsidiary AeroHT presented two types of flying cars at CES, including a sportier eVTOL that made its international debut</li>
<li>Xpeng president Brian Gu said the company is in talks with regulators in China to allow use of the vehicle, but international expansion ‘takes time’</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/407dea1a-dbe1-45b0-ac41-d295e42b8239_80ccf63e.jpg" /><figcaption>Brian Gu Hongdi, vice-chairman and president of Xpeng, discusses the company’s new flying car at CES on January 9, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Seven years after EHang debuted its first passenger drone, Chinese electric vehicle maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng">Xpeng</a> entered the market with its own “flying car”, with the goal of delivering the first batch by the fourth quarter of 2025, whether regulations are ready or not.</p><p>The company’s subsidiary AeroHT presented two types of flying cars at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Tuesday. Its modular Land Aircraft Carrier will start taking pre-orders in the fourth quarter this year, with deliveries to start a year later. The sportier AeroHT eVTOL (electric vertical take-off and landing) car made its international debut at the show, having previously conducted flying tests in China.</p><p>There is no information on pricing or availability for the AeroHT, which has propellers that pop out of the back. It has been demoed for flying in China, but it did not take flight at CES. Brian Gu Hongdi, vice-chairman and president of Xpeng, suggested it could launch before regulations are in place for city use, but that people could eventually buy one and fly it in areas where the use of aircraft is not regulated.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247808/ces-2024-china-tv-makers-hisense-and-tcl-promote-ai-live-sports-us-show" title="">Hisense and TCL push AI in TVs, chase industry trends like smart cars</a></h3><p>“The design of our vehicles is not targeted for urban transportation … [which] requires an extensive regulatory approval process,” Gu said. “That’s why we’re targeting a consumer market, for people to first enjoy the experience of flying and then obviously with the regulatory framework in place, we gradually can move towards urban transportation.”</p><p>While Gu said it was too early to say what pricing might be, he expects it to be “similar to buying a luxury performance car”.</p><p>Similar products have been in the works for years. EHang made a splash when it debuted the EHang 184 at CES in 2016. In the years since, it has <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/innovation/article/3024726/nerves-waiver-screaming-lift-joy-two-minute-test-ride-passenger" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/innovation/article/3024726/nerves-waiver-screaming-lift-joy-two-minute-test-ride-passenger">invited journalists to take rides</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/3030521/chinese-drone-maker-ehang-said-file-ipo-nasdaq" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/3030521/chinese-drone-maker-ehang-said-file-ipo-nasdaq">went public on the Nasdaq</a>.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="AeroHT’s modular Land Aircraft Carrier comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/22700ac5-f38a-4718-b5a7-2df12b039468_00d05c81.jpg" title="AeroHT’s modular Land Aircraft Carrier comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>AeroHT’s modular Land Aircraft Carrier comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Xpeng distanced itself from the EHang comparison, saying its products are different and target different buyers. The EV company, which made its debut at CES two years after EHang with its first car, noted that EHang’s products are just aerial vehicles without the ability to be driven on roads. EHang is also targeting enterprise use, while Xpeng is targeting a wider consumer base.</p><p>“We are targeting the consumer market, which is very different,” Gu said. “I don’t see another company that’s doing that right now.”</p><p>While Xpeng has also highlighted how the Land Aircraft Carrier could be used for public services like emergency rescue, the new eVTOL car is a more stylish option that can conceal its rotors. This will presumably make it more appealing for people to buy, whenever it becomes available, even if they cannot fly it to work every morning.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3247413/ai-will-be-spotlight-consumer-electronics-show-2024-glasses-blind-shoes-make-you-walk-faster-and" title="">AI to dominate CES 2024, with glasses for blind, shoes to walk faster</a></h3><p>Gu said the company is already in talks with regulators in China but international expansion “takes time”.</p><p>Xpeng’s ambitions could face some challenges with current geopolitical tensions, though. Chinese drone tech has been caught in the cross hairs before. Washington put DJI, the world’s largest consumer drone maker, on its Entity List that bars US companies from doing business with it without express approval.</p><p>When asked whether this could present some hurdles, Gu said, “I’m not even thinking about that right now … This business is purely focused on the China market right now.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TSMC halts revenue drop, beats expectations on brisk demand for AI chips from Nvidia, Advanced Micro Devices</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247936/tsmc-halts-revenue-drop-beats-expectations-brisk-demand-ai-chips-nvidia-advanced-micro-devices</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC), the world's largest contract chip maker, reported revenue of NT$625.5 billion in the fourth quarter, matching earnings from the same period a year earlier. Despite exceeding analyst expectations and its own guidance, TSMC's revenue fell short of growth targets. The company attributed the decline to sluggish demand for smartphone and laptop chips, partially offset by strong demand for artificial intelligence (AI) chips.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: TSMC's fourth-quarter revenue meets expectations but misses growth targets due to weak demand in certain segments.</li>    <li>Theme: TSMC's performance amidst changing market dynamics, including the impact of AI on chip demand.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Analysts' perspectives on TSMC's business outlook, AI-driven growth opportunities, and challenges posed by geopolitical factors.</li>    <li>Main information: TSMC's quarterly revenue, comparison to previous year's performance, analyst estimates, capital expenditure plans, and market trends in the semiconductor industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  作为全球最大的晶圆代工企业，台积电第四季度营收为新台币6255亿元，与去年同期持平。尽管超出分析师预期以及自身指引，但台积电202亿美元的季度营收仍未实现增长。公司将业绩下滑归因于智能手机和笔记本电脑芯片需求低迷，部分被对人工智能 (AI) 芯片的强劲需求所抵消。  <ul>    <li>摘要：台积电第四季度营收达到预期，但由于某些领域需求疲软，未能实现增长目标。</li>    <li>主题：台积电在市场动态变化中的表现，包括人工智能对芯片需求的影响。</li>    <li>观点：分析师对台积电业务前景、人工智能驱动的增长机会以及地缘政治因素带来的挑战的看法。</li>    <li>主要信息：台积电季度营收、与去年同期业绩的比较、分析师估计、资本支出计划以及半导体行业的市场趋势。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>outperform (v.) - /ˌaʊtˈpɜːrˌfɔːrm/ 超过，表现更好。    <p>原文例句：While it outdid analyst expectations and its own guidance, TSMC’s US$20.2 billion quarter still fell short of delivering growth. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词是由out（超过）和perform（表现，动作）构成的，表示“超过，表现更好”。在这个例句中，它表示尽管台积电超出了分析师的预期和公司的自身指引，但202亿美元的季度营收仍未实现增长。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>post (v.) - /poʊst/ 张贴，公布。    <p>原文例句：Earlier in the week, fellow chip maker Samsung Electronics posted its sixth successive quarter of declining operating profit, as it weathered the impact of muted consumer demand in its smartphone and memory businesses. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于Old English，表示“放置，张贴，公布”。在这个例句中，它表示三星电子公布了其连续第六个季度营业利润下降，原因是其智能手机和内存业务的消费者需求疲软。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>from time to time - 时不时地，有时候。    <P>原文例句：Over the course of 2023, TSMC moderated its capital expenditure plans as the consumer electronics industry grappled with a glut of unsold inventory.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由from（从），time（时间）和to time（到时间）构成的，表示“时不时地，有时候”。在这个例句中，它表示在整个 2023 年，随着消费电子行业努力应对大量未售出的库存，台积电调整了其资本支出计划。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company has seen its high-performance computing business boosted by demand for AI chips from Nvidia and Advanced Micro Devices. - 该公司的超算业务因英伟达和超威半导体的AI芯片需求而增长。<p>句子分析：这是一个被动句，主语是The company，谓语是被动语态的has seen，宾语是high-performance computing business，介词短语by demand for AI chips from Nvidia and Advanced Micro Devices作状语，表示超算业务增长的原因。这个句子的意思是说，该公司的超算业务因英伟达和超威半导体的AI芯片需求而增长。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>情态动词can - 表示能力，许可，可能性等。    <p>原文例句：China to persist with AI development in 2024 despite US chip curbs: UBS</p>    <p>语法讲解：情态动词can有能力，许可，可能性等意思。在这个例句中，它表示中国将继续坚持AI发展。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Despite exceeding analyst expectations and its own guidance, TSMC’s US$20.2 billion quarter still fell short of delivering growth. </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是由have/has+过去分词构成的，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个例句中，it fell short of delivering growth表示台积电未能实现增长，这个动作从过去的某个时间开始一直持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Hsinchu-based company reported a NT$625.5 billion quarter, matching earnings from the same period a year earlier</li>
<li>While it outdid analyst expectations and its own guidance, TSMC’s US$20.2 billion quarter still fell short of delivering growth</li>
</ul><p>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), the world's largest contract chip maker, saw its fourth-quarter revenue beat estimates of a decline, as demand from artificial intelligence (AI) players helped offset sluggish smartphone and laptop chip sales.</p><p>Hsinchu-based TSMC, the main chip supplier to Apple and Nvidia, reported December sales of NT$176.3 billion (US$5.7 billion), completing a NT$625.5 billion quarter.</p><p>That matched earnings from the same period a year earlier, which was among TSMC’s highest quarterly results. The average analyst estimate for sales over the last three months was NT$616.2 billion.</p><p>Over the course of 2023, TSMC moderated its capital expenditure plans as the consumer electronics industry grappled with a glut of unsold inventory. The chip maker signalled the trough in demand had been reached in the summer and recovery would begin to take hold in the months leading up to 2024.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Overall revenue declined 4.5 per cent last year, to NT$2.16 trillion.</p><p>While it outdid analyst expectations and its own guidance, TSMC’s US$20.2 billion quarter still fell short of delivering growth. December sales were down 8.4 per cent on the same month a year earlier, offering a mixed outlook for the year ahead.</p><p>Top management including chief executive CC Wei have said they expect overall business to grow this year, and the company has seen its high-performance computing business boosted by demand for AI chips from Nvidia and Advanced Micro Devices.</p><p>Earlier in the week, fellow chip maker Samsung Electronics posted <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" target="_self" title="">its sixth successive quarter of declining operating profit</a>, as it weathered the impact of muted consumer demand in its smartphone and memory businesses.</p><p>Still, the latest report from the Semiconductor Industry Association showed the first growth in chip sales in over a year came in November, suggesting momentum is gathering for a resurgence in 2024.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247835/china-persist-ai-development-efforts-2024-despite-setbacks-rigid-us-semiconductor-restrictions-ubs" title="">China to persist with AI development in 2024 despite US chip curbs: UBS</a></h3><p>Upgrades to AI server farms and on-device AI applications are likely to drive an information technology replacement cycle, according to HSBC analysts Ricky Seo and Hankil Chang.</p><p>“For US cloud service providers, we expect capex to grow significantly, about 65 per cent in 2024e. Additionally, AI server purchases will likely total 57 per cent of their investments in 2024e, up from 8 per cent in 2022,” they wrote in a research note on Wednesday.</p><p>Apple, arguably TSMC’s most important customer, has faced headwinds with its latest iPhone generation in China, the world’s biggest smartphone market. Several analysts have downgraded Apple this year on expectations of soft demand, and this week Jefferies said the iPhone sales slump in China is likely to deepen.</p><p>The US company has also been hit by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3233603/china-orders-government-workers-stop-using-iphones-amid-heightened-tensions-us" target="_self" title="">an expanded ban by Chinese agencies and state-owned companies</a> ordering staff to keep iPhones and other foreign devices away from work premises.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
