<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China to persist with AI development in 2024 despite rigid US chip restrictions, UBS analysts say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247835/china-persist-ai-development-efforts-2024-despite-setbacks-rigid-us-semiconductor-restrictions-ubs</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  UBS analysts believe that China will continue developing large language models and generative AI despite US restrictions on advanced semiconductors. China will focus on domestic AI accelerator programs and use computing resources economically. While facing US export controls, China's semiconductor industry has made progress in certain unsanctioned segments, with local suppliers increasing their market share.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's response to US sanctions on advanced semiconductors in the development of AI.</li>    <li>Theme: China's resilience and adaptability in overcoming technology constraints.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: UBS analysts' positive outlook on China's semiconductor industry and AI development.</li>    <li>Main information: China's efforts to tap into domestic AI resources; progress in unsanctioned semiconductor segments; growth in mature-node chip sales; increased market share of domestic chip-making equipment suppliers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  瑞银分析师认为，尽管美国限制先进半导体，中国仍将继续发展大型语言模型和生成式人工智能。中国将重点放在国内人工智能加速器计划上，并经济地使用计算资源。中国半导体行业在面临美国出口管制的同时，在某些未受制裁的细分市场取得了进展，当地供应商的市场份额有所提高。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国应对美国在人工智能发展中对先进半导体的制裁。</li>    <li>主题：中国在克服技术限制方面的韧性和适应性。</li>    <li>观点：瑞银分析师对中国半导体产业和人工智能发展的积极看法。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国利用国内人工智能资源的努力；未受制裁的半导体细分市场的进展；成熟制程芯片销量的增长；国产芯片制造设备供应商市场份额的提高。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>accelerator (n.) - /ˌæk.sɛ.ləˈreɪ.tər/ 加速器，助长器。    <p>原文例句：China is expected to “work within those constraints and try to make progress” by tapping into domestic AI accelerator programmes and being more economical in using computing resources.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于accelerate，表示“加速，助长”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国利用国内人工智能加速器计划来促进人工智能的发展。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>chip (n.) - /tʃɪp/ 芯片。    <p>原文例句：China's semiconductor industry weathers tough year amid tighter US sanction</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词指的是半导体芯片，是电子设备中不可或缺的元件。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>work closely together - 密切合作。    <p>原文例句：A slew of sanctions imposed by the US since 2019 has forced companies across China’s vast tech supply chain to work closely together in supporting domestic artificial intelligence projects.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由work（工作），closely（紧密地），together（一起）组成的，表示“密切合作”。在这个例句中，它表示美国自2019年以来实施的一系列制裁措施迫使中国庞大的技术供应链中的公司紧密合作，以支持国内人工智能项目。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China is expected to “work within those constraints and try to make progress” by tapping into domestic AI accelerator programmes and being more economical in using computing resources. - 中国预计将“在这些限制范围内努力并试图取得进展”通过利用国内人工智能加速器项目和更经济地使用计算资源。</li><p>句子分析：这个句子是一个复合句，主句是China is expected to make progress，其中主语是China，谓语是is expected to make，宾语是progress。by tapping into domestic AI accelerator programmes and being more economical in using computing resources是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示中国将通过利用国内人工智能加速器项目和更经济地使用计算资源来取得进展。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：A slew of sanctions imposed by the US since 2019 has forced companies across China’s vast tech supply chain to work closely together in supporting domestic artificial intelligence projects.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，结构是：be + 动词ing。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，动词要用现在分词形式。这种时态表示动作或状态正在进行，强调动作或状态的延续性或进行性。在这个例句中，它表示美国自2019年以来实施的一系列制裁措施迫使中国庞大的技术供应链中的公司紧密合作，以支持国内人工智能项目，强调这种合作正在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China is expected to ‘work within those constraints’ while making progress via AI accelerators and more economical use of computing resources</li>
<li>The country’s ability to overcome setbacks caused by US exports controls must not be underestimated, according to UBS’ Nicolas Gaudois</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/f68371eb-a605-4c9f-afb0-20abb89d4ca9_a1137b4b.jpg" /><figcaption>A slew of sanctions imposed by the US since 2019 has forced companies across China’s vast tech supply chain to work closely together in supporting domestic artificial intelligence projects. Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>China will press ahead this year with development of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3226942/china-create-and-implement-national-standard-large-language-models-move-regulate-ai-while-using-its" target="_self" title="">large language models</a> (LLMs) – the technology used to train <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3244420/openais-chatgpt-took-ai-world-storm-year-ago-and-china-still-playing-catch-us-piles-pressure" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> and similar applications – and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">generative artificial intelligence</a> (AI) systems, despite restrictions imposed by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> on the mainland’s access to advanced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductors</a>, according to analysts from Swiss investment bank <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3218263/swiss-bank-ubs-raked-us28-billion-wealthy-clients-takeover-troubled-rival-credit-suisse" target="_self" title="">UBS</a>.</p><p>China is expected to “work within those constraints and try to make progress” by tapping into domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">AI</a> accelerator programmes and being more economical in using computing resources, said Nicolas Gaudois, head of Asia-Pacific technology research at UBS, during a webinar hosted by the bank on Tuesday.</p><p>Gaudois said US export controls have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3238354/tech-war-us-ban-tailor-made-nvidia-and-intel-chips-hits-beijings-ai-ambitions" target="_self" title="">blocked China’s access to Nvidia chips used for AI projects</a>, but indicated that the mainland’s ability to overcome such setbacks must not be underestimated.</p><p>The views expressed by UBS analysts reflect how China’s semiconductor industry <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3246736/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-industry-weathers-tough-year-amid-tighter-us-sanctions" target="_self" title="">weathered last year’s escalation of Washington’s tech sanctions</a>, which restricted exports of advanced chip-making equipment and cutting-edge semiconductors for AI projects.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>The mainland’s tech sector appeared to have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china" target="_self" title="">overcome the chokehold of US export controls</a> last year, when <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> made a surprise return to the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/5g/news" target="_self" title="">5G</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> market with new handsets powered by a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233520/tech-war-top-chinese-chip-maker-smic-under-spotlight-breakthrough-5g-processor-used-huaweis-latest?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">“breakthrough” advanced made-in-China processor</a>.</p><p>It showed the lengths taken by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-blacklisted</a> company to build up its operations, following years of struggles on account of trade sanctions.</p><p>Apart from that breakthrough, UBS analysts asserted that China’s semiconductor sector has developed well in certain unsanctioned segments, showing strong market growth over the past few years.</p><p>“Restrictions from the US are very limited on mature nodes,” said Randy Abrams, head of Taiwan Research at UBS, in the same webinar on Tuesday. He pointed out that sales of these mature-node chips have not been restricted.</p><p>“We have seen China make more effort to invest in those areas,” Abrams said. “We will see steady market pickup in mature applications, such as camera image sensors, micro-controllers, analogue chips and discrete semiconductor devices for EVs.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3246736/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-industry-weathers-tough-year-amid-tighter-us-sanctions" title="">China’s semiconductor industry weathers tough year amid tighter US sanctions</a></h3><p>“In semiconductor equipment, local suppliers have built up their market share from very low single-digits into the mid- to high-single-digits,” he said. “Their gains come from supplying China semiconductor manufacturers, as they’ve added mature node capacity.”</p><p>Abrams said domestic chip-making equipment suppliers saw their market share increase to about 20 per cent on the back of demand from Chinese chip fabrication facilities. “So if we leave out the very advanced nodes, there are actually a lot of [investment] opportunities,” he said.</p><p>Global demand for chips, he said, is expected to start picking up, as soon as inventory pressures ease and procurement at semiconductor foundries improves.</p><p>A slew of sanctions imposed by the US since 2019 has also forced companies across China’s vast tech supply chain to work closely together.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">Internet</a> search giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>, which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3239981/baidu-launches-paid-version-ernie-bot-chinese-firms-rush-make-money-their-generative-ai-chatbots?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">runs Ernie Bot and the Ernie LLM</a>, ordered <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3240641/us-china-tech-war-baidu-buys-ai-chips-huawei-us-restricts-nvidia-chip-exports-sources" target="_self" title="">US$61 million worth of Huawei’s 910B Ascend AI chips</a> – which the Chinese firm developed as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226981/huawei-taps-computing-power-shortage-china-touts-self-developed-ai-tech-amid-chatgpt-craze?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">an alternative to Nvidia’s A100 processor</a> – for 200 servers, according to a report in November by Reuters, which cited sources.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s DingTalk updates workplace collaboration app with new AI agent amid growing client demand</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247831/alibabas-dingtalk-updates-workplace-collaboration-app-new-ai-agent-amid-growing-client-demand</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  阿里巴巴集团旗下的钉钉在杭州举行企业活动，发布了7.5版本并添加了人工智能（AI）代理功能，帮助用户简化和定制工作流程。这一功能旨在解决来自 70 多万家企业客户的反馈。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 钉钉7.5版本推出AI代理功能，帮助用户优化工作流程。</li>    <li>Theme: 人工智能在钉钉中的应用，提升企业办公效率。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 人工智能代理是人工智能应用最合适的途径。</li>    <li>Main information: 钉钉7.5版本发布，AI代理功能解决企业反馈，促进AI产品在行业中的应用，目标成为低门槛的AI代理平台。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  DingTalk, a workplace collaboration app developed by Alibaba Group Holding, has launched its 7.5 version with an AI agent feature to streamline and customize user workflows. The tool aims to address feedback received from over 700,000 corporate clients. It intends to promote AI adoption in the industry and become an AI agent platform with low entry barriers. As of the end of 2023, DingTalk has over 700 million users and 25 million organizations, including corporate and educational institutions, with 120,000 paying clients. DingTalk's AI agent is powered by Alibaba's Tongyi Qianwen large language model (LLM), similar to ByteDance's Feishu's AI bot "Feishu Intelligent Buddy." The addition of AI agents highlights the ongoing trend among Chinese Big Tech companies to develop ChatGPT-like products across various sectors.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: DingTalk 7.5 introduces AI agent feature to improve user workflows. </li>    <li>Theme: AI adoption in the workplace through DingTalk's AI agent.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: AI agents provide an accessible gateway for AI applications.</li>    <li>Main information: DingTalk 7.5 launch, AI agent's aim to address client feedback, intent to promote AI adoption, and the aim of becoming an AI agent platform.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>streamline (v.) - /ˈstriːmlaɪn/ 简化，使流线型。    <p>原文例句：The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由stream（流）和line（线）组成的，表示“使像河流一样流畅，简化，使流线型”。在这个例句中，它指的是钉钉7.5的新增功能——AI代理功能。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>customise (v.) - /ˈkʌstəmaɪz/ 定制，个性化。    <p>原文例句：The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于French，由custom（习俗）和-ise（使……成为）组成，表示“定制，个性化”。在这个例句中，它指的是钉钉7.5的新增功能——AI代理功能，可以根据用户的需求进行定制。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>alongside - 和……一起，同时。    <p>原文例句：The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由along（沿着）和side（边）组成，表示“和……一起，同时”。在这个例句中，它表示钉钉7.5的新增功能——AI代理功能与钉钉7.5同时发布。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>come after - 跟随，紧随其后。    <p>原文例句：DingTalk’s addition of an AI agent function, powered by the group’s Tongyi Qianwen large language model (LLM), comes after ByteDance’s Feishu made a similar push last November.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由come（来）和after（之后）组成，表示“跟随，紧随其后”。在这个例句中，它表示钉钉添加AI代理功能是在字节跳动的飞书去年11月推出类似功能之后。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The new tool is expected to promote greater adoption of AI products in the industry, according to the company. - 据该公司称，该公司的新工具预计将促进AI产品在业界的更广泛应用。<p>句子分析：这是一个主动句，主语是The new tool，谓语是expected to promote。greater adoption of AI products in the industry是一个宾语，表示AI产品在业界更广泛的应用。according to the company是一个介词短语作状语，表示据该公司称。这个句子的意思是说，该公司的新工具预计将促进AI产品在业界更广泛的应用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作宾语 - 表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：As the tide of AI-generated content increasingly finds its way into productivity and [business] use cases, AI agents have emerged as the most suitable gateway for AI applications. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在分词短语，结构是：现在分词+宾语。其中现在分词是动词的-ing形式，宾语是名词或代词。这个短语作宾语，说明动作或状态的对象。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能代理是人工智能应用最合适的途径。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>介词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态的发生时间、地点、方式或原因等。    <p>原文例句：As the tide of AI-generated content increasingly finds its way into productivity and [business] use cases, AI agents have emerged as the most suitable gateway for AI applications. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个介词短语，结构是：介词+宾语。介词是连接词，宾语是名词或代词。这个短语作状语，说明动作或状态的发生时间、地点、方式或原因等。在这个例句中，它表示在人工智能生成的内容越来越多地融入到生产力和商业用例中之际，人工智能代理已成为人工智能应用最合适的入口。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>DingTalk’s AI agent function is powered by Alibaba’sTongyi Qianwen large language model</li>
<li>The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/30e71220-1a5a-4efb-b280-5bfdcfbd741d_5ecb7eee.jpg" /><figcaption>The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou. Photo: VCG via Getty Images </figcaption></figure><p>Alibaba Group Holding’s DingTalk launched an updated version of its workplace collaboration app on Tuesday with the addition of an artificial intelligence (AI) agent function to help users streamline and customise their workflow.</p><p>The development comes amid a flurry of activity in the AI sector as Chinese companies rush to incorporate ChatGPT-like services into their products and after a similar move by ByteDance’s rival app Feishu. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>The AI agent feature announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou, capital of eastern Zhejiang province, is designed to address feedback gleaned from more than 700,000 corporate clients, said Ye Jun, president of DingTalk, in a statement.</p><p>The new tool is expected to promote greater adoption of AI products in the industry, according to the company.</p><p>“As the tide of AI-generated content increasingly finds its way into productivity and [business] use cases, AI agents have emerged as the most suitable gateway for AI applications,” said Ye.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242571/bytedance-adds-ai-assistant-office-tool-feishu-joining-rivals-tencent-and-alibaba-workplace-chatbot" title="">ByteDance brings AI to office tool Feishu, taking on Tencent and Alibaba</a></h3><p>Ye added that DingTalk’s goal is to become an AI agent platform with low entry barriers, with the marketplace expected to grow substantially in the next three years.</p><p>As of the end of 2023, Dingtalk had over 700 million users. It also has 25 million organisations, including corporate and educational institutions that use its platform, of which 120,000 are paying clients, said Ye.</p><p>Shoes and apparel giant Belle International has rolled out a customised AI agent on its DingTalk platform to track parcel shipment issues, with plans to expand the use of the agent to more cases, including stock allocation.</p><p>DingTalk’s addition of an AI agent function, powered by the group’s Tongyi Qianwen large language model (LLM), comes after ByteDance’s Feishu made a similar push last November.</p><p>LLMs are the deep learning models, pre-trained on vast amounts of data, that underpin chatbots such as OpenAI’s ChatGPT, which took the world by storm a year ago with its ability to understand complex questions and respond with human-like text.</p><p>At the launch of Feishu 7, ByteDance introduced an AI bot dubbed Feishu Intelligent Buddy, which can help users with daily tasks such as drafting emails, drawing up spreadsheets and summarising long reports.</p><p>Feishu also announced a platform to enable its corporate clients to build and customise AI bots according to business needs, it said at the time.</p><p>After a year of hype over AI chatbots, Chinese Big Tech firms including Alibaba, ByteDance and Baidu have been rushing to build competitor products to ChatGPT, with applications spanning the finance, legal, manufacturing, retail and public sectors.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s logistics arm Cainiao offers shoppers in US grouped delivery service, cutting shipping times to five days</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247829/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-offers-shoppers-us-grouped-delivery-service-cutting-shipping-times</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Cainiao, Alibaba's logistics division, will offer a consolidated shipping service for consumers in the US, allowing them to package and deliver multiple online purchases from various Chinese platforms.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Cainiao opens a new cross-border shipping service to the US.</li>    <li>Theme: Cainiao offers a consolidated shipping service to Chinese consumers and students in the US.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The service aims to reduce delivery times and costs for consumers.</li>    <li>Main information: The consolidated shipping service covers both air and sea transport; packages can be shipped from a warehouse in China to the US in five days by air or at a lower cost by sea.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  菜鸟，阿里巴巴的物流部门，将向美国消费者提供一项综合运输服务，允许他们将从不同中国平台购买的多个在线商品打包和运送。  <ul>    <li>摘要：菜鸟面向美国推出新的跨境运输服务。</li>    <li>主题：菜鸟为美国华人和留学生提供综合运输服务。</li>    <li>观点：该服务旨在为消费者减少交货时间和费用。</li>    <li>主要信息：综合运输服务涵盖空运和海运两种运输方式；包裹可以从中国仓库通过空运五天运送到美国，或者通过海运以更低的成本运送。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>consolidated (adj.) - /kənˈsɑːlɪdeɪtɪd/ 合并的，联合的。    <p>原文例句：The so-called 'consolidated shipping' service covers both air and sea transport routes. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由consolidate（合并，联合）构成的，表示“合并的，联合的”。在这个例句中，它描述了一种将多个在线购物订单合并包装成一个包裹的运输服务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>warehouse (n.) - /ˈweərhaʊs/ 仓库。    <p>原文例句：The so-called “consolidated shipping” service, covering both air and sea transport routes, will collect multiple online shopping orders placed by users on various platforms in a warehouse before shipping them from China. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词表示“仓库”。在这个例句中，它指的是一个收集多个在线购物订单并将其包装成一个包裹的仓库。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in charge of - 负责。    <p>原文例句：Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics unit, will open a new service for consumers in the US to allow them to package several items they have bought together. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），charge（负责，管理）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“负责，管理”。在这个例句中，它表示菜鸟是阿里巴巴集团旗下的物流部门，负责为美国消费者提供综合运输服务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s e-commerce empire, handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023. - 菜鸟作为阿里巴巴电子商务帝国的物流支柱，2023年每日处理超过400万个跨境包裹。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s e-commerce empire，其中主语是Cainiao，谓语是serves，宾语是the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s e-commerce empire。handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示菜鸟在2023年处理超过400万个跨境包裹的具体情况。这个句子的意思是说，菜鸟作为阿里巴巴电子商务帝国的物流支柱，2023年每日处理超过400万个跨境包裹。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由某人或某物接受的。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba announced it would spin off Cainiao in the restructuring announced in March. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be是动词to be的过去式，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则变化形式。在这个例句中，be用的是would，表示过去时态，过去分词是spin off，表示“分离，剥离”。这个句子的意思是说，在三月份宣布的重组中，阿里巴巴宣布将剥离菜鸟。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示两个或多个事物在某一方面存在差异。    <p>原文例句：If the parcel is sent via air, delivery times may be reduced five days after the items are sent out from the warehouse. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个比较级的句子，结构是：主语 + 动词 + 形容词/副词的比较级。在这个例句中，主语是delivery times，动词是may be reduced，形容词的比较级是five days。这个句子的意思是说，如果包裹是通过空运发送的，那么从仓库发出后五天内就可以缩短交货时间。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Cainiao said cross-border shipping service would mainly help Chinese consumers in US who tend to buy lots of goods on Chinese sites</li>
<li>The so-called ‘consolidated shipping’ service covers both air and sea transport routes</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/8c90f6e8-359a-4cee-bbfa-62226abce761_8e97fde8.jpg" /><figcaption>The so-called ‘consolidated shipping’ service covers both air and sea transport routes. Photo: Handout  </figcaption></figure><p>Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics unit, will open a new service for consumers in the US to allow them to package several items they have bought together, cutting delivery times to as little as five days.</p><p>Cainiao said in a statement on Tuesday that the cross-border shipping service would mainly help Chinese consumers and students in the US who tend to buy lots of goods on Chinese e-commerce sites. As of 2020, there were roughly 60 million Chinese living outside the country, according to a report by Huaqiao University.</p><p>If the parcel is sent via air, delivery times may be reduced five days after the items are sent out from the warehouse. If by sea, the new service may cut the cost to as low as 12 yuan (US$1.7), depending on the size of the parcel, according to the statement.</p><p>The new overseas service comes ahead of Cainiao’s planned US$1 billion listing in Hong Kong. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247710/alibabas-aliexpress-pdd-owned-temu-face-supply-chain-challenges-south-korea-amid-rapid-business" title="">Alibaba’s AliExpress, PDD-owned Temu face supply chain challenges in South Korea</a></h3><p>The so-called “consolidated shipping” service, covering both air and sea transport routes, will collect multiple online shopping orders placed by users on various platforms in a warehouse before shipping them from China.</p><p>Prior to its US expansion, Cainiao provided consolidated shipping to shoppers in other markets outside mainland China, including Hong Kong, Singapore and Australia.</p><p>In November, Cainiao and Alibaba were part of a consortium that made a US$57 million offer to buy Chinese logistics company Best. Best is a major courier in China and has a presence in Southeast Asia. In the third quarter of 2023, Best’s global businesses achieved revenue of US$37.7 million, contributing to 12.4 per cent of the total.</p><p>Cainiao has its eye on the overseas market, and recorded more than 1.5 billion cross-border e-commerce parcel deliveries in its recent financial year to March, making it one of the world’s top logistics services providers, according to its prospectus.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to a Post report in September that cited people familiar with the situation. The listing is part of a group-wide restructuring of Alibaba, as the e-commerce titan seeks to free up decision- making amid increased competition.</p><p>Established in 2013, Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s e-commerce empire, handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023. Alibaba announced it would spin off Cainiao in the restructuring announced in March.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China TV makers Hisense and TCL promote AI, live sports at US show</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247808/ces-2024-china-tv-makers-hisense-and-tcl-promote-ai-live-sports-us-show</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>At CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Chinese TV giants Hisense and TCL unveiled their latest AI-powered TVs and competed for the title of the top Chinese brand in the US television market.</li>    <li>They highlighted their in-house production capabilities, including displays and AI chipsets, which they believe set them apart from competitors.</li>    <li>TCL showcased its mini-LED TVs, claiming to have the world's largest at 115 inches, and emphasized its global presence with 32 research and development centers and 43 manufacturing sites.</li>    <li>Hisense introduced its new laser TVs with built-in sound bars and rollable laser TV screens.</li>    <li>Both companies recognized the importance of AI in optimizing picture quality and enhancing the overall TV experience.</li>    <li>They also explored other industry trends, such as smart glasses, augmented reality devices, and the integration of technology into automobiles.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国两大电视品牌海信和TCL在拉斯维加斯举行的CES 2024上展示了最新的产品，并争夺美国电视市场最大中国品牌的称号。</li>    <li>他们强调了其内部生产能力，包括显示器和AI芯片组，他们认为这些能力使他们区别于竞争对手。</li>    <li>TCL展示了其Mini-LED电视，宣称拥有全球最大尺寸115英寸，并强调了其全球影响力，在全球拥有32个研发中心和43个制造基地。</li>    <li>海信推出了新款激光电视，内置了音箱和可卷曲的激光电视屏幕。</li>    <li>两家公司都认识到人工智能在优化画质和增强整体电视体验中的重要性。</li>    <li>他们还探索了其他行业趋势，例如智能眼镜、增强现实设备以及将技术集成到汽车中。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>boast (v.) - /boʊst/ 自夸，夸耀。    <p>原文例句：TCL also boasted about their supply chain prowess and the ability to manufacture leading technologies in-house. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由boost（提升，增加）演变而来的，表示“自夸，夸耀”。在这个例句中，它描述了TCL夸耀他们的供应链实力和内部制造领先技术的能力。</p></li>    <li>mini-LED (n.) - /ˌmɪniˌɛlˌiːdiː/ Mini-LED电视。    <p>原文例句：Mini LEDs featured prominently in the presentations of both Hisense and TCL, as they each presented their brands as the best option for finding this tech in TVs that cost just a few hundred dollars, rather than thousands. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Mini-LED是一种新型的电视显示技术，采用比传统LED更小的发光二极管（LED），以实现更精细的图像和更高的亮度。在这个例句中，它指的是Mini-LED电视，即采用Mini-LED技术的电视机。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Hisense said that mini LEDs – which cram more LEDs into a display to offer a greater range of contrast and image quality – are now integrated into all its models, including one for under US$500. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示海信表示，Mini-LED现在已经集成到他们所有的型号中，包括一个售价低于500美元的型号，而Mini-LED是一种将更多LED塞进显示屏以提供更大对比度和图像质量的技术。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>When you think about global players, I think we are one of less than a handful of companies that have everything that it takes to be able to truly provide a smart home solution. - 当你想到全球玩家时，我认为我们是为数不多的几家能够真正提供智能家居解决方案的公司之一。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是I think we are one of less than a handful of companies that have everything that it takes to be able to truly provide a smart home solution，其中主语是we，谓语是are，宾语是one of less than a handful of companies that have everything that it takes to be able to truly provide a smart home solution。When you think about global players是一个时间状语从句，表示在你想起全球玩家的时候。这个句子的意思是说，当你想起全球玩家时，我认为我们是为数不多的几家能够真正提供智能家居解决方案的公司之一。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company said its newest 8K Sonic Laser TV is the “world’s largest sound-emitting screen”, offering a sound bar-like experience built into the projector. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则变化形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间点之前已经完成。在这个例句中，它表示该公司表示其最新的8K Sonic Laser TV是“世界上最大的发声屏幕”，并在投影仪中内置了类似于条形音箱的体验。这句话说的是，在某一个时间点之前，该公司已经完成了对8K Sonic Laser TV的开发，并且该电视具有内置的类似于条形音箱的体验。</p></li>    <li>不定式作目的语 - 表示动作或状态的目的或意图。    <p>原文例句：Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式作目的语是指不定式用作动词的宾语，表示动作或状态的目的或意图。结构是：动词+不定式。在这个例句中，不定式作目的语是introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses，表示介绍RayNeo X2 Lite智能眼镜的意图。这个句子的意思是说，TCL通讯的首席营销官施特雷特在2024年1月8日拉斯维加斯举行的CES 2024上介绍了RayNeo X2 Lite智能眼镜。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The two biggest Chinese TV brands offered competing narratives about their global stature and AI processing capabilities</li>
<li>The companies emphasised their ability to produce much of their technology in-house and how they are branching out into areas like AR</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/d720b3c6-868e-43ae-b6f8-e7b08d7057b0_128316fa.jpg" /><figcaption>Hisense USA president David Gold on stage at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese television set makers Hisense and TCL unveiled their latest line-ups at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday, with an emphasis on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence">artificial intelligence (AI)</a> and making screens the centre of the home, while pushing into new areas like cars.</p><p>Both companies offered competing narratives, presenting themselves as the biggest Chinese brands in the US television space. They also boasted about their supply chain prowess and the ability to manufacture leading technologies in-house.</p><p>David Gold, president of Hisense USA, said the company’s ability to produce displays and even its own AI chipsets without third parties is something that sets it apart.</p><p>“When you think about global players, I think we are one of less than a handful of companies that have everything that it takes to be able to truly provide a smart home solution,” Gold said after the Hisense presentation. “We have all the ingredients, all the components. There are very few companies out there that can do the same.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>The flagship product from Hisense this year is its new 110-inch ULED X television with a brightness of 10,000 nits and 40,000 backlight zones.</p><p>Not to be outdone, TCL announced what it said is the world’s largest mini-LED TV at 115 inches. TCL referred to itself as a “great global power” with 32 research and development centres and 43 manufacturing sites around the world.</p><p>Mini LEDs featured prominently in the presentations of both Hisense and TCL, as they each presented their brands as the best option for finding this tech in TVs that cost just a few hundred dollars, rather than thousands.</p><p>Hisense said that mini LEDs – which cram more LEDs into a display to offer a greater range of contrast and image quality – are now integrated into all its models, including one for under US$500.</p><p>Hisense also introduced its new so-called laser TVs, which are projectors combined with an ambient-light-rejecting screen. The company said its newest 8K Sonic Laser TV is the “world’s largest sound-emitting screen”, offering a sound bar-like experience built into the projector. It is also offering a new Rollable Laser TV, which is exactly what it sounds like: a projector screen that rolls up and disappears, offering a cleaner look at home when not in use.</p><p>Both companies used sports to draw attention to their new TVs. As more viewers switch to streaming, the focus on live television has largely fallen to sports, a major reason households remain subscribed to cable and satellite TV packages.</p><p>TCL leaned into this heavily, inviting sportscasters including Charissa Thompson and former National Football League player Charles Woodson on stage for nearly the entire duration of the presentation.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/e0266ca3-3156-4fd7-af77-61200f190c62_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Hisense highlighted the ability of its AI chips to enhance picture quality by identifying whether the video is coming from streaming, cable or another source.</p><p>“[Our AI is] about recognising what content it is, the quality, the factor in which it’s being displayed – whether it’s streaming, cable, DVDs, Blu-ray – and finding the way to enhance that picture quality,” Gold said. “Usually you put in one setting and never change it again. What we’re trying to do with AI is automatically detect, ‘Oh, now you’re watching football, let’s move to a sport setting’.”</p><p>Seemingly omnipresent at CES 2024, AI was mentioned repeatedly during both presentations, as it has been by rivals like Samsung and LG.</p><p>TCL talked of enhancing access to its AI processing with three levels of its AIPQ processors, which include “pro” and “ultra” versions. The AI processors are now offered in its cheaper S Class series.</p><p>While TVs are typically the highlight for these events from the Chinese display giants, they are also chasing other trends in the industry. TCL mentioned the latest version of the RayNeo X2 smart glasses, which can display images on the lenses to do things like offer real-time text translation. TCL incubated RayNeo.</p><p>The company also highlighted its newest smartphones and tablets with an emphasis on its Nxtpaper display, which is meant to be easier on the eyes like e-reader displays.</p><p>Hisense is working on its own augmented reality (AR) glasses and a virtual reality headset, but both are just prototypes for now.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1229" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/5dbb9d8d-418e-45e8-ade6-ea407301ebfc_dc8aec28.jpg" title="Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>It has also followed many of its Chinese peers – like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a> – into the auto sector. It is working on bringing its projector technology into cars to, among other things, turn the windscreen into an AR display. The company said this enhances safety because drivers do not need to take their eyes off the road when getting information like navigation.</p><p>“If you’re on the road and your smart refrigerator can tell you, ‘hey, you’re out of eggs; so on your way home, stop by and pick up some eggs,’ that’s the idea that we’re going for,” Gold said.</p><p>Many tech firms are betting on cars as the next big area of growth. As leaders in electric vehicles, Chinese companies are benefiting from the trend. Carmakers <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto">Li Auto</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/great-wall-motors" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/great-wall-motors">Great Wall Motor</a>, Zeekr and Xiaomi will all <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector">use Nvidia’s Drive tech</a> for autonomous driving, the chip firm announced on Monday.</p><p>Samsung and Sony also discussed their own partnerships with carmakers in their presentations on Monday. Sony has partnered with Honda on its Afeela joint venture, while Samsung is partnering with Hyundai to bring its SmartThings platform to cars.</p><p>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>JD.com’s on-demand delivery unit, Dada Nexus, loses 46 per cent of US stock value overnight amid internal inquiry into potential fraud</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247804/jdcoms-demand-delivery-unit-dada-nexus-loses-46-cent-us-stock-value-overnight-amid-internal-inquiry</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  中国电商巨头京东旗下的达达集团在2023年第一季度财务报告中发现约合1.4亿美元的收入和成本有问题。达达已经将此潜在欺诈案件向当地警方报案。这对中国科技股的投资者信心造成了进一步的打击。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 中国电商公司达达集团发现财务报告中存在可疑收入和成本，引发投资者担忧。</li>    <li>Theme: 达达集团被曝财务造假，对其本身以及中国科技股的投资者信心造成负面影响。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 中国科技股市场面临欺诈风险，需要加强监管和投资者保护。</li>    <li>Main information: 达达集团内部审计发现可疑收入和成本；达达集团已向警方报案；京东股价受此影响下跌；达达集团可能面临投资者诉讼。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  京东旗下即时配送公司达达集团因内部审计发现2023年前三个季度的账目中存在10亿人民币的可疑收入和成本，引发了投资者的担忧。这一潜在的欺诈事件对京东股价造成了负面影响，也进一步打击了投资者对中国科技股的信心。达达集团已向警方报案，并表示将与第三方机构合作，对财务报表进行全面审计。  <ul>    <li>摘要：达达集团财务造假，投资者信心受挫。</li>    <li>主题：达达集团涉嫌财务欺诈，引发投资者对中国科技股的担忧。</li>    <li>观点：中国科技股市场面临欺诈风险，需要加强监管和投资者保护。</li>    <li>主要信息：达达集团内部审计发现可疑收入和成本；达达集团已向警方报案；京东股价受此影响下跌；达达集团可能面临投资者诉讼。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.njuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：Dada Nexus, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit. </p>    <p>例句讲解：revenue是revenue的复数形式，revenue源于拉丁语revenire，意思是“归还”，引申为“收入”或“收益”。在这个例句中，revenue指的是达达集团在2023年前三个季度财务报告中发现的可疑收入。</p></li>    <li>fraud (n.) - /frɔːd/ 欺诈，诈骗。    <p>原文例句：A potential case of fraud at JD.com-affiliated, on-demand delivery firm Dada Nexus could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese tech stocks. </p>    <p>例句讲解：fraud源于拉丁语fraus，意思是“欺骗”，引申为“欺诈”或“诈骗”。在这个例句中，fraud指的是达达集团被曝出的财务造假事件。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>for the first three quarters - 在前三个季度中。    <p>原文例句：Dada Nexus, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit. </p>    <p>例句讲解：for the first three quarters是一个介词短语，表示“在前三个季度中”。在这个例句中，it指的是达达集团在2023年前三个季度财务报告中发现的可疑收入和成本。</p></li>    <li>subject of the inquiry - 调查的对象。    <p>原文例句：While the amount that is subject of the inquiry makes up just about a third of Dada’s total revenue in the September quarter, a potential fraud in the company’s books could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese internet stocks.</p>    <p>例句讲解：subject of the inquiry是一个介词短语，表示“调查的对象”。在这个例句中，it指的是达达集团财务报告中发现的可疑收入和成本。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Dada Nexus, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit. - 达达集团在2023年前三个季度财务报告中发现约合1.4亿美元的收入和成本有问题。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Dada Nexus found questionable revenue and costs in its books，其中主语是Dada Nexus，谓语是found，宾语是questionable revenue and costs。during a routine internal audit是一个介词短语作状语，表示“在例行内部审计期间”。for the first three quarters of 2023是一个介词短语作时间状语，表示“在2023年前三个季度中”。1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of是定语从句，修饰revenue and costs，表示“约合1.4亿美元的”。这个句子的意思是说，达达集团在2023年前三个季度财务报告中发现约合1.4亿美元的收入和成本有问题。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>一般现在时 - 表示现在发生的事情或存在的状态。    <p>原文例句：Dada Nexus, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit.</p>    <p>语法讲解：一般现在时是一种时态，表示现在发生的事情或存在的状态。其结构是：主语+谓语（动词原形）。在这个例句中，谓语是found，表示达达集团发现了可疑的收入和成本。</p></li>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是一种时态，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。其结构是：主语+have/has+过去分词。在这个例句中，谓语是has stepped down，表示辛利军已经辞去了职务。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>A routine internal audit at Dada found US$140 million worth of questionable revenue and costs in the firm’s books for the first three quarters of 2023</li>
<li>Shanghai-based Dada has reported the potential case of fraud to police, according to local media</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/c047f84e-6340-412a-9bce-843911227d91_14f4c464.jpg" /><figcaption>A potential case of fraud at JD.com-affiliated, on-demand delivery firm Dada Nexus could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese tech stocks. Image: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>An on-demand delivery firm affiliated with Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> lost 46 per cent of its stock value in New York on Monday, following an inquiry into “suspicious” data during an internal audit, dealing a fresh blow to confidence in China’s tech stocks.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3195587/jdcoms-logistics-arm-pushes-ahead-unmanned-robotic-grocery-deliveries" target="_self" title="">Dada Nexus</a>, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit, according to its corporate filing. Parent JD.com’s share price tumbled 3 per cent on Tuesday in Hong Kong.</p><p>Nasdaq-listed Dada said an estimated 500 million yuan of online advertising and marketing service revenue plus another 500 million yuan of operations and support costs for the first three quarters of 2023 may have been overstated.</p><p>While the amount that is subject of the inquiry makes up just about a third of Dada’s total revenue in the September quarter, a potential fraud in the company’s books could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> stocks.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/933378cf-3ccc-42bf-a060-3d2efc2145c7_55c83460.jpg" title="Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The investigation at Dada comes nearly a month since the company’s chairman, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241791/chinese-e-commerce-giant-jdcom-removes-veteran-executive-retail-ceo-after-brutal-singles-day-price" target="_self" title="">Xin Liju</a>n, stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” effective on December 19. In that same corporate announcement of management changes at Dada, Chen Zhaoming resigned as the firm’s chief financial officer.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a>-based Dada, according to a report by Chinese news outlet The Paper, has reported the potential fraud case to local police.</p><p>A JD.com representative referred the South China Morning Post to Dada’s US filing and declined to provide further details. Dada did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Tuesday.</p><p>Dada had earlier said it was working with third-party agencies, including an accounting company and a law firm, to conduct an independent review of the case.</p><p>In separate filings with regulators, both JD.com and Dada said they are committed to maintaining high corporate-governance standards and internal controls.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246715/chinese-e-commerce-giant-jdcom-wins-antitrust-lawsuit-against-alibaba-which-was-ordered-beijing" title="">Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com wins antitrust lawsuit against Alibaba</a></h3><p>Founded in Shanghai in 2014, Dada runs two core businesses: parent JD.com’s on-demand retail platform JD Daojia and its own Dada Now. Both these operations work with bricks-and-mortar retailers and merchants on fulfilment, including delivery of online orders to consumers in under roughly an hour.</p><p>JD Daojia operates in more than 1,700 counties, districts and cities across mainland China, while Dada Now does business in 2,700 domestic locations.</p><p>In November, Dada reported that total third-quarter revenue rose 20.4 per cent year on year to 2.9 billion yuan.</p><p>On-demand delivery is a hotly contested field on the mainland, where Dada competes against the likes of food delivery giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> and JD.com rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, which owns the Post.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance confirms talks with Tencent, other potential buyers over sale of video game operations</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Chinese internet company ByteDance, owner of the hugely successful short video app TikTok, is in talks with potential buyers for its video game operations, including Tencent Holdings, the world's biggest gaming company by revenue. ByteDance has failed to achieve returns from its gaming investments despite spending more than US$14 million developing titles. The company is restructuring its gaming business and has shut down most game projects that had not been released online.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: ByteDance is selling its video game operations due to lack of profitability.</li>    <li>Theme: ByteDance's struggles in the video game market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The challenges and complexities of expanding into new markets and industries.</li>    <li>Main information: Negotiations with potential buyers, closure of game projects, and restructuring of the gaming business.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  字节跳动公司，凭借短视频应用 TikTok 和其中国版抖音取得巨大成功，目前正在与多位潜在买家洽谈出售其视频游戏业务，其中包括全球游戏行业收入最高的腾讯控股。字节跳动尽管已在游戏研发上投入超1400万美元，却一直未能实现游戏投资的回报。公司正在重组游戏业务，并已关闭了多数尚未在线上线的游戏项目。  <ul>    <li>摘要：字节跳动因盈利不佳出售游戏业务。</li>    <li>主题：字节跳动在游戏市场上的困境。</li>    <li>观点：拓展新市场、进军新行业的挑战和复杂性。</li>    <li>主要信息：与潜在买家的谈判，关闭游戏项目，重组游戏业务。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.njuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：Tencent Holdings, the world’s biggest gaming company by revenue. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Revenue是revenue的单数形式，表示“收入，收益”。在这个例句中，它指的是腾讯控股作为全球游戏行业收入最高的公司。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>disposal (n.) - /dɪˈspoʊz.əl/ 处理，处置。    <p>原文例句：Nuverse was in negotiations with Tencent regarding the disposal of its operations. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Disposal是dispose的派生名词，表示“处理，处置”。在这个例句中，它指的是Nuverse与腾讯谈判处置其业务的事宜。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>despite + 名词/动名词 - 尽管，即使。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance has failed to achieve returns from its gaming investments despite spending more than US$14 million developing titles.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Despite是介词，表示“尽管，即使”。在这个例句中，它表示字节跳动尽管花费超过1400万美元开发游戏，却一直未能实现游戏投资的回报。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance spent around 30 billion yuan on video game acquisitions and investments involving more than 20 studios between 2019 and 2022, according to local media outlet DingjiaoOne. - 根据本地媒体丁香园的一则报道，字节跳动在2019年至2022年间花费约300亿人民币用于与20多家工作室合作的游戏收购和投资。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是ByteDance spent around 30 billion yuan on video game acquisitions and investments involving more than 20 studios between 2019 and 2022，其中主语是ByteDance，谓语是spent，宾语是around 30 billion yuan on video game acquisitions and investments involving more than 20 studios between 2019 and 2022。according to local media outlet DingjiaoOne是一个介词短语作状语，修饰ByteDance spent around 30 billion yuan on video game acquisitions and investments involving more than 20 studios between 2019 and 2022，表示根据本地媒体丁香园的一则报道。这个句子的意思是说，根据本地媒体丁香园的一则报道，字节跳动在2019年至2022年间花费约300亿人民币用于与20多家工作室合作的游戏收购和投资。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达假设，愿望，建议或可能性等不真实或不确定的情况。    <p>原文例句：While the company made US$54 billion in the first half of 2023, less than 1 per cent of that came from their video games business. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气复合句，主句是less than 1 per cent of that came from their video games business，其中主语是less than 1 per cent of that，谓语是came，宾语是from their video games business。While the company made US$54 billion in the first half of 2023是一个让步状语从句，表示即使该公司在2023年上半年赚了540亿美元，但从中赚到的钱却不到1%。这个句子的意思是说，即使该公司在2023年上半年赚了540亿美元，但从中赚到的钱却不到1%。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较级和最高级 - 用于比较两个或多个对象或情况的差异。    <p>原文例句：Tencent Holdings, the world’s biggest gaming company by revenue.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个比较级句，比较的是Tencent Holdings与世界其他游戏公司在收入方面的差距。biggest是big的比较级，表示“最大的”。在这个例句中，它表示腾讯控股是全球游戏行业收入最高的公司。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Local media reported that ByteDance was lowering the valuation of its gaming studios to try and make a deal after spending more than US$14 million developing titles</li>
<li>Despite its huge success with short video app TikTok and its Chinese version Douyin, ByteDance has failed to achieve returns from its gaming investments</li>
</ul><p>TikTok owner ByteDance has confirmed that it is in talks with multiple potential buyers for its video game operations, including Tencent Holdings, the world’s biggest gaming company by revenue.</p><p>The confirmation from a ByteDance representative on Tuesday came after local media outlet LatePost reported that the company's gaming unit Nuverse was in negotiations with Tencent regarding the disposal of its operations. According to the report, ByteDance was lowering the valuation of its video gaming studios to try and make a deal after spending more than 100 million yuan (US$14 million) developing various titles.</p><p>The representative said that the company has not reached an agreement with Tencent.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242972/tiktok-owner-bytedance-retreats-video-gaming-cuts-main-studio-amid-stagnating-market-dominated" target="_self" title="">In November, the South China Morning Post reported</a> that the Beijing-based company told employees that it would shut down most game projects that had not been released online, and sell rights to at least two of its titles – the anime-style role-playing game <em>Crystal of Atlan</em> and sci-fi survival game <em>Earth: Revival.</em></p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after" title="">China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech must end, party paper says</a></h3><p>ByteDance also started lay-offs at its games unit, which employs nearly 2,000 people, although the exact number of affected employees was not clear. Some workers who want to remain at ByteDance could be allowed to transfer to other teams, the Post reported.</p><p>A ByteDance representative said at the time that it decided to “restructure its gaming business” and “make adjustments to focus on long-term strategic growth areas”.</p><p>Despite its huge success with short video app TikTok and its Chinese version Douyin, ByteDance has failed to achieve returns from its video gaming investments. The company spent around 30 billion yuan on video game acquisitions and investments involving more than 20 studios between 2019 and 2022, according to local media outlet DingjiaoOne.</p><p>“While the company made US$54 billion in the first half of 2023, less than 1 per cent of that came from their video games business,” said Lisa Hanson, chief executive of gaming industry consultancy Niko Partners.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Crystal of Atlan, the action role-playing game developed by ByteDance’s Nuverse studio, is up for sale. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1037" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/1b444be4-f8e0-4989-bcc0-6ad82a22dc7a_d4f55384.jpg" title="Crystal of Atlan, the action role-playing game developed by ByteDance’s Nuverse studio, is up for sale. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Crystal of Atlan, the action role-playing game developed by ByteDance’s Nuverse studio, is up for sale. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>ByteDance founder Zhang Yiming, who stepped down as chairman and CEO in 2021, was never a video gaming enthusiast before dipping his toe in the market.</p><p>Yan Shou, head of ByteDance’s video gaming unit, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246294/after-tiktok-owner-bytedance-cuts-fat-focus-fundamentals-social-commerce-challenges-and-us-election" target="_self" title="">spent most of his career in strategic investments</a> and hired several people with a consulting and strategy background to help him run the unit, the Post reported.</p><p>Zhang had grown impatient with the slow development, complaining in 2022 about the lack of progress at the gaming division during a video call with executives, saying that its Moonton studio had not grown despite doubling its headcount, tech media outlet The Information reported in December. Reuters reported a month earlier that ByteDance was in talks to sell Moonton.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia rolls out new chips, claims leadership of &#39;AI PC&#39; race</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247752/nvidia-rolls-out-new-chips-claims-leadership-ai-pc-race</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  英伟达公司在国际消费类电子产品展览会（CES）发布了三款搭载额外组件的台式机显卡芯片，旨在帮助游戏玩家、设计师和其他电脑用户在个人电脑上更好地利用人工智能（AI），而无需依赖通过互联网访问的远程服务。英伟达声称其显卡芯片是驱动新型笔记本电脑和台式机系统的最佳引擎。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Nvidia unveils new AI-powered PC graphics chips at CES.</li>    <li>Theme: Enhancing personal computers with AI capabilities to improve performance and user experience.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Nvidia's emphasis on the superiority of AI-powered PCs over internet-based AI services.</li>    <li>Main information: Introduction of three new graphics chips with AI components; improved performance for AI tasks and ray-tracing games; partnership with software companies for AI-tuned applications.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  英伟达公司在国际消费类电子产品展览会（CES）发布了三款搭载额外组件的台式机显卡芯片，旨在帮助游戏玩家、设计师和其他电脑用户在个人电脑上更好地利用人工智能（AI），而无需依赖通过互联网访问的远程服务。英伟达声称其显卡芯片是驱动新型笔记本电脑和台式机系统的最佳引擎。  <ul>    <li>摘要：英伟达在CES上发布了新款AI驱动PC图形芯片。</li>    <li>主题：用AI功能增强个人电脑，以改善性能和用户体验。</li>    <li>观点：英伟达强调AI驱动的个人电脑优于基于互联网的AI服务。</li>    <li>主要信息：推出三款带有AI组件的新型显卡芯片；提高AI任务和光线追踪游戏的性能；与软件公司合作提供AI优化的应用程序。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>boosted (v.) - /buːst/ 提升，增强。      <p>原文例句：Nvidia stock rose as much as 5 per cent in New York trading on Monday, taking it back above US$500 a share to a record high. </p>      <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于boost（提升），表示“提升，增强”。在这个例句中，它表示英伟达的股票在纽约交易中的涨幅高达5%，使股价回升至500美元以上，创下历史新高。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>triple (v.) - /ˈtrɪpəl/ 三倍于，翻三番。      <p>原文例句：The stock more than tripled last year, giving the company a market value of more than US$1 trillion. </p>      <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于triple（三倍），表示“三倍于，翻三番”。在这个例句中，它表示该公司的股价去年上涨了三倍多，使公司的市值超过了1万亿美元。</p>    </li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fall steeply - 急剧下降。    <P>原文例句：After a spike in sales during the pandemic, PC shipments have fallen steeply, leaving makers and component suppliers burdened with inventory and little growth. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由fall（下降）和steeply（陡峭地）构成的，表示“急剧下降”。在这个例句中，它表示在疫情期间销售激增后，个人电脑的出货量急剧下降，导致制造商和零部件供应商背负着库存且增长乏力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company also unveiled an RTX 4070 Ti Super for US$799 and a 4070 Super for US$599, which will be available later this month. - 该公司还发布了价格为799美元的RTX 4070 Ti Super和价格为599美元的4070 Super，它们将于本月晚些时候上市。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的复合句，主句是The company also unveiled an RTX 4070 Ti Super for US$799 and a 4070 Super for US$599，其中主语是The company，谓语是unveiled，宾语是an RTX 4070 Ti Super for US$799 and a 4070 Super for US$599。which will be available later this month是一个定语从句，修饰an RTX 4070 Ti Super for US$799 and a 4070 Super for US$599，表示它们将于本月晚些时候上市。这个句子的意思是说，该  <ul><li>Intel and AMD have already touted AI PCs as a new era for the industry, arguing that AI software is more secure and responsive on the PC than over the internet</li>
<li>The new GeForce RTX 4080 Super&nbsp;can run Stable Diffusion XL image generation software 1.7 times faster than the equivalent model from the previous generation</li>
</ul><p>Nvidia, whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software, announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”.</p><p>Nvidia unveiled three new desktop graphics chips with extra components that will let gamers, designers and other computer users make better use of AI on their personal machines, without having to rely on remote services accessed over the internet. The chips, updated versions of existing offerings, will be offered at a “great new price”, the company said on Monday in a presentation at the CES trade show in Las Vegas.</p><p>The company's major rivals, Intel and Advanced Micro Devices, have already touted what they say is a new era for the industry: AI PCs. The companies argue that AI software is more secure and responsive when it is run on the PCs themselves rather than over the internet.</p><p>Nvidia now claims its graphics chips are the best engines to power the new types of laptops and desktops.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector" title="">Nvidia expands its reach in China’s electric vehicle sector</a></h3><p>The new GeForce RTX 4080 Super will get more processing cores and faster memory. It can run Stable Diffusion XL image generation software 1.7 times faster than the equivalent model from the previous generation of Nvidia technology, the company said. The new chip will also power games with ray tracing – building an image by calculating the path of individual rays of light – at 4K resolution.</p><p>The product is scheduled to go on sale from January 31 for US$999. The company also unveiled an RTX 4070 Ti Super for US$799 and a 4070 Super for US$599, which will be available later this month.</p><p>Paired with new software and optimisations of AI models that Nvidia is also releasing, the products will offer an “order-of-magnitude” improvement over machines that are powered by Intel chips, according to Justin Walker, an Nvidia vice-president.</p><p>Nvidia’s stock rose as much as 5 per cent in New York trading on Monday, taking it back above US$500 a share to a record high. The stock more than tripled last year, giving the company a market value of more than US$1 trillion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>After a spike in sales during the pandemic, PC shipments have fallen steeply, leaving makers and component suppliers burdened with inventory and little growth. Nvidia has avoided the worst of the PC plunge by owning the market for accelerator chips used to create AI software in data centres. The explosion in demand for that more expensive type of chip has pushed Nvidia’s market value past US$1 trillion, making it the most valuable company in the history of the semiconductor industry.</p><p>For chip makers in general, though, the majority of the volume they ship still goes into PCs. They are searching for a way to persuade laptop owners and corporate buyers to upgrade their equipment and have begun touting AI capabilities as a reason for new purchases.</p><p>Nvidia said the new chips will provide more realistic gaming with high-definition images enhanced by AI, which will also generate improved dialogue by in-game characters. In another example, the products will provide more responsive tools for image-editing software from companies such as Adobe. There are currently 500 applications that are tuned to work better with AI and Nvidia’s RTX technology, the company said.</p><p>Separately, Nvidia said the capabilities of its new products will not trigger rules put in place by the US government to limit the export of AI-related chips to China. The top-of-the-line GTX 4090 already fell afoul of those restrictions, requiring Nvidia to produce a less-capable version for that market.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s Vision Pro headset launches next month, as US tech giant seeks to expand mixed-reality market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247747/apples-vision-pro-headset-launches-next-month-company-seeks-expand-mixed-reality-market</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Apple announced its new high-priced headset, the Vision Pro, a game-changing technology that combines the real and digital worlds. The headset features compatibility with over a million apps designed for iPhone and iPad, making it appealing to a broader audience beyond video gamers and tech enthusiasts. With a hefty price tag of US$3,500 and an in-store fitting requirement, the Vision Pro targets early adopters. Industry analysts are optimistic about Apple's potential to expand the technology's reach, despite the limited success of similar products by other companies. The device's ability to capture 3D videos compatible with the latest iPhones is seen as a way to further drive interest and sales. Despite a slight decline in revenue, Apple still raked in a significant US$383 billion during its last fiscal year, with the iPhone contributing to more than half of that amount.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's Vision Pro headset aims to revolutionize the virtual reality experience with app compatibility and 3D video capabilities.</li>    <li>Theme: The launch of Apple's expensive mixed reality headset, Vision Pro, and its potential to expand the technology's audience.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Apple's headset has the ability to attract a broader audience, moving beyond the current niche market of video gamers and tech enthusiasts.</li>    <li>Main information: The Vision Pro's compatibility with iPhone and iPad apps, the requirement for in-store fitting, its high price tag, and Apple's strategy to maintain sales growth.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  苹果公司宣布了其新款高价耳机 Vision Pro，这是一项将真实世界与数字世界相结合的变革性技术。这款耳机兼容一百多万款专为 iPhone 和 iPad 设计的应用程序，使其对视频游戏玩家和技术爱好者以外的更广泛受众具有吸引力。Vision Pro 以 3500 美元的昂贵价格和店内试戴要求，瞄准早期采用者。行业分析师乐观地认为苹果有潜力扩大这项技术的覆盖范围，尽管其他公司类似产品的成功有限。该设备能够捕获与最新 iPhone 兼容的 3D 视频，被视为进一步推动兴趣和销售的一种方式。尽管收入略有下降，但苹果在截至 9 月的最后一个财年中仍获得了 3830 亿美元的巨额收入，其中 iPhone 贡献了超过一半的收入。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果的 Vision Pro 耳机旨在以应用程序兼容性和 3D 视频功能彻底改变虚拟现实体验。</li>    <li>主题：苹果昂贵的混合现实耳机 Vision Pro 的发布及其扩大该技术受众的潜力。</li>    <li>观点：苹果的耳机有能力吸引更广泛的受众，超越目前的视频游戏玩家和技术爱好者的利基市场。</li>    <li>主要信息：Vision Pro 与 iPhone 和 iPad 应用程序的兼容性、店内试戴的要求、高昂的价格以及苹果维持销售增长的策略。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>niche (n.) - /niːʃ/ 壁龛，利基市场。    <p>原文例句：The Vision Pro already has got largely enthusiastic reviews among the media who were able to test it in tightly controlled demonstrations monitored by Apple, but the device’s price tag probably means relatively few unit sales during its first year on the market. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自法语，意思是“壁龛、利基市场”。在这个例句中，它指的是一个相对小众的市场，通常是针对特定群体或具有特定需求的消费者的市场。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>debut (v.) - /deɪˈbuː/ 首演，首次亮相。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s first new product since its smartwatch debuted a decade ago could set the stage for the introduction of more affordable versions for a broader audience.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自法语，意思是“首次亮相”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司自十年前推出智能手表以来首次推出的新产品。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>set the stage for - 为……奠定基础，创造条件。    <P>原文例句：Apple’s first new product since its smartwatch debuted a decade ago could set the stage for the introduction of more affordable versions for a broader audience. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由set（设置，布置），stage（舞台）和for（为了，针对）构成的，表示“为……设置舞台，为……奠定基础，创造条件”。在这个例句中，它表示苹果公司自十年前推出智能手表以来首次推出的新产品可能会为推出更多价格更实惠的版本奠定基础，以吸引更广泛的受众。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>take place - 发生，举行。    <P>原文例句：The announcement coincides with the annual CES trade show in Las Vegas, where the company has long been conspicuously absent. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，取），place（地方，位置）构成的，表示“发生，举行”。在这个例句中，它表示这一公告与在拉斯维加斯举行的年度 CES 贸易展同时进行，苹果公司长期以来一直明显缺席该展会。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The high-priced headset for toggling between the real and digital world will be available in its stores beginning February 2, launching the trendsetting company’s push to broaden the appeal of what so far has been a niche technology. - 这款用于在现实世界和数字世界之间切换的高价耳机将于 2 月 2 日开始在苹果商店发售，这将开启这家引领潮流的公司为目前为止一直属于利基技术的混合现实扩大吸引力的尝试。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The high-priced headset will be available in its stores beginning February 2，其中主语是The high-priced headset，谓语是will be available，宾语是in its stores beginning February 2。for toggling between the real and digital world是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰The high-priced headset，表示这款耳机可以用来在现实世界和数字世界之间切换。launching the trendsetting company’s push to broaden the appeal of what so far has been a niche technology是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示推出这款耳机是苹果公司为扩大目前为止一直属于利基技术的混合现实的吸引力而做出的尝试。这个句子的意思是说，这款用于在现实世界和数字世界之间切换的高价耳机将于 2 月 2 日开始在苹果商店发售，这将开启这家引领潮流的公司为目前为止一直属于利基技术的混合现实扩大吸引力的尝试。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>情态动词 - 表示说话人对某事的看法或态度。    <p>原文例句：Right now, the Vision Pro will cost seven times more than Meta’s latest virtual-reality headset, the Quest 3. </p>    <p>语法讲解：情态动词是指一类表示说话人的意愿、能力或必然性等主观态度的动词。常见的情态动词有can、may、must、might、should、will等。在例句中，“will”表示“将会”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人对某事的假设或愿望。    <p>原文例句：Apple is looking for ways to juice its sales after suffering a slight decline in revenue during its last fiscal year ended September. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种语法形式，用来表示说话人对某事的假设或愿望。虚拟语气的动词形式通常与主语不一致。在例句中，“suffering”表示“遭受”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad, with pre-orders beginning January 19</li>
<li>Industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far</li>
</ul><p>Apple’s high-priced headset for toggling between the real and digital world will be available in its stores beginning February 2, launching the trendsetting company’s push to broaden the appeal of what so far has been a niche technology.</p><p>Apple unveiled the sleek US$3,500 goggles at a software conference held at its Cupertino, California, headquarters eight months ago – an event that was designed to encourage developers to make apps tailored for a device that projects users into three-dimensional simulations of reality.</p><p>Apple’s announcement coincides with the annual CES trade show in Las Vegas, where the company has long been conspicuously absent.</p><p>Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad. Pre-orders begin January 19, but buyers will have to go to a store to be properly fitted for the goggles, which are controlled with the eyes and a few simple hand gestures.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247367/qualcomm-unveils-chip-mixed-reality-compete-apples-vision-pro" title="">Qualcomm unveils chip for mixed reality to compete with Apple’s Vision Pro</a></h3><p>Although Facebook owner Meta Platforms and other companies have been making virtual-reality headsets for years with limited success, many industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far.</p><p>The Vision Pro already has got largely enthusiastic reviews among the media who were able to test it in tightly controlled demonstrations monitored by Apple, but the device’s price tag probably means relatively few unit sales during its first year on the market.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" class="image-inline caption" height="1271" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/c20a30fc-1af5-4a7c-af6e-4132fe5d819a_b9343cec.jpg" title="Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" width="2000" /><figcaption>Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even so, Apple’s first new product since its smartwatch debuted a decade ago could set the stage for the introduction of more affordable versions for a broader audience. Right now, the Vision Pro will cost seven times more than Meta’s latest virtual-reality headset, the Quest 3.</p><p>In a sign that Apple is expecting the Vision Pro to pave the way to a bigger market, the company included the ability to take 3D videos that can be viewed through the goggles on its latest premium iPhones, the 15 Pro and 15 Pro Max. These videos are so realistic that the people and other images in them appear to be right in front of the viewer watching them.</p><p>Apple is looking for ways to juice its sales after suffering a slight decline in revenue during its last fiscal year ended September. Apple still raked in US$383 billion in sales, with the iPhone accounting for more than half that amount.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung profit tumbles 35% as chip weakness persists</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  South Korean tech giant Samsung Electronics reported a 35% decline in operating income due to weak global demand for consumer electronics and memory chips. The company aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in high-density memory chips and plans to boost capacity by 2.5 times in 2024. Samsung is also looking to its foldable smartphones and new devices to drive future growth.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung reports a fall in operating income, plans to increase memory chip capacity, and aims to boost growth with new devices.</li>    <li>Theme: Challenges faced by Samsung in a sluggish consumer electronics market and its strategies to remain competitive.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of global economic uncertainty on demand for electronics; Samsung's focus on high-density memory chips and foldable smartphones.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's financial results, analysts' estimates, reasons for the decline in revenue, plans to increase memory chip capacity, and expectations for growth in 2024.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  韩国科技巨头三星电子报告称，由于全球对消费电子产品和内存芯片的需求疲软，其营业收入下降了 35%。该公司计划在高密度内存芯片领域赶超竞争对手 SK Hynix，并计划在 2024 年将产能提高 2.5 倍。三星还希望其可折叠智能手机和新设备能够推动未来增长。这家韩国科技集团准备在本月晚些时候在美国发布其最新的小工具，当时投资者担心苹果的 iPhone 15 在发布几个月后可能已失去动力。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星报告营业收入下降，计划提高内存芯片产能，并通过新设备来促进增长。</li>    <li>主题：三星在低迷的消费电子市场中面临的挑战及其保持竞争力的策略。</li>    <li>观点：全球经济不确定性对电子产品需求的影响；三星对高密度内存芯片和可折叠智能手机的关注。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星的财务业绩、分析师的估计、收入下降的原因、提高内存芯片产能的计划以及对 2024 年增长的预期。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sluggish (adj.) - /ˈslʌgɪʃ/ 迟缓，缓慢。    <p>原文例句：Revenue came to 67 trillion won, compared with projections for 70.31 trillion won. The results underscore how demand for smartphones and the memory chips that power modern electronics remains sluggish given economic uncertainty.</p>    <p>例句讲解：该词由“sluggard”（懒惰者）演化而来，意为“懒惰，迟缓，缓慢”。在此句中，它描述了对智能手机和内存芯片的需求仍然低迷。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>trough (n.) - /trɔːf/ 低谷。    <p>原文例句：Prices should start climbing out of troughs around the latter part of 2023, executives said at the time.</p>    <p>例句讲解：该词有“饲槽”和“低谷”两种含义。在此句中，它表示“低谷”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>foldable (adj.) - /ˈfoʊldəbəl/ 可折叠的。    <p>原文例句：Samsung is also counting on a new line-up of devices and foldable smartphones to drive growth in 2024.</p>    <p>例句讲解：该词由“fold”（折叠）演化而来，意为“可折叠的”。在此句中，它描述了一种新型智能手机，可以折叠。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>catch up with - 赶上。    <p>原文例句：Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips.</p>    <p>例句讲解：该词组意为“赶上”。在此句中，它表示三星计划赶上竞争对手 SK Hynix 在高密度内存芯片领域的地位。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>data processing - 数据处理。    <p>原文例句：HBM, an advanced chip that handles data more quickly, works with hardware such as Nvidia’s accelerators to speed up data processing for intensive tasks like training AI models.</p>    <p>例句讲解：该词组意为“数据处理”。在此句中，它表示 HBM 芯片有助于加速数据处理，尤其是在训练 AI 模型等密集任务中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024. - 三星现在计划在蓬勃发展的高密度内存芯片领域赶上竞争对手 SK 海力士，并计划在 2024 年将产能提高 2.5 倍。<p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，由“Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips”和“it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024”组成。前一句描述了三星的目标，后一句描述了三星的计划。介词短语“in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips”修饰动词“catch up”，表示三星计划在高密度内存芯片领域赶上竞争对手 SK 海力士。副词“now”表示三星现在计划赶上竞争对手 SK 海力士。连词“where”引导定语从句，修饰动词“plans”，表示三星计划在高密度内存芯片领域赶上竞争对手 SK 海力士，并计划在 2024 年将产能提高 2.5 倍。介词短语“by 2.5 times”表示三星计划将产能提高 2.5 倍。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：Samsung in October predicted the long-depressed US$160 billion memory market will bounce back gradually in 2024, driven by a boom in artificial intelligence (AI) development.</p>    <p>语法讲解：该句型由“it is/was + 被强调成分 + that/who”构成。在此句中，“it is”是强调句型的标志，“the long-depressed US$160 billion memory market”是被强调成分，“that will bounce back gradually in 2024”是强调内容。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>South Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates</li>
<li>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024</li>
</ul><p>Samsung Electronics posted its sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit, reflecting stubbornly weak demand for consumer electronics globally.</p><p>South Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates. Revenue came to 67 trillion won, compared with projections for 70.31 trillion won.</p><p>The results underscore how demand for smartphones and the memory chips that power modern electronics remains sluggish given economic uncertainty.</p><p>In December, rival Micron Technology delivered a better-than-projected revenue outlook that suggested data centre construction may make up for the lukewarm computing and mobile devices markets.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>“I think this shows that the rebound is slower than we all thought,” said Tom Kang, research director at Counterpoint Technology. “Prices are not rising that fast and the demand from certain sectors is not that strong.”</p><p>Samsung in October predicted the long-depressed US$160 billion memory market will bounce back gradually in 2024, driven by a boom in artificial intelligence (AI) development. Prices should start climbing out of troughs around the latter part of 2023, executives said at the time.</p><p>The company will release a full earnings report, with divisional breakdowns, on January 31.</p><p>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024. HBM, an advanced chip that handles data more quickly, works with hardware such as Nvidia’s accelerators to speed up data processing for intensive tasks like training AI models.</p><p>Samsung is also counting on a new line-up of devices and foldable smartphones to drive growth in 2024. The Korean tech conglomerate is preparing to unveil its latest gadgets in the US later this month, at a time investors worry Apple’s iPhone 15 may be running out of steam mere months after launch.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s AliExpress, PDD-owned Temu face supply chain challenges in South Korea amid rapid business expansion</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247710/alibabas-aliexpress-pdd-owned-temu-face-supply-chain-challenges-south-korea-amid-rapid-business</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>AliExpress and Temu are gaining popularity in South Korea but face challenges in delivery speed and product quality.</li>    <li>Korean consumers are concerned about long delivery times and unstable product quality on these platforms.</li>    <li>South Korea is a major e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023.</li>    <li>AliExpress and Temu are addressing these challenges by improving supply chain efficiency and expanding warehouse capacity.</li>    <li>Korean consumers are also concerned about the proliferation of copycat merchandise on Chinese e-commerce platforms.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>阿里巴巴和拼多多旗下的跨境电商平台 AliExpress 和 Temu 在韩国迅速走红，但也面临着配送速度慢、产品质量不稳定等问题。</li>    <li>韩国消费者对这些平台的商品普遍存在着“担心配送时间长、质量不稳定”的顾虑。</li>    <li>韩国是全球第四大电子商务市场，2023 年预计收入将达到 1398 亿美元。</li>    <li>针对这些问题，AliExpress 和 Temu 均采取了措施来提高供应链效率并扩大了仓库容量。</li>    <li>除此之外，韩国消费者还担心这些平台上充斥着仿冒商品。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>massive (adj.) - /ˈmæsɪv/ 巨大，庞大的。</li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.njuː/ 收入，收益。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba Group Holding and PDD, two of the largest e-commerce companies in China, have been aggressively expanding their foothold in South Korea, offering prices as low as US$1 for some small gadgets on their overseas shopping platforms AliExpress and Temu, respectively. - 阿里巴巴集团和拼多多作为中国最大的两家电子商务公司，积极拓展韩国市场，在其海外购物平台 AliExpress 和 Temu 上提供一些小巧电子配件的价格低至 1 美元。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示持续到现在的动作或状态。</li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Despite their popularity, AliExpress and Temu lag behind the competition in South Korea in terms of fast delivery and product quality assurance</li>
<li>Korean consumers find that proliferation of copycat merchandise is a major problem for Chinese online shopping platforms</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/429e5290-226a-46f7-b76d-3c56e51b65b3_f7ecc5a8.jpg" /><figcaption>Online retail platforms AliExpress and Temu ranked as the two fastest-growing apps in South Korea in 2023, according to market research firm WiseApp. Photos: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giants are now the fastest-growing online platforms for Korean shoppers, but they are still grappling with problems of long delivery time and unstable product quality, according to consumers and retail industry officials.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3243140/discount-e-commerce-giant-pdd-nearly-doubles-quarterly-revenue-closing-alibaba-meituan-also-chalks" target="_self" title="">PDD</a>, two of the largest e-commerce companies in China, have been aggressively expanding their foothold in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a>, offering prices as low as US$1 for some small gadgets on their overseas shopping platforms <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3213632/alibabas-aliexpress-steps-investment-spain-and-south-korea-chinas-e-commerce-players-look-growth" target="_self" title="">AliExpress</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244193/chinese-budget-e-commerce-app-temu-snatching-business-us-dollar-stores-ahead-lucrative-holiday" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>, respectively. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Launched in South Korea in 2018, AliExpress saw its monthly active users surpass 7 million as of last November, nearly doubling the number recorded a year earlier, according to mobile market research firm WiseApp. Temu, which started Korean operations in July, averages 3.5 million users per month. WiseApp ranked the two Chinese platforms as the fastest-growing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">apps</a> in Korea in 2023.</p><p>But on the flip side, some consumers in Korea remain cautious about replacing local online retail sites, such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/2174243/softbank-doubles-down-korean-online-retailer-coupang-us2-billion" target="_self" title="">Coupang</a> and Gmarket, owing to the Chinese platforms’ supply chain problems that include long delivery time and unstable product quality.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/a4611340-1803-40fa-8f74-caa324044017_1126e908.jpg" title="South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Lawrence Woo, a 38-year-old office worker in Seoul, started using AliExpress a year ago after he was lured by the platform’s low prices. Woo found, for example, a laptop stand on AliExpress that costs 30,000 won (US$23) and comes with free shipping, which was a deal around 50 per cent cheaper than those offered by local retail sites.</p><p>Still, Woo said he was confused about the delivery time of merchandise he bought on AliExpress. For instance, it took AliExpress two months to deliver a smartphone camera protector film that he bought last autumn.</p><p>“The delivery time is too long,” Woo said. “I tried to cancel the order, but the customer service was not working.”</p><p>On Temu, product shipping times would range from six to 20 days, according to the Chinese budget shopping app’s website.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3108619/south-korea-some-couriers-are-paying-same-day-deliveries-their" title="">In South Korea, couriers crack under the weight of same-day deliveries</a></h3><p>By comparison, Korean e-commerce giant Coupang is capable of shortening delivery times to within a day through its signature Rocket Delivery service.</p><p>Both AliExpress and Temu work with domestic logistics service providers such as CJ Logistics Corp, the oldest and largest parcel delivery firm in South Korea.</p><p>“It depends on [these companies’] supply chain,” said Zhuang Shuai, founder and chief analyst at Chinese market consultancy Bailian. “For instance, whether the sellers are local merchants or Chinese merchants, and whether the platforms have their own warehouses.”</p><p>Zhuang indicated that Chinese shopping platforms face both policy and cultural barriers in their overseas expansion. “Just like how <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon</a> did not succeed in China, it is also not easy for Chinese companies to operate overseas,” he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235863/alibabas-cainiao-and-aliexpress-start-5-day-global-delivery-service-consumers-uk-spain-netherlands" title="">Alibaba’s Cainiao and AliExpress start ‘5-day global delivery’ service</a></h3><p>Despite those challenges, both AliExpress and Temu have pushed initiatives to improve supply chain efficiency in South Korea.</p><p>The Alibaba unit last March launched a new service called AliExpress Choice that aims to provide Korean consumers with “delivery guarantees and more affordable prices”, touting up to a “three-day delivery window”. AliExpress also expanded the capacity of its warehouses in Weihai and Yantai, two cities in eastern Shandong province, which is close to the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/korean-peninsula-0" target="_self" title="">Korean peninsula</a>.</p><p>Long-time AliExpress user Lee Ye-seul, a 35-year-old resident of Seoul, said the platform’s delivery speed has improved, pointing out that some products she recently ordered arrived within four days of her online purchase. Still, she lamented another major problem: copycat designs widely seen on Chinese e-commerce platforms.</p><p>Lee indicated that there were many merchants on AliExpress selling smartphone cases designed with characters from popular Korean or Japanese brands, such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/article/3131357/hello-kitty-story-how-sanrio-went-silk-sandals-global-superstar" target="_self" title="">Sanrio</a>. “It’s hard to tell if the product you’re buying is plagiarised or an original design,” she said.</p><p>Echoing Lee’s view on copycat merchandise, office worker Woo said it was tough to determine the authenticity of branded products on Chinese shopping platforms. He suggested that these platforms set up a “patrol system” to punish counterfeiters.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" title="">How Temu, an app for US shoppers, helped PDD catch up with Alibaba in market value</a></h3><p>Products bought from AliExpress are “unknowingly circulating” on Korean second-hand sales sites as counterfeits, according to Kang Hyoung-goo, a professor of finance at Hanyang University in Seoul.</p><p>“It is a stumbling block to expanding global outreach through K-fashion exports,” Kang said.</p><p>South Korea has become one of the major battlefields for Alibaba and PDD, as both count on overseas markets to maintain their business momentum amid sluggish user growth and weak spending in their home market.</p><p>Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, followed by Japan, according to a report from online database ECDB.</p><p>Although Chinese platforms have paved the way for many Korean consumers to gain direct access to China-made goods at extremely low prices, Woo and Lee both indicated that these online marketplaces would not become their prime destinations for shopping.</p><p>“I will keep using such platforms, but I’d rather turn to Coupang or Naver Shopping for daily necessities or fashion items,” Woo said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia expands its reach in China’s electric vehicle sector</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Nvidia, a US chip maker, announced that four Chinese electric vehicle brands, including Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and Xiaomi's new EV unit, will adopt its DRIVE technology for automated driving systems. This move reflects Nvidia's determination to expand in China despite stricter export regulations from the US government. Nvidia and other US chip makers face challenges in meeting China's demand for sophisticated chips while complying with US export controls. Meanwhile, Chinese carmakers are competing to introduce more advanced infotainment systems and automated driving features, creating a growth opportunity for semiconductor manufacturers. Nvidia also announced collaborations with various companies, including advertising giant WPP and Lotus, to develop more advanced online shopping tools.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Nvidia's expansion in China for automated driving technology adoption by Chinese EV brands.</li>    <li>Theme: Nvidia's determination to grow in China amid US export restrictions, and the increasing demand for advanced chips in China's automotive industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of collaboration between chip makers and automotive companies to drive innovation in automated driving and online shopping experiences.</li>    <li>Main information: Chinese EV brands adopting Nvidia's DRIVE technology; challenges faced by Nvidia and US chip makers in meeting China's demand for chips; Nvidia's collaboration with companies for online shopping tools development.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  美国芯片制造商英伟达宣布，包括理想汽车、长城汽车、极氪和小米汽车在内的四家中国电动汽车品牌将采用其 DRIVE 技术，用于自动驾驶系统。此举反映了英伟达在面对美国政府更严格的出口管制情况下，依然决心在中国市场扩张。英伟达和其他美国芯片制造商在满足中国对尖端芯片的需求时，面临着遵守美国出口管制的挑战。与此同时，中国汽车制造商正在竞争推出更先进的信息娱乐系统和自动驾驶功能，这为半导体制造商创造了增长机会。英伟达还宣布与包括广告巨头 WPP 和莲花汽车在内的多家公司合作，开发更先进的在线购物工具。  <ul>    <li>摘要：英伟达在中国市场拓展自动驾驶技术，被中国电动汽车品牌采用。</li>    <li>主题：英伟达在面对美国出口限制的情况下，依然决心在中国市场增长，以及中国汽车行业对先进芯片日益增长的需求。</li>    <li>观点：芯片制造商与汽车公司合作对于推动自动驾驶和在线购物体验创新至关重要。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国电动汽车品牌采用英伟达的 DRIVE 技术；英伟达和美国芯片制造商在满足中国对芯片的需求时面临的挑战；英伟达与公司合作开发在线购物工具。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>underscores (v.) - 强调，突出。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia said four Chinese electric vehicle brands will use its technology as the brains for automated driving systems, underscoring the US chip maker’s determination to expand in China despite Washington’s tighter export rules. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于under（在～之下）和score（分数，划痕），表示“在……下划线，强调，突出”。在这个例句中，它指的是英伟达强调了其在美国政府更严格的出口管制下，依然决心在中国市场扩张。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sophisticated (adj.) - 精密的，复杂的。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由sophist（智者）和-ate（与……有关）组成，表示“复杂的，精巧的，复杂的”。在这个例句中，它指的是英伟达和其美国竞争对手面临着满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求，同时保持遵守美国对向中国出口先进半导体的更严格管制的挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in compliance with - 遵守，符合。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在，位于），compliance（遵守，符合）和with（与，用）构成的，表示“根据，遵守，符合”。在这个例句中，它指的是英伟达及其美国竞争对手面临着满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求，同时保持遵守美国对向中国出口先进半导体的更严格管制的挑战。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>more advanced - 更先进的。    <p>原文例句：Chinese carmakers are racing each other to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays and automated driving functions. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由more（更多）和advanced（先进的）构成的，表示“更先进的，更高级的”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国汽车制造商正在竞相推出更先进的车载信息娱乐显示器和自动驾驶功能。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips, while complying with US controls on semiconductor exports to China. - 英伟达和美国竞争对手面临着满足中国对强大芯片的需求，同时遵守美国对向中国出口半导体的管制的挑战。<p>句子分析：这是一个复句，由两个分句组成。第一个分句是Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips，其中主语是Nvidia and US rivals，谓语是face challenges meeting，宾语是China’s demands for powerful chips。第二个分句是while complying with US controls on semiconductor exports to China，其中while是连接词，complying with US controls on semiconductor exports to China是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示英伟达和美国竞争对手在满足中国对强大芯片的需求时，同时遵守美国对向中国出口半导体的管制。这个句子的意思是说，英伟达和美国竞争对手面临着满足中国对强大芯片的需求，同时遵守美国对向中国出口半导体的管制的挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态发生在谓语动词之前，并对谓语动词起修饰作用。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示动作或状态发生在谓语动词之前，并对谓语动词起修饰作用。结构是：过去分词短语 + 谓语动词。其中过去分词短语可以由过去分词、过去分词+宾语、过去分词+宾语+介词短语等形式构成。在这个例句中，过去分词短语是for several years，表示动作或状态持续了很长时间。这个句子的意思是说，该公司已经有好几年在印度生产iPhone和其他产品了，包括最新的iPhone 15。</p></li>  </ul></div>###```  <ul><li>Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday</li>
<li>Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips, while complying with US controls on semiconductor exports to China</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/ca10cd80-a417-41ba-821c-f909879abb0a_5739d5f7.jpg" /><figcaption>A Nvidia logo at the company’s headquarters in Taipei, Taiwan. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia said four Chinese electric vehicle brands will use its technology as the brains for automated driving systems, underscoring the US chip maker’s determination to expand in China despite Washington’s tighter export rules.</p><p>Chinese carmakers Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Chinese telecommunications company Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday at the CES technology conference in Las Vegas.</p><p>China’s rising EV brands are a key market for Nvidia’s automotive technology business. Chinese carmakers are racing each other to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays and automated driving functions. That has created a growth opportunity for Nvidia, Intel, Qualcomm and other semiconductor manufacturers.</p><p>Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>In related CES announcements, Nvidia said it is working with advertising giant WPP, Lotus and six other companies to develop more advanced online shopping tools. Using Nvidia technology, carmakers and dealers hope to create online shopping sites with three dimensional graphics and more lifelike graphics, said Danny Shapiro, Nvidia’s vice-president for automotive.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
