<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Chinese state media calls for crackdown on deceptive pricing in live-streaming e-commerce</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248938/chinese-state-media-calls-crackdown-deceptive-pricing-live-streaming-e-commerce</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  近年来，中国电商直播行业迅猛发展，销售额快速增长。但与之而来的是价格欺诈等乱象层出不穷，损害消费者权益，影响行业健康发展。国家媒体《经济日报》发文呼吁加强对电商直播行业价格欺诈行为的监管，维护消费者权益，促进行业健康发展。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Deceptive pricing practices in live streaming e-commerce raise concerns.</li>    <li>Theme: The article highlights the issue of price fraud in live streaming e-commerce and calls for tighter regulatory scrutiny to protect consumer rights and promote the healthy development of the industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The article emphasizes the need for stricter regulations to curb price fraud in live streaming e-commerce, including increased penalties for offenders and a clearer definition of responsibilities for e-commerce platforms, merchants, and broadcasters.</li>    <li>Main information: The article discusses the rapid growth of live streaming e-commerce in China, the prevalence of price fraud and other deceptive practices in the industry, and the impact of these practices on consumer rights and the reputation of the industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  近年来，中国电商直播行业呈爆发式增长，但与之伴随的价格欺诈等乱象也层出不穷。国家媒体《经济日报》发表文章，呼吁加强对电商直播行业价格欺诈行为的监管，切实维护消费者权益，推动行业健康发展。  <ul>    <li>摘要：电商直播行业价格欺诈乱象引担忧。</li>    <li>主题：文章聚焦电商直播行业价格欺诈问题，呼吁加强监管力度，维护消费者权益，促进行业健康发展。</li>    <li>观点：文章强调需要更加严格的监管措施来遏制电商直播行业价格欺诈行为，包括加大对违规行为的处罚力度，明确电商平台、商家和主播的责任边界。</li>    <li>主要信息：文章讨论了中国电商直播行业的快速发展、行业内普遍存在的标价欺诈和其他欺骗性行为，以及这些行为对消费者权益和行业声誉的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>manipulate (v.) - /məˈnɪpjʊleɪt/ 操纵，控制。    <p>原文例句：Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由manus（手）和pleo（充满）组成，表示“用手充满，用手控制或操作”。在这个例句中，它表示捏造或提高原价并提供虚假折扣被视为价格欺诈。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>deceptive (adj.) - /dɪˈsɛptɪv/ 欺骗的，误导的。    <p>原文例句：Chinese state media Economic Daily has called for tighter regulatory scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由de-（远离）和capere（采取，抓取）组成，表示“拿走，除去”。在这个例句中，它表示欺骗的，误导的，与truth（真相）相对。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>price fraud - 价格欺诈。    <P>原文例句：Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由price（价格）和fraud（欺诈）组成，表示价格欺诈。在这个例句中，它指的是捏造或提高原价并提供虚假折扣的行为，这被认为是价格欺诈。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>These tactics not only hurt consumers’ rights but also damaged the reputation of the live-streaming industry, it added. - 这些做法不仅损害消费者的权益，也损害了直播行业的声誉，它补充说。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是These tactics damaged the reputation of the live-streaming industry，其中主语是These tactics，谓语是damaged，宾语是the reputation of the live-streaming industry。not only…but also…是一个相关连词，表示“不仅……而且……”。在这个例句中，它表示这些做法不仅损害消费者的权益，而且损害了直播行业的声誉。需要注意的是，在这个句子中not only…but also…的完整形式是not only…but also…，第二个but也可以省略。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语 - 用于修饰名词或代词，使句子更生动形象。    <p>原文例句：The call for stricter oversight comes as e-commerce platforms are increasingly relying on live streaming to attract consumers amid fierce domestic competition and weaker consumer spending. </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在分词短语是用现在分词（动词的-ing形式）加上其他成分构成的短语，具有形容词的作用，可以用来修饰名词或代词，使句子更生动形象。在这个例句中，现在分词短语relying on live streaming修饰名词platforms，表示电子商务平台越来越依赖直播来吸引消费者。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>原因状语从句 - 表示原因或理由。    <p>原文例句：Key players in the field include traditional e-commerce platforms such as Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao, as well as short video apps like ByteDance’s Douyin and Kuaishou Technology. </p>    <p>语法讲解：原因状语从句是用because, since, as, for等连接词引导的从句，表示原因或理由。在这个例句中，原因状语从句as well as short video apps like ByteDance’s Douyin and Kuaishou Technology修饰主句Key players in the field include traditional e-commerce platforms such as Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao，表示除了传统的电子商务平台之外，短视频应用也是该领域的关键参与者。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission</li>
<li>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years, with sales jumping 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/da9d4337-120c-49ea-b242-d1f49b587f18_9b05dbbb.jpg" /><figcaption>TikTok Shop and an online influencer prepare for a live-streaming session of selling goods from the Consumer Electronics Show (CES), Las Vegas, January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese state media Economic Daily has called for tighter regulatory scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming, as the country’s e-commerce players increasingly turn to these campaigns to lure customers and drive sales amid fierce competition and macro-economic headwinds.</p><p>In an opinion piece on Thursday, the official media blasted some live streamers for misleading consumers with tactics such as fake price comparisons and exaggerations, adding that more than 5,000 broadcasters were penalised last year for price manipulation.</p><p>Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247160/bytedances-douyin-makes-instant-refunds-mandatory-following-pdd-taobao-and-jdcom-amid-fierce-e" title="">Chinese version of TikTok makes instant refunds mandatory amid e-commerce rivalry</a></h3><p>“Live-streaming e-commerce has become an important part of the digital economy, but price fraud and other chaotic practices have hindered the high-quality development of the economy,” the article said. These tactics not only hurt consumers’ rights but also damaged the reputation of the live-streaming industry, it added.</p><p>The Economic Daily urged the government to improve regulations for the sector and increase the penalties for price fraud. The responsibilities of e-commerce platforms, merchants and broadcasters should be clarified in these cases, the media outlet said.</p><p>E-commerce platforms need to take the initiative to crack down on dubious live-streaming practices, the article urged, and they should impose harsher penalties and even ban those that repeatedly commit violations.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above" title="">Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with broad iPhone discounts</a></h3><p>The call for stricter oversight comes as e-commerce platforms are increasingly relying on live streaming to attract consumers amid fierce domestic competition and weaker consumer spending.</p><p>Key players in the field include traditional e-commerce platforms such as Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao, as well as short video apps like ByteDance’s Douyin and Kuaishou Technology. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years. Sales in the sector jumped 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023, reaching 2.2 trillion yuan (US$311 billion), accounting for 18.1 per cent of all online shopping in China, according to data from the Ministry of Commerce.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1309" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/754d97a1-4883-40b6-b755-d027eb815bcf_113d2948.jpg" title="A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>However, the rapid growth has invited increasing regulatory attention. In April 2021, the Cyberspace Administration of China and six other regulators jointly released rules aimed at curbing malpractice such as selling fake products, falsifying view numbers and promoting pyramid schemes.</p><p>Last month People’s Daily, the chief mouthpiece of the Chinese Communist Party, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3243239/peoples-daily-calls-tighter-control-live-streaming-e-commerce-china-controversies-mount" target="_self" title="">called for tighter oversight of live-streaming e-commerce</a>. The paper said misconduct in the live-streaming industry, from fraudulent advertising to misleading pricing, should be addressed and punished for the sake of the sector’s healthy and sustained growth.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TikTok owner ByteDance looks to expand in US, Canada and Australia amid rising competition and political headwinds</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248932/tiktok-owner-bytedance-looks-expand-us-canada-and-australia-amid-rising-competition-and-political</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In response to growing competition and the booming short video sector, TikTok owner ByteDance plans to expand its operations in the United States, Canada, and Australia. The company aims to secure a large office building in San Jose, California, while simultaneously recruiting talent, primarily computer engineers, to work on apps like TikTok and others in Canada and Australia. Additionally, ByteDance intends to relocate existing employees from various regions to support its expansion.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: ByteDance expands its global reach to Canada and Australia, targeting talent and opening new offices.</li>    <li>Theme: Embracing growth and competition in the short video industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: ByteDance’s strategic moves to reinforce its position amidst rising technological advancements.</li>    <li>Main information: Office acquisition in San Jose, recruitment in Canada and Australia, transfer of employees, and expansion goals.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  TikTok 的所有者字节跳动计划在美国、加拿大和澳大利亚扩张其业务，以应对日益激烈的竞争和蓬勃发展的短视频行业。该公司计划在加利福尼亚州圣何塞获得一座大型办公楼，同时在加拿大和澳大利亚招聘人才，主要是计算机工程师，为 TikTok 等应用工作。此外，字节跳动计划将现有员工从各个地区调动，以支持其扩张。  <ul>    <li>摘要：字节跳动将全球业务扩张至加拿大和澳大利亚，目标是招揽人才和开设新办公室。</li>    <li>主题：在短视频行业中拥抱增长和竞争。</li>    <li>观点：字节跳动在技术日新月异的背景下，采取战略举措巩固其地位。</li>    <li>主要信息：在圣何塞获取办公室、在加拿大和澳大利亚招聘员工、调动员工以及扩张目标。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Momentum (n.) - /ˈmoʊmən.tʌm/ 势头。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance seeks to maintain its business momentum amid rising competition and political headwinds. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Momentum由moment（时刻）和-um（表示“使……成为”或“具有……性质”）构成，意为“动量，势头”。该词常用于描述事物的进展或发展情况，也可用于比喻某人的积极进取的状态。在这个例句中，它指的是字节跳动在面临日益激烈的竞争和政治阻力的情况下，仍旧努力保持其商业发展的势头。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Flagging (v.) - /ˈflæɡ.ɪŋ/ 疲软；衰落。    <p>原文例句：The pace of growth may be flagging, but it has not stopped. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Flagging源自flag（旗帜，飘扬），意为“飘扬，摇摆”。在此处它被用作动词，表示“疲软，衰落”，常用于描述经济、市场等方面的表现。在这个例句中，它指的是经济增长的速度可能正在放缓，但尚未停止。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Short Video Sector (n.) - 短视频行业。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance looks to expand in Silicon Valley in the United States, and also in Canada and Australia as the sector continues to boom. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“Sector”表示“行业，部门”，而“Short Video”则指“短视频”。“Short Video Sector”连用，表示“短视频行业”。在这个例句中，它指的是短视频行业正在蓬勃发展，字节跳动计划在美国硅谷以及加拿大和澳大利亚进行扩张。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company is in talks to sublease a large office building on Coleman Avenue in San Jose, California, according to a report by the Bay Area News Group last week. - 该公司正在洽谈租赁圣何塞科尔曼大道上一座大型办公楼，据湾区新闻集团上周报道。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The company is in talks to sublease a large office building on Coleman Avenue in San Jose, California，其中主语是The company，谓语是is in talks to sublease，宾语是a large office building on Coleman Avenue in San Jose, California。according to a report by the Bay Area News Group last week是一个介词短语作状语，表示这一消息的来源，即据湾区新闻集团上周报道。这个句子的意思是说，该公司正在洽谈租赁圣何塞科尔曼大道上一座大型办公楼，据湾区新闻集团上周报道。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态正在进行，强调动作或状态的持续性。在这个例句中，它表示字节跳动正在将现有员工从其他地区调动到一些新地点。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达假设、愿望、建议等。    <p>原文例句：If ByteDance is successful in its expansion, it could become a major player in the global short video market. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的语态，结构是：If + 主语 + be + 过去式，或If + 主语 + 助动词 + 过去分词。其中主语和be要根据句子的具体情况进行变化。虚拟语气通常用于表达假设、愿望、建议、可能性等。在这个例句中，它表示如果字节跳动在扩张中取得成功，它可能会成为全球短视频市场的主要参与者之一。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In addition to US, ByteDance is looking for talent to join its expanded operations in Canada and Australia to work on apps including TikTok</li>
<li>ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/6f1c2685-a484-454c-8ac6-1cbb7274395c_40276094.jpg" /><figcaption>TikTok owner ByteDance looks to expand in US, Canada and Australia. Photo: AFP  </figcaption></figure><p>ByteDance, which owns global short video hit TikTok, is looking to expand in Silicon Valley in the United States, and also in Canada and Australia as the sector continues to boom and amid rising competition.</p><p>The company is in talks to sublease a large office building on Coleman Avenue in San Jose, California, according to a report by the Bay Area News Group last week.</p><p>Meanwhile, it is looking for talent – mainly computer engineers – to join its expanded operations in Canada and Australia to work on apps including TikTok, video editor CapCut and social media and lifestyle app Lemon8, according to a report on Thursday by Chinese media outlet Jiemian.</p><p>In addition to hiring new staff, ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations. For example, it has relocated 120 people working across product, operations, and research and development from China to Canada and Australia, according to the Jiemian report.</p><p>ByteDance did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>The expansion comes as ByteDance seeks to maintain its business momentum amid rising competition and political headwinds.</p><p>Its flagship app TikTok said in 2021 that its monthly active users (MAU) surpassed 1 billion. CapCut’s MAU has hit 200 million, according to a March report by Baijing, a blog that covers Chinese companies doing business overseas.</p><p>Although ByteDance has retreated in video gaming, it is doubling down on e-commerce by leveraging the popularity of TikTok. It has set an ambitious target for its US shopping operation to increase tenfold to US$17.5 billion in gross merchandise volume this year, according to a Bloomberg report.</p><p>The company’s overall revenue expanded around 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing projected growth at Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings, according to a December Bloomberg report.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance’s Douyin steps up oversight of live-streaming hosts, closing 290,000 accounts last year for ‘harmful’ content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248921/bytedances-douyin-steps-oversight-live-streaming-hosts-closing-290000-accounts-last-year-harmful</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has cracked down on live-streaming hosts for inappropriate practices, such as vulgar language, harassment, improper challenge games, and enticing viewers to spend more money. The platform removed over 290,000 host accounts and banned hosts involved in harmful outdoor live-streaming activities in Changsha. Douyin has also taken action against hosts promoting scams, gambling, and pornographic content, leading to the arrest of over 300 criminal suspects. The crackdown has affected some hosts, resulting in the loss of accounts that took years to build. Douyin has implemented measures to improve the way it manages live streamers, including a revamped host rating system and additional identity checks for virtual hosts.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Douyin's crackdown on inappropriate live-streaming practices leads to account bans and arrests.</li>    <li>Theme: Chinese regulators' tightening control over the live-streaming sector to eliminate harmful content and practices.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of regulating live-streaming platforms to protect users from vulgar language, harassment, and online scams.</li>    <li>Main information: Douyin's removal of over 290,000 host accounts; collaboration with local authorities in Changsha to ban harmful outdoor live-streaming; actions against hosts promoting illegal content; arrest of criminal suspects; introduction of a new host rating system.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  抖音对直播主的不当行为进行整治，例如使用粗俗语言、骚扰他人、不当的挑战游戏，以及引诱观众花钱。该平台已删除了超过29万个主播账号，并禁止参与长沙有害户外直播活动的主播。抖音还对推销诈骗、赌博和色情内容的主播采取行动，导致300多名犯罪嫌疑人被捕。此次打击行动影响了一些主播，导致他们失去了花费数年时间才建立起来的账号。抖音已采取措施改善其管理直播主的方式，包括改进主播评级系统和对虚拟主播进行额外身份检查。  <ul>    <li>摘要：抖音整治不当直播行为，导致账号封禁和逮捕。</li>    <li>主题：中国监管机构加强对直播行业的控制，以消除有害内容和行为。</li>    <li>观点：规范直播平台以保护用户免受粗俗语言、骚扰和网络诈骗侵害的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：抖音删除超过29万个主播账号；与长沙地方当局合作禁止有害户外直播；对推销非法内容的主播采取行动；逮捕犯罪嫌疑人；引入新的主播评级系统。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>harassment (n.) - /həˈræs.mənt/ 骚扰，骚扰行为。    <p>原文例句：Some outdoor live streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由harass（骚扰）和-ment（行为）构成的，表示“骚扰，骚扰行为”。在这个例句中，它指的是户外直播和挑战游戏中的主持人对路人的语言辱骂和骚扰行为。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>improper (adj.) - /ɪmˈprɑː.pər/ 不适当的，不合适的。    <p>原文例句：Improper challenge games and enticed spending were also issues raised by the Cyberspace Administration of China over the past two years, as part of the top Chinese internet watchdog’s campaigns to root out malicious online content.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由in-（否定前缀）和proper（适当的）构成的，表示“不适当的，不合适的”。在这个例句中，它指的是不适当的挑战游戏和引诱消费的行为，这是中国网络空间管理局在过去两年中提出的问题，作为中国最高互联网监管机构根除恶意网络内容的活动的一部分。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li> crackdown (n.) - /ˈkræk.daʊn/ 镇压，打击。    <p>原文例句：Douyin’s live-streaming clampdown also targeted live streamers who were promoting scams, gambling and pornographic content on the platform.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由crack（突然破裂）和down（向下）构成的，表示“镇压，打击”。在这个例句中，它指的是抖音对在平台上推广诈骗、赌博和色情内容的直播者的打击行动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>ban (v.) - /bæn/ 禁止，禁止。    <p>原文例句：The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts, including some top influencers, as the platform sought to weed out practices it deemed harmful, such as outdoor live-streaming containing vulgar content, improper challenge games among hosts, as well as enticing viewers to spend more money, the company said in a post published to its official WeChat account on Tuesday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词的意思是“禁止，禁止”。在这个例句中，它指的是抖音在2023年进行的直播打击行动，关闭了超过29万个主播账号，包括一些顶级影响者，因为该平台试图根除其认为有害的做法，例如包含粗俗内容的户外直播、主持人之间的不当挑战游戏，以及引诱观众消费更多。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take action - 采取行动。    <p>原文例句：Douyin has also taken action against hosts promoting scams, gambling, and pornographic content, leading to the arrest of over 300 criminal suspects.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿）和action（行动）构成的，表示“采取行动”。在这个例句中，它指的是抖音对推销诈骗、赌博和色情内容的主播采取行动，导致300多名犯罪嫌疑人被逮捕。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>pay special attention to - 特别注意。    <p>原文例句：Douyin has introduced restrictions that prevent minors from hosting live sessions or tipping other hosts. It also has safeguards that intervene when its system determines an elderly user is falling prey to online scams on its app.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由pay（支付）和special attention to（特别注意）构成的，表示“特别注意”。在这个例句中，它指的是抖音采取限制措施，防止未成年人主持直播或给其他主播打赏。它还设置了保障措施，当系统确定老年用户在应用程序上成为网络诈骗的受害者时进行干预。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was worth US$98.2 billion in 2023.     <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Chinese regulators，谓语是have increasingly tightened their leash，宾语是the live-streaming sector。worth US$98.2 billion in 2023是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰the live-streaming sector，表示直播行业在2023年的价值为982亿美元。这个句子的意思是说，中国监管机构对直播行业越来越严格，该行业在2023年的价值为982亿美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气的用法 - 表示委婉的请求或建议，或者对事实的猜测。    <p>原文例句：Douyin has introduced restrictions that prevent minors from hosting live sessions or tipping other hosts.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是虚拟语气的用法，prevent是虚拟语气的一般现在时形式，表示“防止，阻止”。在这个例句中，它表示抖音采取限制措施，防止未成年人主持直播或给其他主播打赏。这种用法常用于委婉的请求或建议，或者对事实的猜测。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时的用法 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was worth US$98.2 billion in 2023.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是现在完成时的用法，have tightened是现在完成时的一般现在时形式，表示“已经收紧，已经加强”。在这个例句中，它表示中国监管机构对直播行业越来越  <ul><li>Some outdoor live streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions</li>
<li>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was worth US$98.2 billion in 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/9a28fd60-8832-4f14-b4c3-01657424e7b0_5660f465.jpg" /><figcaption>An advertisement for Douyin seen at a bus stop in China. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure><p>Douyin, the sibling app of ByteDance’s global short video hit TikTok, said it imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023 to rein in inappropriate practices.</p><p>The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts, including some top influencers, as the platform sought to weed out practices it deemed harmful, such as outdoor live-streaming containing vulgar content, improper challenge games among hosts, as well as enticing viewers to spend more money, the company said in a post published to its official WeChat account on Tuesday.</p><p>Some outdoor live-streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions, according to the post.</p><p>In a joint effort with local authorities in Changsha, the capital of central Hunan province, Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>The banned hosts had engaged in “harmful” outdoor live-streaming activities in Changsha, a major tourist spot which attracted live-streamers who wanted to broadcast its bustling nightlife.</p><p>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was forecast to have made 700 billion yuan (US$98.2 billion) in 2023, according to Statista.</p><p>Improper challenge games and enticed spending were also issues raised by the Cyberspace Administration of China over the past two years, as part of the top Chinese internet watchdog’s campaigns to root out malicious online content.</p><p>Douyin’s live-streaming clampdown also targeted live streamers who were promoting scams, gambling and pornographic content on the platform. Nearly two-thirds, or 190,000, of the hosts banned last year were involved in such activities.</p><p>Through efforts with the Chinese police, more than 300 criminal suspects have been arrested, Douyin said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3247755/watched-strangers-china-mother-live-streams-son-9-doing-homework-says-he-works-3-times-faster" title="">Chinese mother live-streams son, 9, doing homework so he is not distracted</a></h3><p>However, the crackdown is taking a toll on some hosts, who said they were incidentally banned as part of the measures. One host, based in the central province of Anhui, who requested anonymity for fear of retribution by the platform, told the South China Morning Post on Thursday that while she agreed with Douyin’s efforts, it was easy for some veteran hosts to get caught up, adding that losing access to accounts that took years to build up is a high cost.</p><p>Douyin did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Thursday.</p><p>The platform has also been improving the way it manages live streamers. Last September, it introduced a revamped host rating system to take into account multiple factors such as the severity of the alleged malpractice, and the hosts’ level of influence and popularity.</p><p>Meanwhile, verified hosts generating “good” content would be rewarded with support from Douyin to create a “healthy and positive” environment for live-streaming activities.</p><p>The rising trend of using artificial intelligence (AI)-powered virtual hosts has also caught Douyin’s attention. The short video app has put in place rules to require more transparency, with additional identity checks required for the individuals behind such virtual hosts.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1332" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0141f38e-3a8c-4a47-84ce-4ce5fdc448a3_3366798b.jpg" title="In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>More than 765 million Chinese internet users had tuned into live sessions across various online services as of last June, according to data from the China Internet Network Information Centre, representing around 70 per cent of the country’s total 1.079 billion netizens.</p><p>The widespread adoption of live-streaming services has included people of all ages, including minors and seniors, two groups which Douyin said it was paying special attention to.</p><p>Douyin has introduced restrictions that prevent minors from hosting live sessions or tipping other hosts. It also has safeguards that intervene when its system determines an elderly user is falling prey to online scams on its app.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Private-equity investors to return to China in search of M&amp;A deals in 2024, Bain &amp; Co says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248937/private-equity-investors-return-china-search-ma-deals-2024-bain-co-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  中国并购交易在连续三年下降后出现回暖迹象，因为全球咨询公司贝恩公司表示，全球和国内私募股权投资者预计将从经济复苏中获益。他们将专注于提高投资组合公司的盈利能力和收入，而不是潜在的虚高估值。尽管交易量下降，但中国大陆在2023年上半年仍占亚太地区交易量的41%。北京将在3月举行的全国人民代表大会上公布2024年国内生产总值、消费者通胀和财政赤字的年度增长目标。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese M&A market rebounds after three consecutive years of decline as investors look to benefit from economic recovery.</li>    <li>Theme: Private equity investors focus on improving profitability and revenue rather than frothy valuations.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Bain's statement is significant as China still accounted for a large share of Asia-Pacific M&A deals despite the drop in deal volumes.</li>    <li>Main information: Beijing's annual growth targets, incentives rolled out in 2023, supportive policies to spur the mainland economy, and the shift from fossil fuel-based economies to new energy and electric vehicles.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2> 中国并购交易在经历了连续三年的下滑之后，开始出现回暖的迹象，因为全球咨询公司贝恩公司表示，全球和国内的私募股权投资者预计将从中国的经济复苏中获益。私募股权投资者在做投资决策时，将专注于提高其投资组合公司的盈利能力和收入，而不是潜在的虚高估值。据标普全球市场情报的数据显示，尽管交易量有所下降，但中国大陆在2023年上半年仍占亚太地区交易量的41%。中国大陆在2023年公布了5156笔并购交易，总价值为3010亿美元，这已经是连续第三年出现下降，并创下了九年的新低。根据Preqin的数据，以美元计价的私募股权基金在去年上半年在中国投资了14亿美元，较前一年减少了约90%。资产管理公司黑石集团将在新加坡扩大私募股权业务。然而，瑞士银行本月预测，随着世界第二大经济体的复苏，中国上市公司的利润增长将在2024年从去年的3%跃升至8%。北京将在3月份举行的全国人民代表大会年度会议上公布2024年的国内生产总值、消费者通胀和财政赤字年度增长目标。此外，中国国家统计局局长康义在周三的新闻发布会上表示，北京去年推出的一些激励措施，如发行1万亿元（1390亿美元）特别国债的计划，将在2024年生效。他补充说，中央政府还将出台新的支持政策以刺激中国经济的发展。贝恩公司表示，大多数拥有大量闲置资金的投资者更青睐于大规模企业，而不是小型高增长企业，因为他们在瞬息万变的市场中追求稳定和可持续的回报。据标普全球和Preqin的数据显示，截至去年12月1日，全球私募股权闲置资金飙升至创纪录的2.59万亿美元，较2022年12月的2.39万亿美元总额增长8%。贝恩公司在周四发布的一份研究报告中表示，随着市盈率倍数的不断提高，收购基金主要受益于中国投资组合公司的估值提升，因为新一轮融资的投资者相信他们未来的增长潜力。贝恩表示，在2012年至2022年期间，估值提升为私募股权基金在中国获得的总回报贡献了55%；收入增加贡献了37%的总回报；而利润增长仅贡献了8%的回报。热衷于从以化石燃料为基础的经济转向的那些中东国家正在寻求中国入境并购交易的机会，特别是在新能源和电动汽车（EV）领域。10月份，沙特阿拉伯的智慧城市开发商Neom向中国自动驾驶技术初创企业小马智行投资了1亿美元，以帮助其研究和开发并资助其运营。12月18日，中国电动汽车制造商蔚来汽车宣布从阿布扎比政府支持的基金CYVN Holdings筹集了22亿美元。  <ul>    <li>摘要：经过连续三年的下滑之后，中国并购市场开始出现回暖迹象，因为投资者预计将从经济复苏中获益。</li>    <li>主题：私募股权投资者专注于提高盈利能力和收入，而不是虚高估值。</li>    <li>观点：贝恩公司的声明很重要，因为尽管交易量下降，但中国仍占亚太地区并购交易的很大份额。</li>    <li>主要信息：北京的年度增长目标、2023年出台的激励措施、刺激中国经济的支持政策以及从化石燃料经济向新能源和电动汽车的转变。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rebound (v.) - /rɪˈbaʊnd/ 反弹，回升，复苏，反击，回放，击球回弹，回音。    <p>原文例句：China M&A activity set for rebound but 2024 won’t be business as usual</p>    <p>例句讲解：“rebound”在这里表示“回升、反弹”，指中国并购活动在经历了连续三年的下降之后，开始出现回暖的迹象。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>spur (v.) - /spɜːr/ 刺激，推动，加速，促进，鞭策，激发。    <p>原文例句：The central government will also prepare new supportive policies to spur the mainland’s economy, he added.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“spur”在这里表示“刺激、推动”，指中国政府将出台新的支持政策以刺激中国经济的发展。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>private-equity fund - 私募股权基金    <p>原文例句：Private-equity investors will focus on improving profitability and bolstering revenue from their portfolio firms,</p>    <p>例句讲解：“private-equity fund”在这里表示“私募股权基金”，指由私募股权投资公司管理的、向非公众投资者募集资金并投资于非上市企业的基金。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>new energy - 新能源    <p>原文例句：Middle Eastern countries that are eager to shift from fossil fuel-based economies are pursuing opportunities for China inbound M&A deals, particularly in the new energy and electric-vehicles (EV) sectors.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“new energy”在这里表示“新能源”，指除化石能源之外的其他可再生能源，如风能、太阳能、水能等。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Bain said in a research report released on Thursday that buyout funds mainly benefited from higher valuations of portfolio firms in China amid increasing price-to-earnings multiples, because investors in new rounds of financing were convinced of their future growth potential. - 贝恩公司在周四发布的一份研究报告中表示，随着市盈率倍数的不断提高，收购基金主要受益于中国投资组合公司的估值提升，因为新一轮融资的投资者相信他们未来的增长潜力。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Bain said，其中主语是Bain，谓语是said，宾语是a research report released on Thursday that buyout funds mainly benefited from higher valuations of portfolio firms in China amid increasing price-to-earnings multiples, because investors in new rounds of financing were convinced of their future growth potential。这是一个由多个并列短语和从句组成的复杂宾语。其中，a research report released on Thursday that buyout funds mainly benefited from higher valuations of portfolio firms in China amid increasing price-to-earnings multiples是一个现在分词短语，作主句的定语，表示贝恩公司在周四发布的一份研究报告中表示，收购基金主要受益于中国投资组合公司的估值提升，因为市盈率倍数的不断提高。because investors in new rounds of financing were convinced of their future growth potential是一个原因状语从句，作主句的状语，表示新一轮融资的投资者相信他们未来的增长潜力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Bain said in a research report released on Thursday that buyout funds mainly benefited from higher valuations of portfolio firms  <ul><li>It may take longer to conclude deals, ‘but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted’ in 2024, Bain executive says</li>
<li>Mainland China M&amp;A deals dropped to a nine-year low last year amid a third straight year of declines, Refinitiv data shows</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/3af570e6-afc9-4398-8253-c7bffe73cf71_6190bf99.jpg" /><figcaption>The Liuiazui financial hub in Shanghai. Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for GDP, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, at the National People’s Congress. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Global and domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3246654/china-ma-activity-set-rebound-2024-amid-renewed-overseas-interest-it-wont-be-business-usual-heres" target="_self" title="">private-equity investors</a> are making a comeback to the Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mergers-acquisitions" target="_self" title="">mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;A)</a> market following three straight years of decline, as they look to profit from an economic recovery, global consultancy Bain &amp; Co said.</p><p>Private-equity investors will focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247667/chinese-stocks-darkest-days-may-be-over-earnings-rebound-property-recovery-seen-lifting-gloom-2024" target="_self" title="">improving profitability and bolstering revenue</a> from their portfolio firms, rather than potential frothy valuations, when they are making investment decisions, said Zhou Hao, head of the firm’s Greater China private equity and M&amp;A practice.</p><p>“New talks on deal making [have] resurfaced since the second half of 2023,” he said. “It may take longer to conclude the deals, but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted this year.”</p><p>Bain’s statement is significant because, despite a drop in deal volumes, mainland China still accounted for 41 per cent of deals in the Asia-Pacific region in the first half of 2023, according to S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence.</p><p>Mainland China reported 5,156 M&amp;A deals in 2023, with a combined value of US$301 billion, according to Refinitiv data. This was a nine-year low and a third straight year of declines, in terms of deal volumes.</p><p>US dollar-denominated private-equity funds that have at least half their capital invested in China raised US$1.4 billion in the first half of last year, down about 90 per cent from a year earlier, according to Preqin data.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3248558/asset-manager-blackstone-expand-private-equity-headcount-singapore-southeast-asia-push" title="">Asset manager Blackstone to expand private-equity headcount in Singapore</a></h3><p>However, earlier this month, UBS forecast that profit growth for Chinese listed companies will jump to 8 per cent in 2024 from 3 per cent last year, buoyed by a recovery in the world’s second-largest economy.</p><p>Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for gross domestic product, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, when the annual session of the National People’s Congress is held.</p><p>Moreover, Kang Yi, head of China’s National Bureau of Statistics, said during a press conference on Wednesday that some incentives Beijing rolled out last year – such as the plan to issue 1 trillion yuan (US$139 billion) worth of special treasury bonds – will take effect in 2024. The central government will also prepare new supportive policies to spur the mainland’s economy, he added.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3246654/china-ma-activity-set-rebound-2024-amid-renewed-overseas-interest-it-wont-be-business-usual-heres" title="">China M&amp;A activity set for rebound but 2024 won’t be business as usual</a></h3><p>Most investors with massive amounts of dry powder prefer large-scale businesses to small, high-growth firms, as they chase stable and sustainable returns in a fast-changing market, Bain said.</p><p>Private-equity dry powder soared to an unprecedented US$2.59 trillion globally as of December 1 last year, an 8 per cent increase over December 2022’s total of US$2.39 trillion, data by S&amp;P Global and Preqin shows.</p><p>Bain said in a research report released on Thursday that buyout funds mainly benefited from higher valuations of portfolio firms in China amid increasing price-to-earnings multiples, because investors in new rounds of financing were convinced of their future growth potential.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3245604/global-ma-deal-makers-miss-us3-trillion-mark-first-time-10-years" title="">Global M&amp;A: deal makers to miss US$3 trillion mark for first time in 10 years</a></h3><p>Higher valuations contributed to 55 per cent of the total returns private-equity funds reaped in China from 2012 to 2022, Bain said. Revenue increases contributed to 37 per cent of total returns while only 8 per cent of the returns were derived from profit rises.</p><p>Middle Eastern countries that are eager to shift from fossil fuel-based economies are pursuing opportunities for China inbound M&amp;A deals, particularly in the new energy and electric-vehicles (EV) sectors.</p><p>In October, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3239304/chinese-self-driving-technology-start-ponyai-gets-us100-million-investment-saudi-arabias-smart-city" target="_self" title="">Saudi Arabian smart city developer Neom</a> invested US$100 million in Chinese autonomous driving technology start-up Pony.ai to help fund its research and development and finance its operations.</p><p>On December 18, Chinese EV maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3242863/chinese-ev-maker-nio-sees-ai-robots-replacing-30-cent-workforce-2027-improve-efficiency-cut-costs" target="_self" title="">Nio</a> announced it had raised US$2.2 billion from CYVN Holdings, a fund backed by the Abu Dhabi government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s lottery players bet on AI chatbots to give winning numbers, but none are millionaires yet</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248909/chinas-lottery-players-bet-ai-chatbots-give-winning-numbers-none-are-millionaires-yet</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  中国的社交媒体用户分享了他们使用生成式人工智能来选择彩票号码的经历。尽管人工智能聊天机器人生成的彩票号码尚未让人们成为百万富翁，但有些人赢得了小额奖金。专家表示，彩票是随机事件，无法通过任何预测模型来预测。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: People share experiences using generative AI to pick lottery numbers, but no one has become a millionaire yet.</li>    <li>Theme: Using generative AI to generate lottery numbers has become a trend.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Experts caution against taking the lottery too seriously and emphasize that it is a random event.</li>    <li>Main information: Gu Xiangnan's experience using Google’s Gemini-Pro to generate lottery numbers; other instances of people winning small sums using generative AI; the popularity of lotteries in China and globally; experts' advice to treat the lottery as a recreational activity.</li>  </ul></div>###<div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国的社交媒体用户分享了他们使用生成式人工智能来选择彩票号码的经历。尽管人工智能聊天机器人生成的彩票号码尚未让人们成为百万富翁，但有些人赢得了小额奖金。专家表示，彩票是随机事件，无法通过任何预测模型来预测。  <ul>    <li>摘要：人们分享了使用生成式人工智能来选择彩票号码的经历，但还没有人因此成为百万富翁。</li>    <li>主题：使用生成式人工智能来生成彩票号码已成为一种趋势。</li>    <li>观点：专家们告诫人们不要把彩票看得太认真，并强调彩票是一个随机事件。</li>    <li>主要信息：顾湘楠使用谷歌的Gemini-Pro生成彩票号码的经历；其他人使用生成式人工智能赢得小额奖金的案例；彩票在中国和全球的流行；专家建议将彩票视为一种娱乐活动。</li>  </ul></div>###<div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sophisticated (adj.) - /səʊˈfɪstɪkeɪtɪd/ 老练的，复杂的。    <p>原文例句：While sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers, it has not stopped people from using AI to try to boost their chances.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由sophus（聪明）和facere（做）构成的，表示“使聪明，变得复杂”。在这个例句中，它描述了先进的人工智能算法虽然在预测幸运数字方面与人类没有特别的优势，但并不能阻止人们使用人工智能来增加中奖几率。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>random (adj.) - /ˈrændəm/ 随机的，随意的。    <p>原文例句：Lotteries are designed to be random, meaning that picking the right numbers from millions of possible combinations depends entirely on luck. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，表示“任意地，不确定地”。在这个例句中，它描述了彩票是随机设计的，这意味着从数百万个可能的组合中选择正确的数字完全取决于运气。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>have a particular edge over - 在……方面具有特别的优势。    <p>原文例句：While sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers, it has not stopped people from using AI to try to boost their chances. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由have（有），a（一个），particular（特别的），edge（优势）和over（超过）组成，表示“在……方面具有特别的优势”。在这个例句中，它表示虽然先进的人工智能算法在预测幸运数字方面没有特别的优势，但并不能阻止人们使用人工智能来增加中奖几率。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Lotteries are designed to be random, meaning that picking the right numbers from millions of possible combinations depends entirely on luck. - 彩票是随机设计的，这意味着从数百万个可能的组合中选择正确的数字完全取决于运气。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Lotteries are designed to be random，其中主语是Lotteries，谓语是are designed to be，宾语是random。meaning that picking the right numbers from millions of possible combinations depends entirely on luck是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示彩票是随机设计的这一事实或原因，即从数百万个可能的组合中选择正确的数字完全取决于运气。这个句子的意思是说，彩票是随机设计的，这意味着从数百万个可能的组合中选择正确的数字完全取决于运气。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在发生或进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：People in other parts of the world have also been turning to generative AI for lottery number suggestions.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态正在发生或进行。在这个例句中，它表示世界其他地方的人们也一直在使用生成式人工智能来获取彩票号码建议。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：While sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers, it has not stopped people from using AI to try to boost their chances.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + been + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则变化形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间点之前已经完成。在这个例句中，它表示虽然先进的人工智能算法在预测幸运数字方面没有特别的优势，但并没有阻止人们使用人工智能来增加中奖几率，其中“没有阻止”这一动作发生在过去某个时间点之前。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Chinese social media users share their experiences using generative AI to pick lottery numbers</li>
<li>The country is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/ef431a3d-68c7-4027-852b-cc9d3567841e_0b6e9536.jpg" /><figcaption>A lottery shop in Beijing. Photo: SCMP/Simon Song</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT and its peers</a> are known for giving smart answers to a variety of questions, but some internet users in China recently found that lottery numbers generated by artificial intelligence (AI) chatbots have yet to turn them into millionaires.</p><p>In one post that went viral on the Instagram-like platform Xiaohongshu, user Gu Xiangnan from eastern Anhui province shared her experience buying lottery tickets using numbers generated by Google’s Gemini-Pro.</p><p>She first fed the chatbot with two years’ worth of historical data from Super Lotto, one of the most popular of its kind in China that asks players to select five numbers from a set of 35 balls and two bonus numbers from another set of 12 balls.</p><p>Among the five combinations picked by Gemini, two of them each contained two winning numbers, while another two each had one correct bonus number. Gu won no money.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Gu also said she previously spent 20 yuan (US$2.8) betting on Union Lotto, another popular lottery in China, using the same approach, winning 5 yuan in total.</p><p>“Although it was just for fun, there is something worth looking into,” she said.</p><p>Lotteries are designed to be random, meaning that picking the right numbers from millions of possible combinations depends entirely on luck. While sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers, it has not stopped people from using AI to try to boost their chances.</p><p>The Xiaohongshu post was liked by more than 5,000 users, with some commenting that they also won small sums using numbers suggested by generative AI. Gemini-Pro and OpenAI’s ChatGPT are officially unavailable in China, although they can be accessed using a virtual private network.</p><p>China, which logged annual lottery sales of around 600 billion yuan last year, is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets.</p><p>People in other parts of the world have also been turning to generative AI for lottery number suggestions.</p><p>In April, Thai man Patthawikorn Boonrin claimed on TikTok that he won 2,000 baht (US$56) using ChatGPT, according to digital media Mashable. A month later, Singaporean man Aaron Tan won a US$40 cash prize with ChatGPT-generated numbers, according to news portal Yahoo.</p><p>Also in May, Paris-based data scientist Rohith Teja bought a 2.5 euro (US$2.7) lottery ticket using random numbers given by ChatGPT, winning 6 euros. Another ticket that he purchased using numbers generated by ChatGPT through analysing historical data contained no winning numbers at all.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3243129/how-chinas-lottery-boom-reflects-long-and-challenging-road-its-economic-recovery" title="">How China’s lottery boom reflects a ‘long and challenging’ economic recovery</a></h3><p>“The lottery is a highly randomised event that cannot be predicted by any predictive model,” Teja concluded in his blog.</p><p>In the case of Gu, the Xiaohongshu user, Gemini explained to her that it tried to predict lottery results by picking recent lucky numbers that also won more frequently in the past.</p><p>While the chatbot said its selection “had a certain degree of randomness as well as a certain degree of regularity”, it advised against taking the lottery too seriously.</p><p>“Treat lottery as a recreational activity, not a way to invest or make money. Good luck,” it said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple chip supplier TSMC expects a return to ‘healthy growth’, backing hopes for global tech recovery in 2024</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248918/apple-chip-supplier-tsmc-expects-return-healthy-growth-backing-hopes-global-tech-recovery-2024</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), the world's largest contract chip manufacturer, expects a solid growth this quarter and plans to raise capital expenditure, indicating a recovery in demand for smartphones and computing. The company projected revenue growth of at least 8% to US$18.8 billion in the March quarter, exceeding expectations and suggesting a rebound from last year's modest decline.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: TSMC expects a return to growth this quarter and plans to increase capital expenditure.</li>    <li>Theme: The global chip-making sector shows signs of recovery after a years-long demand slump.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: TSMC's growth prospects are driven by increasing demand for AI chips and advanced packaging technology.</li>    <li>Main information: TSMC's revenue projection, capital expenditure plans, and analysts' opinions on the company's prospects.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  台积电，作为全球最大的芯片代工制造商，预计本季度将实现强劲增长，并计划增加资本支出，这表明对智能手机和计算的需求正在复苏。公司预计，3 月份当季收入增长至少 8%，达到 188 亿美元，超出了预期，并暗示着将从去年温和的下降中反弹。  <ul>    <li>摘要：台积电预计本季度将恢复增长，并计划增加资本支出。</li>    <li>主题：全球芯片制造业在经历了多年的需求低迷之后，出现了复苏的迹象。</li>    <li>观点：台积电的增长前景受到对人工智能芯片和先进封装技术需求增长的推动。</li>    <li>主要信息：台积电的收入预测、资本支出计划以及分析师对公司前景的看法。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>projected (v.) - /prəˈdʒɛkt/ 预计，预测。    <p>原文例句：Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co expects revenue to grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year. Image: Reuters</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由pro-（向前）和iacere（投掷）组成，意为“向前投掷，预期，预测”。在这个例句中，它表示台积电预计今年的收入将增长在20%至30%的范围内。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>slump (n.) - /slʌmp/ 经济衰退，暴跌。    <p>原文例句：The Taiwanese company’s outlook comes after a years-long slump in tech demand.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于挪威语，意为“滑落，暴跌”。在这个例句中，它表示台积电的前景是在科技需求多年低迷之后做出的。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>low- to mid-20 per cent range - 在20%至30%的范围内。    <P>原文例句：Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co expects revenue to grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year. Image: Reuters</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由low-（低）, mid-（中）, 20（二十）, per（每）, cent（百分比）, range（范围）等词构成，表示在20%至30%的范围内。在这个例句中，它表示台积电预计今年的收入将增长在20%至30%的范围内。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TSMC’s revenue should grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year, he said. That marks a rebound from the modest decline of last year. - 他说，台积电今年的收入应该会在20%到30%的范围内增长。这标志着去年适度下滑后的反弹。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是TSMC’s revenue should grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year，其中主语是TSMC’s revenue，谓语是should grow，宾语是in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year。That marks a rebound from the modest decline of last year是一个结果状语，表示台积电今年的收入增长标志着去年适度下滑后的反弹。这个句子的意思是说，台积电今年的收入应该会在20%到30%的范围内增长，这标志着去年适度下滑后的反弹。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动名词作主语 - 表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Posted a series of falls</p>    <p>语法讲解：动名词作主语时，一般放在句首，其后接be动词或其他系动词。动名词可以表示动作，也可以表示状态。在这个例句中，Posted是post的动名词，表示“公布，发布”。falls是fall的名词复数形式，表示“下降，跌落”。这个句子的意思是说，该公司公布了一系列下降。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TSMC moderated its capital expenditure plans as the consumer electronics industry grappled with a glut of unsold inventory.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态的结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，grappled是grapple的过去分词，表示“努力应对”。这个句子的意思是说，台积电调整了其资本支出计划，因为消费电子行业正在努力应对过多的未售库存。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>TSMC, the world’s largest contract chip manufacturer, projected revenue growth of at least 8 per cent to US$18.8 billion in the March quarter</li>
<li>The Taiwanese company’s outlook comes after a years-long slump in tech demand</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/1ba9ec97-57a0-404c-8f10-74bfd74536c6_76fe20b5.jpg" /><figcaption>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co expects revenue to grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year. Image: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc" target="_self" title="">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a> (TSMC) expects a return to solid growth this quarter and gave itself room to raise capital spending this year, suggesting the world’s most valuable chip maker anticipates a recovery in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> and computing demand.</p><p>The main <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> supplier to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/nvidia" target="_self" title="">Nvidia Corp</a> projected revenue growth of at least 8 per cent to US$18.8 billion in the March quarter, versus expectations for around US$18.2 billion. It is also budgeting capital expenditure of US$28 billion to US$32 billion, potentially up from US$30 billion in 2023.</p><p>The Taiwanese company’s outlook, while not quite surpassing the most bullish estimates, comes after a years-long slump in tech demand. But signs of a recovery for the chip-making sector have emerged in recent weeks. The Semiconductor Industry Association estimated chip sales increased in November after more than a year of declines.</p><p>TSMC chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3206603/apple-supplier-tsmc-worlds-biggest-contract-chip-maker-keep-spending-check-amid-weak-global" target="_self" title="">C C Wei</a> reiterated that he expects a return to “healthy growth” this year.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co logo seen atop a building at the Hsinchu Science Park in Hsinchu, Taiwan, on January 9, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1332" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/fa4428f2-8ef6-41b6-af8b-803745c49428_6c52fb99.jpg" title="The Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co logo seen atop a building at the Hsinchu Science Park in Hsinchu, Taiwan, on January 9, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co logo seen atop a building at the Hsinchu Science Park in Hsinchu, Taiwan, on January 9, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>TSMC, which also counts Android chip design firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/qualcomm" target="_self" title="">Qualcomm</a> among its biggest customers, got a boost from frenzied demand for Nvidia’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) processors in 2023.</p><p>It reported net income for the fourth quarter of NT$238.7 billion (US$7.6 billion), beating the average analyst estimate. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247936/tsmc-halts-revenue-drop-beats-expectations-brisk-demand-ai-chips-nvidia-advanced-micro-devices" target="_self" title="">Revenue was US$625.5 billion</a>, TSMC reported earlier, matching the previous holiday quarter and arresting a series of falls.</p><p>“Our business has bottomed out on a year-over-year basis, and we expect 2024 to be a healthy growth year for TSMC,” Wei said.</p><p>TSMC’s revenue should grow in the low- to mid-20 per cent range this year, he said. That marks a rebound from the modest decline of last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247936/tsmc-halts-revenue-drop-beats-expectations-brisk-demand-ai-chips-nvidia-advanced-micro-devices" title="">Chip-making giant TSMC halts revenue drop on brisk AI demand</a></h3><p>“TSMC could lead global chip foundries through 2023-24 industry headwinds, thanks to growing AI chip demand and migration to next-gen process nodes such as N3 in second half of 2023 and N2 by 2025,” Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Charles Shum said in a research note.</p><p>“Although the smartphone and PC chip market remains stagnant, TSMC’s advanced packaging tech, both 2.5D and 3D, fortifies its position in the contract-chip making market, allowing a potential return to a 53 per cent gross margin following a brief second-half downturn.”</p><p>Over the course of 2023, TSMC moderated its capital expenditure plans as the consumer electronics industry grappled with a glut of unsold inventory.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246852/competitive-pay-tsmc-plant-may-ripple-across-japan-beat-inflation" title="">Competitive pay at TSMC plant may ripple across Japan, beat inflation</a></h3><p>But uncertainty persists. This month, fellow contract semiconductor maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> posted its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" target="_self" title="">sixth successive quarter of declining operating profit</a>, as it weathered the impact of muted consumer demand in its own smartphone and memory chip businesses.</p><p>Questions also overshadow mainland China, the world’s largest computing, smartphone, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> and semiconductor market.</p><p>Apple – long one of TSMC’s most important customers – faced headwinds with its latest generation of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhones</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" target="_self" title="">Several analysts downgraded Apple</a> on expectations of soft demand, and Jefferies has said the iPhone sales slump in China is likely to deepen. The US company has also been hit by a widening <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3233603/china-orders-government-workers-stop-using-iphones-amid-heightened-tensions-us" target="_self" title="">ban on foreign-device use among Chinese government agencies</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/state-owned-enterprises" target="_self" title="">state-owned enterprises</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong’s green tech hub goal: nurture start-ups, identify advantages and create talent pool, fintech body says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3248875/hong-kongs-green-tech-hub-goal-nurture-start-ups-identify-advantages-and-create-talent-pool-fintech</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong is aiming to become a major hub for green technology and finance.</li>    <li>The key to success is collaboration between the government and private sector to support start-ups, attract and develop talent, and foster a risk-taking mentality.</li>    <li>Hong Kong can leverage China's strength in electric vehicles, renewable energy, and hydrogen to its advantage.</li>    <li>Financial assistance from the government and attracting global talent are important aspects of the city's green tech and finance goals.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>香港的目标是成为绿色科技和金融的主要中心。</li>    <li>成功的关键是政府和私营部门合作，支持初创企业，吸引和培养人才，并培养风险承担的心态。</li>    <li>香港可以利用中国在电动汽车、可再生能源和氢能等领域的优势。</li>    <li>政府的财政援助和吸引全球人才对于香港的绿色科技和金融目标而言都是重要的因素。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>non-profit (adj.) - 非盈利的。    <p>原文例句：The Hong Kong government has stated its ambition to become a leading green tech and green finance hub. Photo: ShutterstockHong Kong’s aim of becoming a green technology and finance centre can become a reality if efforts are concentrated on supporting start-ups and leveraging China’s expertise in crucial technologies, according to the FinTech Association of Hong Kong.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“non-profit”一词意为“非盈利的”，指不以盈利为目的的组织或机构。在这个句中，“non-profit”修饰“FinTech Association of Hong Kong”，表明该协会是非盈利的。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>collaborate (v.) - 协作，合作。    <p>原文例句：The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset, said Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“collaborate”一词意为“协作，合作”，指两个人或多个团体共同努力实现共同目标。在这个句中，“collaborate”指政府和私营部门应加强合作，以支持绿色初创企业、吸引和培养人才，并培养风险承担的心态。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>leverage (v.) - 利用，发挥作用。    <p>原文例句：“Various cities are trying to promote themselves as green tech centres” said Sethi, who is also an independent consultant and a former executive at Deutsche Bank. “We feel it is important for Hong Kong to put that flag up and say we are the leading green tech centre. We need to identify sub-sectors where we feel Hong Kong has certain advantages.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：“leverage”一词意为“利用，发挥作用”，指利用某些有利条件或资源来获得优势或实现目标。在这个句中，“leverage”指香港应利用中国在电动汽车、可再生能源和氢能等领域的优势，来发展自己的绿色科技和金融中心。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>green technology - 绿色技术。    <p>原文例句：The Hong Kong government has stated its ambition to become a leading green tech and green finance hub. Photo: ShutterstockHong Kong’s aim of becoming a green technology and finance centre can become a reality if efforts are concentrated on supporting start-ups and leveraging China’s expertise in crucial technologies, according to the FinTech Association of Hong Kong.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“green technology”一词意为“绿色技术”，指利用可再生能源或低碳排放技术来保护环境的技术。在这个句中，“green technology”指香港的目标是成为绿色技术和绿色金融的主要中心。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>risk-taking mindset - 风险承担的心态。    <p>原文例句：The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset, said Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“risk-taking mindset”一词意为“风险承担的心态”，指愿意承担风险以实现目标的心态。在这个句中，“risk-taking mindset”指政府和私营部门应培养风险承担的心态，以支持绿色初创企业、吸引和培养人才。</p></li></ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset, said Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是“The government and the private sector should step up collaboration”，其中主语是“The government and the private sector”，谓语是“should step up collaboration”，宾语是“to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset”。其他部分都是非限制性定语从句，分别修饰“The government and the private sector”和“collaboration”。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>非限制性定语从句 - 用于提供额外信息，但不影响句子主干含义的从句。    <p>原文例句：The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset, said Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句中，“said Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee”是一个非限制性定语从句，它提供了关于Sandeep Sethi的信息，但不影响句子主干含义。这个从句可以用逗号与主句分隔开来，也可以用破折号与主句分隔开来。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Public-private collaboration to fund start-ups, attracting and nurturing talent can help city achieve green tech, finance hub goal: FinTech Association of Hong Kong</li>
<li>City must leverage China’s dominance in fields such as electric vehicles and renewable energy to its advantage, non-profit’s Sandeep Sethi says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/a4b626bb-229f-49f8-979e-4aaf7649c6cd_f97275b3.jpg" /><figcaption>The Hong Kong government has stated its ambition to become a leading green tech and green finance hub. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>Hong Kong’s aim of becoming a green technology and finance centre can become a reality if efforts are concentrated on supporting start-ups and leveraging China’s expertise in crucial technologies, according to the FinTech Association of Hong Kong.</p><p>The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset, said Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee.</p><p>“Various cities are trying to promote themselves as green tech centres” said Sethi, who is also an independent consultant and a former executive at Deutsche Bank. “We feel it is important for Hong Kong to put that flag up and say we are the leading green tech centre. We need to identify sub-sectors where we feel Hong Kong has certain advantages.”</p><p>Given China’s leadership position in electric vehicles, renewable energy and hydrogen, these sectors can be initial targets for collaborations, he added.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/90970213-f607-4ca0-9991-68a291db888d_798e21ed.jpg" title="FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung" width="2000" /><figcaption>FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung</figcaption></figure></div><p>Hong Kong’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3211122/budget-2023-hong-kong-launches-initiatives-become-global-green-innovation-finance-centre" target="_self" title="">ambition</a> to become an international centre for both green tech and green finance was highlighted by Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po in his budget speech last February. Previously, the focus was on building the city into a leading green and sustainable finance hub in Asia.</p><p>The government followed up its intention by setting up a green technology and finance development committee, comprising leaders from the finance, technology, academic and professional services sectors in June.</p><p>Next month, the government is hosting the Hong Kong GreenTech Week, which aims to bring together green tech businesses and investors from around the world, according to co-organiser Green Development Institute.</p><p>On a more basic level, Hong Kong can do better by providing early-stage funding for start-ups involved in areas such as low-carbon energy products, greenhouse gas emissions and tools for collecting and analysing data on physical climate risks, said Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/78343ebc-5f85-4434-9186-b91134e46289_798e21ed.jpg" title="Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung" width="2000" /><figcaption>Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Some green tech start-ups that have done well after getting seed funding of HK$10 million (US$1.3 million) to HK$20 million have struggled to raise additional financing to fund expansion,” said Barford, who is also the Hong Kong financial services consulting data and analytics lead at consultancy EY.</p><p>The government should consider expanding its financial assistance programmes, which would encourage family offices and institutional investors to take part in fundraising by start-ups, he added.</p><p>Towards that end the Hong Kong government is providing assistance. The different research and development funding schemes overseen by the Innovation and Technology Commission had provided total funding of some HK$400 million to about 130 green tech R&amp;D projects as of last June, according to the Environment and Ecology Bureau.</p><p>The bureau also administers a HK$400 million Green Tech Fund that supports R&amp;D projects in net-zero electricity generation, energy savings, green buildings, green transport and waste reduction. Some 30 projects have received HK$132.5 million since the fund was set up in 2020.</p><p>The government’s Hong Kong Science and Technology Parks Corporation and Cyberport have also set up separate funds to co-invest with angel investors and venture capital funds in start-ups at their respective industry parks.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3244092/hong-kong-regains-appeal-among-global-financial-talent-opportunities-open-fintech-esg-and-markets" title="">Hong Kong regains appeal among global talent amid demand in fintech, ESG</a></h3><p>“There is a gap between the intention and the actual projects that get financed,” said Sethi. “A lot of these are new technology projects where it is hard to prove the business case and profitability. This is where public-private collaborative funding can help.”</p><p>Other difficulties facing the government and industries include growing the talent pool, Sethi said.</p><p>Some 80 per cent of senior finance executives in the city, surveyed late last year by the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, said recruiting green and sustainable finance professionals was more difficult compared with other job functions. Talent retention and acquisition was the second most pressing issue after disclosure regulations.</p><p>Fostering a risk-taking mindset is another challenge, according to Sethi.</p><p>“In a lot of Asian countries, the education systems are focused on preparing students to get stable jobs, but in tech we need entrepreneurs who are willing to take risks,” he said. “It takes years and perhaps generations to change the mindset.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s Vision Pro headset will be missing a Netflix app at launch in February</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248870/apples-vision-pro-headset-will-be-missing-netflix-app-launch-february</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Netflix 公司决定不为 Apple 的 Vision Pro 头显推出专门的应用程序，而是让用户通过网络浏览器观看其内容。这种做法意味着 Vision Pro 用户将无法下载 Netflix 内容以供离线观看。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Netflix 不为 Apple Vision Pro 头显发布应用，用户可通过网络浏览器观看。</li>    <li>Theme: Netflix 与 Apple 在流媒体行业竞争，Netflix 不愿为竞争对手提供关键应用程序。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Netflix 不愿帮助竞争对手 Apple 提升其流媒体服务。</li>    <li>Main information: Netflix 已为 Apple 的其他设备提供应用程序，但它不参与 Apple 的 TV 应用程序；Netflix 不愿为 Vision Pro 开发专门的应用程序，用户只能通过网络浏览器观看其内容；Apple 试图通过使其易于将开发者的当前 iPad 应用程序转移到新平台来快速积累广泛的 Vision Pro 软件；Netflix 认为 Vision Pro 尚未准备就绪，希望采取观望态度。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Netflix公司决定不为苹果即将推出的Vision Pro头显开发专门的应用，而是让用户通过网络浏览器观看其内容。这种做法意味着Vision Pro用户将无法下载Netflix内容以供离线观看。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Netflix不为Apple Vision Pro头显推出应用，用户可通过网络浏览器观看。</li>    <li>主题：Netflix与Apple在流媒体行业竞争，Netflix不愿为竞争对手提供关键应用程序。</li>    <li>观点：Netflix不愿帮助竞争对手Apple提升其流媒体服务。</li>    <li>主要信息：Netflix已为Apple的其他设备提供应用程序，但它不参与Apple的TV应用程序；Netflix不愿为Vision Pro开发专门的应用程序，用户只能通过网络浏览器观看其内容；Apple试图通过使其易于将开发者的当前iPad应用程序转移到新平台来快速积累广泛的Vision Pro软件；Netflix认为Vision Pro尚未准备就绪，希望采取观望态度。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>snub (v.) - /snʌb/ 傲慢地对待，冷落，轻视。    <p>原文例句：Netflix is not planning to launch an app for Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset, marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world’s biggest video subscription service.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，由snēapian（快地咬）和snobbē（指责）构成，意为“轻视，冷落”。在这个例句中，它描述了Netflix决定不为Apple的Vision Pro头显推出应用程序，这是对这项新技术的傲慢对待。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>debut (n.) - /ˈdeɪbjuː/ 首次亮相，处女作。    <p>原文例句：The US$3,499 headset debuts on February 2.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于French，由débuter（首次出现）构成，意为“首次出现，首次亮相”。在这个例句中，它指的是Vision Pro头显将于2月2日首次亮相。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>mark a - 标志着，代表着。    <P>原文例句：Netflix is not planning to launch an app for Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset, marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world’s biggest video subscription service. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由mark（标记）和a（一个）构成的，表示“标志着，代表着”。在这个例句中，它表示Netflix决定不为Apple的Vision Pro头显推出应用程序，标志着世界最大的视频订阅服务对这项新技术的傲慢对待。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple is banking on entertainment content to help market the nascent and pricey technology, and Netflix is a must-have streaming service for many consumers. - Apple 依靠娱乐内容来帮助营销这项新兴且昂贵的技术，而 Netflix 是许多消费者必备的流媒体服务。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Apple is banking on entertainment content to help market the nascent and pricey technology，其中主语是Apple，谓语是is banking on，宾语是entertainment content。and Netflix is a must-have streaming service for many consumers是一个并列句，其中主语是Netflix，谓语是is a must-have，宾语是streaming service for many consumers。这个句子的意思是说，Apple依靠娱乐内容来帮助营销这项新兴且昂贵的技术，而Netflix是许多消费者必备的流媒体服务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句： has not been updated in years. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示Netflix的Meta Platforms的Quest 头显的应用程序多年来一直没有更新。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达说话者对某事的猜测、希望或建议。    <p>原文例句：The approach means it will be harder for users to access Netflix on the Vision Pro. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种语气，用于表达说话者对某事的猜测、希望或建议。结构是：should/could/would/might/may + 动词原形。在这个例句中，approach means it will be harder for users to access Netflix on the Vision Pro是一个陈述句，陈述了这种方法意味着用户更难在Vision Pro上访问Netflix的事实。虚拟语气用于表达这种方法可能导致的后果，即用户可能更难在Vision Pro上访问Netflix。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Rather than designing a Vision Pro app or supporting its existing iPad app on the platform, Netflix says users can watch its content on a web browser</li>
<li>The approach means Vision Pro users will not be able to download Netflix content to watch offline on an aeroplane</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0daed4bb-8aac-444e-9863-2f6975c1c780_21ab5745.jpg" /><figcaption>The Apple Vision Pro headset seen at an unveiling event in Cupertino, California last June. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netflix" target="_self" title="">Netflix</a> is not planning to launch an app for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3223224/apples-vision-pro-best-ar-and-vr-mixed-reality-headset-market-and-represents-future-computing-even" target="_self" title="">Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset</a>, marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world’s biggest video subscription service.</p><p>Rather than designing a Vision Pro app – or even just supporting its existing iPad app on the platform – Netflix is essentially taking a pass. The company, which competes with Apple in streaming, said in a statement that users interested in watching its content on the device can do so from the web.</p><p>It is a sizeable omission for the US$3,499 headset, which debuts on February 2. Apple is banking on entertainment content to help market the nascent and pricey technology, and Netflix is a must-have streaming service for many consumers.</p><p>Netflix also offers apps for Apple’s other devices, including the iPhone and iPad, though it does not participate in the company’s TV app.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1329" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/27470cf7-0ad7-471c-936b-45ab61159d8c_ce1fbea2.jpg" title="The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Vision Pro will run two main types of apps: new software written specifically for the device’s interface or existing iPad applications. Apple has sought to make it easy to transfer developers’ current iPad apps over to the new platform, aiming to quickly amass a wide range of Vision Pro software.</p><p>The fact that Netflix is not even willing to support the iPad approach suggests that it is taking a wait-and-see stance with the headset. It is also a bit of a reversal for the company, which said in July that it would support its iPad app on the Vision Pro. Even then, though, Netflix did not plan to release software specifically for the headset’s operating system, visionOS.</p><p>“Our members will be able to enjoy Netflix on the web browser on the Vision Pro, similar to how our members can enjoy Netflix on Macs,” Los Gatos, California-based Netflix said in the statement. Apple declined to comment.</p><p>In contrast with its Vision Pro strategy, Netflix did develop an app for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236053/meta-launches-quest-3-vr-and-ar-headset-just-ahead-apples-vision-pro" target="_self" title="">Meta Platforms’ Quest headsets</a>, though it has not been updated in years.</p><p>The approach means it will be harder for users to access Netflix on the Vision Pro. And they will not be able to download Netflix content to watch offline, potentially making it more of a pain to use on an aeroplane.</p><p>The lack of an app also means Netflix watchers will not have access to custom environments for streaming. That means Netflix cannot create specialised immersive backdrops for its users to watch videos in.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="998" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/946981d0-f40f-4bc7-b1f9-bd435067d043_6ca422b1.jpg" title="An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>While Netflix and Apple do not compete in TV hardware, they are both currently vying for subscribers in the streaming industry.</p><p>Apple is a small player in this category, with less than 10 per cent of the US market. But it has been gathering award wins in the space, and the two companies compete over talent and production deals. It is plausible Netflix does not want to help boost a rival by giving it a key app for its upcoming launch.</p><p>Apple has been marketing the Vision Pro as an entertainment device in the run-up to pre-orders beginning on Friday.</p><p>The Cupertino, California-based company said earlier this week that the headset would have many entertainment options beyond its own TV+ service. That includes programming from Disney+, Max, Peacock, ESPN and Amazon Prime Video, among others.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung Galaxy S24 series smartphones come with Google Gemini AI technology to fight Apple iPhones</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248863/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-smartphones-come-google-gemini-ai-technology-fight-apple-iphones</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung unveils its new Galaxy S24 series smartphones, featuring advanced AI tools based on Google's Gemini technology.</li>    <li>Key AI features include live phone call translation, voice recording transcription, web article summarization, handwriting correction, and generative AI.</li>    <li>Samsung aims to regain market share from Apple by releasing the new phones several months ahead of the next iPhones and introducing innovative AI capabilities.</li>    <li>The devices also boast slimmer bezels, brighter displays, and improved camera systems, catering to various user preferences.</li>    <li>Samsung and Google collaborate on the AI features, with Google providing exclusive generative AI services for Samsung's phones.</li>    <li>The new Galaxy S24 series phones will be available for pre-order starting Wednesday, January 25, and will go on sale on January 31.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>三星发布新款 Galaxy S24 系列智能手机，搭载基于谷歌双子座技术的先进 AI 工具。</li>    <li>主要 AI 功能包括实时电话翻译、语音录音转录、网页文章摘要、手写校正和生成式 AI。</li>    <li>三星旨在通过在下一代 iPhone 发布前几个月发布新款手机并引入创新的 AI 功能来从苹果手中夺回市场份额。</li>    <li>这些设备还具有更窄的边框、更亮的显示屏和改进的相机系统，以满足各种用户偏好。</li>    <li>三星和谷歌在 AI 功能上展开合作，谷歌为三星手机提供独家生成式 AI 服务。</li>    <li>新款 Galaxy S24 系列手机将于 1 月 25 日星期三开始预订，并于 1 月 31 日正式发售。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revamp (v.) - /rɪˈvæmp/ 改造，翻新。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由re-（重新）和vamp（焕发活力）构成的，意思是“重新装修，翻新，使恢复活力”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星电子正在转向人工智能 (AI) 功能来改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>slimmer (adj.) - /ˈslɪmər/ 更纤细的。    <p>原文例句：The devices are also getting slimmer bezels and brighter displays.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由slim（纤细的）构成的，意思是“更纤细的，更苗条的，更窄的”。在这个例句中，它指的是这些设备还具有更窄的边框和更亮的显示屏。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>predecessor (n.) - /prɪˈdɛsəsər/ 前身，前任。    <p>原文例句：The S24 and S24+ come in aluminium and get slightly larger screens than their predecessors.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由pre-（之前的）和decessor（前任）构成的，意思是“前身，前任”。在这个例句中，它指的是S24 和 S24+ 采用铝金属材质，并且屏幕比其前身略大。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>artificial intelligence (AI) - 人工智能。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由artificial（人造的）和intelligence（智能）构成的，意思是“人工智能”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星电子正在转向人工智能 (AI) 功能来改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>top-end model - 顶级型号。    <p>原文例句：Samsung is paying special attention to its top-end model, the S24 Ultra.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由top（最高，最上等）和end（末端）构成的，意思是“最高端的，最顶级的”。在这个例句中，它指的是三星特别关注其顶级型号，即 S24 Ultra。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung Electronics is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones. - 三星电子正转向人工智能 (AI) 功能来改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机。    <p>句子分析：这是一个主动句，主语是Samsung Electronics，谓语是is turning to，宾语是artificial intelligence (AI) features。to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示“为了改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机”。这个句子的意思是说，三星电子正转向人工智能 (AI) 功能来改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The devices can live-translate phone calls, transcribe voice recordings, summarise web articles, fix handwriting and use generative AI to fill in parts of photos. - 这些设备可以实时翻译电话，转录语音录音，总结网页文章，修复手写内容，并使用生成式 AI 来填充照片的各个部分。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The devices can，其中主语是The devices，谓语是can。live-translate phone calls, transcribe voice recordings, summarise web articles, fix handwriting and use generative AI to fill in parts of photos是一个并列结构作谓语，表示这些设备可以执行多种操作，包括实时翻译电话，转录语音录音，总结网页文章，修复手写内容，以及使用生成式 AI 来填充照片的各个部分。这个句子的意思是说，这些设备可以实时翻译电话，转录语音录音，总结网页文章，修复手写内容，并使用生成式 AI 来填充照片的各个部分。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示现在正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在进行时的句子，表示三星电子正在进行的动作或状态。结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be是is，表示现在时态，现在分词是turning，表示正在进行的动作。这个句子的意思是说，三星电子正转向人工智能 (AI) 功能来改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>不定式短语 - 作目的状语。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个不定式短语，结构是：to + 动词原形。在这个例句中，不定式短语是to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones，作目的状语，表示“为了改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机”。这个句子的意思是说，三星电子正转向人工智能 (AI) 功能来改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra can live-translate phone calls, transcribe voice recordings, summarise web articles and fix handwriting</li>
<li>Apple is not expected to showcase its latest plans for artificial intelligence until June, ahead of new iPhones arriving around September</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0bde60ec-206d-4f06-b93f-8cfac56d664e_ad59a457.jpg" /><figcaption>An influencer poses with Samsung’s new phones at the Galaxy Unpacked event in San Jose, California. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones, betting that the technology can give it an advantage over Apple’s iPhone.</p><p>At its Unpacked conference Wednesday in San Jose, California, Samsung unveiled the Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra phones, which all add AI tools based on the Gemini technology from Alphabet’s Google.</p><p>The devices can live-translate phone calls, transcribe voice recordings, summarise web articles, fix handwriting and use generative AI to fill in parts of photos.</p><p>The launch is one of the most ambitious attempts to weave AI into a smartphone’s interface and features. The new devices also provide Google with a chance to put its most advanced software in the hands of more users, a potential edge in its fight for AI dominance with Microsoft and start-up OpenAI.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="From left to right, Samsung’s Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra smartphones. Photo: AP Photo" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/4ab7c02b-e978-4125-8c59-49f05c81b629_1126e908.jpg" title="From left to right, Samsung’s Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra smartphones. Photo: AP Photo" width="2000" /><figcaption>From left to right, Samsung’s Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra smartphones. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure></div><p>The AI features are the highlight of the new phones, but the devices are also getting slimmer bezels and brighter displays. Samsung is paying special attention to its top-end model, the S24 Ultra. That product, which starts at US$1,299, will have a new titanium frame, matching the iPhone 15 Pro models released in September.</p><p>The borders around the displays are 42 per cent thinner, and the screen is 40 per cent brighter than the phone’s predecessor. It also sports flatter edges and a front-facing camera cut-out that is 11 per cent smaller.</p><p>The US$799 S24 and US$999 S24+ come in aluminium and get slightly larger screens than their predecessors, moving from 6.1-inch and 6.6-inch panels to 6.2-inch and 6.7-inch displays, respectively. The S24 Ultra, like the S23 Ultra, has a 6.8-inch screen.</p><p>Qualcomm is providing the main chip of the new Samsung phones in at least some regions. The S24 line-up will be based on its Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 applications processor, the company said in a separate statement. That component offers the latest Wi-fi capabilities and will handle AI-assisted features such as live translation and transcription, Qualcomm said.</p><p>The new models come at a crucial time for Samsung, which is contending with market share losses and a broader smartphone slump. Last year, it lost its crown as the No 1 smartphone supplier to Apple, marking the first time Samsung has not led the market since 2010.</p><p>Samsung’s phone shipments declined nearly 14 per cent to 226.6 million units in 2023, according to research firm IDC. Apple, on the other hand, saw unit shipments increase 3.7 per cent to 234.6 million.</p><p>Samsung looks to reverse its fortunes by getting a several-month head start on AI. Apple is not expected to showcase its latest plans for artificial intelligence until June, ahead of new iPhones arriving around September. The new Galaxy phones come out on January 31, with pre-orders starting Wednesday.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Interpreter application on a Samsung S24 Ultra smartphone. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/6f875bae-b575-4bd1-9cab-fc3b1f6d77c4_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="The Interpreter application on a Samsung S24 Ultra smartphone. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Interpreter application on a Samsung S24 Ultra smartphone. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Samsung decided to adopt the Gemini AI technology after surveying offerings from competitors, according to Thomas Kurian, head of Google’s cloud computing unit. As part of a multi-year agreement, Google will be the sole provider of generative AI for Samsung’s phones and applications, including features for taking notes and recording audio, according to Kurian.</p><p>“This is a validation of the quality of our models,” Kurian said. “They were free to choose whoever they wanted.”</p><p>Users will be able to switch between two options: one called Gemini Nano that runs on the phone itself and a higher-powered Pro version that uses cloud computing. That flexibility helped Google’s offerings stand out from the competition, Kurian said.</p><p>In conjunction with Samsung’s announcements, Google also introduced a feature called “Circle to Search,” which lets people search anything on their phone screens without switching apps.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/1452f636-7686-4413-86a3-f946ab0883d5_34f54c2a.jpg" title="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Users of Google’s Android operating system can scribble or circle on top of images, text or video in the app they are on – say, YouTube Shorts or TikTok – to find out more information about the item. The feature is launching globally on the new Galaxy S24, as well as on Google’s own Pixel 8 smartphones on January 31.</p><p>AI features on the Samsung devices will also let users change the language of a message depending on the context, such as whether it is a work memo or social media post. And new capabilities for Android Auto – Google’s in-car interface – will summarise incoming text messages and other alerts.</p><p>The companies are also applying AI to the phones’ camera systems, which are getting upgraded with new sensors, with tools to make photos sharper. The S24 Ultra replaces one of its 10-megapixel telephoto cameras with a 50-megapixel version. The S24 and S24+, meanwhile, include the same camera specifications as their predecessors.</p><p>The S24 Ultra comes with as much as 1 terabyte of storage, while the S24+ tops out at 512 gigabytes. The S24 has as much as 256GB of space. The S24+ and S24 Ultra include 12GB of memory, which is used for shorter-term storage of data, while the regular S24 has 8GB.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Google to let global Android users search for content within other apps</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248800/google-let-global-android-users-search-content-within-other-apps</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Google发布了名为Circle to Search的新功能，允许用户在不离开其他应用的情况下搜索内容，从而在Android智能手机和平板电脑上提高用户体验和参与度。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Google Circle to Search, a new feature that boosts user engagement and search experience on Android devices.</li>    <li>Theme: Google's strategy to enhance the search engine business and drive app developer engagement.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The integration of Circle to Search within various apps as a valuable innovation.</li>    <li>Main information: Circle to Search functionality, activation process, user applications, early testing results, and Google's financial performance.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  谷歌发布了一个名为Circle to Search的新功能，该功能允许用户在其他应用程序中搜索内容，而无需退出这些应用程序，从而提高了安卓智能手机和平板电脑上的用户体验和参与度。  <ul>    <li>摘要：谷歌Circle to Search，一项在安卓设备上提升用户参与度和搜索体验的新功能。</li>    <li>主题：谷歌提升搜索引擎业务和推动应用程序开发者参与度的策略。</li>    <li>观点：Circle to Search功能在各种应用程序中整合被视为一项有价值的创新。</li>    <li>主要信息：Circle to Search功能、激活过程、用户应用、早期测试结果以及谷歌财务业绩。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>function (n.) - /ˈfʌŋkʃən/ 功能，作用。    <p>原文例句：Google did not disclose when the function will be available on iPhones</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，意为“进行，履行”。它可以表示“功能，作用，职能”，也可以表示“函数，公式”。在这个例句中，它表示Google没有透露该功能何时将在iPhone上可用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>boost (v.) - /buːst/ 促进，推动。    <p>原文例句：a move aimed at boosting its search engine business and driving engagement for app developers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，意为“用棒或矛刺穿”。它可以表示“刺穿，穿透”，也可以表示“提升，鼓舞，推进”。在这个例句中，它表示一项旨在促进其搜索引擎业务和推动应用程序开发者参与度的举措。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>to be rolled out - 推出，实施。    <P>原文例句：The company's new Circle to Search feature, to be rolled out “gradually” from January 31 on some premium Android smartphones...</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由to be（是）和roll out（推出，实施）构成的，表示“推出，实施，展开”。在这个例句中，它表示该公司的Circle to Search新功能将从1月31日起在一些高级安卓智能手机上“逐步”推出。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Circle to Search功能允许用户在不离开应用程序的情况下快速访问信息。</li><p>句子分析：这是一句简单句，主语是Circle to Search功能，谓语是允许，宾语是用户。在不离开应用程序的情况下和快速访问信息分别是两个介词短语，分别作状语和宾语补语。这个句子的意思是说，Circle to Search功能允许用户在不离开应用程序的情况下快速访问信息。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去式 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Google did not disclose when the function will be available on iPhones.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是过去式的一种，表示过去发生的动作或状态。结构是：一般现在时态+ed。在这个例句中，did not disclose是过去式的否定形式，表示Google没有透露该功能何时将在iPhone上可用。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示现在正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company is still facing uncertainties in Hong Kong, where the government is seeking to have the US technology giant remove the protest song “Glory to Hong Kong”, which became popular during anti-government unrest in the city in 2019.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是现在进行时的一种，表示现在正在进行的动作或状态。结构是：be + 现在分词。在这个例句中，is seeking是现在进行时的否定形式，表示政府目前正在寻求让美国科技巨头移除抗议歌曲“光荣属于香港”，该歌曲在2019年香港的反政府示威活动中广受欢迎。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Circle to Search feature, available from January 31 on some premium Android smartphones, will enable quick access to information without having to leave the app</li>
<li>Google did not disclose when the new function will be available on iPhones</li>
</ul><p>Google will let global Android smartphone users search for content in other applications without having to exit them, a move aimed at boosting its search engine business and driving engagement for app developers.</p><p>The company's new Circle to Search feature, to be rolled out “gradually” from January 31 on some premium Android smartphones, will allow users to select text, images or videos in any other apps, and have Google search them within the apps, the US technology giant said on Thursday.</p><p>For example, users will be able to search for details on what a content creator is wearing in a video by circling or tapping on the items, after they activate the Circle to Search function by long-pressing their Android phone’s home button or navigation bar, the company said.</p><p>The feature will enable quick access to information without having to leave the app, potentially driving engagement for apps and the content displayed, it said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above" title="">Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with broad iPhone discounts</a></h3><p>Early testing showed that users “typically return to the app they’re using” after activating the feature, according to Google.</p><p>The company did not disclose when the function will be available on iPhones, with a representative telling the South China Morning Post that it “looks forward to bringing this powerful new capability to more people over time”.</p><p>Android handsets that will feature the new function will include Samsung Electronics’ new Galaxy S24 Series, it said.</p><p>Google parent Alphabet’s revenue in the three months ending September 30 rose 11 per cent from the same period a year before, which the company attributed to “meaningful growth” in search and YouTube, according to its earnings report published in October. Advertising revenue grew 9.5 per cent year on year to US$59.6 billion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Google will let global Android smartphone users search for content in other applications without having to exit them. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/8860e509-75b9-47e4-a0bc-02b333db06d9_e3f05cd0.jpg" title="Google will let global Android smartphone users search for content in other applications without having to exit them. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>Google will let global Android smartphone users search for content in other applications without having to exit them. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>The company is still facing uncertainties in Hong Kong, where the government is seeking to have the US technology giant remove the protest song “Glory to Hong Kong”, which became popular during anti-government unrest in the city in 2019.</p><p>Google has expressed unwillingness to ban the song from its search engine without a court order.</p><p>While a Hong Kong court <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3229252/hong-kong-court-dismisses-government-bid-ban-protest-song" target="_self" title="">blocked</a> the government’s injunction bid in July, a month later it allowed the city’s government to appeal the decision.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei sets up new smart car unit as it accelerates automotive ambitions in wake of earlier deal with Changan</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248785/huawei-sets-new-smart-car-unit-it-accelerates-automotive-ambitions-wake-earlier-deal-changan</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Huawei Technologies, a Chinese telecom equipment giant, has established a new smart car company called Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan. This move follows Huawei's signing of a memorandum of cooperation with Changan Automobile in November to establish a joint venture in the smart car sector. The new company will focus on smart car equipment manufacturing, AI system integration, and AI software development, among other areas. Huawei plans to transfer its smart-car system business to the new entity and integrate its core technologies into the new company. The venture aims to serve the industry better with Huawei's smart car solutions and is open to more industry partners joining to form a technology platform with diversified equity.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei establishes a new smart car company, Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's expansion into the smart car industry through a new company and a joint venture with Changan Automobile.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Huawei's strategic move to diversify its business and capitalize on the growing demand for smart vehicles.</li>    <li>Main information: Details of the new company's business scope, Huawei's plans to transfer its smart-car system business, and the potential involvement of other industry partners.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  中国电信设备巨头华为技术有限公司成立了一家名为“深圳市银王智能技术有限公司”的新智能汽车公司，注册资本为 10 亿元人民币。此举是在华为于 11 月与长安汽车签署合作备忘录，在智能汽车领域建立合资企业之后做出的。该公司将专注于智能汽车设备制造、人工智能 (AI) 系统集成和人工智能软件开发等领域。华为计划将其智能汽车系统业务转移到新实体，并将核心技术集成到新公司中。该合资企业旨在通过华为的智能汽车解决方案更好地服务行业，并向更多行业合作伙伴开放，共同打造一个股权多元化的技术平台。    <ul>    <li>摘要：华为成立新智能汽车公司深圳市银王智能技术有限公司。</li>    <li>主题：华为通过一家新公司和与长安汽车成立的合资企业向智能汽车行业扩张。</li>    <li>观点：华为多元化业务、利用智能汽车日益增长的市场需求的战略举措。</li>    <li>主要信息：新公司业务范围的详细信息、华为将其智能汽车系统业务转移的计划以及其他行业合作伙伴潜在的参与。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>diversified (adj.) - /daɪˈvɜːrsɪfaɪd/ 多元化的，多样化的。    <p>原文例句：While Huawei currently holds 100 per cent of the new firm, it is open to more industry partners joining to become a technology platform with diversified equity, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Securities Times.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由diversify（多样化）构成的，表示“多样化的，多元化的，具有不同来源或种类的”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为的新公司是一个多元化的技术平台，具有多种来源或种类的股权。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>equity (n.) - /ˈekwɪti/ 股权，权益。    <p>原文例句：While Huawei currently holds 100 per cent of the new firm, it is open to more industry partners joining to become a technology platform with diversified equity, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Securities Times.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于法语équité，表示“股权，权益，公正，公平”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为的新公司是一个多元化的技术平台，具有多种来源或种类的股权。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take an equity stake in - 持有股权，入股。    <P>原文例句：Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group and chairman of its Intelligent Automotive Solution business unit, called on Chinese carmakers Seres Group, Chery Automobile, JAC Motors and BAIC Motor to take an equity stake in the Huawei-Changan JV.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，持有），equity（股权，权益）和stake（股权，权益）构成的，表示“持有股权，入股”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为的余承东呼吁中国汽车制造商赛力斯集团、奇瑞汽车、江淮汽车和北汽汽车入股华为-长安合资企业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei Technologies has set up a new smart car company as the US-sanctioned telecoms equipment giant steps up its ambitions in the automobile industry. - 华为技术有限公司成立了一家新的智能汽车公司，因为这家受到美国制裁的电信设备巨头正在加紧在汽车行业的野心。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huawei Technologies has set up a new smart car company，其中主语是Huawei Technologies，谓语是has set up，宾语是a new smart car company。as the US-sanctioned telecoms equipment giant steps up its ambitions in the automobile industry是一个时间状语从句，表示华为成立新智能汽车的时间或原因，即因为这家受到美国制裁的电信设备巨头正在加紧在汽车行业的野心。这个句子的意思是说，华为技术有限公司成立了一家新的智能汽车公司，因为这家受到美国制裁的电信设备巨头正在加紧在汽车行业的野心。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 表示动作、状态或方式。    <p>原文例句：While Huawei currently holds 100 per cent of the new firm, it is open to more industry partners joining to become a technology platform with diversified equity, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Securities Times.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在分词短语，由现在分词holding和介词of组成的，表示动作、状态或方式。在这个例句中，它表示华为目前持有新公司的全部股权。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>非谓语动词作主语 - 表示动词或动作的状态。    <p>原文例句：Signing a memorandum of cooperation in November with Changan Automobile, a major state-owned carmaker based in Chongqing, southwestern Sichuan province, to start a new smart car JV was one of Huawei’s recent moves.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个非谓语动词短语作主语，由现在分词signing和介词of组成的，表示动词或动作的状态。在这个例句中，it表示华为近期动作之一是在11月与重庆西南四川省国有汽车制造商长安汽车签署了合作备忘录，启动新的智能汽车合资企业。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The new company, named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, has a registered capital of 1 billion yuan</li>
<li>Development comes after Huawei signed a memorandum of cooperation in November with Changan Automobile</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/e37393ee-ae53-42e1-b91e-e3573624b3f0_f7eb1e73.jpg" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies has set up a new smart car company. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has set up a new smart car company as the US-sanctioned telecoms equipment giant steps up its ambitions in the automobile industry, following its earlier announcement of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242954/us-sanctioned-huawei-forms-smart-vehicle-joint-venture-state-owned-changan-automobile-amid-effort" target="_self" title="">a joint venture (JV) with Chinese state-owned carmaker Changan Automobile</a>.</p><p>The new company, named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, was set up on Tuesday with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan (US$140.3 million) and is wholly owned by Huawei, according to records on business registry information platform Tianyancha.</p><p>The records show that the new firm’s business covers smart car equipment manufacturing, artificial intelligence (AI) system integration services, and AI software development, among other areas.</p><p>The development comes after Huawei signed a memorandum of cooperation in November with Changan Automobile, a major state-owned carmaker based in Chongqing, southwestern Sichuan province, to start a new smart car JV.</p><p>Under the partnership, Huawei said it plans to transfer its smart-car system business to a new unit with investments from Changan Automobile and “integrate the core technologies and resources of [Huawei’s] smart car solutions into the new company”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" title="">Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights</a></h3><p>The new venture was set up by Huawei’s car unit to serve the industry better with its smart car solutions, according to a person familiar with the situation who declined to be named. Huawei declined to comment on the relationship between the new entity and its JV with Changan.</p><p>While Huawei currently holds 100 per cent of the new firm, it is open to more industry partners joining to become a technology platform with diversified equity, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Securities Times.</p><p>In November, Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group and chairman of its Intelligent Automotive Solution business unit, called on Chinese carmakers Seres Group, Chery Automobile, JAC Motors and BAIC Motor to take an equity stake in the Huawei-Changan JV.</p><p>All four of these companies – generally considered smaller carmakers in the country – currently partner with Huawei to develop and sell new brands under the so-called Huawei Select model, through which the smartphone giant collaborates closely with companies on everything from product design to sales. These brands include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3238274/huaweis-ev-brand-aito-hits-sales-jackpot-new-suv-will-compensate-buyers-delivery-delays-sizzling?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Aito with Seres</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3235762/superior-teslas-model-s-huawei-and-chery-automobile-ev-venture-luxeed-launch-first-production-model?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Luxeed with Chery</a>.</p><p>At Changan’s global partnership conference on Tuesday, the automaker’s chairman Zhu Huarong revealed that Huawei had promised not to produce cars under their JV deal, which was sealed within three months of initiating discussions, according to a live-streamed video of the event.</p><p>Zhu also said that the two companies are in the process of discussing the details of their partnership and its establishment, which is tentatively named “Newcool” in English.</p><p>The Huawei-Changan JV will also be open to more firms, Zhu said, adding that it will focus on seven main businesses including intelligent automotive systems, smart cockpits and a digital platform.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s IC output grew 6.9% in 2023, defying weaker customer demand, tighter US sanctions</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248776/chinas-ic-output-grew-69-2023-defying-weaker-customer-demand-tighter-us-sanctions</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  China produced 351.4 billion ICs in 2023, despite sluggish demand and Western sanctions. SMIC faced lower capacity utilisation and weak customer demand, with its total wafer shipments dropping by 24% year on year. China's overall semiconductor exports decreased in volume and value, while imports also declined significantly.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's IC production in 2023 showed growth despite challenges.</li>    <li>Theme: China's semiconductor industry faced challenges such as sluggish demand and US sanctions in 2023.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of domestic chip manufacturing and the impact of external factors on the industry.</li>    <li>Main information: China's IC production increase; SMIC's capacity utilisation decline; China's semiconductor export and import changes.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  2023年，中国集成电路（IC）产量增长至3514亿块，但同时面临疲软需求和西方制裁等挑战。中芯国际的产能利用率和客户需求下降，其晶圆总出货量同比下降24%。中国整体半导体出口在数量和价值上均有所下降，进口也大幅减少。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国2023年集成电路产量在挑战中保持增长。</li>    <li>主题：中国半导体产业在2023年面临需求低迷、美国制裁等挑战。</li>    <li>观点：本土芯片制造的重要性以及外部因素对行业的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国集成电路产量增长；中芯国际产能利用率下降；中国半导体出口和进口变化。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>integrated circuit (IC) (n.) - /ˈɪntɪˌgreɪtɪd ˈsɜːrkjʊɪt/ 集成电路。    <p>原文例句：China’s total output of integrated circuits (ICs) in 2023 increased 6.9 per cent from a year earlier despite sluggish demand at one of its largest wafer foundries in the second half.</p>    <p>例句讲解：integrated circuit是指将多个电路元件集成在一个小块半导体晶片上的电子电路，简称IC。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>wafer foundry (n.) - /ˈweɪfə ˈfaʊndri/ 晶圆代工厂。    <p>原文例句：SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year, reflecting weaker demand from its main customers in sectors spanning from smartphones to carmakers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：wafer foundry是指制造半导体芯片的工厂，通常为其他公司提供晶圆代工服务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>capacity utilisation (n.) - /kəˈpæsɪti jˌyʊtəlɪˈzeɪʃən/ 产能利用率。    <p>原文例句：SMIC, which derived 84 per cent of its total revenue from the domestic market in the third quarter, saw its capacity utilisation rate fall to an average of 74 per cent in the first three quarters of last year, compared with 96 per cent in the same period the year before.</p>    <p>例句讲解：capacity utilisation是指实际产量与潜在产能之比，通常用百分比表示。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>year on year - 同比。    <p>原文例句：SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：year on year是指与上一年同期相比，通常用于比较两个时期的数据变化。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year, reflecting weaker demand from its main customers in sectors spanning from smartphones to carmakers. - 中芯国际从 2023 年 1 月到 9 月的晶圆总出货量同比下降 24%，反映了来自智能手机到汽车制造商等主要客户的需求疲软。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是SMIC’s total shipments of wafers declined by 24 per cent year on year，其中主语是SMIC’s total shipments of wafers，谓语是declined，宾语是24 per cent year on year。reflecting weaker demand from its main customers in sectors spanning from smartphones to carmakers是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示中芯国际晶圆总出货量下降的原因或背景，即反映了来自智能手机到汽车制造商等主要客户的需求疲软。这个句子的意思是说，中芯国际从 2023 年 1 月到 9 月的晶圆总出货量同比下降 24%，反映了来自智能手机到汽车制造商等主要客户的需求疲软。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>尽管（although） - 表示让步或转折。    <p>原文例句：China’s total output of integrated circuits (ICs) in 2023 increased 6.9 per cent from a year earlier despite sluggish demand at one of its largest wafer foundries in the second half.</P>    <p>语法讲解：尽管（although）是一个连词，表示让步或转折，常用于句子开头。它引导一个让步状语从句，其中包含一个与主句相反或相反的事实或情况。在这个例句中，although引导的让步状语从句是despite sluggish demand at one of its largest wafer foundries in the second half，表示尽管下半年其中一家最大的晶圆厂需求疲软，但中国2023年集成电路总产量仍增长了6.9%。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The country produced 351.4 billion ICs last year, compared with 324.2 billion in 2022, according to data published by China’s National Bureau of Statistics</li>
<li>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year, reflecting weaker demand from its main customers</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/ce7b587c-5f38-411c-9843-cac4990a5c01_4b7791c6.jpg" /><figcaption>A semiconductor wafer foundry in Western Science City in southwest China’s Chongqing Municipality, Aug. 24, 2023. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China’s total output of integrated circuits (ICs) in 2023 increased 6.9 per cent from a year earlier despite sluggish demand at one of its largest wafer foundries in the second half.</p><p>The country produced 351.4 billion ICs last year, compared with 324.2 billion in 2022, according to data published on Wednesday by China’s National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).</p><p>The NBS data counted a variety of chips to reach the total IC number, including logic, memory, analogue and special chips, plus sensors and chip modules.</p><p>In 2023, China’s semiconductor manufacturing industry was marred by factors such as weaker economic post-pandemic recovery, sluggish demand from smartphone and personal-computer makers, and tighter US-led sanctions that restricted its access to advanced technologies.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3241136/china-chip-design-expert-warns-losses-due-industry-overcrowding-says-more-cautious-path-self" title="">China chip design expert warns of losses due to industry overcrowding</a></h3><p>China’s top foundry <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240965/chinese-chip-maker-smics-sales-fall-third-straight-quarter-despite-boost-huaweis-5g-smartphone" target="_self" title="">Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC),</a> which derived 84 per cent of its total revenue from the domestic market in the third quarter, saw its capacity utilisation rate fall to an average of 74 per cent in the first three quarters of last year, compared with 96 per cent in the same period the year before.</p><p>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year, reflecting weaker demand from its main customers in sectors spanning from smartphones to carmakers.</p><p>The company will report its fourth-quarter and full-year results on February 7.</p><p>The market softness was also felt by China’s second-largest foundry Hua Hong Semiconductor, which saw revenue in the first nine months of last year drop 0.79 per year on year, while third-quarter capacity utilisation sank to 86.8 per cent from a capacity overload situation in the second quarter, according to data from the company.</p><p>Industry analysts have predicted the sluggish demand to continue in the current quarter, with signs of recovery only becoming visible in the second quarter.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/ebdd4d9b-53c5-45d6-928a-bbc3ebc20246_d7e8111e.jpg" title="SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>Overall semiconductor foundry capacity utilisation rates are still under downward pressure amid the prevailing economic turbulence this quarter, Taiwan-based IC research company TrendForce said in a recent note.</p><p>TrendForce predicted that foundry inventory levels will improve in the second quarter, returning to a healthier equilibrium despite the continuing murky outlook for end-customer orders.</p><p>Separately, China exported a total of 267.8 billion ICs worth US$135.9 billion in 2023, down 1.8 per cent by volume and 10.1 per cent lower in value from 2022.</p><p>Meanwhile, China imported 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion, down 10.8 per cent by volume and 15.4 per cent in value from 2022, official data showed.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
