<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Google to let global Android users search for content within other apps</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248800/google-let-global-android-users-search-content-within-other-apps</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Google's Circle to Search feature, available on premium Android smartphones, enables users to search within other apps without exiting them. The function allows users to select text, images, or videos and have Google search them within the app. Google aims to boost its search engine and drive engagement for app developers. The feature will be rolled out gradually from January 31st and will be available on the Samsung Galaxy S24 Series. Google's revenue grew 11% in the third quarter of 2023 due to growth in search and YouTube. However, the company faces uncertainties in Hong Kong, where the government seeks to remove the protest song "Glory to Hong Kong" from its search engine.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Google's Circle to Search feature enables in-app searching, boosting engagement for apps and Google's search engine.</li>    <li>Theme: Google introduces a new feature that allows Android users to search within other apps, enhancing the user experience and increasing engagement.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Google's focus on improving user experience through innovative search features and driving engagement for app developers.</li>    <li>Main information: Availability of the Circle to Search feature on premium Android smartphones; how the feature works; potential benefits for apps and content creators; Google's revenue growth in Q3 2023; uncertainties in Hong Kong regarding the protest song "Glory to Hong Kong".</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  谷歌的 Circle to Search 功能可在高级安卓智能手机上使用，允许用户在其他应用程序中进行搜索，无需退出应用程序。该功能允许用户选择文本、图像或视频，并让 Google 在应用程序中搜索它们。谷歌旨在通过此举提升其搜索引擎的使用率并推动应用程序开发者的参与度。该功能将从 1 月 31 日起逐步推出，并将适用于三星 Galaxy S24 系列。谷歌在 2023 年第三季度的收入增长了 11%，这要归功于搜索和 YouTube 的“显著增长”。然而，公司在香港面临着不确定性，因为香港政府试图将其搜索引擎中由反政府运动而流行起来的抗议歌曲《荣耀香港》下架。谷歌表示，若无法院命令，公司不愿禁止该歌曲在其搜索引擎中出现。尽管香港法院在 7 月驳回了政府的禁令请求，但一个月后，法院还是允许香港政府对该裁决提出上诉。  <ul>    <li>摘要：谷歌的 Circle to Search 功能支持应用程序内搜索，提高对应用程序以及谷歌搜索引擎的参与度。</li>    <li>主题：谷歌推出一个能够让安卓用户在其他应用程序内进行搜索的新功能，增强用户体验，提高参与度。</li>    <li>观点：谷歌专注于通过创新的搜索功能改善用户体验，并提高应用程序开发者的参与度。</li>    <li>主要信息：Circle to Search 功能在高级安卓智能手机上的可用性；该功能的工作原理；对应用程序和内容创建者的潜在好处；谷歌在 2023 年第三季度的收入增长；香港对歌曲《荣耀香港》的不确定性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>premium (adj.) - /ˈpriːmiəm/ 高级的，优质的。    <p>原文例句：The Circle to Search feature, available from January 31 on some premium Android smartphones, will enable quick access to information without having to leave the app.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“premium”意为“高级的，优质的”，指产品或服务具有较高的价值和质量。在例句中，“premium Android smartphones”指高配置和高性能的安卓智能手机。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>select (v.) - /sɪˈlɛkt/ 选择，挑选。    <p>原文例句：For example, users will be able to search for details on what a content creator is wearing in a video by circling or tapping on the items, after they activate the Circle to Search function by long-pressing their Android phone’s home button or navigation bar, the company said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“select”意为“选择，挑选”，指从多个选项中做出选择。在例句中，“users will be able to select text, images or videos”指用户可以选择要搜索的文本、图片或视频。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Circle to Search - 指环搜索。    <p>原文例句：Google’s new Circle to Search feature, to be rolled out “gradually” from January 31 on some premium Android smartphones, will allow users to select text, images or videos in any other apps, and have Google search them within the apps, the US technology giant said on Thursday. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“Circle to Search”是谷歌推出的一项新功能，允许用户在其他应用程序中选择文本、图像或视频，并让 Google 在应用程序中进行搜索。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>drive engagement - 推动参与度。    <p>原文例句：The feature will enable quick access to information without having to leave the app, potentially driving engagement for apps and the content displayed, it said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“drive engagement”意为“推动参与度”，指吸引用户参与和互动。在例句中，“potentially driving engagement for apps and the content displayed”指该功能可能会推动应用程序和显示内容的参与度。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Google’s new Circle to Search feature, to be rolled out “gradually” from January 31 on some premium Android smartphones, will allow users to select text, images or videos in any other apps, and have Google search them within the apps, the US technology giant said on Thursday. - 谷歌的 Circle to Search 新功能将于 1 月 31 日起在部分高级安卓智能手机上“逐步”推出，它将允许用户选择任何其他应用中的文本、图像或视频，并让谷歌在应用内对其进行搜索，这家美国科技巨头周四表示。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，包含一个主句和多个从句。主句是 Google’s new Circle to Search feature will allow users to select text, images or videos in any other apps, and have Google search them within the apps，其中主语是 Google’s new Circle to Search feature，谓语是 will allow，宾语是 users to select text, images or videos in any other apps, and have Google search them within the apps。从句 to be rolled out “gradually” from January 31 on some premium Android smartphones 是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示推出时间和范围。从句 the US technology giant said on Thursday 是一个同位语从句，补充说明主语 Google’s new Circle to Search feature。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Google has expressed unwillingness to ban the song from its search engine without a court order. </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态由 have/has + 过去分词构成，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在例句中，has expressed 表示谷歌已经表达了不愿意禁止这首歌的意愿，且这种意愿一直持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Circle to Search feature, available from January 31 on some premium Android smartphones, will enable quick access to information without having to leave the app</li>
<li>Google did not disclose when the new function will be available on iPhones</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/0ef11e92-e140-40ff-9bb4-6c867083b49a_dcba723e.jpg" /><figcaption>A person holds up Google’s Pixel 8 Pro smartphone in New York City, October 4, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Google will let global Android smartphone users search for content in other applications without having to exit them, a move aimed at boosting its search engine and driving engagement for app developers.</p><p>Google’s new Circle to Search feature, to be rolled out “gradually” from January 31 on some premium Android smartphones, will allow users to select text, images or videos in any other apps, and have Google search them within the apps, the US technology giant said on Thursday.</p><p>For example, users will be able to search for details on what a content creator is wearing in a video by circling or tapping on the items, after they activate the Circle to Search function by long-pressing their Android phone’s home button or navigation bar, the company said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above" title="">Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with broad iPhone discounts</a></h3><p>The feature will enable quick access to information without having to leave the app, potentially driving engagement for apps and the content displayed, it said.</p><p>Early testing showed that users “typically return to the app they’re using” after activating the feature, according to Google.</p><p>The company did not disclose when the function will be available on iPhones, with a representative telling the South China Morning Post that it “looks forward to bringing this powerful new capability to more people over time”. Android handsets that will feature the new function will include the Samsung Electronics’ new Galaxy S24 Series, it said.</p><p>Google parent Alphabet’s revenue in the three months ending September 30 rose 11 per cent from the same period a year before, which the company attributed to “meaningful growth” in search and YouTube, according to its earnings report published in October. Advertising revenue grew 9.5 per cent year on year to US$59.6 billion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Google will let global Android smartphone users search for content in other applications without having to exit them. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/8860e509-75b9-47e4-a0bc-02b333db06d9_e3f05cd0.jpg" title="Google will let global Android smartphone users search for content in other applications without having to exit them. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>Google will let global Android smartphone users search for content in other applications without having to exit them. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>The company is still facing uncertainties in Hong Kong, where the government is seeking to have the US technology giant remove the protest song “Glory to Hong Kong”, which became popular during anti-government unrest in the city in 2019. Google has expressed unwillingness to ban the song from its search engine without a court order.</p><p>While a Hong Kong court <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3229252/hong-kong-court-dismisses-government-bid-ban-protest-song" target="_self" title="">blocked</a> the government’s injunction bid in July, a month later it allowed the city’s government to appeal the decision.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei sets up new smart car unit as it accelerates automotive ambitions in wake of earlier deal with Changan</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248785/huawei-sets-new-smart-car-unit-it-accelerates-automotive-ambitions-wake-earlier-deal-changan</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  华为进军汽车业务，成立新公司深圳银王智能技术有限公司，注册资本达10亿元人民币。该公司的业务范围涉及智能汽车设备制造、人工智能（AI）系统集成服务、AI软件开发等。此次设立新公司是继华为在11月与长安汽车签订合作备忘录后，启动智能汽车领域的重大举措。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei establishes a new smart car company, Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei expands its involvement in the automobile industry by setting up a new smart car company, focusing on areas like smart car equipment manufacturing and AI system integration.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Huawei's expansion into the smart car market signifies its commitment to diversifying its business and becoming a technology leader in the automotive industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology's business scope; Huawei's partnership with Changan Automobile; potential future collaborations with other carmakers; Huawei's "no-car-production" promise to Changan.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  华为进军汽车领域，成立新公司深圳银王智能技术有限公司，注册资本10亿元人民币。这家新公司的业务范围包括智能汽车设备制造、人工智能系统集成服务和人工智能软件开发等。这一新公司的成立是在华为与长安汽车在去年11月签署合作备忘录后启动智能汽车领域的一项重大举措。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为成立新的智能汽车公司深圳银王智能技术有限公司，注册资本10亿元人民币。</li>    <li>主题：华为通过成立新的智能汽车公司，重点关注智能汽车设备制造和人工智能系统集成等领域，扩大其在汽车行业的参与度。</li>    <li>观点：华为进军智能汽车市场表明其致力于业务多元化，并成为汽车行业的技术领导者。</li>    <li>主要信息：深圳银王智能技术有限公司的业务范围；华为与长安汽车的合作；与其他汽车制造商的潜在未来合作；华为对长安的“不生产汽车”承诺。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>venture (n.) - /ˈventʃər/ 一个项目，任务，业务。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies has set up a new smart car company as the US-sanctioned telecoms equipment giant steps up its ambitions in the automobile industry, following its earlier announcement of a joint venture (JV) with Chinese state-owned carmaker Changan Automobile.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由venture（冒险）演变而来，表示“一个项目，任务，业务”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为与中国国有汽车制造商长安汽车的合资企业。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>diversified (adj.) - /daɪˈvɜːsɪfaɪd/ 多元化的，多样化的。    <p>原文例句：While Huawei currently holds 100 per cent of the new firm, it is open to more industry partners joining to become a technology platform with diversified equity, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Securities Times. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由diversify（多样化）演变而来，表示“多元化的，多样化的”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为新公司欢迎更多行业合作伙伴加入，成为一个股权多元化的技术平台。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take an equity stake (in) - 持有股份，入股。    <p>原文例句：Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group and chairman of its Intelligent Automotive Solution business unit, called on Chinese carmakers Seres Group, Chery Automobile, JAC Motors and BAIC Motor to take an equity stake in the Huawei-Changan JV.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿取，拥有），equity（股权，权益）和stake（股份，利益）组成的，表示“持有股份，入股”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为消费者业务集团首席执行官、智能汽车解决方案业务单元董事长余承东呼吁中国汽车制造商赛力斯集团、奇瑞汽车、江淮汽车和北汽汽车入股华为-长安合资企业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In November, Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group and chairman of its Intelligent Automotive Solution business unit, called on Chinese carmakers Seres Group, Chery Automobile, JAC Motors and BAIC Motor to take an equity stake in the Huawei-Changan JV. - 在11月，华为消费者业务集团首席执行官、智能汽车解决方案业务单元董事长余承东呼吁中国汽车制造商赛力斯集团、奇瑞汽车、江淮汽车和北汽汽车入股华为-长安合资企业。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是余承东呼吁中国汽车制造商入股华为-长安合资企业，其中主语是余承东，谓语是呼吁，宾语是中国汽车制造商。In November, Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group and chairman of its Intelligent Automotive Solution business unit, called是一个时间状语，修饰主句，表示呼吁的时间是在11月。To take an equity stake in the Huawei-Changan JV是一个不定式短语作目的状语，修饰呼吁，表示呼吁的目的或结果，即入股华为-长安合资企业。这个句子的意思是说，在11月，华为消费者业务集团首席执行官、智能汽车解决方案业务单元董事长余承东呼吁中国汽车制造商赛力斯集团、奇瑞汽车、江淮汽车和北汽汽车入股华为-长安合资企业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示一个动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies has set up a new smart car company as the US-sanctioned telecoms equipment giant steps up its ambitions in the automobile industry, following its earlier announcement of a joint venture (JV) with Chinese state-owned carmaker Changan Automobile.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，has set up表示华为已经成立了一家新的智能汽车公司，并且这一行动是持续进行的，强调华为在汽车行业的野心不断增强。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The new company, named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, has a registered capital of 1 billion yuan</li>
<li>Development comes after Huawei signed a memorandum of cooperation in November with Changan Automobile</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/e37393ee-ae53-42e1-b91e-e3573624b3f0_f7eb1e73.jpg" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies has set up a new smart car company. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has set up a new smart car company as the US-sanctioned telecoms equipment giant steps up its ambitions in the automobile industry, following its earlier announcement of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242954/us-sanctioned-huawei-forms-smart-vehicle-joint-venture-state-owned-changan-automobile-amid-effort" target="_self" title="">a joint venture (JV) with Chinese state-owned carmaker Changan Automobile</a>.</p><p>The new company, named Shenzhen Yinwang Intelligent Technology, was set up on Tuesday with a registered capital of 1 billion yuan (US$140.3 million) and is wholly owned by Huawei, according to records on business registry information platform Tianyancha.</p><p>The records show that the new firm’s business covers smart car equipment manufacturing, artificial intelligence (AI) system integration services, and AI software development, among other areas.</p><p>The development comes after Huawei signed a memorandum of cooperation in November with Changan Automobile, a major state-owned carmaker based in Chongqing, southwestern Sichuan province, to start a new smart car JV.</p><p>Under the partnership, Huawei said it plans to transfer its smart-car system business to a new unit with investments from Changan Automobile and “integrate the core technologies and resources of [Huawei’s] smart car solutions into the new company”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" title="">Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights</a></h3><p>The new venture was set up by Huawei’s car unit to serve the industry better with its smart car solutions, according to a person familiar with the situation who declined to be named. Huawei declined to comment on the relationship between the new entity and its JV with Changan.</p><p>While Huawei currently holds 100 per cent of the new firm, it is open to more industry partners joining to become a technology platform with diversified equity, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Securities Times.</p><p>In November, Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group and chairman of its Intelligent Automotive Solution business unit, called on Chinese carmakers Seres Group, Chery Automobile, JAC Motors and BAIC Motor to take an equity stake in the Huawei-Changan JV.</p><p>All four of these companies – generally considered smaller carmakers in the country – currently partner with Huawei to develop and sell new brands under the so-called Huawei Select model, through which the smartphone giant collaborates closely with companies on everything from product design to sales. These brands include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3238274/huaweis-ev-brand-aito-hits-sales-jackpot-new-suv-will-compensate-buyers-delivery-delays-sizzling?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Aito with Seres</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3235762/superior-teslas-model-s-huawei-and-chery-automobile-ev-venture-luxeed-launch-first-production-model?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Luxeed with Chery</a>.</p><p>At Changan’s global partnership conference on Tuesday, the automaker’s chairman Zhu Huarong revealed that Huawei had promised not to produce cars under their JV deal, which was sealed within three months of initiating discussions, according to a live-streamed video of the event.</p><p>Zhu also said that the two companies are in the process of discussing the details of their partnership and its establishment, which is tentatively named “Newcool” in English.</p><p>The Huawei-Changan JV will also be open to more firms, Zhu said, adding that it will focus on seven main businesses including intelligent automotive systems, smart cockpits and a digital platform.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s IC output grew 6.9% in 2023, defying weaker customer demand, tighter US sanctions</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248776/chinas-ic-output-grew-69-2023-defying-weaker-customer-demand-tighter-us-sanctions</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Despite weaker demand and various challenges, China's semiconductor industry saw a slight increase in IC production in 2023, according to data from the National Bureau of Statistics. However, leading foundries like SMIC faced significant production declines.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's semiconductor industry shows resilience in 2023 despite obstacles.</li>    <li>Theme: Amidst economic turbulence and weak market conditions, China's chip production saw a modest rise, while key players experienced downturn.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: China's efforts to sustain its semiconductor industry need to address challenges and capitalize on growth areas.</li>    <li>Main information: China's total IC production in 2023 increased by 6.9%; SMIC's wafer shipments decreased by 24%; overall capacity utilization rates dropped due to sluggish demand from key sectors; China's chip exports and imports both declined in volume and value.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  尽管需求疲软、挑战重重，根据国家统计局的公布数据，中国半导体产业在2023年录得小幅增长。然而，像中芯国际这样的大型晶圆厂却面临严重的产能下滑情况。  <ul>    <li>摘要：2023年中国半导体行业展示出韧性。</li>    <li>主题：在经济动荡和市场疲软的环境中，中国芯片产量小幅增长，而行业关键企业却经历了低迷。</li>    <li>观点：中国应正确认识到芯片产业的挑战，以应对挑战和把握增长领域。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国2023年集成电路总产量增长6.9%；中芯国际晶圆出货量下降24%；总体产能利用率下降，主要原因是主要行业的需求低迷；中国芯片出口和进口量和价值量均下降。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sluggish (adj.) - /ˈslʌɡɪʃ/ 缓慢的，迟缓的。    <p>原文例句：In 2023, China’s semiconductor manufacturing industry was marred by factors such as weaker economic post-pandemic recovery, sluggish demand from smartphone and personal-computer makers, and tighter US-led sanctions that restricted its access to advanced technologies. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Sluggish在这里的意思是缓慢的、迟缓的。这句话描述了在2023年，中国半导体制造业受到了一些因素的影响，包括疫情后经济复苏乏力、智能手机和个人电脑制造商的需求低迷，以及美国领导的制裁加剧，限制了中国获得先进技术的机会。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>overcrowding (n.) - /ˌoʊvərˈkraʊdɪŋ/ 人满为患，过度拥挤。    <p>原文例句：China chip design expert warns of losses due to industry overcrowding.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Overcrowding表示过度拥挤。这句话是说中国芯片设计专家警告，由于行业过度拥挤，可能会产生损失。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>capacity (n.) - /kəˈpasəti/ 产能，容量。    <p>原文例句：SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year, reflecting weaker demand from its main customers in sectors spanning from smartphones to carmakers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Capacity在这里是指产能。这句话描述了从2023年1月到9月，中芯国际的晶圆总出货量同比下降24%，这反映了其来自智能手机到汽车制造商等主要客户的需求疲软。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the first three quarters - 在前三个季度。    <p>原文例句：SMIC’s capacity utilisation rate fell to an average of 74 per cent in the first three quarters of last year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：In the first three quarters表示在前三个季度。这句话的意思是，去年，中芯国际的前三个季度的产能利用率平均下降到74%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>by volume - 按数量。    <p>原文例句：Separately, China exported a total of 267.8 billion ICs worth US$135.9 billion in 2023, down 1.8 per cent by volume and 10.1 per cent lower in value from 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：By volume表示按数量。这句话的意思是，2023年中国出口了总计2678亿个集成电路，价值1359亿美元，与2022年相比，数量下降了1.8%，价值下降了10.1%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company will report its fourth-quarter and full-year results on February 7. - 该公司将于2月7日公布其第四季度和全年业绩。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是The company，谓语是will report，宾语是its fourth-quarter and full-year results。on February 7是一个介词短语，表示在2月7日。这个句子的意思是，该公司将于2月7日公布其第四季度和全年业绩。</p></li>    </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>含有“despite”的句子 - 表示尽管如此。    <p>原文例句：The country produced 351.4 billion ICs last year, compared with 324.2 billion in 2022, according to data published on Wednesday by China’s National Bureau of Statistics (NBS). The NBS data counted a variety of chips to reach the total IC number, including logic, memory, analogue and special chips, plus sensors and chip modules. In 2023, China’s semiconductor manufacturing industry was marred by factors such as weaker economic post-pandemic recovery, sluggish demand from smartphone and personal-computer makers, and tighter US-led sanctions that restricted its access to advanced technologies.</p>    <p>语法讲解：含有“despite”的句子表示尽管如此。在这个句子中，Despite weaker economic post-pandemic recovery, sluggish demand from smartphone and personal-computer makers, and tighter US-led sanctions that restricted its access to advanced technologies.是一个含有“despite”的句子，表示尽管经济复苏疲软、智能手机和个人电脑制造商的需求低迷以及美国领导的制裁加剧，限制了中国获得先进技术的机会。</p></li>  </ul>  </div>  <ul><li>The country produced 351.4 billion ICs last year, compared with 324.2 billion in 2022, according to data published by China’s National Bureau of Statistics</li>
<li>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year, reflecting weaker demand from its main customers</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/ce7b587c-5f38-411c-9843-cac4990a5c01_4b7791c6.jpg" /><figcaption>A semiconductor wafer foundry in Western Science City in southwest China’s Chongqing Municipality, Aug. 24, 2023. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China’s total output of integrated circuits (ICs) in 2023 increased 6.9 per cent from a year earlier despite sluggish demand at one of its largest wafer foundries in the second half.</p><p>The country produced 351.4 billion ICs last year, compared with 324.2 billion in 2022, according to data published on Wednesday by China’s National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).</p><p>The NBS data counted a variety of chips to reach the total IC number, including logic, memory, analogue and special chips, plus sensors and chip modules.</p><p>In 2023, China’s semiconductor manufacturing industry was marred by factors such as weaker economic post-pandemic recovery, sluggish demand from smartphone and personal-computer makers, and tighter US-led sanctions that restricted its access to advanced technologies.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3241136/china-chip-design-expert-warns-losses-due-industry-overcrowding-says-more-cautious-path-self" title="">China chip design expert warns of losses due to industry overcrowding</a></h3><p>China’s top foundry <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240965/chinese-chip-maker-smics-sales-fall-third-straight-quarter-despite-boost-huaweis-5g-smartphone" target="_self" title="">Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC),</a> which derived 84 per cent of its total revenue from the domestic market in the third quarter, saw its capacity utilisation rate fall to an average of 74 per cent in the first three quarters of last year, compared with 96 per cent in the same period the year before.</p><p>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year, reflecting weaker demand from its main customers in sectors spanning from smartphones to carmakers.</p><p>The company will report its fourth-quarter and full-year results on February 7.</p><p>The market softness was also felt by China’s second-largest foundry Hua Hong Semiconductor, which saw revenue in the first nine months of last year drop 0.79 per year on year, while third-quarter capacity utilisation sank to 86.8 per cent from a capacity overload situation in the second quarter, according to data from the company.</p><p>Industry analysts have predicted the sluggish demand to continue in the current quarter, with signs of recovery only becoming visible in the second quarter.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/ebdd4d9b-53c5-45d6-928a-bbc3ebc20246_d7e8111e.jpg" title="SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>SMIC’s total shipments of wafers from January to September 2023 declined by 24 per cent year on year. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>Overall semiconductor foundry capacity utilisation rates are still under downward pressure amid the prevailing economic turbulence this quarter, Taiwan-based IC research company TrendForce said in a recent note.</p><p>TrendForce predicted that foundry inventory levels will improve in the second quarter, returning to a healthier equilibrium despite the continuing murky outlook for end-customer orders.</p><p>Separately, China exported a total of 267.8 billion ICs worth US$135.9 billion in 2023, down 1.8 per cent by volume and 10.1 per cent lower in value from 2022.</p><p>Meanwhile, China imported 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion, down 10.8 per cent by volume and 15.4 per cent in value from 2022, official data showed.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s internet giants must step up opening their ‘walled gardens’, state media says, ahead of Tencent flagship game’s return to Douyin</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248762/chinas-internet-giants-must-step-opening-their-walled-gardens-state-media-says-ahead-tencent</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese internet companies need to break digital barriers and promote cross-platform collaboration for industry growth and to face market pressures.</li>    <li>Theme: Call for more open-minded and inclusive cooperation among China's major internet companies.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The article emphasizes the importance of breaking down platform barriers, promoting collaboration, and embracing inclusivity to drive industry expansion and resilience.</li>    <li>Main information: Collaboration between Tencent's Honour of Kings and ByteDance's Douyin, regulatory uncertainties in the video gaming industry, pressure from market challenges like waning investor confidence and property market slump, and examples of previous partnerships between rival companies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国互联网公司需要打破数字壁垒，推动跨平台合作，以实现行业增长并应对市场压力。</li>    <li>主题：呼吁中国主要互联网公司之间开展更加开放和包容的合作。</li>    <li>观点：文章强调了打破平台壁垒、促进合作、拥抱包容性的重要性，以推动行业扩张和复原力。</li>    <li>主要信息：腾讯《王者荣耀》与字节跳动旗下抖音的合作，视频游戏行业的监管不确定性，来自市场挑战（如投资者信心减弱和房地产市场低迷）的压力，以及竞争对手互联网平台运营商之间以往合作的案例。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>collaboration (n.) - /kəˌlæbəˈreɪʃən/ 协作，合作。      <p>原文例句：Collaborations among these Big Tech firms ‘are far from deep’, according to an article by Securities Times.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Collaboration是指两个人或多个团体共同合作以实现共同目标。在这个例句中，collaboration指的是这些科技巨头之间的合作。</p>    </li>    <li>inclusive (adj.) - /ɪnˈklusɪv/ 包容的，包括一切的。      <p>原文例句：“In the future, internet companies need to be more open-minded and inclusive to promote truly win-win cooperation in the industry,” the Securities Times article said.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Inclusive是指包括一切的，不排斥任何人的。在这个例句中，inclusive指的是互联网公司需要更加包容，以促进行业内的真正双赢合作。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>face market pressures - 面临市场压力。      <p>原文例句：“Internet companies need to leverage each other to face the market pressures together,” the Securities Times article said.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Face market pressures是指面对市场压力。在这个例句中，face market pressures指的是互联网公司需要相互合作以共同应对市场压力。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China’s major internet companies ‘need to be more open-minded’ about enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms, according to the Securities Times article. - 证券时报的文章称，中国主要互联网公司“需要更加开放”地让它们的生态系统跨平台运作。    <p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是China’s major internet companies，谓语是need to be more open-minded，宾语是about enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms。这个句子表达了中国主要互联网公司需要更加开放地让它们的生态系统跨平台运作的观点。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。      <p>原文例句：Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming.</p>      <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是由have/has和过去分词构成的时态，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个例句中，allow是动词，过去分词是allowed，现在完成时态是has allowed，表示腾讯允许抖音播放《王者荣耀》视频，这个动作从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Collaborations among these Big Tech firms ‘are far from deep’, according to an article by Securities Times</li>
<li>The call to break more digital barriers in China’s internet industry comes days before Tencent’s Honour of Kings returns to Douyin’s platform</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/e3c9aa50-df1e-4b22-8f21-d4b06c403b4e_0bbdcb09.jpg" /><figcaption>China’s major internet companies ‘need to be more open-minded’ about enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms, according to the Securities Times article. Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants must accelerate efforts to open up their “walled gardens”, enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms as a means “to face market pressures together” and assure the industry’s further expansion, according to state-owned media.</p><p>At present, collaborations among these companies “are far from deep”, said an article published on Tuesday by Shenzhen-based Securities Times, a financial newspaper owned by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chinas-communist-party" target="_self" title="">Chinese Communist Party</a> mouthpiece People’s Daily.</p><p>The call to break more digital barriers in China’s internet industry comes days before <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honour-kings" target="_self" title="">Honour of Kings</a>, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3116088/honour-kings-became-worlds-most-popular-game-it-was-desperate?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">world’s most popular mobile game</a>, officially returns to the popular live-streaming platform of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3101626/douyin-chinas-tiktok-grows-daily-active-users-600-million-home" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>, which has more than 600 million daily active users, from January 21.</p><p>“In the future, internet companies need to be more open-minded and inclusive to promote truly win-win cooperation in the industry,” the Securities Times article said.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Increased collaboration between China’s major internet companies are expected to not only benefit consumers, but help further expand the industry, according to state media. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/4358c69f-a073-4444-8f19-753e8dd060b9_53933fe2.jpg" title="Increased collaboration between China’s major internet companies are expected to not only benefit consumers, but help further expand the industry, according to state media. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Increased collaboration between China’s major internet companies are expected to not only benefit consumers, but help further expand the industry, according to state media. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>The collaboration between ByteDance and Tencent comes amid the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> industry’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248249/chinas-video-gaming-market-ended-2023-battered-and-bruised-can-world-beating-titles-and-innovation?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">regulatory uncertainties and a weaker macro environment in China</a>.</p><p>While China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248694/china-gdp-beijings-long-do-list-boost-economy-2024" target="_self" title="">gross domestic product rose by 5.2 per cent</a> year on year in 2023, the world’s second-largest economy still faced mounting concerns this year including waning investor confidence, a protracted property market slump and a weak private sector.</p><p>“Internet companies need to leverage each other to face the market pressures together,” the Securities Times article said.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a> owner ByteDance earlier this month confirmed that it was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">in talks with multiple potential buyers</a>, including Tencent, to sell its video gaming operations.</p><p>Last April, Tencent and Douyin <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3216333/tencent-and-douyin-end-years-copyright-disputes-signing-cooperation-agreement-content-distribution" target="_self" title="">agreed to a partnership in video content distribution</a> after years of contentious copyright disputes.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>Under that deal, Tencent authorised Douyin to distribute its video content and clarify copyright rules for users to produce modifications and adaptations. As a result, users of ByteDance-owned platforms Douyin, Xigua Video and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/abacus/culture/article/3074051/why-chinas-favorite-news-app-lets-users-order-food" target="_self" title="">Jinri Toutiao</a> will be able to produce derivative works based on Tencent-owned videos.</p><p>There have been other cases of collaboration between rival internet platform operators over the years,</p><p>In November, Alibaba Group Holding’s grocery chain <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/e-commerce/article/3103476/alibabas-freshippo-opens-first-membership-only-store-shanghai" target="_self" title="">Freshippo</a> opened a store on rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3155846/chinas-internet-walled-gardens-may-be-cracking-users-face-long" title="">Beijing wants to smash online walls but Big Tech treads carefully</a></h3><p>Tencent’s super app <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> and Alibaba’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247985/alibabas-taobao-and-tmall-group-pushes-new-ai-tools-boost-merchants-service-consumers-first-major" target="_self" title="">Taobao and Tmall Group</a> in September announced an expanded collaboration, which enabled users who click on advertisements on WeChat to be <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235835/alibaba-tencent-break-more-digital-barriers-between-wechat-and-taobao-tmall-economic-uncertainty" target="_self" title="">directed to shops and live-streaming campaigns on Taobao and Tmall</a>.</p><p>In November 2021, Tencent opened WeChat to third-party online links including those of Douyin and Taobao.</p><p>In September that same year, Alibaba started allowing consumers to use Tencent’s WeChat Pay as a payment option on a number of its platforms including food delivery platform <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3227745/alibabas-eleme-food-delivery-platform-extends-welfare-coverage-3-million-couriers-collective" target="_self" title="">Ele.me</a>, video-streaming platform <a href="https://www.scmp.com/abacus/who-what/what/article/3028268/how-youku-went-being-chinas-youtube-chinas-hulu" target="_self" title="">Youku</a>, online ticketing platform Damai and cross-border e-commerce platform Kaola.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s hi-tech manufacturing faces ‘extraordinary pressures’ as 2023 output stalls</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248773/chinas-hi-tech-manufacturing-faces-extraordinary-pressures-2023-output-stalls</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In 2023, the industrial output of China's hi-tech manufacturing industry increased by only 2.7% year on year, the lowest growth rate since records began in 2018. The decline was due to a weak economy and escalating containment efforts from the United States. As a result, Beijing's ambition to become a superpower is facing challenges.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: The growth of China's hi-tech manufacturing industry slowed down significantly in 2023, impacting the country's economic development.</li>    <li>Theme: The challenges faced by China's hi-tech manufacturing industry and the implications for the country's economic growth and global competitiveness.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of innovation and technology in driving economic growth, the impact of external pressure on China's hi-tech sector, and the need for China to adapt to global changes.</li>    <li>Main information: The decline in the growth rate of hi-tech manufacturing output, the impact of the US tech war and deglobalization, and the challenges faced by Chinese tech companies in going public.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023年，中国高技术制造业的工业产值同比增长只有2.7%，是2018年有记录以来的历史最低增速，原因是经济疲软且美国不断升级围堵打压。这也让北京的超级大国抱负遭遇阻击。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国高技术制造业增速2023年明显回落，影响到这个国家经济发展前景。</li>    <li>主题：中国高技术制造业面临的挑战及其对国家经济增长和全球竞争力的影响。</li>    <li>观点：创新和技术在经济增长中的重要性，外部压力对中国高技术产业的影响，中国需要适应全球变化。</li>    <li>主要信息：高技术制造业产值增速下滑，中美科技战和去全球化的影响，中国高技术企业上市面临的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>containment (n.) - /kənˈteɪnmənt/ 遏制，围堵。    <p>原文例句：Output from China’s hi-tech manufacturing sector grew at the slowest pace on record last year amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States, with the decline weighing on Beijing’s march towards superpower status.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语containre（包括），表示“包含，围堵，限制”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国不断升级的围堵打压，即对中国的贸易、技术和产业进行限制和打击。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>decoupling (n.) - /diːˈkʌplɪŋ/ 脱钩，解耦。    <p>原文例句：“The hi-tech recovery will require China to return to higher economic growth and counteract US decoupling.“It also demands the country’s ability to adapt to deglobalisation, but maintain a strong global exporter role.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语de-（away from，分开）和couple（连接），表示“脱钩，解耦，断开连接”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国与中国在贸易、技术和产业领域的脱钩，即减少依赖中国，并与之分开发展。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>deglobalization (n.) - /diːˌgləʊbəlaɪˈzeɪʃn/ 去全球化。    <p>原文例句：“The hi-tech recovery will require China to return to higher economic growth and counteract US decoupling.“It also demands the country’s ability to adapt to deglobalisation, but maintain a strong global exporter role.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由de-（away from，分开）global（全球的）和-ization（过程）组成的，表示“去全球化，全球一体化的逆转”。在这个例句中，它指的是全球化的逆转，即各国减少经济和贸易联系，变得更加孤立和自给自足。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>go public - 上市。    <P>原文例句：Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public, the potential sanctions would affect their market valuations</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由go（去）和public（公开）组成的，表示“上市，发行股票”。在这个例句中，它指的是科技制造商通过发行股票来筹集资金，并被允许在证券交易所进行交易。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“The US tech war has largely thwarted Chinese tech companies’ [initial public offering] opportunities. Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public, the potential sanctions would affect their market valuations,” said Chen. - “美国科技战在很大程度上阻碍了中国科技公司的[首次公开募股]机会。即使这些科技制造商成功上市，潜在的制裁也会影响它们的市场估值，”陈说。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public, the potential sanctions would affect their market valuations，其中主语是the potential sanctions，谓语是would affect，宾语是their market valuations。Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public是一个让步状语从句，表示即使这些科技制造商成功上市，即使这个条件成立。“The US tech war has largely thwarted Chinese tech companies’ [initial public offering] opportunities”是一个过去完成时态的句子，表示美国科技战在很大程度上阻碍了中国科技公司的首次公开募股机会，这是导致即使这些科技制造商成功上市，潜在的制裁也会影响它们的市场估值的原因。这个句子的意思是说，即使这些科技制造商成功上市，潜在的制裁也会影响它们的市场估值，因为美国科技战在很大程度上阻碍了中国科技公司的首次公开募股机会。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物引起的。    <p>原文例句：Output from China’s hi-tech manufacturing sector grew at the slowest pace on record last year amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States, with the decline weighing on Beijing’s march towards superpower status.</p>    <p>语法讲解：一种句法结构，其中句子主语是动作或状态的承受者，而不是动作或状态的执行者。在被动语态中，be动词（am、is、are）和过去分词一起使用。在这个例句中，grew at the slowest pace on record是过去分词，表示“增长速度创历史新低”，with the decline weighing on Beijing’s march towards superpower status是一个介词短语作状语，表示“下降对北京迈向超级大国地位的影响”。这个句子的意思是说，去年，中国高技术制造业的产值增长速度创历史新低，其原因是经济疲软和美国不断升级的围堵打压，这种下降对北京迈向超级大国地位的影响很重。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023, but this marked the lowest level of growth since records began in 2018</li>
<li>Beijing has pinned its hopes on innovation and technology to power the world’s second-largest economy as it seeks to find new growth engines</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/bb42c49a-576e-447b-9e8e-c4b1bce62af6_f90326de.jpg" /><figcaption>Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Output from China’s hi-tech manufacturing sector grew at the slowest pace on record last year amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States, with the decline weighing on Beijing’s march towards superpower status.</p><p>Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023, falling behind an increase of 5 per cent from the overall manufacturing industry, marking the lowest level of growth since the National Bureau of Statistics started to release the figures in 2018.</p><p>The hi-tech manufacturing industry had seen its growth soar to a record high of 18.2 per cent in 2021 before easing to 7.4 per cent in 2022, having stood at 7.1 per cent in 2020 amid coronavirus-induced disruptions to the global supply chain.</p><p>Beijing has pinned its hopes on innovation and technology to power the world’s second-largest economy as it seeks to find new growth engines to replace the real estate sector, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248695/chinas-population-falls-208-million-14097-billion-2023-births-tumble-adding-demographic-concerns" target="_self" title="">address its demographic challenges</a> and move up the advanced industrial chain.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>Investment in hi-tech manufacturing grew by 9.9 per cent last year, beating the 6.5 per cent increase seen in the overall manufacturing industry, but the financing still registered the slowest pace since records began in 2015.</p><p>Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, said the sector is heading into a cooling period after years of rapid expansion.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248694/china-gdp-beijings-long-do-list-boost-economy-2024" target="_self" title="">“The latest economic data</a> indicate that the whole economic recovery is weak, and market confidence in many sectors is shaky, including tech,” he said.</p><p>“The hi-tech recovery will require China to return to higher economic growth and counteract US decoupling.</p><p>“It also demands the country’s ability to adapt to deglobalisation, but maintain a strong global exporter role.”</p><blockquote>Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public, the potential sanctions would affect their market valuationsChen Zhiwu</blockquote><p>In December, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246040/china-targets-industries-future-2024-humanoid-robots-and-biomedicines-drive-high-quality-economic" target="_self" title="">said it would increase funding</a> to nurture the transformation of traditional manufacturers into hi-tech producers.</p><p>It said China’s hi-tech manufacturing industry was currently facing challenges from insufficient innovation and increasing external pressure.</p><p>Chen Zhiwu, a chair professor of finance at the University of Hong Kong, said headwinds such as risks of a global recession and US-China tensions would continue to exert “extraordinary pressures” on China’s hi-tech push.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies" title="">‘More, better’: premier urges China to focus on application of core technologies</a></h3><p>“The US tech war has largely thwarted Chinese tech companies’ [initial public offering] opportunities. Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public, the potential sanctions would affect their market valuations,” said Chen.</p><p>He added China’s weak economic momentum is also weighing on the market’s overall willingness to invest, with hi-tech manufacturing just one element.</p><p>“The rapid development of hi-tech industries over the past 20 years has provided China with a massive boost to its economic boom, this was partly due to the impact of a stable external environment on investor confidence,” Chen said.</p><p>“Many hi-tech companies I’ve surveyed recently said that market demand for tech products is relatively low, and with uncertain market sentiment, consumers are tightening their wallets so much that companies have to cut back on production.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Saudi Arabia is eyeing a ‘sizeable’ investment to kick off kingdom’s foray into semiconductors</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248768/saudi-arabia-eying-sizeable-investment-kick-kingdoms-foray-semiconductors</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Saudi Arabia's sovereign wealth fund, the Public Investment Fund (PIF), plans to invest significantly in the semiconductor and space industries in 2023. As part of its strategy to diversify the economy away from oil, PIF aims to make substantial investments in these sectors.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Saudi Arabia's PIF to invest heavily in semiconductors and space.</li>    <li>Theme: Saudi Arabia's PIF making major investments in the semiconductor and space industries to reduce dependency on oil.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: PIF's investments aimed at fostering domestic industry, creating a space company, and promoting regional and global leadership.</li>    <li>Main information: PIF's investment plans, focus on developing communications in space, and efforts to attract investment from both US and Chinese technology companies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  沙特阿拉伯的主权财富基金——公共投资基金(PIF)计划在2023年对半导体和太空产业进行“大量投资”。作为其经济多元化战略的一部分，PIF旨在对这些行业进行大量投资。  <ul>    <li>摘要：沙特PIF将大力投资半导体和太空。</li>    <li>主题：沙特PIF在半导体和太空产业进行重大投资，以减少对石油的依赖。</li>    <li>观点：PIF的投资旨在培育国内产业，创建一家太空公司，并促进地区乃至全球的领导地位。</li>    <li>主要信息：PIF的投资计划，专注于发展太空通信，以及为吸引来自美国和中国技术公司的投资而做出的努力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sovereign wealth fund (n.) - 国家财富基金。    <p>原文例句：Saudi Arabia’s sovereign wealth fund is planning to make big investments in both the semiconductor and space industries this year as the kingdom accelerates efforts to diversify its economy away from oil.</p>    <p>例句讲解：sovereign意为主权的，wealth意为财富，fund意为基金。所以这个词语合起来的意思就是国家财富基金。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>diversify (v.) - 多样化，使多样化。    <p>原文例句：The Public Investment Fund is looking at making a “sizeable investment” this year into the semiconductor industry, Saudi Minister of Communications and Information Technology Abdullah Al-Swaha said in an interview at the World Economic Forum in Davos.</p>    <p>例句讲解：diversify意为多样化，使多样化。在这个句子中，PIF计划在半导体行业进行“大量投资”，使其投资组合多样化。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>national space company - 国家航天公司。    <p>原文例句：Alswaha, who is chairman of the kingdom’s Space Agency as well, said the fund will also look to create a national space company to invest and acquire assets in that sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：national意为国家的，space意为航天，company意为公司。所以这个词语合起来的意思就是国家航天公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Saudi Arabia expects to be able to continue to attract investment from both US and Chinese technologies companies, even as tensions between the world’s two largest economies escalate. - 沙特阿拉伯期望能够继续吸引来自美国和中国科技公司的投资，即使世界两大经济体之间的紧张局势正在升级。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复句，主句是Saudi Arabia expects to be able to continue to attract investment，其中主语是Saudi Arabia，谓语是expects to be able to continue to attract investment，宾语是investment。from both US and Chinese technologies companies是一个介词短语，表示投资来自美国和中国科技公司。even as tensions between the world’s two largest economies escalate是一个时间状语从句，表示即使世界两大经济体之间的紧张局势正在升级。这个句子的意思是说，即使世界两大经济体之间的紧张局势正在升级，沙特阿拉伯期望能够继续吸引来自美国和中国科技公司的投资。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作。    <p>原文例句：The Public Investment Fund is looking at making a “sizeable investment” this year into the semiconductor industry, Saudi Minister of Communications and Information Technology Abdullah Al-Swaha said in an interview at the World Economic Forum in Davos.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在进行时是由be动词的现在时态和现在分词构成的。be动词的现在时态包括am、is、are，现在分词是由动词原形加上-ing构成的。现在进行时表示正在进行的动作。在这个例句中，is looking at表示PIF正在考虑在半导体行业进行“大量投资”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Public Investment Fund is looking at making a “sizeable investment” this year into the semiconductor industry, the Saudi communications minister said</li>
<li>PIF plans to make an announcement on a particular champion within the space to lead the Saudi efforts, the minister said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/3343fdd8-ac9c-4f06-8626-ba93903d1af0_6ec679cb.jpg" /><figcaption>Riyadh, capital of Saudi Arabia. Photo: Natalie Wong</figcaption></figure><p>Saudi Arabia’s sovereign wealth fund is planning to make big investments in both the semiconductor and space industries this year as the kingdom accelerates efforts to diversify its economy away from oil.</p><p>The Public Investment Fund is looking at making a “sizeable investment” this year into the semiconductor industry, Saudi Minister of Communications and Information Technology Abdullah Al-Swaha said in an interview at the World Economic Forum in Davos. “They plan to make an announcement on a particular champion within the space to lead the Saudi efforts,” he said, declining to give further details.</p><p>Alswaha, who is chairman of the kingdom’s Space Agency as well, said the fund will also look to create a national space company to invest and acquire assets in that sector. The space industry is “ripe right now” for M&amp;A, he said.</p><p>The fund, known as PIF, has emerged as one of the key parts of Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman’s plan to shake up the Saudi economy and wean it off a reliance on oil sales. It has rapidly built up assets of around US$700 billion after a spending spree on everything from electric carmakers to backing upstart golf tournaments, and plans to control US$1 trillion by 2025.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3226303/saudi-arabia-deepen-ties-hong-kong-using-city-bridge-mainland-chinas-world-class-digital-prowess" title="">Saudi Arabia to use Hong Kong as bridge to China’s tech prowess</a></h3><p>One of its key initiatives has been to develop an auto manufacturing hub on the west coast of the kingdom. US EV maker Lucid Group is already assembling cars from the site, and is set to be joined by Hyundai Motor and Ceer, a brand created by the PIF. The plan involves developing downstream industries that is expected to also include making semiconductors and batteries.</p><p>The kingdom launched its space programme in 2018 and sent astronauts into space last year, as part of a wider plan to invest in the industry.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>“The new space economy is definitely the next trillion-dollar opportunity,” Al-Swaha said. “The kingdom is very bullish on not only becoming a regional leader in this space but also a global leader. The ambition by 2030 is to definitely establish regional leadership and then move on by 2040 to global leadership.”</p><p>A key part of Saudi Arabia’s space investments will be in communications, Alswaha said. “2.6 billion people in 2024 are still not connected and the only way to connect the unconnected is from the skies.”</p><p>Alswaha said that Saudi Arabia expects to be able to continue to attract investment from both US and Chinese technologies companies, even as tensions between the world’s two largest economies escalate. The kingdom “has demonstrated our partnership with both east and west on protecting their intellectual property and patents and any potential technology leakage,” Alswaha said.</p><p>Saudi Arabia is “pro-investment, pro-partnership and open market,” he said. “Anybody that complies with our regulatory, security requirements, serves our national interest, we will work with.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei chases enterprise clients in South Korea as consumers hold onto Samsung, Apple smartphones</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248755/huawei-chases-enterprise-clients-south-korea-consumers-hold-samsung-apple-smartphones</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Huawei is facing difficulties in regaining its position in South Korea's smartphone market due to the dominance of Samsung and Apple, the lingering impact of US sanctions, and local preferences. The company is focusing on enterprise services and cloud computing, aiming to expand its business in the information technology and cultural entertainment industries.  <ul>    <li>Main idea: Huawei's efforts to regain market share in South Korea's smartphone market are hindered by several factors, leading the company to focus on enterprise services and cloud computing.</li>    <li>Challenges: Persistent influence of US sanctions, intense competition with local and international rivals, and preference for Samsung and Apple among consumers and operators.</li>    <li>New Focus: Huawei is shifting its attention to enterprise services like data center networks, campus networks, and storage, as well as expanding its cloud computing division in Korea.</li>    <li>Partnerships: LG Uplus, South Korea's third-largest mobile carrier, is a key partner for Huawei, particularly in the deployment of its 5G base stations.</li>    <li>Goals: Huawei aims to contribute to South Korea's digitalization and carbon neutrality goals, while cultivating 1,000 next-generation information technology professionals.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  华为在韩国智能手机市场重获一席之地的努力面临数重阻碍，包括三星和苹果的市场主导地位、美国制裁的影响余波，以及本地对三星和苹果产品的偏好。该公司正将重心转向企业服务和云计算，目标是拓展其在信息技术和文化娱乐行业的业务。  <ul>    <li>要点：华为想要重获韩国智能手机市场的份额，却受到多重因素影响，因此转向专注于企业服务和云计算。</li>    <li>挑战：面临美国制裁持续影响、与本地及国际对手激烈竞争，以及消费者和运营商对三星和苹果的偏好。</li>    <li>新重点：华为正将注意力转移至企业服务，如数据中心网络、校园网络和存储服务，并拓展其在韩国的云计算部门。</li>    <li>合作伙伴关系：韩国第三大移动运营商 LG Uplus 是华为的关键合作伙伴，尤其在华为 5G 基站的部署上。</li>    <li>目标：华为致力于为韩国的数字化和碳中和目标做出贡献，同时也致力于培养 1000 名下一代信息技术专业人士。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>double-digit (adj.) - 双位数的。    <p>原文例句：Huawei is forecast to move into the spotlight in the smartphone industry in 2024, with projected double-digit growth in global shipments, according to a report published last week by research firm TechInsights.    <p>例句讲解：double-digit 在这里作形容词，意思是“双位数的”。在这个句子中，它表示华为预计将在 2024 年成为智能手机行业的焦点，全球出货量预计将实现两位数增长。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>penetration (n.) - 渗透，普及。    <p>原文例句：South Korea’s smartphone market is 5G-heavy, with a 5G penetration of more than 95 per cent for 2023, so it made little sense for consumers to buy Huawei’s 4G-powered phones,” he said.    <p>例句讲解：penetration 在这里作名词，意思是“渗透，普及”。在这个句子中，它表示韩国智能手机市场 5G 渗透率很高，2023 年达到 95% 以上，因此消费者购买华为的 4G 手机没有任何道理。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take place - 发生，举行。    <P>原文例句：The annual meeting of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) leaders is set to take place in Phnom Penh, Cambodia, next month. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，取）和place（位置，场所）构成的，表示“发生，举行”。在这个例句中，它表示东南亚国家联盟（东盟）领导人年度会议将于下个月在柬埔寨金边举行。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei has tried to launch both premium and affordable smartphones in Korea since 2014, but it has been unable to gain ground “largely due to local operators’ preference for Samsung,” said Woody Oh, service director at TechInsights. “To be successful in the Korean market, [manufacturers] must seek operators’ support.”- 华为自 2014 年以来一直尝试在韩国推出高档和经济实惠的智能手机，但未能取得进展，“主要原因是当地运营商更青睐三星，”TechInsights 服务总监 Woody Oh 说。 “要成功打入韩国市场，[制造商]必须争取运营商的支持。”<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huawei has been unable to gain ground，其中主语是Huawei，谓语是has been unable to gain ground，宾语是ground。自 2014 年以来一直尝试在韩国推出高档和经济实惠的智能手机是一个现在完成时态的动词短语作状语，表示华为自 2014 年以来一直尝试在韩国推出高档和经济实惠的智能手机。largely due to local operators’ preference for Samsung是一个现在分词短语作原因状语，表示主要原因是当地运营商更青睐三星。To be successful in the Korean market, [manufacturers] must seek operators’ support是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示为成功打入韩国市场，[制造商]必须争取运营商的支持。这个句子的意思是说，华为自 2014 年以来一直尝试在韩国推出高档和经济实惠的智能手机，但未能取得进展，主要原因是当地运营商更青睐三星。要成功打入韩国市场，[制造商]必须争取运营商的支持。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用来表示虚拟、假设或愿望的情况。    <p>原文例句：If I had known that, I would never have come. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气通常用在if引导的条件句中，表示虚拟、假设或愿望的情况。在虚拟语气中，过去式用来表示现在或未来的情况，过去完成时用来表示过去的情况。在这个例句中，虚拟语气用在if引导的条件句中，表示如果我知道这一点，我绝不会来。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>that引导的定语从句 - 用于修饰名词或代词。    <p>原文例句：The fact that he was innocent was proved in court. </p>    <p>语法讲解：that引导的定语从句通常用于修饰名词或代词，表示该名词或代词所指的事物或人的属性或特征。在这个例句中，that引导的定语从句修饰名词fact，表示该名词所指的事实或情况。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Huawei is unlikely to gain ground in the South Korean smartphone market, which is dominated by Samsung and Apple, analysts say</li>
<li>The Chinese firm’s new cloud division in the country is eyeing business from the local tech and entertainment industries</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/d6d72751-e72c-48a7-a6f8-b7bfee2bdd85_b0324fe1.jpg" /><figcaption>Huawei is trying to expand its cloud business in South Korea. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>Chinese telecommunications equipment giant Huawei Technologies is poised to make a comeback in the global smartphone market this year, but in South Korea, the company must contend with the lingering impact of US sanctions and intense competition with international and local rivals, according to industry watchers.</p><p>Huawei is forecast to move into the spotlight in the smartphone industry in 2024, with projected double-digit growth in global shipments, according to a report published last week by research firm TechInsights, which described the Chinese company as a potential “big surprise”.</p><p>But in Korea – home to smartphone and semiconductor titan Samsung Electronics – Huawei is struggling to expand its market share or secure trust from local partners amid the US-China tech rivalry, analysts said.</p><p>The Shenzhen-based company, which has been offering various products and services to Korean customers for two decades, has been effectively absent from the country’s smartphone market in the past few years due to its “inability to source 5G chipsets”, said Abhilash Kumar, an analyst at TechInsights.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/425f24ee-d4dd-4d9c-94ca-0de11642cc70_34f54c2a.jpg" title="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“South Korea’s smartphone market is 5G-heavy, with a 5G penetration of more than 95 per cent for 2023, so it made little sense for consumers to buy Huawei’s 4G-powered phones,” he said.</p><p>Since 2019, Washington has barred the Chinese company, on national security grounds, from accessing US technologies including Google’s most popular apps, which are commonly pre-installed in Android phones sold by rivals like Samsung. That has dealt a heavy blow to Huawei’s overseas sales.</p><p>Huawei, which briefly surpassed Samsung to lead global smartphone shipments in early 2020, has dropped out of the global top five since 2021. Last year, the world’s five biggest smartphone vendors were Apple, Samsung, Xiaomi, Transsion and Vivo, according to a report published on Monday by research firm IDC.</p><p>In Korea, Huawei had a market share of just 0.1 per cent as of December, far lagging Samsung’s 68.7 per cent and Apple’s 26.5 per cent, numbers from online database Statcounter showed.</p><p>Huawei made a splash in its home market China last August with the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233636/huaweis-mate-60-pro-will-help-it-take-lost-ground-china-can-it-help-smartphone-giant-regain-global" target="_self" title="">surprise launch of the Mate 60 Pro</a> handset equipped with an advanced, domestically-developed 5G chip. The company is reportedly aiming to bring its handsets back to some overseas markets, including in Europe.</p><p>Still, “it looks unlikely” that the firm would return to the Korean smartphone market, Kumar said.</p><p>“Now that Huawei might have managed to source 5G chipsets locally,” he said. “It’s still difficult for it because [South Korea] is Samsung- and Apple-heavy and doesn’t have much acceptance for Chinese vendors.”</p><p>Huawei has tried to launch both premium and affordable smartphones in Korea since 2014, but it has been unable to gain ground “largely due to local operators’ preference for Samsung,” said Woody Oh, service director at TechInsights. “To be successful in the Korean market, [manufacturers] must seek operators’ support.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Customers at an Apple store in Hanam, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/b995137c-2916-4199-9a6d-622ad91aadb4_a66cec46.jpg" title="Customers at an Apple store in Hanam, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Customers at an Apple store in Hanam, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Amid difficulties in the consumer market, Huawei is pinning its hopes on enterprise services, according to Wang Balian, CEO of Huawei Korea.</p><p>The Huawei-supported 5G network used by Korean carriers ranked first in global tests last year, Wang said at a year-end event in Seoul last month. The company’s enterprise products include data centre networks, campus networks and storage services.</p><p>Wang said the company was also expanding its foothold in the cloud computing market, having established a cloud division in Korea last year in hope of serving the information technology and cultural entertainment industries.</p><p>The executive highlighted Huawei’s commitment to the Korean market despite running into controversies last year, when SK Hynix – the second-largest memory chip maker in Korea – announced it was investigating how its products ended up in the Mate 60 Pro.</p><p>Hynix said at the time that it “no longer does business with Huawei since the introduction of the US restrictions against the company”.</p><p>One of Huawei’s key business partners in Korea is LG Electronics. Wang called LG Uplus, South Korea’s third-largest mobile carrier and the country’s sole mobile network operator using Huawei’s 5G base stations, has been touted as one of the Chinese firm’s “important global clients”.</p><p>Looking to 2024, Wang said Huawei Korea, which has more than 230 employees, planned to help the country achieve its digitisation and carbon neutrality goals, while continuing to support the cultivation of 1,000 next-generation information technology professionals.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Should we let AI take over mundane work? Not so fast</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3248614/should-we-let-ai-take-over-mundane-work-not-so-fast</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Generative AI like ChatGPT may increase productivity, but it can also limit supplementary learning. Outsourcing tasks to AI can lead to reduced motivation and loss of inter-task learning, potentially hindering long-term skill development. The impact on human capability should be carefully considered when deploying AI.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Generative AI's impact on human capability: advantages and potential drawbacks.</li>    <li>Theme: The trade-off between productivity gains and learning opportunities with generative AI implementation.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: AI should be deployed with care, considering learning and training objectives, task interdependence, and necessary training and support.</li>    <li>Main information: The study on Python maintainers' productivity after introducing a crowdsourcing program; the importance of inter-task learning and its potential loss with generative AI; suggestions for managing generative AI use in organizations and schools.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  像ChatGPT这样的生成式人工智能可能会提高生产力，但它也会限制补充学习。将任务外包给人工智能可能会导致动机降低和任务间学习的丧失，从而可能阻碍长期的技能发展。在部署人工智能时，应仔细考虑对人类能力的影响。  <ul>    <li>摘要：生成式人工智能对人类能力的影响：优势和潜在的缺点。</li>    <li>主题：在实施生成式人工智能时，权衡生产力提升和学习机会之间的关系。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能应谨慎部署，考虑学习和培训目标、任务的相互依赖性，以及必要的培训和支持。</li>    <li>主要信息：在引入众包程序后对Python维护人员的工作效率进行的研究；任务间学习的重要性和生成式人工智能可能导致的丧失；对企业和学校管理生成式人工智能使用的建议。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>outperform (v.) - /ˌaʊtˈpɜːrfɔːrm/ 优于，胜过。    <p>原文例句：ChatGPT outperformed physicians in terms of both quality of information and empathy. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由out（在……之外）和perform（表演，执行）组成，表示“优于，胜过”。在这个例句中，它表示ChatGPT在信息质量和同情心方面都优于医生。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>intertwined (adj.) - /ˌɪntərˈtwaɪnd/ 交织的，紧密相连的。    <p>原文例句：We might wish to discourage AI’s use for deeply intertwined tasks. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由inter（相互）和twined（缠绕）组成的，表示“交织的，紧密相连的”。在这个例句中，它表示我们可能希望阻止AI用于深度交织的任务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>intrinsic (adj.) - /ɪnˈtrɪnsɪk/ 内在的，固有的。    <p>原文例句：People are intrinsically lazy. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin的intrinsecus，表示“内在的，固有的”。在这个例句中，它表示人们具有内在的惰性。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>supplement learning - 补充学习。    <p>原文例句：However, it might actually limit the supplementary learning that occurs when people do certain tasks. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由supplement（补充）和learning（学习）组成，表示“补充学习”。在这个例句中，它表示使用生成式AI可能会限制人们在做某些任务时获得的补充学习。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：ChatGPT outperformed physicians in terms of both quality of information and empathy.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示ChatGPT在信息质量和同情心方面都优于医生。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>task interdependence - 任务相互依存。    <p>原文例句：Start classifying tasks by nature, in terms of whether they are interrelated. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由task（任务），interdependence（相互依存）组成的，表示“任务相互依存”。在这个例句中，它表示开始按照任务的性质对它们进行分类，比如它们是否相互相关。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The official Python maintainers not only discovered fewer bugs after the IBB program, they also made fewer enhancements to Python. - 官方的 Python 维护者在 IBB 计划后不仅发现的 bug 更少，而且对 Python 所做的改进也更少。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The official Python maintainers made fewer enhancements to Python，其中主语是The official Python maintainers，谓语是made，宾语是fewer enhancements to Python。not only ... but also表示“不仅……而且……”，连接两个并列的谓语，表示两个动作或情况同时发生。在这个例句中，它表示官方的Python维护者不仅发现了更少的bug，而且对Python所做的改进也更少。这个句子的意思是说，官方的Python维护者在IBB计划后不仅发现的bug更少，而且对Python所做的改进也更少。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The IBB program should have made the Python maintainers’ job easier, giving them more time to perform other tasks and hence increasing their productivity in those tasks. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + been + 过去分词。其中had是have的过去式，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示在过去某个时间之前已经完成的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示IBB程序本应使Python维护人员的工作更容易，给他们更多的时间来执行其他任务，从而提高他们在这些任务中的工作效率。had made表示在过去某个时间之前已经完成的动作或状态，即IBB程序应该已经让Python维护人员的工作更容易了。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人对某件事的主观看法或假设。    <p>原文例句：We might wish to discourage AI’s use for deeply intertwined tasks. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个语态，表示说话人对某件事的主观看法或假设。结构是：助动词（may、might、should、could、would）+ 动词原形。在这个例句中，它表示我们可能希望阻止AI用于深度交织的任务。might wish to discourage表示说话人对阻止AI用于深度交织任务这一行为的主观看法或假设。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>It may seem that outsourcing tasks to generative AI like ChatGPT could increase productivity</li>
<li>However, it might actually limit the supplementary learning that occurs when people do certain tasks, so AI must be deployed with care</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/5a7e78e1-6d56-4263-b127-4cf22193c5c2_b285be82.jpg" /><figcaption>After the public gained access to OpenAI’s chatbot, which can create human-like written responses to simple user prompts, in November 2022, it shifted how people think about artificial intelligence. Photo: TNS</figcaption></figure><p>Generative artificial intelligence, especially OpenAI’s implementation of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243449/chatgpt-one-year-how-openais-chatbot-brought-generative-artificial-intelligence-public-consciousness" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT,</a> has opened up new possibilities for the creation of intelligent content. In fact, AI-generated content is so good that it reads almost as if it was written by a human being.</p><p>For example, a study by researchers from US universities published in May found that when answering random patient questions from a social media platform, ChatGPT outperformed physicians in terms of both quality of information and empathy. And OpenAI has a said GPT4, the state-of-the-art model underlying ChatGPT Plus, could score in the top 10 per cent in the SAT reading exam for college admissions, the GRE verbal test for graduate school admissions and the uniform bar exam for lawyers.</p><p>This tool is expected to be deployed in companies and other organisations to enhance worker productivity. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3227884/chatgpt-helps-hong-kong-students-critical-thinking-teachers-stay-ahead-human-touch" target="_self" title="">Schools and teachers</a> are also keen to embrace it. Many universities now <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3233269/hong-kong-universities-relent-rise-chatgpt-ai-tools-teaching-and-assignments-keep-eye-out-plagiarism" target="_self" title="">allow students</a> to use generative AI in course work and assignments. Some local institutions offer free access to ChatGPT, encouraging students to use it in school.</p><p>However, generative AI has its limitations. Because the content it produces is generated from a complex large-language model instead of logically developed and based on facts, AI sometimes “hallucinates”, that is, produces incorrect or misleading results, due to insufficient training data, bias and incorrect assumptions. In June, two lawyers in the US <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223490/us-lawyer-sorry-after-chatgpt-creates-fake-cases" target="_self" title="">were sanctioned</a> for using ChatGPT to produce a legal brief with fictitious case citations. They claimed they weren’t aware ChatGPT could make up cases.</p><p>This case raises an important question: how does generative AI affect human capability when people no longer need to develop logical arguments and verify facts when creating content?</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Using generative AI to produce work is akin to outsourcing it to other people. Thus, we can infer its impact on human capability by referencing outsourcing.</p><p>We conducted research on how contributions to the well-known programming language, Python, changed after the introduction of a crowdsourcing program called Internet Bug Bounty (IBB), which rewards people for finding security vulnerabilities in open source software – but excludes the official system maintainers, who have been reporting and fixing bugs, and making enhancements, from the reward.</p><p>The IBB program should have made the Python maintainers’ job easier, giving them more time to perform other tasks and hence increasing their productivity in those tasks.</p><p>Interestingly, we found the opposite. The official Python maintainers not only discovered fewer bugs after the IBB program, they also made fewer enhancements to Python. This means their overall productivity fell after bug reporting was outsourced.</p><p>We looked at many reasons for the drop in productivity, including a loss of motivation due to not being rewarded in the IBB program. We concluded that it was mainly due to a lack of inter-task learning. There was a bigger drop in productivity among Python maintainers who reported more bugs before the IBB program than those who reported fewer. The drop was also bigger when the bug reporting and enhancement tasks were more closely related.</p><p>We surveyed a number of Python maintainers, most of whom said that finding vulnerabilities helped them learn and gain ideas for how to enhance the program. This implies that when performing a task, we not only contribute to the outcome, we learn at the same time.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Internet Bug Bounty program, which rewards people for identifying security vulnerabilities in open source software, should have helped increase the productivity of those whose job it is to find and fix bugs, but that has not necessarily happened. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1021" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/d1810c19-5739-4f42-8dda-8bdb3366e566_50b374a4.jpg" title="The Internet Bug Bounty program, which rewards people for identifying security vulnerabilities in open source software, should have helped increase the productivity of those whose job it is to find and fix bugs, but that has not necessarily happened. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Internet Bug Bounty program, which rewards people for identifying security vulnerabilities in open source software, should have helped increase the productivity of those whose job it is to find and fix bugs, but that has not necessarily happened. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>This inter-task learning side-effect is illuminating. It suggests that learning and other capabilities may be sacrificed when we enjoy the power and convenience of generative AI. The short-term gain in productivity could be offset by the long-term loss in capability. Worse, this capability may be key to our contribution to future tasks, including, possibly, intelligent knowledge work.</p><p>So how should generative AI use be managed in an organisation? First, distinguish between objectives – are we seeking work output or learning and training? In most places, work output may be the priority, so it would be reasonable to actively deploy generative AI tools. Even so, we must be aware this may slow employees’ learning of how to perform tasks.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3247902/how-ai-development-fostered-digital-sweatshop-and-why-it-matters-technologys-future" title="">How AI development has fostered a digital ‘sweatshop’ in poor countries</a></h3><p>Second, start classifying tasks by nature, in terms of whether they are interrelated. Generative AI tools may be better deployed for tasks that have little relation to other tasks, for example, pure automation jobs. We might wish to discourage AI’s use for deeply intertwined tasks.</p><p>Third, more training should be provided once generative AI is deployed. People are intrinsically lazy. If we let them use generative AI without supplementing it with learning opportunities, their ability may deteriorate over time.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>At school, the priority should be learning rather than work output. We must seek to prevent the unrestrained use of generative AI in homework or assignments. If students don’t do homework themselves but outsource it entirely to AI, they may soon lose the ability to reason, innovate and produce more advanced knowledge.</p><p>We must revisit the common question, “Why waste time doing mundane work when AI can do it for us?” This is a dangerous sentiment because we do work not only to produce an outcome, but to learn as well. Such learning builds the foundation for future knowledge production.</p><p>We should not get carried away by generative AI, thinking that only work outcomes matter. The learning itself is equally important, if not more so.</p><p><strong>Kai-Lung Hui is Elman Family Professor of Business and senior associate dean at Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Business School</strong></p><p><strong>Jiali Zhou is an assistant professor at the American University in Washington DC</strong></p><p><strong>The views expressed here are the authors’ own</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Davos 2024: OpenAI CEO Altman, Time owner Benioff disagree on AI’s use of copyrighted content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248702/davos-2024-openai-ceo-altman-time-owner-benioff-disagree-ais-use-copyrighted-content</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Salesforce CEO and Time owner Marc Benioff calls on AI companies to standardize payments to content creators fairly. OpenAI CEO Sam Altman argues that training data is not as valuable as its owners perceive. AI companies face increasing scrutiny for using copyrighted materials without permission. Publications like Time, CNN, Fox, and The New York Times are negotiating with OpenAI for licensing agreements. Altman maintains that OpenAI does not use content without permission and believes fair data pricing standards are necessary. Both Benioff and Altman express concerns about the impact of AI on the democratic process, particularly through social media.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: AI companies' use of copyrighted content raises concerns; fair payment and responsible AI practices are crucial.</li>    <li>Theme: Balancing the interests of AI companies and content creators; addressing ethical and legal implications of AI's use of copyrighted materials.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Benioff emphasizes the need for standardized payments to content creators, while Altman defends OpenAI's practices and highlights the importance of fair data pricing.</li>    <li>Main information: Allegations of stolen training data; ongoing negotiations between media outlets and AI companies; OpenAI's partnerships with news agencies; concerns about AI's impact on democracy and the role of social media.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Salesforce 首席执行官兼时代杂志所有者马克·贝尼奥夫呼吁人工智能公司标准化向内容创作者支付的费用，以公平对待他们。OpenAI 首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼认为，训练数据并没有其所有者认为的那么有价值。人工智能公司因在未经许可的情况下使用受版权保护的材料而面临越来越多的审查。时代、CNN、福克斯和纽约时报等出版物正在与 OpenAI 就许可协议进行谈判。阿尔特曼坚持认为，OpenAI 不会在未经许可的情况下使用内容，并认为有必要制定公平的数据定价标准。贝尼奥夫和阿尔特曼都对人工智能在许多国家选举年期间对民主进程构成的风险表示担忧，特别是通过社交媒体。  <ul>    <li>摘要：人工智能公司使用受版权保护的内容引发担忧；公平付费和负责任的人工智能实践至关重要。</li>    <li>主题：平衡人工智能公司和内容创作者的利益；解决人工智能使用受版权保护材料的伦理和法律影响。</li>    <li>观点：贝尼奥夫强调需要向内容创作者支付标准化费用，而阿尔特曼则为 OpenAI 的做法辩护，并强调公平数据定价的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：窃取训练数据指控；媒体机构和人工智能公司之间正在进行的谈判；OpenAI 与新闻机构的合作伙伴关系；对人工智能对民主进程的影响和社交媒体角色的担忧。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>standardise (v.) - /ˈstændəˌdaɪz/ 使标准化。    <p>原文例句：AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly, says Salesforce CEO and Time owner Marc Benioff. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由stand（立场，观点）和-ardise（标准化）构成的，表示“使标准化”。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能公司应该标准化支付给内容创作者的费用，以公平对待他们。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>negotiate (v.) - /nɪˈɡoʊʃieɪt/ 谈判。    <p>原文例句：Time is among publications currently negotiating with ChatGPT maker OpenAI to license their news work, as first reported by Bloomberg. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由neg（否定）和otium（闲暇）组成，意为“从事商业或政治活动”。在这个例句中，它表示Time正在与ChatGPT的制造商OpenAI进行谈判，以获得他们在新闻作品上的许可权，这是彭博社最先报道的。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>copyright (n.) - /ˈkɔːpɪˌraɪt/ 版权。    <p>原文例句：There is increasing scrutiny on the makers of large language models that power generative AI services, such as ChatGPT, over their use of copyrighted materials.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由copy（复制）和right（权利）组成，表示“著作权”。在这个例句中，它表示对 ChatGPT 等生成式人工智能服务的制造商越来越严格审查，这些服务使用受版权保护的材料。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>archives (n.) - /ˈɑːrkaɪvz/ 档案，档案馆。    <p>原文例句：In July, OpenAI signed an agreement with the Associated Press to access some of the news agency’s archives.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于希腊语，由archaios（古代的）和graphe（文字）组成，意为“古代的文字或文件”。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI 在 7 月与美联社签署了一项协议，以访问该新闻机构的一些档案。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>standardise payments - 标准化支付。    <p>原文例句：AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly, says Salesforce CEO and Time owner Marc Benioff.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示人工智能公司应该标准化支付给内容创作者的费用，以公平对待他们。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>license agreements - 许可协议。    <p>原文例句：Publications like Time, CNN, Fox, and The New York Times are negotiating with OpenAI for licensing agreements.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示出版物与 OpenAI 正在就许可协议进行谈判。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>social media - 社交媒体。    <p>原文例句：When asked whether AI presented risks to the democratic process in an election year for many countries, Benioff said his biggest concern is still social media.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示社会媒体。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Salesforce markets its AI-powered software features as including a “trust layer” to prevent the misuse of customer data. - Salesforce公司在其人工智能驱动的软件功能中包含一个“信任层”，以防止客户数据的滥用。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Salesforce markets its AI-powered software features，其中主语是Salesforce，谓语是markets，宾语是its AI-powered software features。as including a “trust layer” to prevent the misuse of customer data是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示Salesforce公司在其人工智能驱动的软件功能中包含一个“信任层”，以防止客户数据的滥用。这个句子的意思是说，Salesforce公司在其人工智能驱动的软件功能中包含一个“信任层”，以防止客户数据的滥用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 用来比较两个或两个以上的事物或人的差异。    <p>原文例句：Negotiations between media outlets and AI companies are ongoing, but Altman downplayed the significance of such deals relative to the magnitude of the data OpenAI has already collected.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是指比较两个或两个以上的事物或人的差异。比较级通常是通过在形容词或副词的词尾加上-er或more来构成的。在这个例句中，more significant是形容词significant的比较级，表示“更加重要的”。这个句子的意思是说，媒体机构和人工智能公司之间的谈判正在进行，但 Altman淡化了此类交易相对于 OpenAI 已经收集的数据规模的重要性。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly, says Salesforce CEO and Time owner Marc Benioff</li>
<li>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman says training data often is not as valuable as its owners think it is</li>
</ul><p>Marc Benioff, the Salesforce chief executive who also owns Time magazine, said artificial intelligence (AI) companies ripped off intellectual property to build their technology.</p><p>“All the training data has been stolen,” Benioff said on Tuesday in an interview at Bloomberg House at the World Economic Forum in Davos. Content from media outlets including Time and The New York Times surfaces in results from AI companies, he said.</p><p>There is increasing scrutiny on the makers of large language models that power generative AI services, such as ChatGPT, over their use of copyrighted materials. Benioff’s Time is among publications currently negotiating with ChatGPT maker OpenAI to license their news work, as first reported by Bloomberg.</p><p>Other companies include Warner Bros Discovery’s CNN and Fox. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3246432/new-york-times-sues-chatgpt-maker-openai-microsoft-copyright-infringement-unlawful-use-stories-train" target="_self" title="">The New York Times sued OpenAI</a> and its partner Microsoft in November for using the publication’s articles without permission.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/256a3cae-17dc-4815-bfb6-2b8f632dd1af_a66cec46.jpg" title="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Nobody really exactly knows” what a fair price for this data is, Benioff added, but AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly. Benioff’s Salesforce markets its AI-powered software features as including a “trust layer” to prevent the misuse of customer data.</p><p>OpenAI has disputed that it used protected material without permission. CEO Sam Altman, in an interview earlier on Tuesday with Bloomberg, said training data often is not as valuable as its owners think it is.</p><p>“We do not want to train on The New York Times data,” Altman said, adding that research is more focused on learning from small amounts of high-quality data. It should be possible to avoid any news content that is off limits, he said.</p><p>OpenAI has been striking partnerships for specific uses of news content and more are coming, Altman said. “I think there’s going to be great new ways to consume and monetise news.”</p><p>In July, OpenAI signed an agreement with the Associated Press to access some of the news agency’s archives. OpenAI also reached <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content" target="_self" title="">a three-year deal in December with Axel Springer</a> to use the German media company’s work for an undisclosed sum.</p><p>When asked whether AI presented risks to the democratic process in an election year for many countries, Benioff said his biggest concern is still social media. “Regulators have not done their job,” he added.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Davos 2024: Microsoft CEO ‘comfortable’ with OpenAI non-profit board structure despite Altman ousting</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248699/davos-2024-microsoft-ceo-comfortable-openai-non-profit-board-structure-despite-altman-ousting</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In a recent interview, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella expressed his satisfaction with the governance structure of OpenAI, acknowledging the company's ownership of a minority stake. He addressed concerns raised by employees following the brief removal of OpenAI's CEO, Sam Altman. The current focus is on completing the board and implementing structural changes to enhance governance. Meanwhile, Microsoft's investment in OpenAI's computing capabilities is viewed as a bold and unconventional move. Competition authorities in various regions are scrutinizing Microsoft's stake in OpenAI and its impact on market dynamics.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Examining Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella's perspective on OpenAI's governance structure, investments, and regulatory scrutiny.</li>    <li>Theme: Microsoft's unique partnership with OpenAI, including non-controlling ownership, governance challenges, and competitive implications.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Nadella emphasizes the pro-competitive nature of the Microsoft-OpenAI deal and defends the investment in computing power.</li>    <li>Main information: Nadella's comments on OpenAI's governance; Microsoft's minority stake and its distinction from full ownership; ongoing governance reforms; scrutiny from competition authorities; and the significance of Microsoft's investment in OpenAI's computing capabilities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉在最近一次采访中表示，他对 OpenAI 的治理结构感到满意，承认该公司拥有少数股份。他回应了 OpenAI 首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼短暂离职后员工提出的担忧。目前，工作重点是完成董事会并实施结构性改革以加强治理。与此同时，微软对 OpenAI 计算能力的投资被视为一项大胆且非传统举措。各地区的竞争当局正在审查微软对 OpenAI 的股份及其对市场动态的影响。  <ul>    <li>摘要：审视微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉对 OpenAI 治理结构、投资和监管审查的看法。</li>    <li>主题：微软与 OpenAI 的独特合作伙伴关系，包括非控股所有权、治理挑战和竞争影响。</li>    <li>观点：纳德拉强调了微软与 OpenAI 交易的竞争性质，并为对计算能力的投资进行了辩护。</li>    <li>主要信息：纳德拉对OpenAI治理的评论；微软的少数股权及其与完全所有权的区别；正在进行的治理改革；竞争当局的审查；微软对 OpenAI 计算能力投资的重要性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>governance (n.) - /ˈgʌvənəns/ 治理，管理。    <p>原文例句：Satya Nadella, speaking on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum’s meeting in Davos, says he has ‘no issues with any structure’ at OpenAI. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“Governance”表示统治国家或组织的系统或方法。在这个例句中，它指的是 OpenAI 的治理结构，即处理组织事务的系统或方法，这句话的意思是说微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉在达沃斯举行的世界经济论坛会议的场外表示，他对 OpenAI 的任何结构都没有意见。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>scrutinize (v.) - /ˈskruːtɪnaɪz/ 详细检查，仔细审查。    <p>原文例句：Competition authorities in Europe, Britain and reportedly the United States have started looking closely at the Microsoft-OpenAI relationship. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“Scrutinize”表示仔细检查或检查某物，特别是为了寻找瑕疵或错误。在这个例句中，它指的是竞争当局开始仔细检查微软和 OpenAI 之间的关系，这句话的意思是说欧洲，英国和据报道的美国竞争当局已经开始密切关注微软与 OpenAI 的关系。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>pro-competitive - 有利于竞争的。    <p>原文例句：“Partnerships is one avenue of, in fact, having competition,” he said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“Pro-competitive”表示采取有利于竞争或防止垄断的措施或政策。在这个例句中，它指的是合作伙伴关系是引入竞争的一种方式，这句话的意思是说，纳德拉说：“合作伙伴关系实际上是一种引入竞争的方式”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The surprise November dismissal of OpenAI’s CEO Sam Altman over an alleged communication breakdown triggered a crisis at the start-up behind ChatGPT, in which employees threatened to resign en masse and go work for Microsoft, which is backing OpenAI with billions of dollars. - 由于涉嫌沟通中断，11 月 OpenAI 首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼意外被解雇，引发了这家支持 ChatGPT 的初创公司陷入危机，员工们威胁要集体辞职，并为支持 OpenAI 数十亿美元的微软工作。    <p>句子分析：这个句子很长，包含多个从句。主句是“The surprise November dismissal ... triggered a crisis”，其中主语是“The surprise November dismissal ...”，谓语是“triggered a crisis”。“over an alleged communication breakdown”是一个介词短语，作原因状语，表示解雇的原因是涉嫌沟通中断。“in which employees threatened to resign en masse and go work for Microsoft”是一个定语从句，修饰“crisis”，表示危机中员工们威胁要集体辞职，并为支持 OpenAI 数十亿美元的微软工作。“which is backing OpenAI with billions of dollars”是一个非限制性定语从句，也修饰“Microsoft”，表示微软是支持 OpenAI 数十亿美元的公司。这个句子的意思是说，由于涉嫌沟通中断，11 月 OpenAI 首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼意外被解雇，引发了这家支持 ChatGPT 的初创公司陷入危机，员工们威胁要集体辞职，并为支持 OpenAI 数十亿美元的微软工作。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft’s investments in computing power and years-old bet on OpenAI before its ChatGPT fame, Nadella said, were a “highly risky bet” and “not all conventional wisdom”.  </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。其结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。在这个例句中，“Microsoft’s investments ...”是主语，“were”是谓语，其中“been”是助动词，“a”是不定冠词，“highly risky bet”和“not all conventional wisdom”是宾语。这句话的意思是，纳德拉说，微软在计算能力上的投资和在 ChatGPT 声名鹊起之前对 OpenAI 多年来的押注，是一次“高风险的赌注”，而且“并非所有人都认同”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Satya Nadella, speaking on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum’s meeting in Davos, says he has ‘no issues with any structure’ at OpenAI</li>
<li>The fact that Microsoft does not fully own OpenAI distinguished their deal in a pro-competitive way, according to Nadella</li>
</ul><p>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella on Tuesday said he had no issue with partner OpenAI’s governance structure, two months after the start-up’s non-profit board temporarily ousted its chief executive without regard to investors’ interests.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3241992/chatgpt-maker-open-ai-pushes-out-co-founder-and-ceo-sam-altman-says-he-wasnt-consistently-candid" target="_self" title="">surprise November dismissal</a> of OpenAI’s CEO Sam Altman over an alleged communication breakdown triggered a crisis at the start-up behind ChatGPT, in which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242258/nearly-all-openai-staff-threaten-go-microsoft-unless-board-quits-investors-try-bring-back-altman" target="_self" title="">employees threatened to resign en masse</a> and go work for Microsoft, which is backing OpenAI with billions of dollars.</p><p>“I’m comfortable. I have no issues with any structure,” Nadella said at a Bloomberg News event on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum’s annual meeting in Davos.</p><p>OpenAI’s board, charged with protecting the start-up non-profit’s mission to develop powerful artificial intelligence that benefits humanity, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242394/microsoft-pushes-changes-openai-after-board-start-sought-merger-rival-anthropic" target="_self" title="">ultimately restored Altman</a> days later and now is in the process of filling out its membership.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1309" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/0651d6dd-f234-47b6-97b5-741fcb1f1268_28052076.jpg" title="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“I expect us to make a lot of progress on that in the coming months,” OpenAI CEO Altman said at a later Bloomberg event in Davos. “And then after that, the new board will take a look at the governance structure.”</p><p>“We’ll go look at it from all angles,” he said.</p><p>Microsoft has now secured a non-voting observer position on the OpenAI board.</p><p>Competition authorities in Europe, Britain and reportedly the United States have started looking closely at the Microsoft-OpenAI relationship. Their agreement guarantees the Windows maker large chunks of the start-up’s profits depending on certain conditions, a person briefed on the terms has said.</p><p>According to Nadella, the fact that Microsoft does not fully own OpenAI distinguished their deal in a pro-competitive way.</p><p>“Partnerships is one avenue of, in fact, having competition,” he said.</p><p>Microsoft’s investments in computing power and years-old bet on OpenAI before its ChatGPT fame, Nadella said, were a “highly risky bet” and “not all conventional wisdom”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
