<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Chinese state media calls for crackdown on deceptive pricing in live-streaming e-commerce</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248938/chinese-state-media-calls-crackdown-deceptive-pricing-live-streaming-e-commerce</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In recent years, live-streaming e-commerce has seen a rapid growth in China, but it has also been plagued by deceptive pricing tactics, such as marking up the original price and offering fake discounts. This has led to calls for stricter regulatory scrutiny of the sector, with the Economic Daily urging the government to clarify the responsibilities of e-commerce platforms, merchants, and broadcasters in these cases.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Deceptive pricing tactics in live-streaming e-commerce hinder the healthy development of the economy and harm consumers' rights.</li>    <li>Theme: The government calls for tighter regulatory scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live-streaming e-commerce to promote the healthy development of the sector.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The Economic Daily criticizes live streamers for misleading consumers with tactics such as fake price comparisons and exaggerations.</li>    <li>Main information: The Economic Daily urges the government to improve regulations for the sector and increase the penalties for price fraud; e-commerce platforms need to take the initiative to crack down on dubious live-streaming practices.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  近年来，中国直播电商快速发展，但同时也存在标价欺诈等乱象。对此，经济日报刊文呼吁政府加强对直播电商的监管，明确电子商务平台、商家、主播等在价格欺诈中的责任。  <ul>    <li>摘要：直播电商价格欺诈乱象阻碍经济健康发展，损害消费者权益。</li>    <li>主题：政府要求加强对直播电商价格欺诈乱象的监管，促进直播电商行业的健康发展。</li>    <li>观点：经济日报批评部分直播主通过虚构原价、夸大折扣等手段误导消费者。</li>    <li>主要信息：经济日报呼吁政府完善直播电商监管制度，加大对价格欺诈行为的处罚力度；电商平台要主动作为，严厉打击虚假宣传、价格欺诈等违法行为。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>exponential (adj.) - 指数的，指数级增长的。    <p>原文例句：Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years, with sales jumping 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“exponential”是“exponent（指数）”的形容词形式，表示“指数的，指数级增长的”。在这个例句中，“exponential growth”意为“指数级增长”，指直播电商在近年来快速增长。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>deceptive (adj.) - 欺骗性的，误导性的。    <p>原文例句：Chinese state media Economic Daily has called for tighter regulatory scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming, as the country’s e-commerce players increasingly turn to these campaigns to lure customers and drive sales amid fierce competition and macro-economic headwinds.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“deceptive”意为“欺骗性的，误导性的”。在这个例句中，“deceptive pricing tactics”指“欺骗性的定价策略”，即直播电商中常见的虚假原价、虚假折扣等行为。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>turn to - 求助于，诉诸于。    <p>原文例句：In an opinion piece on Thursday, the official media blasted some live streamers for misleading consumers with tactics such as fake price comparisons and exaggerations, adding that more than 5,000 broadcasters were penalised last year for price manipulation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“turn to”意为“求助于，诉诸于”。在这个例句中，“e-commerce players increasingly turn to these campaigns”指“电商商家越来越多地诉诸于这些活动”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The responsibilities of e-commerce platforms, merchants and broadcasters should be clarified in these cases, the media outlet said. - 该媒体表示，在这些情况下，应明确电子商务平台、商家和主播的责任。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The responsibilities should be clarified，其中主语是The responsibilities，谓语是should be clarified，宾语是in these cases。e-commerce platforms, merchants and broadcasters是一个并列结构，作主语The responsibilities的同位语，表示电子商务平台、商家和主播的责任。the media outlet said是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示这一观点是由媒体提出的。这个句子的意思是说，在这些情况下，应明确电子商务平台、商家和主播的责任，这一观点是由媒体提出的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成式 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with broad iPhone discounts.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成式由have/has + 过去分词构成，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个例句中，Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with broad iPhone discounts是一个现在完成式的句子，表示苹果公司从过去的某个时间开始一直持续到现在的行为是“更加深入地参与到中国的智能手机价格战中”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission</li>
<li>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years, with sales jumping 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/da9d4337-120c-49ea-b242-d1f49b587f18_9b05dbbb.jpg" /><figcaption>TikTok Shop and an online influencer prepare for a live-streaming session of selling goods from the Consumer Electronics Show (CES), Las Vegas, January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese state media Economic Daily has called for tighter regulatory scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming, as the country’s e-commerce players increasingly turn to these campaigns to lure customers and drive sales amid fierce competition and macro-economic headwinds.</p><p>In an opinion piece on Thursday, the official media blasted some live streamers for misleading consumers with tactics such as fake price comparisons and exaggerations, adding that more than 5,000 broadcasters were penalised last year for price manipulation.</p><p>Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247160/bytedances-douyin-makes-instant-refunds-mandatory-following-pdd-taobao-and-jdcom-amid-fierce-e" title="">Chinese version of TikTok makes instant refunds mandatory amid e-commerce rivalry</a></h3><p>“Live-streaming e-commerce has become an important part of the digital economy, but price fraud and other chaotic practices have hindered the high-quality development of the economy,” the article said. These tactics not only hurt consumers’ rights but also damaged the reputation of the live-streaming industry, it added.</p><p>The Economic Daily urged the government to improve regulations for the sector and increase the penalties for price fraud. The responsibilities of e-commerce platforms, merchants and broadcasters should be clarified in these cases, the media outlet said.</p><p>E-commerce platforms need to take the initiative to crack down on dubious live-streaming practices, the article urged, and they should impose harsher penalties and even ban those that repeatedly commit violations.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above" title="">Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with broad iPhone discounts</a></h3><p>The call for stricter oversight comes as e-commerce platforms are increasingly relying on live streaming to attract consumers amid fierce domestic competition and weaker consumer spending.</p><p>Key players in the field include traditional e-commerce platforms such as Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao, as well as short video apps like ByteDance’s Douyin and Kuaishou Technology. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years. Sales in the sector jumped 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023, reaching 2.2 trillion yuan (US$311 billion), accounting for 18.1 per cent of all online shopping in China, according to data from the Ministry of Commerce.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1309" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/754d97a1-4883-40b6-b755-d027eb815bcf_113d2948.jpg" title="A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>However, the rapid growth has invited increasing regulatory attention. In April 2021, the Cyberspace Administration of China and six other regulators jointly released rules aimed at curbing malpractice such as selling fake products, falsifying view numbers and promoting pyramid schemes.</p><p>Last month People’s Daily, the chief mouthpiece of the Chinese Communist Party, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3243239/peoples-daily-calls-tighter-control-live-streaming-e-commerce-china-controversies-mount" target="_self" title="">called for tighter oversight of live-streaming e-commerce</a>. The paper said misconduct in the live-streaming industry, from fraudulent advertising to misleading pricing, should be addressed and punished for the sake of the sector’s healthy and sustained growth.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance’s Douyin steps up oversight of live-streaming hosts, closing 290,000 accounts last year for ‘harmful’ content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248921/bytedances-douyin-steps-oversight-live-streaming-hosts-closing-290000-accounts-last-year-harmful</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has cracked down on harmful live-streaming practices in 2023.</li>    <li>The company shut down over 290,000 host accounts for promoting vulgar content, improper challenge games, and enticing viewers to spend more money.</li>    <li>Douyin also collaborated with local authorities to remove the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts in Changsha who engaged in harmful outdoor live-streaming activities.</li>    <li>Additionally, the platform has taken steps to address improper challenge games, enticed spending, scams, gambling, and pornographic content.</li>    <li>Over the past two years, Douyin has been working with the Cyberspace Administration of China to root out malicious online content.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>2023年，抖音对有害的直播行为进行了严厉打击。</li>    <li>公司关闭了超过29万个直播账户，原因是这些账户推广低俗内容、进行不当挑战游戏和诱骗观众花钱。</li>    <li>抖音还与地方当局合作，取缔了长沙超过1万名参与有害户外直播活动的直播主账号。</li>    <li>此外，该平台还采取措施解决不当挑战游戏、诱骗花钱、诈骗、赌博和色情内容等问题。</li>    <li>在过去两年中，抖音一直与中国网络空间管理局合作，根除恶意网络内容。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>crack down on (v.) - /kræk daʊn ɑːn/ 镇压，严厉打击。    <p>原文例句：Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has cracked down on harmful live-streaming practices in 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由crack（断裂，破碎）和down（向下）组成，表示“严厉打击，镇压”。在这个例句中，它表示抖音在2023年对有害的直播行为进行了严厉打击。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>shut down (v.) - /ʃʌt daʊn/ 关闭，停止。    <p>原文例句：The company shut down over 290,000 host accounts for promoting vulgar content, improper challenge games, and enticing viewers to spend more money.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由shut（关闭，停止）和down（向下）组成，表示“关闭，停止”。在这个例句中，它表示公司关闭了超过29万个直播账户，原因是这些账户推广低俗内容、进行不当挑战游戏和诱骗观众花钱。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>intervene (v.) - /ˌɪntərˈviːn/ 干预，介入。    <p>原文例句：It also has safeguards that intervene when its system determines an elderly user is falling prey to online scams on its app.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由inter（之间）和venire（来）组成，表示“介入，干预”。在这个例句中，它表示该平台还具有干预措施，当其系统确定老年用户在其应用程序上遭遇在线诈骗时进行干预。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>harmful live-streaming practices - 有害的直播行为。    <p>原文例句：Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has cracked down on harmful live-streaming practices in 2023.</p>    <p>词组讲解：这个词组由harmful（有害的）和live-streaming practices（直播行为）组成，表示“有害的直播行为”。在这个例句中，它表示抖音在2023年对有害的直播行为进行了严厉打击。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>improper challenge games - 不当挑战游戏。    <p>原文例句：The company shut down over 290,000 host accounts for promoting vulgar content, improper challenge games, and enticing viewers to spend more money.</p>    <p>词组讲解：这个词组由improper（不当的）和challenge games（挑战游戏）组成，表示“不当挑战游戏”。在这个例句中，它表示公司关闭了超过29万个直播账户，原因是这些账户推广低俗内容、进行不当挑战游戏和诱骗观众花钱。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>enticed spending - 诱骗花钱。    <p>原文例句：The company shut down over 290,000 host accounts for promoting vulgar content, improper challenge games, and enticing viewers to spend more money.</p>    <p>词组讲解：这个词组由enticed（诱骗的）和spending（花钱）组成，表示“诱骗花钱”。在这个例句中，它表示公司关闭了超过29万个直播账户，原因是这些账户推广低俗内容、进行不当挑战游戏和诱骗观众花钱。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has cracked down on harmful live-streaming practices in 2023. - 抖音，中国版的TikTok，在2023年对有害的直播行为进行了严厉打击。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Douyin has cracked down on harmful live-streaming practices in 2023，其中主语是Douyin，谓语是has cracked down，宾语是harmful live-streaming practices。in 2023是一个时间状语，表示在2023年。The Chinese version of TikTok是一个定语从句，修饰Douyin，表示抖音是TikTok的中国版本。这个句子的意思是说，抖音，中国版的TikTok，在2023年对有害的直播行为进行了严厉打击。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company shut down over 290,000 host accounts for promoting vulgar content, improper challenge games, and enticing viewers to spend more money.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + been + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示在过去某个时间之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示公司关闭了超过29万个直播账户，原因是这些账户推广低俗内容、进行不当挑战游戏和诱骗观众花钱，而关闭这些账户的动作发生在过去某个时间之前。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：Over the past two years, Douyin has been working with the Cyberspace Administration of China to root out malicious online content.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个语态，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词。被动语态表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。在这个例句中，它表示在过去两年中，抖音一直与中国网络空间管理局合作，根除恶意网络内容，而根除恶意网络内容的动作是由抖音承受的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Some outdoor live streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions</li>
<li>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was worth US$98.2 billion in 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/9a28fd60-8832-4f14-b4c3-01657424e7b0_5660f465.jpg" /><figcaption>An advertisement for Douyin seen at a bus stop in China. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure><p>Douyin, the sibling app of ByteDance’s global short video hit TikTok, said it imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023 to rein in inappropriate practices.</p><p>The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts, including some top influencers, as the platform sought to weed out practices it deemed harmful, such as outdoor live-streaming containing vulgar content, improper challenge games among hosts, as well as enticing viewers to spend more money, the company said in a post published to its official WeChat account on Tuesday.</p><p>Some outdoor live-streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions, according to the post.</p><p>In a joint effort with local authorities in Changsha, the capital of central Hunan province, Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>The banned hosts had engaged in “harmful” outdoor live-streaming activities in Changsha, a major tourist spot which attracted live-streamers who wanted to broadcast its bustling nightlife.</p><p>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was forecast to have made 700 billion yuan (US$98.2 billion) in 2023, according to Statista.</p><p>Improper challenge games and enticed spending were also issues raised by the Cyberspace Administration of China over the past two years, as part of the top Chinese internet watchdog’s campaigns to root out malicious online content.</p><p>Douyin’s live-streaming clampdown also targeted live streamers who were promoting scams, gambling and pornographic content on the platform. Nearly two-thirds, or 190,000, of the hosts banned last year were involved in such activities.</p><p>Through efforts with the Chinese police, more than 300 criminal suspects have been arrested, Douyin said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3247755/watched-strangers-china-mother-live-streams-son-9-doing-homework-says-he-works-3-times-faster" title="">Chinese mother live-streams son, 9, doing homework so he is not distracted</a></h3><p>However, the crackdown is taking a toll on some hosts, who said they were incidentally banned as part of the measures. One host, based in the central province of Anhui, who requested anonymity for fear of retribution by the platform, told the South China Morning Post on Thursday that while she agreed with Douyin’s efforts, it was easy for some veteran hosts to get caught up, adding that losing access to accounts that took years to build up is a high cost.</p><p>Douyin did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Thursday.</p><p>The platform has also been improving the way it manages live streamers. Last September, it introduced a revamped host rating system to take into account multiple factors such as the severity of the alleged malpractice, and the hosts’ level of influence and popularity.</p><p>Meanwhile, verified hosts generating “good” content would be rewarded with support from Douyin to create a “healthy and positive” environment for live-streaming activities.</p><p>The rising trend of using artificial intelligence (AI)-powered virtual hosts has also caught Douyin’s attention. The short video app has put in place rules to require more transparency, with additional identity checks required for the individuals behind such virtual hosts.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1332" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0141f38e-3a8c-4a47-84ce-4ce5fdc448a3_3366798b.jpg" title="In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>More than 765 million Chinese internet users had tuned into live sessions across various online services as of last June, according to data from the China Internet Network Information Centre, representing around 70 per cent of the country’s total 1.079 billion netizens.</p><p>The widespread adoption of live-streaming services has included people of all ages, including minors and seniors, two groups which Douyin said it was paying special attention to.</p><p>Douyin has introduced restrictions that prevent minors from hosting live sessions or tipping other hosts. It also has safeguards that intervene when its system determines an elderly user is falling prey to online scams on its app.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Private-equity investors to return to China in search of M&amp;A deals in 2024, Bain &amp; Co says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248937/private-equity-investors-return-china-search-ma-deals-2024-bain-co-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In China, due to the international economic downturn in 2023, M&A transactions hit a nine-year low, and the investment prospects for the future are not optimistic.</li>    <li>Private equity investors are starting to turn to the Chinese market, looking forward to participating in a potential economic recovery. However, investors are cautious and prefer sustainable profits rather than high valuations.</li>    <li>Advisors say that there is a lot of dry powder seeking investment and are looking for big companies instead of high-growth small companies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>2023年，受国际经济下行影响，中国并购交易量创九年新低，未来投资前景并不乐观。</li>    <li>私募投资者开始转向中国市场，期待参与潜在的经济复苏。然而，投资者持谨慎态度，更偏好可持续的利润而非高估值。</li>    <li>顾问称，市场上有大量的闲置资金正在寻求投资，并且更青睐大企业而不是高增长的中小企业。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unprecedented (adj.) - /ˌʌnprɪsˈiːdəntid/ 前所未有的，空前的。    <p>原文例句：Private-equity dry powder soared to an unprecedented US$2.59 trillion globally as of December 1 last year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由un-（没有）和precedented（先例，前例）构成的，表示“没有先例的，前所未有的”。在这个例句中，它指的是截至去年12月1日，全球私募股权闲置资金暴增至创纪录的2.59万亿美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>stable (adj.) - /ˈsteɪbəl/ 稳定的，牢固的。    <p>原文例句：Most investors with massive amounts of dry powder prefer large-scale businesses to small, high-growth firms, as they chase stable and sustainable returns in a fast-changing market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语stabilis，表示“牢固的，稳定的”。在这个例句中，它指的是大多数拥有大量闲置资金的投资者更青睐大规模企业，而不是小型高增长企业，因为他们在快速变化的市场中追逐稳定和可持续的回报。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>economic recovery - 经济复苏。    <P>原文例句：Private-equity investors are starting to turn to the Chinese market, looking forward to participating in a potential economic recovery.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由economic（经济的）和recovery（恢复）组成的，表示“经济复苏”。在这个例句中，它指的是私募投资者开始转向中国市场，希望参与到潜在的经济复苏中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In October, Saudi Arabian smart city developer Neom invested US$100 million in Chinese autonomous driving technology start-up Pony.ai to help fund its research and development and finance its operations. - 在10月份，沙特阿拉伯智能城市开发商Neom向中国自动驾驶技术初创企业小马智行投资1亿美元，以帮助其资助研发并为其运营提供资金。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Neom invested US$100 million in Chinese autonomous driving technology start-up Pony.ai，其中主语是Neom，谓语是invested，宾语是US$100 million in Chinese autonomous driving technology start-up Pony.ai。to help fund its research and development and finance its operations是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示投资的目的或意图，即帮助小马智行资助其研发并为其运营提供资金。这个句子的意思是说，在10月份，沙特阿拉伯智能城市开发商Neom向中国自动驾驶技术初创企业小马智行投资1亿美元，以帮助其资助研发并为其运营提供资金。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式短语作目的状语 - 表示目的或意图。    <p>原文例句：In October, Saudi Arabian smart city developer Neom invested US$100 million in Chinese autonomous driving technology start-up Pony.ai to help fund its research and development and finance its operations.</p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式短语是由不定式和to构成的，不定式是动词的-ing形式，to是介词。不定式短语作目的状语时，放在句中作状语，表示动作或行为的目的或意图。在这个例句中，不定式短语to help fund its research and development and finance its operations作目的状语，表示Neom投资小马智行的目的是为了帮助其资助研发并为其运营提供资金。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Private-equity dry powder soared to an unprecedented US$2.59 trillion globally as of December 1 last year.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是由have/has和过去分词构成的，have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是由动词的词干加上-ed或不规则变化形式构成。现在完成时表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或已经完成的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性或完成性。在这个例句中，现在完成时soared表示私募股权闲置资金截至去年12月1日已经暴增至创纪录的2.59万亿美元。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>It may take longer to conclude deals, ‘but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted’ in 2024, Bain executive says</li>
<li>Mainland China M&amp;A deals dropped to a nine-year low last year amid a third straight year of declines, Refinitiv data shows</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/3af570e6-afc9-4398-8253-c7bffe73cf71_6190bf99.jpg" /><figcaption>The Liuiazui financial hub in Shanghai. Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for GDP, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, at the National People’s Congress. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Global and domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3246654/china-ma-activity-set-rebound-2024-amid-renewed-overseas-interest-it-wont-be-business-usual-heres" target="_self" title="">private-equity investors</a> are making a comeback to the Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mergers-acquisitions" target="_self" title="">mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;A)</a> market following three straight years of decline, as they look to profit from an economic recovery, global consultancy Bain &amp; Co said.</p><p>Private-equity investors will focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247667/chinese-stocks-darkest-days-may-be-over-earnings-rebound-property-recovery-seen-lifting-gloom-2024" target="_self" title="">improving profitability and bolstering revenue</a> from their portfolio firms, rather than potential frothy valuations, when they are making investment decisions, said Zhou Hao, head of the firm’s Greater China private equity and M&amp;A practice.</p><p>“New talks on deal making [have] resurfaced since the second half of 2023,” he said. “It may take longer to conclude the deals, but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted this year.”</p><p>Bain’s statement is significant because, despite a drop in deal volumes, mainland China still accounted for 41 per cent of deals in the Asia-Pacific region in the first half of 2023, according to S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence.</p><p>Mainland China reported 5,156 M&amp;A deals in 2023, with a combined value of US$301 billion, according to Refinitiv data. This was a nine-year low and a third straight year of declines, in terms of deal volumes.</p><p>US dollar-denominated private-equity funds that have at least half their capital invested in China raised US$1.4 billion in the first half of last year, down about 90 per cent from a year earlier, according to Preqin data.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3248558/asset-manager-blackstone-expand-private-equity-headcount-singapore-southeast-asia-push" title="">Asset manager Blackstone to expand private-equity headcount in Singapore</a></h3><p>However, earlier this month, UBS forecast that profit growth for Chinese listed companies will jump to 8 per cent in 2024 from 3 per cent last year, buoyed by a recovery in the world’s second-largest economy.</p><p>Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for gross domestic product, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, when the annual session of the National People’s Congress is held.</p><p>Moreover, Kang Yi, head of China’s National Bureau of Statistics, said during a press conference on Wednesday that some incentives Beijing rolled out last year – such as the plan to issue 1 trillion yuan (US$139 billion) worth of special treasury bonds – will take effect in 2024. The central government will also prepare new supportive policies to spur the mainland’s economy, he added.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3246654/china-ma-activity-set-rebound-2024-amid-renewed-overseas-interest-it-wont-be-business-usual-heres" title="">China M&amp;A activity set for rebound but 2024 won’t be business as usual</a></h3><p>Most investors with massive amounts of dry powder prefer large-scale businesses to small, high-growth firms, as they chase stable and sustainable returns in a fast-changing market, Bain said.</p><p>Private-equity dry powder soared to an unprecedented US$2.59 trillion globally as of December 1 last year, an 8 per cent increase over December 2022’s total of US$2.39 trillion, data by S&amp;P Global and Preqin shows.</p><p>Bain said in a research report released on Thursday that buyout funds mainly benefited from higher valuations of portfolio firms in China amid increasing price-to-earnings multiples, because investors in new rounds of financing were convinced of their future growth potential.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3245604/global-ma-deal-makers-miss-us3-trillion-mark-first-time-10-years" title="">Global M&amp;A: deal makers to miss US$3 trillion mark for first time in 10 years</a></h3><p>Higher valuations contributed to 55 per cent of the total returns private-equity funds reaped in China from 2012 to 2022, Bain said. Revenue increases contributed to 37 per cent of total returns while only 8 per cent of the returns were derived from profit rises.</p><p>Middle Eastern countries that are eager to shift from fossil fuel-based economies are pursuing opportunities for China inbound M&amp;A deals, particularly in the new energy and electric-vehicles (EV) sectors.</p><p>In October, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3239304/chinese-self-driving-technology-start-ponyai-gets-us100-million-investment-saudi-arabias-smart-city" target="_self" title="">Saudi Arabian smart city developer Neom</a> invested US$100 million in Chinese autonomous driving technology start-up Pony.ai to help fund its research and development and finance its operations.</p><p>On December 18, Chinese EV maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3242863/chinese-ev-maker-nio-sees-ai-robots-replacing-30-cent-workforce-2027-improve-efficiency-cut-costs" target="_self" title="">Nio</a> announced it had raised US$2.2 billion from CYVN Holdings, a fund backed by the Abu Dhabi government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s lottery players bet on AI chatbots to give winning numbers, but none are millionaires yet</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248909/chinas-lottery-players-bet-ai-chatbots-give-winning-numbers-none-are-millionaires-yet</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2> 在中国，社交媒体用户分享了他们使用生成式人工智能来选择彩票号码的经验。尽管人工智能算法在预测幸运数字方面与人类相比没有特别的优势，但一些用户仍然使用人工智能来提高他们的中奖概率。然而，官方不可用的人工智能聊天机器人生成的号码并没有带来很多成功案例。彩票的随机性决定了中奖完全依赖运气，无数学算法也无法破解。因此，对彩票应该抱着娱乐的心态，而不应该将其视为一种投资或赚钱的方式。  <ul>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2> 在中国，社交媒体用户分享了他们使用生成式人工智能来选择彩票号码的经历。尽管人工智能算法在预测幸运数字方面与人类相比没有特别的优势，但有些人仍然使用人工智能来提高他们的中奖概率。然而，官方不可用的人工智能聊天机器人生成的号码并没有带来很多成功案例。彩票的随机性决定了中奖完全依赖运气，无数学算法也无法破解。因此，对彩票应该抱着娱乐的心态，而不应该将其视为一种投资或赚钱的方式。  <ul>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>generative AI (n.) - /ˈdʒɛnərətɪv aɪ/ 生成式人工智能。    <p>原文例句：Chinese social media users share their experiences using generative AI to pick lottery numbers. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由generative（生成）和AI（人工智能）组成的，表示“能自动生成文本，代码，图像，音乐等内容的人工智能”。在这个例句中，它指的是社交媒体用户分享他们使用生成式人工智能来选择彩票号码的经历。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>edge (n.) - /ɛdʒ/ 优势，优势。    <p>原文例句：While sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由古英语ecge（边缘）派生而来的，表示“优势，优势”。在这个例句中，它指的是虽然复杂的AI算法在预测幸运数字方面没有特别的优势。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>turn into - 转变为，变成。    <p>原文例句：but some internet users in China recently found that lottery numbers generated by artificial intelligence (AI) chatbots have yet to turn them into millionaires.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由turn（转动）和into（进入）组成的，表示“转变为，变成”。在这个例句中，它指的是但是一些中国互联网用户最近发现，由人工智能（AI）聊天机器人生成的彩票号码尚未使他们成为百万富翁。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Among the five combinations picked by Gemini, two of them each contained two winning numbers, while another two each had one correct bonus number. - 在Gemini选出的五个组合中，其中两个各有二个中奖号码，另外两个各有一个正确的奖金号码。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Two of them each contained two winning numbers，其中主语是Two of them，谓语是contained，宾语是two winning numbers。while another two each had one correct bonus number是一个让步状语从句，表示另外一种情况。这个句子的意思是说，在Gemini选出的五个组合中，其中两个各有二个中奖号码，另外两个各有一个正确的奖金号码。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 表示强调。    <p>原文例句：It is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种句型，结构是：It is/was + 被强调部分 + that + 主语 + 谓语。其中that可以省略。这种句型可以强调句中的某个部分，使之成为句子的重点。在这个例句中，被强调的部分是nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets，表示中国有大约2亿体育彩票和福利彩票的常客。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：People in other parts of the world have also been turning to generative AI for lottery number suggestions.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示世界其他地区的人们也一直在使用生成式人工智能来获取彩票号码的建议。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Chinese social media users share their experiences using generative AI to pick lottery numbers</li>
<li>The country is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/ef431a3d-68c7-4027-852b-cc9d3567841e_0b6e9536.jpg" /><figcaption>A lottery shop in Beijing. Photo: SCMP/Simon Song</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT and its peers</a> are known for giving smart answers to a variety of questions, but some internet users in China recently found that lottery numbers generated by artificial intelligence (AI) chatbots have yet to turn them into millionaires.</p><p>In one post that went viral on the Instagram-like platform Xiaohongshu, user Gu Xiangnan from eastern Anhui province shared her experience buying lottery tickets using numbers generated by Google’s Gemini-Pro.</p><p>She first fed the chatbot with two years’ worth of historical data from Super Lotto, one of the most popular of its kind in China that asks players to select five numbers from a set of 35 balls and two bonus numbers from another set of 12 balls.</p><p>Among the five combinations picked by Gemini, two of them each contained two winning numbers, while another two each had one correct bonus number. Gu won no money.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Gu also said she previously spent 20 yuan (US$2.8) betting on Union Lotto, another popular lottery in China, using the same approach, winning 5 yuan in total.</p><p>“Although it was just for fun, there is something worth looking into,” she said.</p><p>Lotteries are designed to be random, meaning that picking the right numbers from millions of possible combinations depends entirely on luck. While sophisticated AI algorithms have no particular edge over humans when it comes to predicting lucky numbers, it has not stopped people from using AI to try to boost their chances.</p><p>The Xiaohongshu post was liked by more than 5,000 users, with some commenting that they also won small sums using numbers suggested by generative AI. Gemini-Pro and OpenAI’s ChatGPT are officially unavailable in China, although they can be accessed using a virtual private network.</p><p>China, which logged annual lottery sales of around 600 billion yuan last year, is estimated to have nearly 200 million regular buyers of sports and welfare lottery tickets.</p><p>People in other parts of the world have also been turning to generative AI for lottery number suggestions.</p><p>In April, Thai man Patthawikorn Boonrin claimed on TikTok that he won 2,000 baht (US$56) using ChatGPT, according to digital media Mashable. A month later, Singaporean man Aaron Tan won a US$40 cash prize with ChatGPT-generated numbers, according to news portal Yahoo.</p><p>Also in May, Paris-based data scientist Rohith Teja bought a 2.5 euro (US$2.7) lottery ticket using random numbers given by ChatGPT, winning 6 euros. Another ticket that he purchased using numbers generated by ChatGPT through analysing historical data contained no winning numbers at all.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3243129/how-chinas-lottery-boom-reflects-long-and-challenging-road-its-economic-recovery" title="">How China’s lottery boom reflects a ‘long and challenging’ economic recovery</a></h3><p>“The lottery is a highly randomised event that cannot be predicted by any predictive model,” Teja concluded in his blog.</p><p>In the case of Gu, the Xiaohongshu user, Gemini explained to her that it tried to predict lottery results by picking recent lucky numbers that also won more frequently in the past.</p><p>While the chatbot said its selection “had a certain degree of randomness as well as a certain degree of regularity”, it advised against taking the lottery too seriously.</p><p>“Treat lottery as a recreational activity, not a way to invest or make money. Good luck,” it said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong’s green tech hub goal: nurture start-ups, identify advantages and create talent pool, fintech body says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3248875/hong-kongs-green-tech-hub-goal-nurture-start-ups-identify-advantages-and-create-talent-pool-fintech</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong aims to become a leading green tech and green finance hub by supporting start-ups, leveraging China's expertise, and encouraging public-private collaboration.</li>    <li>The government and private sector should work together to create funding structures, attract and nurture talent, and promote a risk-taking mindset.</li>    <li>China's leadership in electric vehicles, renewable energy, and hydrogen can be leveraged for collaborations.</li>    <li>Hong Kong should focus on sub-sectors where it has advantages, such as low-carbon energy products, greenhouse gas emissions, and data collection for physical climate risks.</li>    <li>The government should consider expanding financial assistance programs to encourage family offices and institutional investors to participate in start-up fundraising.</li>    <li>Challenges include growing the talent pool, retaining and acquiring talent, and fostering a risk-taking mindset.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>香港旨在通过支持初创企业、利用中国的专业知识并鼓励公私合作，成为领先的绿色技术和绿色金融中心。</li>    <li>政府和私营部门应共同努力，创建融资结构、吸引和培养人才，并促进承担风险的心态。</li>    <li>可以利用中国在电动汽车、可再生能源和氢能方面的领先地位进行合作。</li>    <li>香港应关注自身具有优势的子行业，如低碳能源产品、温室气体排放以及物理气候风险数据收集。</li>    <li>政府应考虑扩大财政援助计划，以鼓励家族办公室和机构投资者参与初创企业融资。</li>    <li>面临的挑战包括扩大人才库、留住和吸引人才，以及培养承担风险的心态。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>leverage (v.) - 利用，发挥杠杆作用。    <p>原文例句：Hong Kong’s aim of becoming a green technology and finance centre can become a reality if efforts are concentrated on supporting start-ups and leveraging China’s expertise in crucial technologies.     <p>例句讲解：这个词源于法语lever，意为“提升，利用”。在这个例句中，它表示利用中国的专业知识，发挥其杠杆作用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>nurture (v.) - 培养，培育。    <p>原文例句：The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset.     <p>例句讲解：这个词源于拉丁语nutrire，意为“营养，喂养”。在这个例句中，它表示培养和培育人才库。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>public-private collaboration - 公私合作。    <p>原文例句：Public-private collaboration to fund start-ups, attracting and nurturing talent can help city achieve green tech, finance hub goal: FinTech Association of Hong Kong.     <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指政府和私营部门之间的合作。在这个例句中，它表示政府和私营部门之间的合作可以帮助城市实现绿色技术和金融中心的目标。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Fostering a risk-taking mindset is another challenge, according to Sethi. - 塞西表示，培养承担风险的心态是另一个挑战。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的陈述句，主语是Fostering a risk-taking mindset，谓语是is，宾语是another challenge。according to Sethi是一个介词短语，表示根据塞西的说法。这个句子的意思是说，根据塞西的说法，培养承担风险的心态是另一个挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The government followed up its intention by setting up a green technology and finance development committee, comprising leaders from the finance, technology, academic and professional services sectors in June. - 6 月份，政府根据其意图成立了一个绿色技术和金融发展委员会，其中包括来自金融、技术、学术和专业服务部门的领导者。    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时的句子，表示政府从过去的某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。主语是government，谓语是has followed，宾语是its intention，up是一个副词，表示“根据”。这个句子的意思是说，政府根据其意图成立了一个绿色技术和金融发展委员会，其中包括来自金融、技术、学术和专业服务部门的领导者。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Public-private collaboration to fund start-ups, attracting and nurturing talent can help city achieve green tech, finance hub goal: FinTech Association of Hong Kong</li>
<li>City must leverage China’s dominance in fields such as electric vehicles and renewable energy to its advantage, non-profit’s Sandeep Sethi says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/a4b626bb-229f-49f8-979e-4aaf7649c6cd_f97275b3.jpg" /><figcaption>The Hong Kong government has stated its ambition to become a leading green tech and green finance hub. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>Hong Kong’s aim of becoming a green technology and finance centre can become a reality if efforts are concentrated on supporting start-ups and leveraging China’s expertise in crucial technologies, according to the FinTech Association of Hong Kong.</p><p>The government and the private sector should step up collaboration to create funding structures to back green start-ups, attract and nurture a talent pool and foster a risk-taking mindset, said Sandeep Sethi, co-chair of the non-profit’s green tech and ESG committee.</p><p>“Various cities are trying to promote themselves as green tech centres” said Sethi, who is also an independent consultant and a former executive at Deutsche Bank. “We feel it is important for Hong Kong to put that flag up and say we are the leading green tech centre. We need to identify sub-sectors where we feel Hong Kong has certain advantages.”</p><p>Given China’s leadership position in electric vehicles, renewable energy and hydrogen, these sectors can be initial targets for collaborations, he added.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/90970213-f607-4ca0-9991-68a291db888d_798e21ed.jpg" title="FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung" width="2000" /><figcaption>FinTech Association of Hong Kong’s Sandeep Sethi has some suggestions on turning Hong Kong into a green tech powerhouse. Photo: Sun Yeung</figcaption></figure></div><p>Hong Kong’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3211122/budget-2023-hong-kong-launches-initiatives-become-global-green-innovation-finance-centre" target="_self" title="">ambition</a> to become an international centre for both green tech and green finance was highlighted by Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po in his budget speech last February. Previously, the focus was on building the city into a leading green and sustainable finance hub in Asia.</p><p>The government followed up its intention by setting up a green technology and finance development committee, comprising leaders from the finance, technology, academic and professional services sectors in June.</p><p>Next month, the government is hosting the Hong Kong GreenTech Week, which aims to bring together green tech businesses and investors from around the world, according to co-organiser Green Development Institute.</p><p>On a more basic level, Hong Kong can do better by providing early-stage funding for start-ups involved in areas such as low-carbon energy products, greenhouse gas emissions and tools for collecting and analysing data on physical climate risks, said Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/78343ebc-5f85-4434-9186-b91134e46289_798e21ed.jpg" title="Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung" width="2000" /><figcaption>Chris Barford, a director of the FinTech Association of Hong Kong. Photo: Sun Yeung</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Some green tech start-ups that have done well after getting seed funding of HK$10 million (US$1.3 million) to HK$20 million have struggled to raise additional financing to fund expansion,” said Barford, who is also the Hong Kong financial services consulting data and analytics lead at consultancy EY.</p><p>The government should consider expanding its financial assistance programmes, which would encourage family offices and institutional investors to take part in fundraising by start-ups, he added.</p><p>Towards that end the Hong Kong government is providing assistance. The different research and development funding schemes overseen by the Innovation and Technology Commission had provided total funding of some HK$400 million to about 130 green tech R&amp;D projects as of last June, according to the Environment and Ecology Bureau.</p><p>The bureau also administers a HK$400 million Green Tech Fund that supports R&amp;D projects in net-zero electricity generation, energy savings, green buildings, green transport and waste reduction. Some 30 projects have received HK$132.5 million since the fund was set up in 2020.</p><p>The government’s Hong Kong Science and Technology Parks Corporation and Cyberport have also set up separate funds to co-invest with angel investors and venture capital funds in start-ups at their respective industry parks.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3244092/hong-kong-regains-appeal-among-global-financial-talent-opportunities-open-fintech-esg-and-markets" title="">Hong Kong regains appeal among global talent amid demand in fintech, ESG</a></h3><p>“There is a gap between the intention and the actual projects that get financed,” said Sethi. “A lot of these are new technology projects where it is hard to prove the business case and profitability. This is where public-private collaborative funding can help.”</p><p>Other difficulties facing the government and industries include growing the talent pool, Sethi said.</p><p>Some 80 per cent of senior finance executives in the city, surveyed late last year by the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, said recruiting green and sustainable finance professionals was more difficult compared with other job functions. Talent retention and acquisition was the second most pressing issue after disclosure regulations.</p><p>Fostering a risk-taking mindset is another challenge, according to Sethi.</p><p>“In a lot of Asian countries, the education systems are focused on preparing students to get stable jobs, but in tech we need entrepreneurs who are willing to take risks,” he said. “It takes years and perhaps generations to change the mindset.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s Vision Pro headset will be missing a Netflix app at launch in February</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248870/apples-vision-pro-headset-will-be-missing-netflix-app-launch-february</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Netflix will not develop a dedicated app for Apple's upcoming Vision Pro headset, instead opting for web browser support.</li>    <li>This decision means that Vision Pro users will not be able to download Netflix content for offline viewing, limiting its usefulness on airplanes.</li>    <li>The move is seen as a strategic choice by Netflix, which competes with Apple in the streaming industry and may not want to contribute to the success of a rival platform.</li>    <li>Apple has been promoting the Vision Pro as an entertainment device and has secured partnerships with various streaming services, but Netflix's absence is a notable omission.</li>    <li>Netflix's decision highlights the competitive landscape in the streaming industry, where companies vie for subscribers and seek to differentiate their offerings.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Netflix不会为苹果即将推出的Vision Pro头显开发专门的应用程序，而是选择支持网络浏览器。</li>    <li>这一决定意味着Vision Pro用户将无法下载Netflix内容进行离线观看，从而限制了其在飞机上的使用。</li>    <li>这一举动被视为Netflix的战略选择，该公司在流媒体行业与苹果竞争，可能不想为竞争对手平台的成功做出贡献。</li>    <li>苹果一直在宣传Vision Pro是一款娱乐设备，并已与多家流媒体服务建立合作关系，但Netflix的缺席是一个明显的遗漏。</li>    <li>Netflix的决定凸显了流媒体行业的竞争格局，各公司争夺用户并寻求差异化自己的产品。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>headset (n.) - /ˈhedˌsɛt/ 头戴式耳机。    <p>原文例句：The Apple Vision Pro headset seen at an unveiling event in Cupertino, California last June. Photo: AP </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由head（头）和set（集合，装置）构成的，表示“头戴式耳机”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果在去年六月的发布会上展示的Vision Pro头戴式耳机。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>offline (adj.) - /ˈɒfˌlaɪn/ 离线的，不在线的。    <p>原文例句：The approach means Vision Pro users will not be able to download Netflix content to watch offline on an aeroplane</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由off（离开）和line（线）构成的，表示“离线，不在线”。在这个例句中，它表示Vision Pro用户无法下载Netflix内容以便在飞机上离线观看。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>nascent (adj.) - /ˈneɪs(ə)nt/ 新生的，萌芽的。    <p>原文例句：Apple is banking on entertainment content to help market the nascent and pricey technology, and Netflix is a must-have streaming service for many consumers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由nasci（出生）构成的，表示“新生的，萌芽的”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果押注娱乐内容来帮助营销新生的和昂贵的技术，并且Netflix对于许多消费者来说是一个必须拥有的流媒体服务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>immersive (adj.) - /ɪˈmɜːsɪv/ 沉浸式的，身临其境的。    <p>原文例句：That means Netflix cannot create specialised immersive backdrops for its users to watch videos in.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由immersus（沉浸）构成的，表示“沉浸式的，身临其境的”。在这个例句中，它指的是Netflix无法为其用户创建专门的身临其境的背景来观看视频。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take a wait-and-see stance - 持观望态度。    <p>原文例句：The fact that Netflix is not even willing to support the iPad approach suggests that it is taking a wait-and-see stance with the headset.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（采取）, wait（等待）, see（看见）和stance（立场）构成的，表示“持观望态度”。在这个例句中，它指的是Netflix甚至不愿意支持iPad解决方案的事实表明，该公司对该头显持观望态度。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>vie for something - 争夺某物，竞相争取某物。    <p>原文例句：While Netflix and Apple do not compete in TV hardware, they are both currently vying for subscribers in the streaming industry.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由vie（竞争，争夺）和for（为了）构成的，表示“争夺某物，竞相争取某物”。在这个例句中，它指的是虽然Netflix和Apple不在电视硬件方面竞争，但他们目前都在流媒体行业争夺用户。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The move is seen as a strategic choice by Netflix, which competes with Apple in the streaming industry and may not want to contribute to the success of a rival platform. - 这一举动被视为Netflix的战略选择，该公司在流媒体行业与苹果竞争，可能不想为竞争对手平台的成功做出贡献。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The move is seen as a strategic choice by Netflix，其中主语是The move，谓语是is seen as，宾语是a strategic choice by Netflix。which competes with Apple in the streaming industry and may not want to contribute to the success of a rival platform是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰Netflix，表示Netflix与苹果在流媒体行业竞争，并且可能不想为竞争对手平台的成功做出贡献。这个句子的意思是说，这一举动被视为Netflix的战略选择，该公司在流媒体行业与苹果竞争，可能不想为竞争对手平台的成功做出贡献。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式作宾语 - 不定式可以作动词的宾语。    <p>原文例句：Apple is banking on entertainment content to help market the nascent and pricey technology, and Netflix is a must-have streaming service for many consumers.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个不定式作宾语的例子。不定式是动词的非限定形式，可以表示动作或状态。在这个例句中，不定式to help market the nascent and pricey technology作动词bank的宾语，表示帮助营销新兴且昂贵的技术。不定式for many consumers作形容词must-have的宾语，表示对于许多消费者来说。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>非限定性定语从句 - 非限定性定语从句是对先行词做进一步解释或说明的从句，在从句中不包含先行词。    <p>原文例句：The fact that Netflix is not even willing to support the iPad approach suggests that it is taking a wait-and-see stance with the headset.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个非限定性定语从句的例子。非限定性定语从句是对先行词The fact that Netflix is not even willing to support the iPad approach做进一步解释或说明的从句，在从句中不包含先行词。that it is taking a wait-and-see stance with the headset是对先行词The fact that Netflix is not even willing to support the iPad approach的进一步解释或说明，表示Netflix对该头显持观望态度。这个句子使用了that引导的非限定性定语从句，that可以省略。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Rather than designing a Vision Pro app or supporting its existing iPad app on the platform, Netflix says users can watch its content on a web browser</li>
<li>The approach means Vision Pro users will not be able to download Netflix content to watch offline on an aeroplane</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0daed4bb-8aac-444e-9863-2f6975c1c780_21ab5745.jpg" /><figcaption>The Apple Vision Pro headset seen at an unveiling event in Cupertino, California last June. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netflix" target="_self" title="">Netflix</a> is not planning to launch an app for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3223224/apples-vision-pro-best-ar-and-vr-mixed-reality-headset-market-and-represents-future-computing-even" target="_self" title="">Apple’s upcoming Vision Pro headset</a>, marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world’s biggest video subscription service.</p><p>Rather than designing a Vision Pro app – or even just supporting its existing iPad app on the platform – Netflix is essentially taking a pass. The company, which competes with Apple in streaming, said in a statement that users interested in watching its content on the device can do so from the web.</p><p>It is a sizeable omission for the US$3,499 headset, which debuts on February 2. Apple is banking on entertainment content to help market the nascent and pricey technology, and Netflix is a must-have streaming service for many consumers.</p><p>Netflix also offers apps for Apple’s other devices, including the iPhone and iPad, though it does not participate in the company’s TV app.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1329" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/27470cf7-0ad7-471c-936b-45ab61159d8c_ce1fbea2.jpg" title="The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Netflix office building in Hollywood, California. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Vision Pro will run two main types of apps: new software written specifically for the device’s interface or existing iPad applications. Apple has sought to make it easy to transfer developers’ current iPad apps over to the new platform, aiming to quickly amass a wide range of Vision Pro software.</p><p>The fact that Netflix is not even willing to support the iPad approach suggests that it is taking a wait-and-see stance with the headset. It is also a bit of a reversal for the company, which said in July that it would support its iPad app on the Vision Pro. Even then, though, Netflix did not plan to release software specifically for the headset’s operating system, visionOS.</p><p>“Our members will be able to enjoy Netflix on the web browser on the Vision Pro, similar to how our members can enjoy Netflix on Macs,” Los Gatos, California-based Netflix said in the statement. Apple declined to comment.</p><p>In contrast with its Vision Pro strategy, Netflix did develop an app for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236053/meta-launches-quest-3-vr-and-ar-headset-just-ahead-apples-vision-pro" target="_self" title="">Meta Platforms’ Quest headsets</a>, though it has not been updated in years.</p><p>The approach means it will be harder for users to access Netflix on the Vision Pro. And they will not be able to download Netflix content to watch offline, potentially making it more of a pain to use on an aeroplane.</p><p>The lack of an app also means Netflix watchers will not have access to custom environments for streaming. That means Netflix cannot create specialised immersive backdrops for its users to watch videos in.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="998" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/946981d0-f40f-4bc7-b1f9-bd435067d043_6ca422b1.jpg" title="An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>An Apple promotional image demonstrating how the Vision Pro can be used. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>While Netflix and Apple do not compete in TV hardware, they are both currently vying for subscribers in the streaming industry.</p><p>Apple is a small player in this category, with less than 10 per cent of the US market. But it has been gathering award wins in the space, and the two companies compete over talent and production deals. It is plausible Netflix does not want to help boost a rival by giving it a key app for its upcoming launch.</p><p>Apple has been marketing the Vision Pro as an entertainment device in the run-up to pre-orders beginning on Friday.</p><p>The Cupertino, California-based company said earlier this week that the headset would have many entertainment options beyond its own TV+ service. That includes programming from Disney+, Max, Peacock, ESPN and Amazon Prime Video, among others.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung Galaxy S24 series smartphones come with Google Gemini AI technology to fight Apple iPhones</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248863/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-smartphones-come-google-gemini-ai-technology-fight-apple-iphones</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Samsung's New Galaxy S24 Series Boasts AI-Powered Features, Including Live Phone Call Translation, Voice Recording Transcription, Web Article Summarization, and Handwriting Improvement.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung unveils its latest Galaxy S24 smartphones with advanced AI capabilities, aiming to gain an edge over Apple's iPhone.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's focus on AI integration in its flagship phones, offering a range of features to enhance user experience.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of AI in the smartphone industry and Samsung's strategic move to adopt Gemini AI technology from Google.</li>    <li>Main information: Details of the new Galaxy S24, S24+, and S24 Ultra models, including AI features, display improvements, and camera upgrades.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  三星新推出的Galaxy S24系列手机主打AI功能，包括实时电话翻译、语音录音转写、网页文章总结和手写改进等，旨在获得相较于苹果iPhone的优势。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星在最新一代Galaxy S24智能手机中集成了先进的人工智能功能，增强用户体验。</li>    <li>主题：三星在旗舰手机中突出人工智能应用，提供一系列功能提升用户体验。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能在智能手机行业的重要性，三星采纳谷歌Gemini AI技术的战略举措。</li>    <li>主要信息：新款Galaxy S24、S24+和S24 Ultra型号的详细信息，包括人工智能功能、显示屏改进和摄像头升级等。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unveil (v.) - /ʌnˈveɪl/ 公开展示，公布。    <p>原文例句：At its Unpacked conference Wednesday in San Jose, California, Samsung unveiled the Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra phones, which all add AI tools based on the Gemini technology from Alphabet’s Google.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由un-（相反）和veil（面纱）组成，意为“揭开面纱，公开展示或公布”。在这个例句中，它表示三星在加利福尼亚州圣何塞的Unpacked发布会上发布了Galaxy S24、S24+和S24 Ultra手机，这些手机都添加了基于Alphabet的Google的Gemini技术的AI工具。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>slump (n.) - /slʌmp/ 低迷，不景气。    <p>原文例句：Samsung looks to reverse its fortunes by getting a several-month head start on AI. Apple is not expected to showcase its latest plans for artificial intelligence until June, ahead of new iPhones arriving around September. The new Galaxy phones come out on January 31, with pre-orders starting Wednesday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自挪威语slump（湿滑），意为“低迷，不景气”。在这个例句中，它表示三星希望通过在人工智能方面领先苹果几个月来扭转自己的命运，苹果预计将在6月份展示其人工智能的最新计划，而新款iPhone手机将在9月份左右上市，新款Galaxy手机将于1月31日上市，并从星期三开始接受预订。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in conjunction with - 与……一起，连同……一起。    <P>原文例句：In conjunction with Samsung’s announcements, Google also introduced a feature called “Circle to Search,” which lets people search anything on their phone screens without switching apps.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由in（在……里面），conjunction（连词）和with（和……一起）组成，表示“和……一起，连同……一起”。在这个例句中，它表示在与三星的公告同时进行时，谷歌还推出了一个名为“Circle to Search”的功能，该功能允许人们在不切换应用程序的情况下在手机屏幕上搜索任何内容。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung Electronics is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones, betting that the technology can give it an advantage over Apple’s iPhone. - 三星电子正转向人工智能 (AI) 功能来改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机，押注这项技术可以使其相较于苹果的 iPhone 具有优势。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，由主句 Samsung Electronics is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones 和两个从句 betting that the technology can give it an advantage over Apple’s iPhone 和 believing this technology will help its phones stand out from the competition 组成。主句 Samsung Electronics is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones 的主语是 Samsung Electronics，谓语是 is turning，宾语是 artificial intelligence (AI) features，介词短语to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones 作状语，表示三星电子正在转向人工智能功能来改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机。从句 betting that the technology can give it an advantage over Apple’s iPhone 的主语是 betting，谓语是 can give，宾语是 it an advantage，介词短语over Apple’s iPhone 作状语，表示押注该技术可以赋予其相较于苹果 iPhone 的优势。从句 believing this technology will help its phones stand out from the competition 的主语是 believing，谓语是 will help，宾语是 its phones，介词短语 from the competition 作状语，表示相信这项技术将帮助其手机在竞争中脱颖而出。这个句子的意思是说，三星电子正转向人工智能 (AI) 功能来改造其旗舰 Galaxy 智能手机，押注该技术可以赋予其相较于苹果 iPhone 的优势，并相信这项技术将帮助其手机在竞争中脱颖而出。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态的承受者。    <p>原文例句：Samsung’s phone shipments declined nearly 14 per cent to 226.6 million units in 2023, according to research firm IDC. </p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是英语中的一种语法形式，表示动作或状态的承受者。它的结构是：be + 过去分词。在这个例句中，be是was，过去分词是declined，表示三星手机的出货量下降了将近14%，降至2.266亿部。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式 - 表示动作、状态或结果。    <p>原文例句：The Interpreter application on a Samsung S24 Ultra smartphone. Photo: Bloomberg</p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式是一种非限定性动词形式，表示动作、状态或结果。它的结构是：to + 动词原形。在这个例句中，不定式是to search，表示搜索的意思。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra can live-translate phone calls, transcribe voice recordings, summarise web articles and fix handwriting</li>
<li>Apple is not expected to showcase its latest plans for artificial intelligence until June, ahead of new iPhones arriving around September</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0bde60ec-206d-4f06-b93f-8cfac56d664e_ad59a457.jpg" /><figcaption>An influencer poses with Samsung’s new phones at the Galaxy Unpacked event in San Jose, California. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> is turning to artificial intelligence (AI) features to revamp its flagship Galaxy smartphones, betting that the technology can give it an advantage over Apple’s iPhone.</p><p>At its Unpacked conference Wednesday in San Jose, California, Samsung unveiled the Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra phones, which all add AI tools based on the Gemini technology from Alphabet’s Google.</p><p>The devices can live-translate phone calls, transcribe voice recordings, summarise web articles, fix handwriting and use generative AI to fill in parts of photos.</p><p>The launch is one of the most ambitious attempts to weave AI into a smartphone’s interface and features. The new devices also provide Google with a chance to put its most advanced software in the hands of more users, a potential edge in its fight for AI dominance with Microsoft and start-up OpenAI.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="From left to right, Samsung’s Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra smartphones. Photo: AP Photo" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/4ab7c02b-e978-4125-8c59-49f05c81b629_1126e908.jpg" title="From left to right, Samsung’s Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra smartphones. Photo: AP Photo" width="2000" /><figcaption>From left to right, Samsung’s Galaxy S24, S24+ and S24 Ultra smartphones. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure></div><p>The AI features are the highlight of the new phones, but the devices are also getting slimmer bezels and brighter displays. Samsung is paying special attention to its top-end model, the S24 Ultra. That product, which starts at US$1,299, will have a new titanium frame, matching the iPhone 15 Pro models released in September.</p><p>The borders around the displays are 42 per cent thinner, and the screen is 40 per cent brighter than the phone’s predecessor. It also sports flatter edges and a front-facing camera cut-out that is 11 per cent smaller.</p><p>The US$799 S24 and US$999 S24+ come in aluminium and get slightly larger screens than their predecessors, moving from 6.1-inch and 6.6-inch panels to 6.2-inch and 6.7-inch displays, respectively. The S24 Ultra, like the S23 Ultra, has a 6.8-inch screen.</p><p>Qualcomm is providing the main chip of the new Samsung phones in at least some regions. The S24 line-up will be based on its Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 applications processor, the company said in a separate statement. That component offers the latest Wi-fi capabilities and will handle AI-assisted features such as live translation and transcription, Qualcomm said.</p><p>The new models come at a crucial time for Samsung, which is contending with market share losses and a broader smartphone slump. Last year, it lost its crown as the No 1 smartphone supplier to Apple, marking the first time Samsung has not led the market since 2010.</p><p>Samsung’s phone shipments declined nearly 14 per cent to 226.6 million units in 2023, according to research firm IDC. Apple, on the other hand, saw unit shipments increase 3.7 per cent to 234.6 million.</p><p>Samsung looks to reverse its fortunes by getting a several-month head start on AI. Apple is not expected to showcase its latest plans for artificial intelligence until June, ahead of new iPhones arriving around September. The new Galaxy phones come out on January 31, with pre-orders starting Wednesday.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Interpreter application on a Samsung S24 Ultra smartphone. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/6f875bae-b575-4bd1-9cab-fc3b1f6d77c4_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="The Interpreter application on a Samsung S24 Ultra smartphone. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Interpreter application on a Samsung S24 Ultra smartphone. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Samsung decided to adopt the Gemini AI technology after surveying offerings from competitors, according to Thomas Kurian, head of Google’s cloud computing unit. As part of a multi-year agreement, Google will be the sole provider of generative AI for Samsung’s phones and applications, including features for taking notes and recording audio, according to Kurian.</p><p>“This is a validation of the quality of our models,” Kurian said. “They were free to choose whoever they wanted.”</p><p>Users will be able to switch between two options: one called Gemini Nano that runs on the phone itself and a higher-powered Pro version that uses cloud computing. That flexibility helped Google’s offerings stand out from the competition, Kurian said.</p><p>In conjunction with Samsung’s announcements, Google also introduced a feature called “Circle to Search,” which lets people search anything on their phone screens without switching apps.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/1452f636-7686-4413-86a3-f946ab0883d5_34f54c2a.jpg" title="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Users of Google’s Android operating system can scribble or circle on top of images, text or video in the app they are on – say, YouTube Shorts or TikTok – to find out more information about the item. The feature is launching globally on the new Galaxy S24, as well as on Google’s own Pixel 8 smartphones on January 31.</p><p>AI features on the Samsung devices will also let users change the language of a message depending on the context, such as whether it is a work memo or social media post. And new capabilities for Android Auto – Google’s in-car interface – will summarise incoming text messages and other alerts.</p><p>The companies are also applying AI to the phones’ camera systems, which are getting upgraded with new sensors, with tools to make photos sharper. The S24 Ultra replaces one of its 10-megapixel telephoto cameras with a 50-megapixel version. The S24 and S24+, meanwhile, include the same camera specifications as their predecessors.</p><p>The S24 Ultra comes with as much as 1 terabyte of storage, while the S24+ tops out at 512 gigabytes. The S24 has as much as 256GB of space. The S24+ and S24 Ultra include 12GB of memory, which is used for shorter-term storage of data, while the regular S24 has 8GB.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
