<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China’s internet giants must step up opening their ‘walled gardens’, state media says, ahead of Tencent flagship game’s return to Douyin</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248762/chinas-internet-giants-must-step-opening-their-walled-gardens-state-media-says-ahead-tencent</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  中国证券报评论文章指出，中国互联网巨头企业“携手”合作还“远不够”，应打破生态壁垒，加强跨平台合作，携手应对市场压力。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese internet giants must accelerate efforts to open up their ecosystems and promote win-win cooperation in the industry.</li>    <li>Theme: Breaking down digital barriers and promoting collaboration among internet companies in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The necessity and benefits of cross-platform cooperation, as well as the government's role in promoting it.</li>    <li>Main information: Call for more open-minded and inclusive approach to industry cooperation; collaboration between Tencent and Douyin as an example; other recent cases of cross-platform collaborations; the government's push to break down online walls.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国证券报发表评论文章指出，当前中国互联网巨头企业合作“还远不够”，应打破生态壁垒，加强跨平台合作，携手应对市场压力。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国互联网巨头要加快开放生态壁垒，推进行业内合作共赢。</li>    <li>主题：打破藩篱，推动中国互联网企业合作。</li>    <li>观点：强调跨平台合作必要性和益处，以及政府在这方面的推动作用。</li>    <li>主要信息：呼吁互联网企业更开放、包容，推动真正共赢合作；以腾讯与抖音合作为例；介绍近年其他跨平台合作案例；政府出面推动打破网络壁垒。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>walled garden (n.) - /wɔːld ˈgɑːdn/ 封闭的花园。    <p>原文例句：China’s internet giants must accelerate efforts to open up their “walled gardens”, enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms as a means “to face market pressures together” and assure the industry’s further expansion, according to state-owned media.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“walled garden”是一个比喻，指互联网公司为了保护自己的利益，而将自己的产品和服务限制在自己的平台内，不与其他平台互通。这个比喻来自于中世纪欧洲贵族的花园，这些花园通常都有高高的围墙，以防止外人进入。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>inclusive (adj.) - /ɪnˈkluːsɪv/ 包容的，兼收并蓄的。    <p>原文例句：“In the future, internet companies need to be more open-minded and inclusive to promote truly win-win cooperation in the industry,” the Securities Times article said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“inclusive”是一个形容词，指对所有人或所有事物都持包容的态度，不歧视任何人和任何事物。在这个例句中，它表示互联网公司需要更加开放和包容，以促进行业内真正的双赢合作。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>break down (v.) - /breɪk daʊn/ 崩溃，瓦解。    <p>原文例句：Beijing wants to smash online walls but Big Tech treads carefully</p>    <p>例句讲解：“break down”是一个动词词组，指打破或瓦解某物。在这个例句中，它表示北京希望打破网络壁垒，但大型科技公司对此采取谨慎态度。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>cross-platform (adj.) - /krɔːs ˈplætfɔːrm/ 跨平台的。    <p>原文例句：China’s major internet companies ‘need to be more open-minded’ about enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms</p>    <p>例句讲解：“cross-platform”是一个形容词，指可以在多个平台上运行或使用的。在这个例句中，它表示中国的互联网公司需要更加开放，以使他们的生态系统可以在多个平台上运行。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tencent’s super app WeChat and Alibaba’s Taobao and Tmall Group in September announced an expanded collaboration, which enabled users who click on advertisements on WeChat to be directed to shops and live-streaming campaigns on Taobao and Tmall. - 腾讯的超级应用程序微信以及阿里巴巴的淘宝和天猫集团在 9 月宣布展开更广泛的合作，该合作使用户能够点击微信上的广告，然后被导向淘宝和天猫上的店铺和直播活动。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Tencent’s super app WeChat and Alibaba’s Taobao and Tmall Group announced an expanded collaboration，其中主语是Tencent’s super app WeChat and Alibaba’s Taobao and Tmall Group，谓语是announced，宾语是an expanded collaboration。which enabled users who click on advertisements on WeChat to be directed to shops and live-streaming campaigns on Taobao and Tmall是一个定语从句，修饰collaboration，表示这项合作使点击微信上广告的用户能够被导向淘宝和天猫上的店铺和直播活动。这个句子的意思是说，9 月份，腾讯的超级应用程序微信以及阿里巴巴的淘宝和天猫集团宣布展开更广泛的合作，该合作使点击微信上广告的用户能够被导向淘宝和天猫上的店铺和直播活动。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物承担或经历的。    <p>原文例句：TikTok owner ByteDance earlier this month confirmed that it was in talks with multiple potential buyers, including Tencent, to sell its video gaming operations.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是it，谓语是被动语态的动词was confirmed，宾语是that it was in talks with multiple potential buyers, including Tencent, to sell its video gaming operations。这个句子的意思是说，本月早些时候，TikTok 的所有者字节跳动证实，它正在与包括腾讯在内的多位潜在买家进行洽谈，以出售其视频游戏业务。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或到说话时的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时的句子，主语是Tencent，谓语是被动语态的动词allows，宾语是Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos。现在完成时的构成是“have/has + been + 过去分词”，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或到说话时的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示腾讯允许抖音播放王者荣耀视频，因为字节跳动退出了游戏领域。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Collaborations among these Big Tech firms ‘are far from deep’, according to an article by Securities Times</li>
<li>The call to break more digital barriers in China’s internet industry comes days before Tencent’s Honour of Kings returns to Douyin’s platform</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/e3c9aa50-df1e-4b22-8f21-d4b06c403b4e_0bbdcb09.jpg" /><figcaption>China’s major internet companies ‘need to be more open-minded’ about enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms, according to the Securities Times article. Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants must accelerate efforts to open up their “walled gardens”, enabling their ecosystems to work across platforms as a means “to face market pressures together” and assure the industry’s further expansion, according to state-owned media.</p><p>At present, collaborations among these companies “are far from deep”, said an article published on Tuesday by Shenzhen-based Securities Times, a financial newspaper owned by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chinas-communist-party" target="_self" title="">Chinese Communist Party</a> mouthpiece People’s Daily.</p><p>The call to break more digital barriers in China’s internet industry comes days before <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honour-kings" target="_self" title="">Honour of Kings</a>, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3116088/honour-kings-became-worlds-most-popular-game-it-was-desperate?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">world’s most popular mobile game</a>, officially returns to the popular live-streaming platform of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3101626/douyin-chinas-tiktok-grows-daily-active-users-600-million-home" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>, which has more than 600 million daily active users, from January 21.</p><p>“In the future, internet companies need to be more open-minded and inclusive to promote truly win-win cooperation in the industry,” the Securities Times article said.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Increased collaboration between China’s major internet companies are expected to not only benefit consumers, but help further expand the industry, according to state media. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/4358c69f-a073-4444-8f19-753e8dd060b9_53933fe2.jpg" title="Increased collaboration between China’s major internet companies are expected to not only benefit consumers, but help further expand the industry, according to state media. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Increased collaboration between China’s major internet companies are expected to not only benefit consumers, but help further expand the industry, according to state media. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>The collaboration between ByteDance and Tencent comes amid the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> industry’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248249/chinas-video-gaming-market-ended-2023-battered-and-bruised-can-world-beating-titles-and-innovation?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">regulatory uncertainties and a weaker macro environment in China</a>.</p><p>While China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248694/china-gdp-beijings-long-do-list-boost-economy-2024" target="_self" title="">gross domestic product rose by 5.2 per cent</a> year on year in 2023, the world’s second-largest economy still faced mounting concerns this year including waning investor confidence, a protracted property market slump and a weak private sector.</p><p>“Internet companies need to leverage each other to face the market pressures together,” the Securities Times article said.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a> owner ByteDance earlier this month confirmed that it was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">in talks with multiple potential buyers</a>, including Tencent, to sell its video gaming operations.</p><p>Last April, Tencent and Douyin <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3216333/tencent-and-douyin-end-years-copyright-disputes-signing-cooperation-agreement-content-distribution" target="_self" title="">agreed to a partnership in video content distribution</a> after years of contentious copyright disputes.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>Under that deal, Tencent authorised Douyin to distribute its video content and clarify copyright rules for users to produce modifications and adaptations. As a result, users of ByteDance-owned platforms Douyin, Xigua Video and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/abacus/culture/article/3074051/why-chinas-favorite-news-app-lets-users-order-food" target="_self" title="">Jinri Toutiao</a> will be able to produce derivative works based on Tencent-owned videos.</p><p>There have been other cases of collaboration between rival internet platform operators over the years,</p><p>In November, Alibaba Group Holding’s grocery chain <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/e-commerce/article/3103476/alibabas-freshippo-opens-first-membership-only-store-shanghai" target="_self" title="">Freshippo</a> opened a store on rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3155846/chinas-internet-walled-gardens-may-be-cracking-users-face-long" title="">Beijing wants to smash online walls but Big Tech treads carefully</a></h3><p>Tencent’s super app <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> and Alibaba’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247985/alibabas-taobao-and-tmall-group-pushes-new-ai-tools-boost-merchants-service-consumers-first-major" target="_self" title="">Taobao and Tmall Group</a> in September announced an expanded collaboration, which enabled users who click on advertisements on WeChat to be <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235835/alibaba-tencent-break-more-digital-barriers-between-wechat-and-taobao-tmall-economic-uncertainty" target="_self" title="">directed to shops and live-streaming campaigns on Taobao and Tmall</a>.</p><p>In November 2021, Tencent opened WeChat to third-party online links including those of Douyin and Taobao.</p><p>In September that same year, Alibaba started allowing consumers to use Tencent’s WeChat Pay as a payment option on a number of its platforms including food delivery platform <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3227745/alibabas-eleme-food-delivery-platform-extends-welfare-coverage-3-million-couriers-collective" target="_self" title="">Ele.me</a>, video-streaming platform <a href="https://www.scmp.com/abacus/who-what/what/article/3028268/how-youku-went-being-chinas-youtube-chinas-hulu" target="_self" title="">Youku</a>, online ticketing platform Damai and cross-border e-commerce platform Kaola.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s hi-tech manufacturing faces ‘extraordinary pressures’ as 2023 output stalls</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248773/chinas-hi-tech-manufacturing-faces-extraordinary-pressures-2023-output-stalls</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China's high-tech manufacturing industry experienced its slowest growth on record in 2023, with output rising by only 2.7%.</li>    <li>The decline is attributed to a faltering economy and escalating containment efforts from the United States.</li>    <li>Beijing's hopes of driving economic growth through innovation and technology are being challenged.</li>    <li>Investment in high-tech manufacturing grew by 9.9% in 2023, but this was the slowest pace since 2015.</li>    <li>Experts say China's high-tech sector is facing headwinds from a global recession and US-China tensions.</li>    <li>The weak economic momentum is also discouraging investment in high-tech manufacturing.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>2023年，中国高技术制造业产值同比增长2.7%，创历史新低。</li>    <li>增速放缓的原因在于经济疲软和美国日益加剧的遏制措施。</li>    <li>北京通过创新和技术推动世界第二大经济体的希望正受到挑战。</li>    <li>2023年，高技术制造业投资增长9.9%，但这是自2015年以来最慢的增速。</li>    <li>专家表示，中国高技术行业正面临来自全球经济衰退和中美紧张局势的逆风。</li>    <li>疲弱的经济势头也抑制了对高技术制造业的投资意愿。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>falter (v.) - /ˈfɔːltər/ 蹒跚行走，失去动力。    <p>原文例句：Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023, falling behind an increase of 5 per cent from the overall manufacturing industry...</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle French的fauteur（错误），本意为“失误，犯错”，引申为“蹒跚行走，失去动力”。在这个例句中，它表示高科技制造业的产值增长落后于整体制造业。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>escalate (v.) - /ˈeskəleɪt/ 升级，加剧。    <p>原文例句： amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States,...</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin的scala（阶梯，天梯），本意为“逐级上升”，引申为“升级，加剧”。在这个例句中，它表示美国的遏制措施不断升级。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ever-escalating - 不断升级的。    <p>原文例句： amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States,...</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由ever（总是，不断）和escalating（升级）构成，表示“不断升级的”。在这个例句中，它表示美国的遏制措施不断升级。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The rapid development of hi-tech industries over the past 20 years has provided China with a massive boost to its economic boom, this was partly due to the impact of a stable external environment on investor confidence.<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The rapid development of hi-tech industries over the past 20 years has provided China with a massive boost to its economic boom，其中主语是The rapid development of hi-tech industries，谓语是has provided，宾语是China with a massive boost to its economic boom。this was partly due to the impact of a stable external environment on investor confidence是一个原因状语从句，表示经济迅速发展的原因之一是稳定的外部环境对投资者信心的影响。这个句子的意思是说，过去20年来高新技术产业的快速发展为中国经济的快速增长提供了巨大的推动力，这部分原因是稳定的外部环境对投资者信心的影响。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Comparative and superlative - 比较级和最高级。    <p>原文例句：Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023, falling behind an increase of 5 per cent from the overall manufacturing industry, marking the lowest level of growth since the National Bureau of Statistics started to release the figures in 2018.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级和最高级是形容词或副词的两种形式，用于比较两个或多个事物。比较级通常用“-er”或“more”来表示，最高级通常用“-est”或“most”来表示。在这个例句中，lowest是形容词low的最高级，表示“最低的”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>Reported speech - 间接引语。    <p>原文例句：Chen Zhiwu, a chair professor of finance at the University of Hong Kong, said headwinds such as risks of a global recession and US-China tensions would continue to exert “extraordinary pressures” on China’s hi-tech push.</p>    <p>语法讲解：间接引语是把别人的话用自己的语言复述出来。间接引语中，陈述句的主语和谓语通常要发生变化，时态也可能发生变化。在这个例句中，said是陈述句的谓语，headwinds such as risks of a global recession and US-China tensions是主语，would continue to exert “extraordinary pressures” on China’s hi-tech push是宾语。在间接引语中，said变成了say，主语Chen Zhiwu变成了he，谓语would continue to exert变成了would continue to exert，时态没有发生变化。这个句子的意思是说，香港大学金融学讲席教授陈志武表示，全球经济衰退风险和中美紧张局势等不利因素将继续对中国高新技术产业的发展施加“巨大压力”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023, but this marked the lowest level of growth since records began in 2018</li>
<li>Beijing has pinned its hopes on innovation and technology to power the world’s second-largest economy as it seeks to find new growth engines</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/bb42c49a-576e-447b-9e8e-c4b1bce62af6_f90326de.jpg" /><figcaption>Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Output from China’s hi-tech manufacturing sector grew at the slowest pace on record last year amid a faltering economy and ever-escalating containment efforts from the United States, with the decline weighing on Beijing’s march towards superpower status.</p><p>Industrial output from hi-tech manufacturers rose by 2.7 per cent year on year in 2023, falling behind an increase of 5 per cent from the overall manufacturing industry, marking the lowest level of growth since the National Bureau of Statistics started to release the figures in 2018.</p><p>The hi-tech manufacturing industry had seen its growth soar to a record high of 18.2 per cent in 2021 before easing to 7.4 per cent in 2022, having stood at 7.1 per cent in 2020 amid coronavirus-induced disruptions to the global supply chain.</p><p>Beijing has pinned its hopes on innovation and technology to power the world’s second-largest economy as it seeks to find new growth engines to replace the real estate sector, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248695/chinas-population-falls-208-million-14097-billion-2023-births-tumble-adding-demographic-concerns" target="_self" title="">address its demographic challenges</a> and move up the advanced industrial chain.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>Investment in hi-tech manufacturing grew by 9.9 per cent last year, beating the 6.5 per cent increase seen in the overall manufacturing industry, but the financing still registered the slowest pace since records began in 2015.</p><p>Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, said the sector is heading into a cooling period after years of rapid expansion.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248694/china-gdp-beijings-long-do-list-boost-economy-2024" target="_self" title="">“The latest economic data</a> indicate that the whole economic recovery is weak, and market confidence in many sectors is shaky, including tech,” he said.</p><p>“The hi-tech recovery will require China to return to higher economic growth and counteract US decoupling.</p><p>“It also demands the country’s ability to adapt to deglobalisation, but maintain a strong global exporter role.”</p><blockquote>Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public, the potential sanctions would affect their market valuationsChen Zhiwu</blockquote><p>In December, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246040/china-targets-industries-future-2024-humanoid-robots-and-biomedicines-drive-high-quality-economic" target="_self" title="">said it would increase funding</a> to nurture the transformation of traditional manufacturers into hi-tech producers.</p><p>It said China’s hi-tech manufacturing industry was currently facing challenges from insufficient innovation and increasing external pressure.</p><p>Chen Zhiwu, a chair professor of finance at the University of Hong Kong, said headwinds such as risks of a global recession and US-China tensions would continue to exert “extraordinary pressures” on China’s hi-tech push.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies" title="">‘More, better’: premier urges China to focus on application of core technologies</a></h3><p>“The US tech war has largely thwarted Chinese tech companies’ [initial public offering] opportunities. Even if these tech manufacturers succeed in going public, the potential sanctions would affect their market valuations,” said Chen.</p><p>He added China’s weak economic momentum is also weighing on the market’s overall willingness to invest, with hi-tech manufacturing just one element.</p><p>“The rapid development of hi-tech industries over the past 20 years has provided China with a massive boost to its economic boom, this was partly due to the impact of a stable external environment on investor confidence,” Chen said.</p><p>“Many hi-tech companies I’ve surveyed recently said that market demand for tech products is relatively low, and with uncertain market sentiment, consumers are tightening their wallets so much that companies have to cut back on production.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Saudi Arabia is eyeing a ‘sizeable’ investment to kick off kingdom’s foray into semiconductors</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248768/saudi-arabia-eying-sizeable-investment-kick-kingdoms-foray-semiconductors</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund (PIF) plans to make substantial investments in the semiconductor and space industries this year to diversify its economy beyond oil. The fund aims to lead the country's efforts in these sectors and establish a national space company for investments and acquisitions. The kingdom is also developing an auto manufacturing hub and plans to control $1 trillion in assets by 2025. Despite global economic tensions, Saudi Arabia aims to attract investments from both US and Chinese technology companies.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Saudi Arabia's PIF to invest heavily in semiconductor and space industries.</li>    <li>Theme: Saudi Arabia diversifies its economy through major investments in emerging sectors.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: PIF's role in leading Saudi Arabia's economic transformation.</li>    <li>Main information: Investments in semiconductor industry, creation of national space company, development of auto manufacturing hub, goal of controlling $1 trillion in assets.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  沙特阿拉伯公共投资基金（PIF）计划在今年对半导体和太空产业进行大量投资，以实现经济多元化，摆脱对石油的依赖。该基金旨在引领国家在这些领域的努力，并建立一家国家太空公司进行投资和收购。该国还正在发展汽车制造中心，并计划到 2025 年控制价值 1 万亿美元的资产。尽管全球经济紧张，但沙特阿拉伯仍希望吸引来自美国和中国科技公司的投资。  <ul>    <li>摘要：沙特公共投资基金将大量投资于半导体和太空产业。</li>    <li>主题：沙特阿拉伯通过对新兴行业的重大投资实现经济多元化。</li>    <li>观点：PIF 在领导沙特经济转型中的作用。</li>    <li>主要信息：对半导体行业的投资、成立国家太空公司、发展汽车制造中心、计划控制 1 万亿美元资产的目标。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>encompass (v.) - /ɪnˈkʌmpəs/ 涵盖，包括。    <p>原文例句：The company is actively testing and developing advanced technologies, encompassing everything from processors to memory to artificial intelligence.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由en-（使……成为）和compass（范围）构成的，表示“使围绕，使包含，使涵盖”。在这个例句中，它指的是该公司正在积极测试和开发先进技术，包括从处理器到内存到人工智能的所有内容。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>diversification (n.) - /daɪvɜːsɪfɪˈkeɪʃən/ 多元化，多样化。    <p>原文例句：Saudi Arabia’s sovereign wealth fund is planning to make big investments in both the semiconductor and space industries this year as the kingdom accelerates efforts to diversify its economy away from oil.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由diversify（使多样化）构成的，表示“多样化，使多样化”。在这个例句中，它指的是沙特阿拉伯的主权财富基金计划在今年对半导体和太空产业进行大量投资，因为该王国正在加快努力使其经济实现多元化，摆脱对石油的依赖。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take a lead in - 带头，引领。    <P>原文例句：The Public Investment Fund is looking at making a “sizeable investment” this year into the semiconductor industry, Saudi Minister of Communications and Information Technology Abdullah Al-Swaha said in an interview at the World Economic Forum in Davos. “They plan to make an announcement on a particular champion within the space to lead the Saudi efforts,” he said, declining to give further details.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，接受）和lead（领导）构成的，表示“带头，引领”。在这个例句中，它指的是沙特公共投资基金正计划在今年对半导体行业进行“大量投资”，沙特通讯和信息技术部长阿卜杜拉·阿尔苏瓦哈在达沃斯世界经济论坛上接受采访时表示，“他们计划宣布在该领域内选定一家领头羊来领导沙特的努力，”他说，但拒绝透露更多细节。这个词组表示沙特公共投资基金希望在半导体行业中发挥领导作用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Saudi Arabia to use Hong Kong as bridge to China’s tech prowess - 沙特阿拉伯将香港作为通往中国科技实力的桥梁。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Saudi Arabia，谓语是to use Hong Kong as bridge to China’s tech prowess。介词短语as bridge to China’s tech prowess作状语，表示沙特阿拉伯将香港作为通往中国科技实力的桥梁。这个句子的意思是说，沙特阿拉伯将香港作为通往中国科技实力的桥梁。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>there be 句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Public Investment Fund is looking at making a “sizeable investment” this year into the semiconductor industry, the Saudi communications minister said</li>
<li>PIF plans to make an announcement on a particular champion within the space to lead the Saudi efforts, the minister said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/3343fdd8-ac9c-4f06-8626-ba93903d1af0_6ec679cb.jpg" /><figcaption>Riyadh, capital of Saudi Arabia. Photo: Natalie Wong</figcaption></figure><p>Saudi Arabia’s sovereign wealth fund is planning to make big investments in both the semiconductor and space industries this year as the kingdom accelerates efforts to diversify its economy away from oil.</p><p>The Public Investment Fund is looking at making a “sizeable investment” this year into the semiconductor industry, Saudi Minister of Communications and Information Technology Abdullah Al-Swaha said in an interview at the World Economic Forum in Davos. “They plan to make an announcement on a particular champion within the space to lead the Saudi efforts,” he said, declining to give further details.</p><p>Alswaha, who is chairman of the kingdom’s Space Agency as well, said the fund will also look to create a national space company to invest and acquire assets in that sector. The space industry is “ripe right now” for M&amp;A, he said.</p><p>The fund, known as PIF, has emerged as one of the key parts of Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman’s plan to shake up the Saudi economy and wean it off a reliance on oil sales. It has rapidly built up assets of around US$700 billion after a spending spree on everything from electric carmakers to backing upstart golf tournaments, and plans to control US$1 trillion by 2025.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3226303/saudi-arabia-deepen-ties-hong-kong-using-city-bridge-mainland-chinas-world-class-digital-prowess" title="">Saudi Arabia to use Hong Kong as bridge to China’s tech prowess</a></h3><p>One of its key initiatives has been to develop an auto manufacturing hub on the west coast of the kingdom. US EV maker Lucid Group is already assembling cars from the site, and is set to be joined by Hyundai Motor and Ceer, a brand created by the PIF. The plan involves developing downstream industries that is expected to also include making semiconductors and batteries.</p><p>The kingdom launched its space programme in 2018 and sent astronauts into space last year, as part of a wider plan to invest in the industry.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>“The new space economy is definitely the next trillion-dollar opportunity,” Al-Swaha said. “The kingdom is very bullish on not only becoming a regional leader in this space but also a global leader. The ambition by 2030 is to definitely establish regional leadership and then move on by 2040 to global leadership.”</p><p>A key part of Saudi Arabia’s space investments will be in communications, Alswaha said. “2.6 billion people in 2024 are still not connected and the only way to connect the unconnected is from the skies.”</p><p>Alswaha said that Saudi Arabia expects to be able to continue to attract investment from both US and Chinese technologies companies, even as tensions between the world’s two largest economies escalate. The kingdom “has demonstrated our partnership with both east and west on protecting their intellectual property and patents and any potential technology leakage,” Alswaha said.</p><p>Saudi Arabia is “pro-investment, pro-partnership and open market,” he said. “Anybody that complies with our regulatory, security requirements, serves our national interest, we will work with.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei chases enterprise clients in South Korea as consumers hold onto Samsung, Apple smartphones</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248755/huawei-chases-enterprise-clients-south-korea-consumers-hold-samsung-apple-smartphones</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  Huawei's comeback in the global smartphone market is expected, but the South Korean market remains challenging due to Samsung's dominance, US sanctions, and weak local partnerships. Huawei's focus on enterprise services, cloud computing, and cultural industries may offer opportunities for growth in Korea.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei faces obstacles in gaining market share in South Korea's smartphone market.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's strategic shift towards enterprise services and cloud computing in the face of challenges in the South Korean smartphone market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Analysts' perspectives on Huawei's prospects in South Korea, highlighting the difficulties in penetrating the market dominated by Samsung and Apple.</li>    <li>Main information: Huawei's absence from the South Korean smartphone market due to 5G chip sourcing issues; the company's focus on enterprise services and cloud computing; Huawei's plans to support Korea's digitization and carbon neutrality goals.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  分析师认为，华为不太可能在由三星和苹果主导的韩国智能手机市场站稳脚跟。这家中国公司的云计算部门正在进军当地科技和娱乐产业领域。华为正在韩国尝试扩大其云业务。本文最初由韩国时报与南华早报合作发表。中国电信设备巨头华为技术有限公司今年有望在全球智能手机市场卷土重来，但在韩国，该公司必须应对美国制裁的持续影响以及与国际和本地竞争对手的激烈竞争。根据研究公司 TechInsights 上周发布的一份报告，到 2024 年，华为预计将成为智能手机行业的焦点，全球出货量预计将实现两位数增长，将这家中国公司描述为潜在的“大惊喜”。但分析师表示，在智能手机和半导体巨头三星电子的所在地韩国，华为正努力扩大市场份额或赢得当地合作伙伴的信任，原因是中美技术竞争激烈。TechInsights 的分析师阿比拉什·库马尔表示，这家总部位于深圳的公司二十年来一直向韩国客户提供各种产品和服务，在过去几年中已实际上退出该国智能手机市场，原因是其“无法采购 5G 芯片组”。“韩国的智能手机市场以 5G 为主，预计 2023 年 5G 普及率将超过 95%，因此消费者购买华为的 4G 手机几乎没有意义。”他说。自 2019 年以来，出于国家安全考虑，华盛顿禁止这家中国公司访问包括谷歌最受欢迎的应用程序在内的美国技术，这些应用程序通常预装在竞争对手三星销售的安卓手机中。这对华为的海外销售造成了沉重打击。华为曾在 2020 年初一度超越三星成为全球智能手机出货量领先者，但自 2021 年以来已跌出全球排名前五。根据研究公司 IDC 周一发布的一份报告，去年全球五家最大的智能手机供应商分别是苹果、三星、小米、传音和 vivo。Statcounter 的在线数据库数据显示，截至 12 月，华为在韩国的市场份额仅为 0.1%，远落后于三星的 68.7% 和苹果的 26.5%。去年 8 月，华为在中国国内市场大放异彩，推出了配备先进的国产 5G 芯片的 Mate 60 Pro 手机。据报道，该公司计划将其手机带回包括欧洲在内的一些海外市场。尽管如此，库马尔表示，“公司不太可能”重返韩国智能手机市场。他说：“现在华为可能已经设法在本地采购 5G 芯片组。” “但这仍然很困难，因为（韩国）以三星和苹果为主，对中国供应商的接受度不高。自 2014 年以来，华为一直在韩国推出高端和负担得起智能手机，但该公司未能站稳脚跟，“很大程度上是因为当地运营商更青睐三星。”TechInsights 服务总监伍迪·吴说。“为了在韩国市场取得成功，[制造商]必须寻求运营商的支持。”据华为韩国首席执行官王柏莲称，由于在消费市场面临困难，华为寄希望于企业服务。王柏莲上个月在首尔举行的一年一度活动中表示，韩国运营商使用的华为支持的 5G 网络去年在全球测试中排名第一。该公司提供的企业产品包括数据中心网络、园区网络和存储服务。王柏莲表示，公司还正在扩大其在云计算市场的立足点，并于去年在韩国成立了一个云计算部门，希望为信息技术和文化娱乐产业提供服务。这位高管强调了华为对韩国市场的承诺，尽管该公司去年陷入争议，当时韩国第二大内存芯片制造商 SK 海力士宣布正在调查其产品如何出现在 Mate 60 Pro 中。海力士当时表示，“自美国对该公司实施限制以来，我们不再与华为开展业务”。华为在韩国的一个关键业务合作伙伴是 LG 电子。王柏莲称 LG Uplus 是韩国第三大移动运营商，也是该国唯一使用华为 5G 基站的移动网络运营商，并被誉为中国公司的“重要全球客户”之一。展望 2024 年，王柏莲表示，拥有 230 多名员工的华为韩国计划帮助该国实现数字化和碳中和目标，同时继续支持培养 1,000 名下一代信息技术专业人才。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为在韩国智能手机市场赢得市场份额面临障碍。</li>    <li>主题：华为在韩国智能手机市场面临挑战时，战略性地转向企业服务和云计算。</li>    <li>观点：分析师对华为在韩国的前景的看法，强调了渗透三星和苹果主导的市场所面临的困难。</li>    <li>主要信息：华为因 5G 芯片采购问题而缺席韩国智能手机市场；该公司专注于企业服务和云计算；华为计划支持韩国的数字化和碳中和目标。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>struggle (v.) - /ˈstrʌɡəl/ 挣扎，奋斗。    <p>原文例句：Huawei is struggling to expand its market share or secure trust from local partners amid the US-China tech rivalry, analysts said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由strug（扭曲，缠绕）和-le构成的，表示“扭动，挣扎，奋斗”。在这个例句中，它表示华为在中美技术竞争的背景下，正在努力扩大其市场份额或赢得当地合作伙伴的信任。</p>   </li>    <li>cultivation (n.) - /ˈkʌltɪveɪʃən/ 培养，发展。    <p>原文例句：Wang said Huawei Korea, which has more than 230 employees, planned to help the country achieve its digitisation and carbon neutrality goals, while continuing to support the cultivation of 1,000 next-generation information technology professionals.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由cultivate（耕种，栽培）和-tion构成的，表示“耕种，栽培，培养，发展”。在这个例句中，它表示华为韩国公司计划帮助韩国实现数字化和碳中和目标，同时继续支持培养1000名下一代信息技术专业人才。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>enterprise services - 企业服务。    <p>原文例句：Amid difficulties in the consumer market, Huawei is pinning its hopes on enterprise services, according to Wang Balian, CEO of Huawei Korea.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“企业服务”，指的是华为的云计算、数据中心和存储服务等面向企业的产品和解决方案。</p>    </li>    <li>cloud computing - 云计算。    <p>原文例句：The company’s enterprise products include data centre networks, campus networks and storage services. Wang said the company was also expanding its foothold in the cloud computing market, having established a cloud division in Korea last year in hope of serving the information technology and cultural entertainment industries.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“云计算”，指的是华为的云计算平台和服务，例如华为云等，为企业和个人提供计算、存储、网络和数据库等云服务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei’s enterprise products include data centre networks, campus networks and storage services. 华为的企业产品包括数据中心网络、校园网络和存储服务。    <P>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Huawei’s enterprise products，谓语是include，宾语是data centre networks, campus networks and storage services。这个句子表示华为的企业产品包括数据中心网络、校园网络和存储服务。</p></li>    <li>Wang said the company was also expanding its foothold in the cloud computing market, having established a cloud division in Korea last year in hope of serving the information technology  <ul><li>Huawei is unlikely to gain ground in the South Korean smartphone market, which is dominated by Samsung and Apple, analysts say</li>
<li>The Chinese firm’s new cloud division in the country is eyeing business from the local tech and entertainment industries</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/d6d72751-e72c-48a7-a6f8-b7bfee2bdd85_b0324fe1.jpg" /><figcaption>Huawei is trying to expand its cloud business in South Korea. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>Chinese telecommunications equipment giant Huawei Technologies is poised to make a comeback in the global smartphone market this year, but in South Korea, the company must contend with the lingering impact of US sanctions and intense competition with international and local rivals, according to industry watchers.</p><p>Huawei is forecast to move into the spotlight in the smartphone industry in 2024, with projected double-digit growth in global shipments, according to a report published last week by research firm TechInsights, which described the Chinese company as a potential “big surprise”.</p><p>But in Korea – home to smartphone and semiconductor titan Samsung Electronics – Huawei is struggling to expand its market share or secure trust from local partners amid the US-China tech rivalry, analysts said.</p><p>The Shenzhen-based company, which has been offering various products and services to Korean customers for two decades, has been effectively absent from the country’s smartphone market in the past few years due to its “inability to source 5G chipsets”, said Abhilash Kumar, an analyst at TechInsights.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/425f24ee-d4dd-4d9c-94ca-0de11642cc70_34f54c2a.jpg" title="A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Samsung store in Seoul, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“South Korea’s smartphone market is 5G-heavy, with a 5G penetration of more than 95 per cent for 2023, so it made little sense for consumers to buy Huawei’s 4G-powered phones,” he said.</p><p>Since 2019, Washington has barred the Chinese company, on national security grounds, from accessing US technologies including Google’s most popular apps, which are commonly pre-installed in Android phones sold by rivals like Samsung. That has dealt a heavy blow to Huawei’s overseas sales.</p><p>Huawei, which briefly surpassed Samsung to lead global smartphone shipments in early 2020, has dropped out of the global top five since 2021. Last year, the world’s five biggest smartphone vendors were Apple, Samsung, Xiaomi, Transsion and Vivo, according to a report published on Monday by research firm IDC.</p><p>In Korea, Huawei had a market share of just 0.1 per cent as of December, far lagging Samsung’s 68.7 per cent and Apple’s 26.5 per cent, numbers from online database Statcounter showed.</p><p>Huawei made a splash in its home market China last August with the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233636/huaweis-mate-60-pro-will-help-it-take-lost-ground-china-can-it-help-smartphone-giant-regain-global" target="_self" title="">surprise launch of the Mate 60 Pro</a> handset equipped with an advanced, domestically-developed 5G chip. The company is reportedly aiming to bring its handsets back to some overseas markets, including in Europe.</p><p>Still, “it looks unlikely” that the firm would return to the Korean smartphone market, Kumar said.</p><p>“Now that Huawei might have managed to source 5G chipsets locally,” he said. “It’s still difficult for it because [South Korea] is Samsung- and Apple-heavy and doesn’t have much acceptance for Chinese vendors.”</p><p>Huawei has tried to launch both premium and affordable smartphones in Korea since 2014, but it has been unable to gain ground “largely due to local operators’ preference for Samsung,” said Woody Oh, service director at TechInsights. “To be successful in the Korean market, [manufacturers] must seek operators’ support.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Customers at an Apple store in Hanam, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/b995137c-2916-4199-9a6d-622ad91aadb4_a66cec46.jpg" title="Customers at an Apple store in Hanam, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Customers at an Apple store in Hanam, South Korea. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Amid difficulties in the consumer market, Huawei is pinning its hopes on enterprise services, according to Wang Balian, CEO of Huawei Korea.</p><p>The Huawei-supported 5G network used by Korean carriers ranked first in global tests last year, Wang said at a year-end event in Seoul last month. The company’s enterprise products include data centre networks, campus networks and storage services.</p><p>Wang said the company was also expanding its foothold in the cloud computing market, having established a cloud division in Korea last year in hope of serving the information technology and cultural entertainment industries.</p><p>The executive highlighted Huawei’s commitment to the Korean market despite running into controversies last year, when SK Hynix – the second-largest memory chip maker in Korea – announced it was investigating how its products ended up in the Mate 60 Pro.</p><p>Hynix said at the time that it “no longer does business with Huawei since the introduction of the US restrictions against the company”.</p><p>One of Huawei’s key business partners in Korea is LG Electronics. Wang called LG Uplus, South Korea’s third-largest mobile carrier and the country’s sole mobile network operator using Huawei’s 5G base stations, has been touted as one of the Chinese firm’s “important global clients”.</p><p>Looking to 2024, Wang said Huawei Korea, which has more than 230 employees, planned to help the country achieve its digitisation and carbon neutrality goals, while continuing to support the cultivation of 1,000 next-generation information technology professionals.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Should we let AI take over mundane work? Not so fast</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3248614/should-we-let-ai-take-over-mundane-work-not-so-fast</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Outsourcing tasks to generative AI like ChatGPT may increase productivity in the short term but can limit supplementary learning and skill development in the long term.</li>    <li>Generative AI's impact on human capability is similar to outsourcing work to others, as it reduces the need for individuals to develop logical arguments and verify facts.</li>    <li>Research on the Python programming language showed that outsourcing bug reporting tasks to a crowdsourcing program led to a decrease in overall productivity among Python maintainers.</li>    <li>The decline in productivity was mainly attributed to a lack of inter-task learning, as maintainers who reported more bugs before outsourcing experienced a greater drop in productivity.</li>    <li>Organizations should consider the trade-off between short-term productivity gains and long-term capability loss when deploying generative AI tools.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>将任务外包给像 ChatGPT 这样的生成式 AI 可能会在短期内提高生产力，但从长远来看会限制补充学习和技能发展。</li>    <li>生成式 AI 对人类能力的影响类似于将工作外包给其他人，因为它减少了个人发展逻辑论证和验证事实的需要。</li>    <li>对 Python 编程语言的研究表明，将错误报告任务外包给众包程序会导致 Python 维护人员的整体生产力下降。</li>    <li>生产力下降的主要原因是缺乏任务间学习，因为在将错误报告外包之前报告错误较多的维护人员生产力下降幅度更大。</li>    <li>在部署生成式 AI 工具时，组织应考虑短期生产力收益与长期能力下降之间的权衡。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>interrelation (n.) - /ˌɪntərɪˈleɪʃən/ 相互关系，相互关联。    <p>原文例句：We might wish to discourage AI’s use for deeply intertwined tasks. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由inter-（相互的）和relation（关系）组成，表示“相互关系，相互关联”。在这个例句中，它指的是AI的使用不应该被用于那些相互关联性很强的任务，比如需要综合运用多种技能和知识的任务。</p></li>    <li>mundane (adj.) - /mʌnˈdeɪn/ 世俗的，平庸的。    <p>原文例句：We must revisit the common question, “Why waste time doing mundane work when AI can do it for us?” </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语mundus（世界），表示“世俗的，平庸的”。在这个例句中，它指的是那些枯燥、乏味、没有挑战性、不重要的工作。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>deploy with care - 谨慎地部署。    <p>原文例句：AI must be deployed with care.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这是一个动词短语，表示“谨慎地部署，小心地使用”。在这个例句中，它指的是在使用生成式AI时，需要谨慎考虑其对人类能力的潜在影响，避免过度依赖AI而忽略了人类自身的学习和发展。</p></li>    <li>short-term gain - 短期收获。    <p>原文例句：The short-term gain in productivity could be offset by the long-term loss in capability. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这是一个名词短语，表示“短期的收获，暂时的利益”。在这个例句中，它指的是生成式AI在短期内可能带来的生产力提升，但需要注意的是，这种提升可能会以牺牲长期的能力发展为代价。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>In fact, AI-generated content is so good that it reads almost as if it was written by a human being. - 事实上，AI 生成的内容非常好，读起来几乎就像是由人类写的。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是AI-generated content is so good，其中主语是AI-generated content，谓语是is so good。that it reads almost as if it was written by a human being是一个结果状语从句，表示AI生成的文本非常流畅自然，读起来几乎就像是由人类写的。这个句子的意思是说，人工智能生成的内容非常出色，读起来几乎就像是由人类写的。</p>    <li>The official Python maintainers not only discovered fewer bugs after the IBB program, they also made fewer enhancements to Python. - 在 IBB 计划之后，Python 官方维护者不仅发现的错误更少，而且对 Python 的改进也更少。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，由两个简单句组成。第一个简单句是The official Python maintainers not only discovered fewer bugs after the IBB program，其中主语是The official Python maintainers，谓语是discovered fewer bugs，宾语是after the IBB program。第二个简单句是they also made fewer enhancements to Python，其中主语是they，谓语是made fewer enhancements，宾语是Python。这个句子的意思是说，在IBB计划之后，Python官方维护者不仅发现的错误更少，而且对Python的改进也更少。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Comparative and superlative adjectives - 比较级和最高级形容词。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI has a said GPT4, the state-of-the-art model underlying ChatGPT Plus, could score in the top 10 per cent in the SAT reading exam for college admissions, the GRE verbal test for graduate school admissions and the uniform bar exam for lawyers.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个比较级和最高级形容词的例句。比较级形容词是用来比较两个事物或以上，最高级形容词是用来比较三个事物或以上。比较级形容词的结构是：形容词词根+er，最高级形容词的结构是：形容词词根+est。在这个例句中，最具有比较意义的是the top 10 per cent，意思是前10%，表示在SAT阅读考试、GRE语言考试和统一律师考试中，GPT4的分数可以排在前10%。</p></li>    <li>Subjunctive mood - 虚拟语气。    <p>原文例句：They claimed they weren’t aware ChatGPT could make up cases.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气的例句。虚拟语气是一种语气，用来表达说话人对某件事情的主观想法或态度。虚拟语气的结构是：were/was/be + 过去分词。在这个例句中，虚拟语气用的是were aware，表示他们声称他们不知道ChatGPT可以编造案例。这个句子的意思是说，他们声称他们不知道ChatGPT可以编造案例。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>It may seem that outsourcing tasks to generative AI like ChatGPT could increase productivity</li>
<li>However, it might actually limit the supplementary learning that occurs when people do certain tasks, so AI must be deployed with care</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/5a7e78e1-6d56-4263-b127-4cf22193c5c2_b285be82.jpg" /><figcaption>After the public gained access to OpenAI’s chatbot, which can create human-like written responses to simple user prompts, in November 2022, it shifted how people think about artificial intelligence. Photo: TNS</figcaption></figure><p>Generative artificial intelligence, especially OpenAI’s implementation of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243449/chatgpt-one-year-how-openais-chatbot-brought-generative-artificial-intelligence-public-consciousness" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT,</a> has opened up new possibilities for the creation of intelligent content. In fact, AI-generated content is so good that it reads almost as if it was written by a human being.</p><p>For example, a study by researchers from US universities published in May found that when answering random patient questions from a social media platform, ChatGPT outperformed physicians in terms of both quality of information and empathy. And OpenAI has a said GPT4, the state-of-the-art model underlying ChatGPT Plus, could score in the top 10 per cent in the SAT reading exam for college admissions, the GRE verbal test for graduate school admissions and the uniform bar exam for lawyers.</p><p>This tool is expected to be deployed in companies and other organisations to enhance worker productivity. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3227884/chatgpt-helps-hong-kong-students-critical-thinking-teachers-stay-ahead-human-touch" target="_self" title="">Schools and teachers</a> are also keen to embrace it. Many universities now <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3233269/hong-kong-universities-relent-rise-chatgpt-ai-tools-teaching-and-assignments-keep-eye-out-plagiarism" target="_self" title="">allow students</a> to use generative AI in course work and assignments. Some local institutions offer free access to ChatGPT, encouraging students to use it in school.</p><p>However, generative AI has its limitations. Because the content it produces is generated from a complex large-language model instead of logically developed and based on facts, AI sometimes “hallucinates”, that is, produces incorrect or misleading results, due to insufficient training data, bias and incorrect assumptions. In June, two lawyers in the US <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223490/us-lawyer-sorry-after-chatgpt-creates-fake-cases" target="_self" title="">were sanctioned</a> for using ChatGPT to produce a legal brief with fictitious case citations. They claimed they weren’t aware ChatGPT could make up cases.</p><p>This case raises an important question: how does generative AI affect human capability when people no longer need to develop logical arguments and verify facts when creating content?</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Using generative AI to produce work is akin to outsourcing it to other people. Thus, we can infer its impact on human capability by referencing outsourcing.</p><p>We conducted research on how contributions to the well-known programming language, Python, changed after the introduction of a crowdsourcing program called Internet Bug Bounty (IBB), which rewards people for finding security vulnerabilities in open source software – but excludes the official system maintainers, who have been reporting and fixing bugs, and making enhancements, from the reward.</p><p>The IBB program should have made the Python maintainers’ job easier, giving them more time to perform other tasks and hence increasing their productivity in those tasks.</p><p>Interestingly, we found the opposite. The official Python maintainers not only discovered fewer bugs after the IBB program, they also made fewer enhancements to Python. This means their overall productivity fell after bug reporting was outsourced.</p><p>We looked at many reasons for the drop in productivity, including a loss of motivation due to not being rewarded in the IBB program. We concluded that it was mainly due to a lack of inter-task learning. There was a bigger drop in productivity among Python maintainers who reported more bugs before the IBB program than those who reported fewer. The drop was also bigger when the bug reporting and enhancement tasks were more closely related.</p><p>We surveyed a number of Python maintainers, most of whom said that finding vulnerabilities helped them learn and gain ideas for how to enhance the program. This implies that when performing a task, we not only contribute to the outcome, we learn at the same time.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Internet Bug Bounty program, which rewards people for identifying security vulnerabilities in open source software, should have helped increase the productivity of those whose job it is to find and fix bugs, but that has not necessarily happened. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1021" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/d1810c19-5739-4f42-8dda-8bdb3366e566_50b374a4.jpg" title="The Internet Bug Bounty program, which rewards people for identifying security vulnerabilities in open source software, should have helped increase the productivity of those whose job it is to find and fix bugs, but that has not necessarily happened. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Internet Bug Bounty program, which rewards people for identifying security vulnerabilities in open source software, should have helped increase the productivity of those whose job it is to find and fix bugs, but that has not necessarily happened. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>This inter-task learning side-effect is illuminating. It suggests that learning and other capabilities may be sacrificed when we enjoy the power and convenience of generative AI. The short-term gain in productivity could be offset by the long-term loss in capability. Worse, this capability may be key to our contribution to future tasks, including, possibly, intelligent knowledge work.</p><p>So how should generative AI use be managed in an organisation? First, distinguish between objectives – are we seeking work output or learning and training? In most places, work output may be the priority, so it would be reasonable to actively deploy generative AI tools. Even so, we must be aware this may slow employees’ learning of how to perform tasks.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3247902/how-ai-development-fostered-digital-sweatshop-and-why-it-matters-technologys-future" title="">How AI development has fostered a digital ‘sweatshop’ in poor countries</a></h3><p>Second, start classifying tasks by nature, in terms of whether they are interrelated. Generative AI tools may be better deployed for tasks that have little relation to other tasks, for example, pure automation jobs. We might wish to discourage AI’s use for deeply intertwined tasks.</p><p>Third, more training should be provided once generative AI is deployed. People are intrinsically lazy. If we let them use generative AI without supplementing it with learning opportunities, their ability may deteriorate over time.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>At school, the priority should be learning rather than work output. We must seek to prevent the unrestrained use of generative AI in homework or assignments. If students don’t do homework themselves but outsource it entirely to AI, they may soon lose the ability to reason, innovate and produce more advanced knowledge.</p><p>We must revisit the common question, “Why waste time doing mundane work when AI can do it for us?” This is a dangerous sentiment because we do work not only to produce an outcome, but to learn as well. Such learning builds the foundation for future knowledge production.</p><p>We should not get carried away by generative AI, thinking that only work outcomes matter. The learning itself is equally important, if not more so.</p><p><strong>Kai-Lung Hui is Elman Family Professor of Business and senior associate dean at Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Business School</strong></p><p><strong>Jiali Zhou is an assistant professor at the American University in Washington DC</strong></p><p><strong>The views expressed here are the authors’ own</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Davos 2024: OpenAI CEO Altman, Time Owner Benioff disagree on AI’s use of copyrighted content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248702/davos-2024-openai-ceo-altman-time-owner-benioff-disagree-ais-use-copyrighted-content</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  Marc Benioff, the Salesforce CEO and owner of Time magazine, raised concerns about AI companies using copyrighted materials without proper compensation. He criticized AI companies for exploiting stolen training data and called for standardization of payments to fairly compensate content creators.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Fairness and compensation in AI training data usage.</li>    <li>Theme: AI companies need to ensure fair treatment of content creators by paying for usage of their copyrighted materials in training data.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The need for standardization in payment structures and responsible AI data usage.</li>    <li>Main information: AI companies using content from media outlets without permission; ongoing negotiations with publications like Time and The New York Times; OpenAI's perspective on the value of training data; partnerships between AI companies and news organizations.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  Salesforce首席执行官兼《时代》杂志所有者马克·贝尼奥夫对人工智能公司在未经适当补偿的情况下使用受版权保护的材料表示担忧。他批评人工智能公司利用窃取的训练数据，并呼吁标准化付款方式来公平地补偿内容创作者。  <ul>    <li>摘要：人工智能训练数据使用中的公平性和补偿。</li>    <li>主题：人工智能公司需要通过支付使用其受版权保护的材料作为训练数据的费用来确保对内容创建者的公平待遇。</li>    <li>观点：在支付结构和负责任的人工智能数据使用方面的标准化的必要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：人工智能公司在未经许可的情况下使用来自媒体机构的内容；与《时代》和《纽约时报》等出版物的持续谈判；OpenAI对训练数据价值的看法；人工智能公司与新闻机构之间的合作关系。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>standardise (v.) - 标准化，使标准化。    <p>原文例句：Benioff added, but AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由standard（标准，规范）和-ise（使……标准化）组成，表示“使标准化，使一致”。在这个例句中，它表示人工智能公司应该标准化付款方式，以公平地对待内容创建者。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>archive (n.) - 档案，档案馆。    <p>原文例句：In July, OpenAI signed an agreement with the Associated Press to access some of the news agency’s archives.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于法语archives，表示“档案，档案馆”。在这个例句中，它指的是新闻机构的档案库，其中存储了大量新闻报道和资料。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make use of - 利用，使用。    <P>原文例句：OpenAI has been striking partnerships for specific uses of news content and more are coming. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由make（使，做）和use（使用）构成的，表示“利用，使用”。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI一直在为特定用途的新闻内容建立合作关系，并且还有更多合作关系即将到来。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>OpenAI has been striking partnerships for specific uses of news content and more are coming, Altman said. - Altman说，OpenAI一直在为特定用途的新闻内容建立合作关系，而且还有更多合作关系即将到来。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Altman said，其中主语是Altman，谓语是said，宾语是more are coming。OpenAI has been striking partnerships for specific uses of news content是一个现在完成进行时态的句子，其中主语是OpenAI，谓语是has been striking，宾语是partnerships。这个句子的意思是说，OpenAI一直在为特定用途的新闻内容建立合作关系，而且还有更多合作关系即将到来，这句话来自Altman的讲话。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Salesforce markets its AI-powered software features as including a “trust layer” to prevent the misuse of customer data.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示Salesforce一直在营销其人工智能驱动的软件功能，其中包括一个“信任层”，以防止客户数据的滥用。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、愿望、建议或命令等。    <p>原文例句：OpenAI has disputed that it used protected material without permission. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语气，结构是：should/could/would + 动词原形。其中should表示应该，could表示可能，would表示愿意或将要。这种语气常用于表示假设、愿望、建议或命令等。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI否认在未经许可的情况下使用受保护的材料。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly, says Salesforce CEO and Time owner Marc Benioff</li>
<li>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman says training data often is not as valuable as its owners think it is</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/205a42a4-b828-49fe-9b5b-64ae3191358d_a0e69d62.jpg" /><figcaption>Marc Benioff, CEO of Salesforce.com, at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Marc Benioff, the Salesforce chief executive officer who also owns Time magazine, said artificial intelligence (AI) companies ripped off intellectual property to build their technology.</p><p>“All the training data has been stolen,” Benioff said Tuesday in an interview at Bloomberg House at the World Economic Forum in Davos. Content from media outlets including Time and The New York Times surfaces in results from AI companies, he said.</p><p>There is increasing scrutiny on the makers of large language models that power generative AI tools such as ChatGPT over their use of copyrighted materials. Benioff’s Time is among publications currently negotiating with ChatGPT maker OpenAI to license their news work, as first reported by Bloomberg.</p><p>Other companies include Warner Bros Discovery’s CNN and Fox. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3246432/new-york-times-sues-chatgpt-maker-openai-microsoft-copyright-infringement-unlawful-use-stories-train" target="_self" title="">The New York Times sued OpenAI</a> and its partner Microsoft in November for using the publication’s articles without permission.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/256a3cae-17dc-4815-bfb6-2b8f632dd1af_a66cec46.jpg" title="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, in Davos on Monday. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Nobody really exactly knows” what a fair price for this data is, Benioff added, but AI companies should standardise payments to treat content creators fairly. Benioff’s Salesforce markets its AI-powered software features as including a “trust layer” to prevent the misuse of customer data.</p><p>OpenAI has disputed that it used protected material without permission. CEO Sam Altman, in an interview earlier Tuesday with Bloomberg, said training data often is not as valuable as its owners think it is.</p><p>“We do not want to train on The New York Times data,” Altman said, adding that research is more focused on learning from small amounts of high-quality data. It should be possible to avoid any news content that is off limits, he said.</p><p>OpenAI has been striking partnerships for specific uses of news content and more are coming, Altman said. “I think there’s going to be great new ways to consume and monetise news.”</p><p>In July, OpenAI signed an agreement with the Associated Press to access some of the news agency’s archives. OpenAI also reached <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content" target="_self" title="">a three-year deal in December with Axel Springer</a> to use the German media company’s work for an undisclosed sum.</p><p>When asked whether AI presented risks to the democratic process in an election year for many countries, Benioff said his biggest concern is still social media. “Regulators have not done their job,” he added.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Davos 2024: Microsoft CEO ‘comfortable’ with OpenAI non-profit board structure despite Altman ousting</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248699/davos-2024-microsoft-ceo-comfortable-openai-non-profit-board-structure-despite-altman-ousting</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉在达沃斯出席世界经济论坛期间表示，他“对OpenAI的任何结构都没有意见”。微软没有完全拥有OpenAI这一事实以一种有利于竞争的方式区分了他们的交易。微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉在瑞士达沃斯举行的世界经济论坛年会上。图片来源：法新社微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉周二表示，他对合作伙伴OpenAI的治理结构没有异议，此前这家初创公司的非营利董事会无视投资者的利益暂时赶下台首席执行官。11月，OpenAI首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼因涉嫌沟通故障而被突然解雇，引发了这家支持ChatGPT的初创公司危机，员工威胁要集体辞职，为微软工作，而微软正向OpenAI投资数十亿美元。“我感到轻松。我对任何结构都没有意见，”纳德拉在彭博新闻社在达沃斯举行世界经济论坛年会期间的活动中表示。OpenAI董事会负责保护这家非营利初创公司的使命，即开发造福人类的强大人工智能，最终在几天后恢复了阿尔特曼的职务，目前正在对其成员进行补充。OpenAI首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼周二在达沃斯举行的彭博社活动中表示：“我预计在未来几个月内，我们会在这方面取得很大进展。”“之后，新董事会将审视治理结构。”他说：“我们将从各个角度进行审视。”微软现在在OpenAI董事会获得了不参加投票的观察员席位。据报道，欧洲、英国和美国的竞争当局已开始密切关注微软与OpenAI的关系。据了解条款的人士称，他们的协议保证了这家Windows制造商在符合特定条件的情况下获得大量初创公司的利润。纳德拉表示，微软没有完全拥有OpenAI这一事实以一种有利于竞争的方式区分了他们的交易。“事实上，建立合作关系是进行竞争的一种途径，”他说。纳德拉表示，微软对计算能力的投资以及在ChatGPT成名之前多年对OpenAI的押注，是一场“高风险的赌注”，“并非所有传统智慧都如此”。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella has no issues with OpenAI's governance structure, even after the start-up's non-profit board ousted its chief executive.</li>    <li>Theme: Microsoft's partnership with OpenAI and the ongoing discussions about its governance structure.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Nadella's perspective on the OpenAI deal, the role of partnerships in competition, and微软's investments in OpenAI.</li>    <li>Main information: Nadella's comments at the World Economic Forum in Davos; OpenAI's temporary removal of its CEO and subsequent reinstatement; OpenAI's mission to develop AI for the benefit of humanity; Microsoft's non-voting observer position on the OpenAI board; scrutiny of the Microsoft-OpenAI relationship by competition authorities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉在世界经济论坛达沃斯会议期间表示，他对OpenAI的“任何架构”都不存在异议。纳德拉表示，微软不完全拥有OpenAI这一事实以有利于竞争的方式区别了他们的交易。微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉周二表示，他对合作伙伴OpenAI的治理结构没有异议，此前这家初创公司的非营利董事会无视投资者的利益暂时驱逐了其首席执行官。 11 月，OpenAI 首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼因涉嫌沟通故障而被突然解雇，引发了这家支持 ChatGPT 的初创公司的危机，员工威胁要集体辞职，为微软工作，而微软正在向 OpenAI 投资数十亿美元。“我很自在。我对任何结构都没有异议。”纳德拉在彭博新闻社在达沃斯举行的世界经济论坛年会期间的活动中表示。 OpenAI 董事会负责保护这家非营利初创公司的使命，即开发造福人类的强大人工智能，最终在几天后恢复了阿尔特曼的职务，目前正在对其成员进行补充。 OpenAI 首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼周二在达沃斯举行的彭博社活动中表示：“我预计我们将在未来几个月内在这一点上取得很大进展。”“之后，新董事会将审视治理结构。”他说：“我们将从各个角度进行审视。”微软现在在 OpenAI 董事会获得了不参加投票的观察员席位。据报道，欧洲、英国和美国的竞争当局已开始密切关注微软与 OpenAI 的关系。据了解条款的人士称，他们的协议保证了这家 Windows 制造商在符合特定条件的情况下获得大量初创公司的利润。纳德拉表示，微软不完全拥有OpenAI这一事实以有利于竞争的方式区别了他们的交易。“事实上，建立合作伙伴关系是进行竞争的一种途径，”他说。纳德拉表示，微软对计算能力的投资以及在 ChatGPT 成名之前多年对 OpenAI 的押注，是一场“高风险的赌注”，“并非所有传统智慧都如此”。  <ul>    <li>摘要：微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉对 OpenAI 的治理结构没有异议。</li>    <li>主题：微软与 OpenAI 的合作伙伴关系及其治理结构的持续讨论。</li>    <li>观点：纳德拉对 OpenAI 交易的看法、合作伙伴关系在竞争中的作用以及微软对 OpenAI 的投资。</li>    <li>主要信息：纳德拉在达沃斯举行的世界经济论坛上的评论； OpenAI 暂时免除其首席执行官并随后恢复原职； OpenAI 开发造福人类的 AI 的使命；微软在 OpenAI 董事会的不具投票权的观察员席位；竞争当局对微软与 OpenAI 关系的审查。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>chunk (n.) - /tʃʌŋk/ 大块，块。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft’s investments in computing power and years-old bet on OpenAI before its ChatGPT fame, Nadella said, were a “highly risky bet” and “not all conventional wisdom”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词指的是一块大块的物质，尤其是一大块无定形的物质。在这个例句中，它指的是微软对OpenAI的投资，以及在ChatGPT成名之前多年对它的押注。</p></li>    <li>framework (n.) - /ˈfreɪmˌwɜːk/ 框架，结构。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft’s investments in computing power and years-old bet on OpenAI before its ChatGPT fame, Nadella said, were a “highly risky bet” and “not all conventional wisdom”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词指的是支持或包含某物的结构。在这个例句中，它指的是微软在ChatGPT成名之前多年对OpenAI的投资和押注。</p></li>    </ul>  <ul>    <li>in fact - 事实上，实际上。    <p>原文例句：“Partnerships is one avenue of, in fact, having competition,” he said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“实际上”或“事实上”。在这个例句中，它强调了纳德拉认为合作伙伴关系实际上是实现竞争的一种途径。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>go look at sth. from all angles - 从各个角度审视某事。    <P>原文例句：“We’ll go look at it from all angles,” he said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示从不同的角度、全面地审视或考虑某事。在这个例句中，它表示OpenAI的新董事会将从各个角度审视治理结构。</p></li>    <li>take a look at sth. - 看一看某事，审视某事。    <P>原文例句：“And then after that, the new board will take a look at the governance structure.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示看一看或审视某事。在这个例句中，它表示开放AI的新董事会将审视治理结构。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“Partnerships is one avenue of, in fact, having competition,” he said. - 他说：“合作关系实际上是进行竞争的一种途径”。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Partnerships is one avenue of having competition，其中主语是Partnerships，谓语是is，宾语是一one avenue of having competition。in fact是一个插入语，表示“实际上”。在这个句子中，纳德拉表达了这样的观点：合作伙伴关系实际上是实现竞争的一种途径。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Satya Nadella, speaking on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum’s meeting in Davos, says he has ‘no issues with any structure’ at OpenAI</li>
<li>The fact that Microsoft does not fully own OpenAI distinguished their deal in a pro-competitive way, according to Nadella</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/82fe2885-0760-4ede-8a50-6e322e78b818_940b6a88.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella at the World Economic Forum annual meeting in Davos, Switzerland on Tuesday. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella on Tuesday said he had no issue with partner OpenAI’s governance structure, two months after the start-up’s non-profit board temporarily ousted its chief executive without regard to investors’ interests.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3241992/chatgpt-maker-open-ai-pushes-out-co-founder-and-ceo-sam-altman-says-he-wasnt-consistently-candid" target="_self" title="">surprise November dismissal</a> of OpenAI’s CEO Sam Altman over an alleged communication breakdown triggered a crisis at the start-up behind ChatGPT, in which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242258/nearly-all-openai-staff-threaten-go-microsoft-unless-board-quits-investors-try-bring-back-altman" target="_self" title="">employees threatened to resign en masse</a> and go work for Microsoft, which is backing OpenAI with billions of dollars.</p><p>“I’m comfortable. I have no issues with any structure,” Nadella said at a Bloomberg News event on the sidelines of the World Economic Forum’s annual meeting in Davos.</p><p>OpenAI’s board, charged with protecting the start-up non-profit’s mission to develop powerful artificial intelligence that benefits humanity, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242394/microsoft-pushes-changes-openai-after-board-start-sought-merger-rival-anthropic" target="_self" title="">ultimately restored Altman</a> days later and now is in the process of filling out its membership.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1309" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/0651d6dd-f234-47b6-97b5-741fcb1f1268_28052076.jpg" title="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI in Davos on Tuesday. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>“I expect us to make a lot of progress on that in the coming months,” OpenAI CEO Altman said at a later Bloomberg event in Davos. “And then after that, the new board will take a look at the governance structure.”</p><p>“We’ll go look at it from all angles,” he said.</p><p>Microsoft has now secured a non-voting observer position on the OpenAI board.</p><p>Competition authorities in Europe, Britain and reportedly the United States have started looking closely at the Microsoft-OpenAI relationship. Their agreement guarantees the Windows maker large chunks of the start-up’s profits depending on certain conditions, a person briefed on the terms has said.</p><p>According to Nadella, the fact that Microsoft does not fully own OpenAI distinguished their deal in a pro-competitive way.</p><p>“Partnerships is one avenue of, in fact, having competition,” he said.</p><p>Microsoft’s investments in computing power and years-old bet on OpenAI before its ChatGPT fame, Nadella said, were a “highly risky bet” and “not all conventional wisdom”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with widening iPhone discounts, but rival Huawei stays above the fray</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com offers discounts on iPhone 15 up to US$112, exceeding Apple's price cuts. Apple dethroned Samsung as the global smartphone shipment leader in 2023, according to IDC. Chinese smartphone vendors respond with discounts on Android handsets. Huawei makes a comeback in the 5G smartphone market but faces supply shortages. Apple's mainland sales are down due to competition and economic challenges. Huawei's Mate 60 Pro 5G is popular but limited by production constraints.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Price war intensifies as Apple and Chinese vendors offer discounts on smartphones in mainland China.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple gains market share globally but faces challenges in mainland China amid a price war.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of price wars and brand loyalty in the competitive smartphone market.</li>    <li>Main information: JD.com's iPhone 15 discounts; Apple's record global smartphone shipments; Chinese vendors' response with Android discounts; Huawei's return and Mate 60 Pro 5G popularity; Apple's mainland sales decline and Huawei's supply shortage.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  中国电商巨头京东周一大力宣传iPhone 15降价高达800元人民币（约合112.24美元），高于苹果自身的价格减让。据研究公司IDC称，苹果在2023年全球智能手机出货量上超越了长期占据领先地位的三星。中国智能手机厂商纷纷通过线上线下零售活动降低了旗下各种安卓手机的价格，以应对最新一轮的iPhone降价。图片：Shutterstock随着苹果首次在2023年在全球年出货量上超越竞争对手三星电子，内地价格战激烈升级，内地是全球最大的智能手机市场。中国电商巨头京东周一大肆宣传iPhone 15最新机型降价高达800元人民币（约合112.24美元），就在同一天，苹果宣布下调多款机型的价格，包括去年9月发布的iPhone 13及其新手机，降价幅度最高达500元人民币。中国主要智能手机厂商，包括小米和荣耀，纷纷通过线上线下零售活动降低了旗下各种安卓机型的价格。去年在5G智能手机市场复出的华为并未采取类似策略。苹果在中国内地采取非典型的降价措施，表明这家美国科技巨头专注于在全球第二大经济体中站稳脚跟，尽管全球iPhone销量疲软，导致该公司在本月初遭遇两级评级下调。2023年9月8日，华为Mate 60 Pro智能手机在上海的商店中展出。这家总部位于深圳的公司迄今为止还没有采取措施降低其最新5G手机的价格。 Photo: ReutersIDC亚太区客户设备高级研究经理威尔·黄表示：“与世界其他地区相比，苹果在中国面临更多挑战。”“它不仅面临来自华为的竞争，还面临消费者现在更加谨慎支出情绪的变化。”根据1月7日发布的杰富瑞研究报告，在今年的第一周里，内地iPhone销量同比下降了30%。该经纪公司表示，iPhone 14和14 Plus机型的“折扣大幅增加”，而较新的iPhone 15和15 Plus机型的折扣“适度增加”。据杰富瑞称，去年内地iPhone的总销量较2022年下降了3%，相当于苹果市场份额下降了0.4%。本月，由于对智能手机需求的担忧，苹果股价下跌，使微软在1月12日收盘价高于iPhone制造商后成为全球最有价值的公司。微软以2.89万亿美元市值超越苹果，成为全球最有价值的公司不过，苹果周一收到了一些好消息，研究公司IDC报告称，这家总部位于加州库比蒂诺的公司去年在全球智能手机出货量上超越了长期占据领先地位的三星。据IDC称，苹果去年的全球智能手机出货量达到2.346亿台，使该公司创纪录地获得了20.1%的市场份额，较2022年的2.263亿台增长了3.7%。苹果也是排名前四的智能手机供应商中唯一一家在2023年实现出货量增长的公司，其他三家公司分别是三星、小米和OPPO。IDC全球移动和消费者设备追踪器部门的集团副总裁瑞安·赖斯表示，在激烈的全球智能手机竞争中，“整个Android领域正在内部多样化。”“华为已经回归，并在中国迅速取得进展。”华为总部位于深圳，去年8月推出了Mate 60 Pro 5G手机，搭载先进的国产处理器，无视美国的科技限制，从而重返智能手机市场的溢价细分市场。该公司的新款5G智能手机及其先进芯片被誉为中国在挑战美国严厉制裁方面取得胜利的象征，引发了强烈的爱国热潮，从而转化为强劲的国内销售。分析师认为，华为Mate 60 Pro对美国制裁是一次打击，但战斗仍在继续然而，由于生产限制，华为面临Mate 60 Pro的供应短缺。这款热门的5G机型仍在实行预约购买计划，在该公司官方网站上无法立即购买。IDC的黄表示，由于内地宏观经济环境疲软，苹果及其中国竞争对手转向价格促销，华为将需要依靠其品牌的强大实力来抵御这些不利因素。“生产限制似乎是华为面临的一个障碍，但它也可能是营销策略[创造更大的需求]，”黄说。###</div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>discount (n.) - /ˈdɪskaʊnt/ 折扣，优惠。    <p>原文例句：Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com on Monday touted discounts of as much as US$112 off on the iPhone 15, higher than Apple’s own local price markdown. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由dis-（降低，减少）和count（算，计数）构成的，表示“减少的价格或价值”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国电商巨头JD.com在周一宣传的iPhone 15高达112美元的折扣，高于苹果自身的价格减让。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>shipments (n.) - /ˈʃɪpmənt/ 发货，运输。    <p>原文例句：Apple topped global smartphone shipments in 2023 to unseat long-standing market leader Samsung, according to research firm IDC.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由ship（船）和ment（状态，条件）构成的，表示“通过船只、飞机或卡车运送的货物”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司根据研究公司IDC的数据，在2023年全球智能手机发货量中名列前茅，击败了长期占据领先地位的三星。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>price war - 价格战。    <P>原文例句：A price war in mainland China, the world’s largest smartphone market, has intensified amid widening discounts offered for iPhones by online marketplaces, as Apple unseated rival Samsung Electronics in annual industry shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由price（价格）和war（战争）构成的，表示“为了吸引顾客而进行的价格竞争”。在这个例句中，它指的是在内地价格战加剧，因为在线市场为iPhone提供的折扣不断扩大，这是因为苹果首次在2023年在全球年出货量上超越了竞争对手三星电子。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters - 2023 年 9 月 8 日，华为 Mate 60 Pro 智能手机在其上海门店展出。这家总部位于深圳的公司到目前为止还没有采取措施降低其最新 5G 手机的价格。图片：路透社。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones，谓语是are seen on display，宾语是at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023。The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets是一个现在完成时的否定句，表示这家总部位于深圳的公司到目前为止还没有采取措施降低其最新 5G 手机的价格。Photo: Reuters是一个插入语，表示图片的来源是路透社。这个句子的意思是说，华为 Mate 60 Pro 智能手机于 2023 年 9 月 8 日在其上海门店展出。这家总部位于深圳的公司到目前为止还没有采取措施降低其  <ul><li>Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com on Monday touted discounts of as much as US$112 off on the iPhone 15, higher than Apple’s own local price markdown</li>
<li>Apple topped global smartphone shipments in 2023 to unseat long-standing market leader Samsung, according to research firm IDC</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/66dac82e-619d-4ada-b6cc-c633141a8133_2a932251.jpg" /><figcaption>The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>A price war in mainland China, the world’s largest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> market, has intensified amid widening discounts offered for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhones</a> by online marketplaces, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> unseated rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> in annual industry shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023.</p><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> on Monday touted deeper discounts of as much as 800 yuan (US$112.24) off on the latest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3235981/apple-iphone-15-review-faster-cheaper-new-standard-models-are-big-jump-over-their-predecessors" target="_self" title="">iPhone 15</a> model in a post on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a>, which was on the same day <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248529/apples-china-price-cuts-iphones-macbooks-cancel-out-pressure-rivals-chasing-premium-segment-say" target="_self" title="">Apple offered to cut prices by up to 500 yuan</a> on a range of models, including the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3148864/apples-iphone-13-may-not-have-many-new-features-its-lower-price-tag" target="_self" title="">iPhone 13</a> and its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235532/apples-iphone-15-draws-long-lines-china-despite-competition-huawei" target="_self" title="">new handsets that debuted last September</a>.</p><p>The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honor" target="_self" title="">Honor</a>, knocked down prices on their various Android models in both online and offline retail campaigns. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, which last year <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china" target="_self" title="">made a comeback in the 5G smartphone market</a>, did not pursue a similar strategy.</p><p>Apple’s atypical discount drive on the mainland shows the US tech giant’s focus to gain ground in the world’s second-biggest economy amid sluggish global iPhone sales, which has seen the company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">hit by two ratings downgrades</a> in the first week of this year.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/49690f1b-f395-4601-bae1-959ea30c7d93_ca1ba25a.jpg" title="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Apple faced more challenges in China compared to the rest of the world,” said Will Wong, senior research manager for client devices at IDC Asia-Pacific. “It not only faced competition from Huawei, but also a change in consumers’ sentiment that is now more cautious in spending.”</p><p>In the first week of the year, iPhone sales on the mainland were already down 30 per cent year on year, according to a Jefferies research note published on January 7. The brokerage indicated that there was “a big rise in discounts” for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3209228/apple-cuts-iphone-14-prices-china-us125-making-rare-sales-push-following-quarterly-revenue-drop" target="_self" title="">iPhone 14</a> and 14 Plus models, while the newer iPhone 15 and 15 Plus models saw “a moderate rise” in discounts.</p><p>The iPhone’s total sales volume last year on the mainland was down 3 per cent from 2022, which translated to a 0.4 per cent decline in Apple’s market share, according to Jefferies.</p><p>Worries about smartphone demand have pushed Apple’s shares down this month, enabling <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft</a> to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248395/microsoft-overtakes-apple-worlds-most-valuable-company-us289-trillion-market-capitalisation" target="_self" title="">become the world’s most valuable company</a> after ending the January 12 trading session in the US higher than the iPhone maker.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248395/microsoft-overtakes-apple-worlds-most-valuable-company-us289-trillion-market-capitalisation" title="">Microsoft overtakes Apple as world’s most valuable company at US$2.89 trillion</a></h3><p>Still, Apple received some good news on Monday when research firm IDC reported that the Cupertino, California-based company topped global smartphone shipments last year to dethrone long-standing market leader Samsung.</p><p>Apple’s global smartphone shipments last year reached 234.6 million units that gave the company a record market share of 20.1 per cent, up 3.7 per cent from 226.3 million in 2022, according to IDC. Apple was also the sole smartphone vendor in the top-four rankings – including Samsung, Xiaomi and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> – to record unit shipment growth in 2023.</p><p>On the intense global smartphone competition, the “overall Android space is diversifying within itself”, said Ryan Reith, group vice-president at IDC’s Worldwide Mobility and Consumer Device Trackers unit. “Huawei is back and making inroads quickly within China.”</p><p>Shenzhen-based Huawei’s return to the premium segment of the smartphone market was paved by its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china" target="_self" title="">launch last August of the Mate 60 Pro 5G handset</a>, powered by an advanced home-grown processor that defied US tech restrictions. The company’s new 5G smartphone and its advanced chip was hailed as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">symbolic of China’s victory in defying tough US sanctions</a>, fanning strong patriotic fervour that translated into robust domestic sales.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain" title="">Huawei’s Mate 60 Pro is a blow to US sanctions but battles remain, analysts say</a></h3><p>Huawei, however, faces a supply shortage for the Mate 60 Pro because of production constraints. The popular 5G model is still subject to a reservation purchase scheme without immediate availability on the company’s official website.</p><p>As Apple and its Chinese rivals turn to price promotions amid the weak macroeconomic environment on the mainland, Huawei will need to rely on the strength of its brand name to weather these headwinds, according to IDC’s Wong.</p><p>“The production constraints seem like a hurdle to Huawei, but it may also be a marketing tactic [to create greater demand],” Wong said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>HashKey claims ‘unicorn status’ after raising US$100 million for one of Hong Kong’s two licensed cryptocurrency exchanges</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248601/hashkey-claims-unicorn-status-after-raising-us100-million-one-hong-kongs-two-licensed-cryptocurrency</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>HashKey Group, which is a cryptocurrency exchange company, has raised US$100 million in a funding round, achieving a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, making it a unicorn company.</li>    <li>The funds will be applied to enhance its web3 ecosystem, diversify product offerings, and expand internationally.</li>    <li>HashKey operates HashKey Exchange, HashKey Capital, and other blockchain technology services.</li>    <li>It was approved to provide services to retail investors in Hong Kong in 2018, attracting 15,500 registered users with daily trading volume reaching US$630 million in December 2023.</li>    <li>Hong Kong is making efforts to become a crypto hub, despite the market plunge caused by scandals.</li>    <li>Venture capital funding for cryptocurrency decreased last year, but is recovering due to positive news such as the approval of the first spot Bitcoin exchange-traded funds in the US.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>HashKey Group，一家加密货币交易所公司，在融资中筹集了 1 亿美元，实现了 12 亿美元的估值，成为独角兽公司。</li>    <li>这些资金将用于增强其 web3 生态系统、多样化产品服务并进行国际扩张。</li>    <li>HashKey 经营 HashKey Exchange、HashKey Capital 和其他区块链技术服务。</li>    <li>该公司于 2018 年获得许可，在香港为零售投资者提供服务，截至 2023 年 12 月，已吸引 15500 名注册用户，日交易量超过 6.3 亿美元。</li>    <li>香港正在努力成为一个加密货币中心，尽管市场因丑闻而暴跌。</li>    <li>去年加密货币的风投资金减少，但由于诸如美国批准第一批现货比特币交易所交易基金 (ETF) 等利好消息，正在复苏。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>funding round - 融资轮。    <p>原文例句：HashKey Group, the company behind one of Hong Kong’s two cryptocurrency exchanges approved to serve retail investors, said it raised nearly US$100 million in a funding round that valued it at more than US$1 billion, making it a so-called unicorn company.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：funding round 是指公司或企业为了筹集资金而进行的一轮融资。这个词组由 funding（融资）和 round（轮）组成，表示“融资轮”。在这个例句中，它指的是 HashKey Group 在一轮融资中筹集了近 1 亿美元的资金。</p></li>    <li>pre-money valuation - 公司在融资前的估值。    <p>原文例句：Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, the Hong Kong-based company said in a statement on Tuesday, without disclosing any names.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：pre-money valuation 是指公司在融资前的估值。这个词组由 pre（在……之前）和 money（钱）以及 valuation（估值）组成，表示“融资前的估值”。在这个例句中，它指的是 HashKey Group 在新一轮融资前的估值为 12 亿美元。</p></li>    <li>unicorn company - 独角兽公司。    <p>原文例句：HashKey Group, the company behind one of Hong Kong’s two cryptocurrency exchanges approved to serve retail investors, said it raised nearly US$100 million in a funding round that valued it at more than US$1 billion, making it a so-called unicorn company.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：unicorn company 是指估值超过 10 亿美元的未上市科技公司。这个词语由 unicorn（独角兽）和 company（公司）组成，表示“独角兽公司”。在这个例句中，它指的是 HashKey Group 在融资后成为了一家估值超过 10 亿美元的独角兽公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>retail investors - 散户投资者。    <p>原文例句：HashKey Group, the company behind one of Hong Kong’s two cryptocurrency exchanges approved to serve retail investors, said it raised nearly US$100 million in a funding round that valued it at more than US$1 billion, making it a so-called unicorn company.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：retail investors 是指那些非专业或机构的个人投资者。这个词组由 retail（零售）和 investors（投资者）组成，表示“散户投资者”。在这个例句中，它指的是 HashKey Group 获得批准为散户投资者提供服务。</p></li>    <li>virtual asset exchange license - 虚拟资产交易所牌照。    <p>原文例句：OKX Ventures, the investment arm of OKX, one of the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchanges and an applicant for Hong Kong’s virtual asset exchange license, is one of the lead investors in HashKey’s funding round, Bloomberg reported.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：virtual asset exchange license 是指虚拟资产交易所获得的经营许可证。这个词组由 virtual（虚拟的）、asset（资产）、exchange（交易所）和 license（许可证）组成，表示“虚拟资产交易所牌照”。在这个例句中，它指的是 OKX Ventures 是 HashKey 融资轮的领投方之一，而 OKX Ventures 是 OKX 的投资部门，OKX 是世界上最大的加密货币交易所之一，也是香港虚拟资产交易所牌照的申请者。</p></li>    <li>venture capital funding - 风险投资资金。    <p>原文例句：Venture capital funding in the cryptocurrency industry plunged last year following a series of collapses in 2022.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：venture capital funding 是指风险投资机构提供的资金。这个词组由 venture（冒险）、capital（资本）和 funding（资金）组成，表示“风险投资资金”。在这个例句中，它指的是加密货币行业的风险投资资金在 2022 年经历了一系列崩盘后大幅下降。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15. - 该公司已经在印度生产 iPhone 和其他产品很多年了，其中包括最新的 iPhone 15。    <p>句子分析：这是一个现在完成进行时态的句子，表示该动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。主语是 the company，谓语是 has been making，其中 making 是动词 make 的现在分词形式。宾语是 iPhones and other products，介词短语 in India 表示地点，for several years 表示时间段。including the latest iPhone 15 是一个现在分词短语，作状语，表示动作或状态的伴随情况。这个句子的意思是，该公司已经在印度生产 iPhone 和其他产品很多年了，其中包括最新的 iPhone 15。</p></li>    <li>In the three months ending September 2023, cryptocurrency firms around the world raised US$1.8 billion across 309 deals, representing a 69.6 per cent decline in deal value and 55.9 per cent drop in deal numbers from the same period a year ago, according to data by PitchBook. - 根据 PitchBook 的数据，在截至 2023 年 9 月的三个月里，全球加密货币公司在 309 笔交易中筹集了 18 亿美元，与去年同期相比，交易价值下降了 69.6%，交易数量下降了 55.9%。    <p>句子分析：这是一个比较复杂的句子，包含了一个主句和两个从句。主句是 cryptocurrency firms around the world raised US$1.8 billion across 309 deals，其中主语是 cryptocurrency firms around the world，谓语是 raised，宾语是 US$1.8 billion。从句之一是 in the three months ending September 2023，其中 in the three months ending September 2023 是一个介词短语，作时间状语，表示截止到 2023 年 9 月的三个月。另一个从句是 representing a 69.6 per cent decline in deal value and 55.9 per cent drop in deal numbers from the same period a year ago，其中 representing a 69.6 per cent decline in deal value and 55.9 per cent drop in deal numbers from the same period a year ago 是一个现在分词短语，作结果状语  <ul><li>Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, HashKey Group said</li>
<li>OKX Ventures is one of the lead investors in HashKey’s funding round, Bloomberg reported</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/3db425dc-5d1c-4046-8dd8-4e916a7cbc11_056fab3a.jpg" /><figcaption>A view of HashKey Group’s booth during the 2021 Hong Kong FinTech Week at the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre on 3 November 2021. Photo: Shutterstock.</figcaption></figure><p>HashKey Group, the company behind one of Hong Kong’s two cryptocurrency exchanges approved to serve retail investors, said it raised nearly US$100 million in a funding round that valued it at more than US$1 billion, making it a so-called unicorn company.</p><p>Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, the Hong Kong-based company <a href="https://group.hashkey.com/en/newsroom/HashKey-Group-Series-A-Financing-Round" target="_self" title="">said in a statement</a> on Tuesday, without disclosing any names.</p><p>OKX Ventures, the investment arm of OKX, one of the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchanges and an applicant for Hong Kong’s virtual asset exchange license, is one of the lead investors in HashKey’s funding round, Bloomberg reported. HashKey and OKX both declined to comment.</p><p>HashKey operates the licensed HashKey Exchange, the HashKey Capital venture capital and asset management arm and other blockchain technology services. It will use the funding to “solidify” its web3 ecosystem, diversify its licensed product offerings in Hong Kong and develop its business globally, it said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246047/chinas-crypto-craving-back-door-binance-traders-look-more-important-exchanges-future-wake-us" title="">China’s back-door cryptocurrency traders look more important than ever to Binance’s future</a></h3><p>HashKey Group, established in Hong Kong in 2018, was approved by the Securities and Futures Commission <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3229913/hashkey-and-osl-receive-hong-kongs-first-approvals-operate-crypto-exchanges-retail-investors" target="_self" title="">last August</a> to serve retail investors under the city’s new regime for centralised cryptocurrency exchanges.</p><p>The exchange attracted 15,500 registered users at the end of 2023, with daily trading volume exceeding US$630 million in December, HashKey said last month. Nearly 40 per cent of the value traded on its platform came from professional investors, it said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3201697/what-are-virtual-assets-hong-kong-and-what-do-citys-new-rules-mean-crypto-trading" title="">What does Hong Kong mean by virtual assets?</a></h3><p>HashKey Exchange handled US$15.3 million in trading volume over 24 hours through Tuesday, according to the market tracker CoinGecko. That is a trickle compared with the US$13.6 billion transacted over the same period on Binance, the world’s largest exchange for cryptocurrencies.</p><p>HashKey is one of a range of cryptocurrency firms banking on Hong Kong’s push to embrace the virtual asset industry, even as public perception of the sector has plunged following scandals involving companies including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ftx" target="_self" title="">FTX</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jpex-cryptocurrency-scandal" target="_self" title="">JPEX</a>.</p><p>Twelve companies have so far submitted their applications for Hong Kong’s licence for virtual asset trading platforms.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3237817/hong-kongs-crypto-hub-dream-mired-high-costs-other-barriers-one-year-jpex-one-stumbling-block" title="">High costs cloud Hong Kong’s crypto hub dream</a></h3><p>Venture capital funding in the cryptocurrency industry plunged last year following a series of collapses in 2022. In the three months ending September 2023, cryptocurrency firms around the world raised US$1.8 billion across 309 deals, representing a 69.6 per cent decline in deal value and 55.9 per cent drop in deal numbers from the same period a year ago, according to data by PitchBook.</p><p>The market recently bounced back on the back of enthusiasm brought by the US’ approval of the first spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs), which allow investors to gain exposure to virtual assets without directly buying any cryptocurrency tokens.</p><p>Hong Kong last month also said that it will move to open up retail access to cryptocurrency spot ETFs, after previously only allowing retail participation in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3203539/crypto-futures-etfs-debut-hong-kong-lukewarm-interest-after-market-turmoil-ftx-collapse?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">cryptocurrency futures ETFs</a>, which hold cryptocurrency futures contracts, instead of direct investments in cryptocurrency tokens at their spot prices.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech war: Chinese chip-tool giant Naura forecasts surge in 2023 sales on strong local demand amid US export controls</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3248610/tech-war-chinese-chip-tool-giant-naura-forecasts-surge-2023-sales-strong-local-demand-amid-us-export</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2><ul>  <li>Naura Technology Group anticipates a significant rise in revenue and net profit for 2023 due to technological advancements that boost domestic demand.</li>  <li>Following the departure of foreign semiconductor equipment manufacturers from China, domestic chip makers are seeking local alternatives to fill the gap.</li></ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2><ul>  <li>纳芯科技集团预计 2023 年营收和净利润将大幅增长，因为技术突破推动了本地需求。</li>  <li>随着外国半导体设备制造商退出中国，本土芯片制造商纷纷寻找国内替代品。</li></ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue - (n.) 收入，进账。    <p>原文例句：Naura Technology Group expects last year’s sales to grow by roughly half.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Revenue指从销售商品或提供服务中获得的收入或进账。在这个例句中，Naura Technology Group预计去年的销售额将增长大约一半。</p></li>    <li>profit - (n.) 利润。    <p>原文例句：Net profits are expected to increase between 57 per cent and 80 per cent to between 3.3 billion yuan and 3.8 billion yuan.    <p>例句讲解：Profit通常指从销售商品或提供服务中获得的收入减去成本和费用后的剩余部分。在这个例句中，纳芯科技的净利润预计将增长57%到80%，介于33亿到38亿人民币之间。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>leap in - (n.) 飞跃，重大进步。    <p>原文例句：[Naura] has made technology breakthroughs and achieved volume production of more than a dozen of semiconductor equipment including etching, deposition and cleaning, and furnace, which help the company to cover more semiconductor manufacturing processes, leading to higher market shares.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Leap in通常指突然或大幅度的进步、提升或增长。在这个例句中，纳芯科技取得了技术突破，实现了包括蚀刻、沉积、清洗和炉子在内的十几种半导体设备的批量生产，帮助公司覆盖了更多的半导体制造工艺，从而提高了市场份额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“技术突破和批量量产了包括刻蚀、沉积清洗、炉管工艺在内的十余种半导体设备，帮助公司覆盖了更多半导体制造工艺，带动市场份额提升。”纳芯科技说。    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，包含了两个分句。主句是“纳芯科技说”，其中主语是“纳芯科技”，谓语是“说”。第一分句是“技术突破和批量量产了包括刻蚀、沉积清洗、炉管工艺在内的十余种半导体设备”，其中主语是“纳芯科技”，谓语是“技术突破和批量量产了”。第二分句是“帮助公司覆盖了更多半导体制造工艺，带动市场份额提升”，其中主语是“技术突破和批量量产了包括刻蚀、沉积清洗、炉管工艺在内的十余种半导体设备”，谓语是“帮助公司覆盖了更多半导体制造工艺，带动市场份额提升”。这个句子的意思是说，纳芯科技取得了技术突破，实现了包括蚀刻、沉积、清洗和炉子在内的十几种半导体设备的批量生产，帮助公司覆盖了更多的半导体制造工艺，从而提高了市场份额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>半导体设备及其应用 - 半导体设备是用于制造半导体器件的机器和设备。半导体器件是电子设备的基础，广泛应用于计算机、手机、汽车等领域。</li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Naura Technology expects a jump in both its revenue and net profit in 2023, as technology breakthroughs drive local demand</li>
<li>With foreign semiconductor equipment manufacturers pulling out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/dc40cd20-632e-4e89-9957-bc5f891f0b1e_628de1bf.jpg" /><figcaption>Naura Technology Group expects last year’s sales to grow by roughly half. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>State-backed Chinese semiconductor equipment giant Naura Technology Group expects its 2023 revenue to jump by around half from a year earlier, as leaps in its technology helped it gain a larger market share in the country.</p><p>The company said in a regulatory filing on Monday evening that its revenue last year is projected to grow between 42 per cent and 57 per cent to 20.9 billion yuan and 23.1 billion yuan (US$2.93 billion and US$3.24 billion).</p><p>“[Naura] has made technology breakthroughs and achieved volume production of more than a dozen of semiconductor equipment including etching, deposition and cleaning, and furnace, which help the company to cover more semiconductor manufacturing processes, leading to higher market shares,” Naura said.</p><p>Net profits are expected to increase between 57 per cent and 80 per cent to between 3.3 billion yuan and 3.8 billion yuan.</p><p>The company said it received over 30 billion yuan worth of new equipment orders in 2023, over 70 per cent of them related to semiconductor-related tools. It did not disclose similar figures in its revenue forecasts for 2022 or 2021.</p><p>Beijing-based Naura counts China’s largest foundries as major clients, such as Yangtze Memory Technologies Corp (YMTC).</p><p>Amid a government-supported semiconductor self-sufficiency drive, YMTC has been in talks with domestic tool suppliers, including what was said to be a major company based in the Chinese capital, to produce replacements for crucial parts widely found in its equipment made by US firm Lam Research, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3235074/tech-war-chinas-top-memory-chip-maker-ymtc-forges-closer-ties-domestic-supplier-replace-us-parts" target="_self" title="">sources told the Post last year</a>.</p><p>Lam Research has suspended equipment supply and services to clients in mainland China after Washington tightened US export controls in October 2022.</p><p>With foreign players pulling their staff and operations out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives. The surging demand has helped lift sales of Chinese equipment manufacturers, although most of their products – especially those in advanced nodes below 10 nanometres – are thought to lag in quality.</p><p>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment China, Naura’s main rival, has said it expects 2023 revenue to rise more than 30 per cent on the back of strong demand from mainland fabs.</p><p>Shares of Shenzhen-listed Naura rose around 3 per cent to nearly 239 yuan in the morning trading session on Tuesday.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
