<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Chinese EV maker Geely introduces first pure electric Galaxy model, to woo mainstream buyers from BYD, foreign brands</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247567/chinese-ev-maker-geely-introduces-first-pure-electric-galaxy-model-woo-mainstream-buyers-byd-foreign</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Geely Automobile Group launched the Galaxy E8, a pure electric sedan, under its mass-market brand Galaxy to compete with BYD's popular models. The E8 starts at 175,800 yuan (US$24,752), undercutting BYD's Han EV by 34,000 yuan. Geely aims to sell seven models under the Galaxy brand by 2025, targeting budget-minded consumers. The company also plans to manufacture and sell a total of seven models under the Galaxy brand compared to its Zeekr-branded EVs, which compete against premium models built by companies like Tesla.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Geely launches a new pure electric sedan, the Galaxy E8, to compete with BYD's popular models. </li>    <li>Theme: Geely aims to grab a larger share of the Chinese EV market with its new Galaxy E8 model.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The Galaxy E8 is positioned as a budget-friendly alternative to BYD's Han EV.</li>    <li>Main information: The Galaxy E8's pricing, features, and target market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  吉利汽车集团推出了一款纯电动轿车——极氪E8，该车基于旗下大众市场品牌极氪打造，旨在与比亚迪旗下热销车型竞争。极氪E8起售价为175,800元（合24,752美元），低于比亚迪的汉EV 34,000元。吉利计划到2025年在极氪品牌下销售七款车型，目标是预算敏感型大陆车主。该公司还计划与旗下子品牌极氪合作，制造和销售总共七款车型，与特斯拉等公司生产的高端车型竞争。  <ul>    <li>摘要：吉利推出新纯电动轿车极氪E8，以与比亚迪旗下的畅销车型竞争。</li>    <li>主题：吉利的目标是在中国电动汽车市场上凭借其新的极氪E8车型抢占更大的市场份额。</li>    <li>观点：极氪E8被定位为比亚迪汉EV的经济实惠的替代品。</li>    <li>主要信息：极氪E8的定价、特性和目标市场。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>budget-minded (adj.) - 注重预算的，注重成本的。    <p>原文例句：Based on the company’s Sustainable Experience Architecture (SEA), the E8 is also its first full-electric car, following two plug-in hybrid vehicles – the L7 sport-utility vehicle and the L6 sedan – launched in 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由budget（预算）和minded（思想的，注意到的）组成的，意为“注重预算的，注重成本的”。在这个例句中，它指的是目标注重预算的消费者。</p></li>    <li>premium (adj.) - 优质的，高档的。    <p>原文例句：The company plans to manufacture and sell a total of seven models under the Galaxy brand by 2025. The cars will be more affordable for mainland consumers than the company’s Zeekr-branded EVs, which compete against premium models built by companies like Tesla</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，意为“优秀的，第一位的”。在这个例句中，它指的是优质的，高档的。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>battery swapping (n.) - 电池交换。    <p>原文例句：Battery-swapping technology allows owners of electric cars to quickly exchange a spent battery pack for a fully charged one.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个名词是由battery（电池）和swapping（交换）组成的，意为“电池交换”。在这个例句中，它指的是一种允许电动汽车车主快速更换电池组的技术。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：In terms of safety, design, performance and intelligence, E8 proves to be superior to all blockbuster models,” he said during a media briefing after a launch ceremony on Friday. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示在安全性，设计，性能和智能方面，E8都优于所有热门车型。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Geely Holding has a nearly 6 per cent share of mainland China’s EV market. - 吉利控股在中国大陆电动汽车市场份额接近6%。<p>句子分析：这是一个主动语态的肯定句，主语是Geely Holding，谓语是has，宾语是a nearly 6 per cent share of mainland China’s EV market。nearly 6 per cent share of mainland China’s EV market是一个名词短语，作宾语。在这个句子中，它表示吉利控股在中国大陆电动汽车市场份额接近6%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示主体遭受或接受动作。    <p>原文例句：The E8 is also its first full-electric car, following two plug-in hybrid vehicles – the L7 sport-utility vehicle and the L6 sedan – launched in 2023.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，表示动作的接受者（E8）遭受或接受了动作（launched）。助动词是is，过去分词是launched。在这个句子的主语（E8）之前有介词短语following two plug-in hybrid vehicles – the L7 sport-utility vehicle and the L6 sedan –，表示在两款插电式混合动力汽车——L7运动型多用途汽车和L6轿车——于2023年推出之后。这个句子可以改写为：Two plug-in hybrid vehicles – the L7 sport-utility vehicle and the L6 sedan – were launched in 2023, and the E8 is also its first full-electric car.</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示虚拟的情况或假设。    <p>原文例句：The company plans to manufacture and sell a total of seven models under the Galaxy brand by 2025. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气，表示公司的计划或打算。助动词是plans，原形动词是manufacture and sell。在这个句子中，虚拟语气表示公司计划到2025年在银河品牌下生产和销售总共七款车型。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Galaxy E8 sells for almost about US$25,000, nearly US$5,000 less than BYD’s Han model</li>
<li>Geely plans to offer seven models under the affordable Galaxy brand by 2025, while its Zeekr brand targets more affluent buyers</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/07/fe08d875-eae8-4f43-a06b-0f78505b4ace_faa77576.jpg" /><figcaption>Geely Automobile Group’s Galaxy E8 sells for 175,800 yuan (US$24,752). Photo: Geely</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/geely" target="_self" title="">Geely Automobile Group</a>, one of China’s largest private carmakers, has launched a pure electric sedan under its mass-market brand Galaxy to take on BYD’s bestselling models amid intensified competition.</p><p>The basic edition of the E8, with a driving range of 550 kilometres, sells for 175,800 yuan (US$24,752), 34,000 yuan lower than the Han <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> built by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a>, which has a range of 506km.</p><p>Hangzhou-based Geely will begin delivering the Class B sedan in February, hoping to target budget-sensitive mainland motorists, according to the company’s CEO Gan Jiayue.</p><p>“In terms of safety, design, performance and intelligence, E8 proves to be superior to all blockbuster models,” he said during a media briefing after a launch ceremony on Friday. “We expect it to be an ideal model to replace both existing petrol and electric cars.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The E8 features a 45-inch screen supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology. Photo: Geely" class="image-inline caption" height="1275" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/07/d39c782a-7ceb-4ed9-8296-284ba2472139_c5eb9682.jpg" title="The E8 features a 45-inch screen supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology. Photo: Geely" width="2000" /><figcaption>The E8 features a 45-inch screen supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology. Photo: Geely</figcaption></figure></div><p>Geely lowered the price of the model by 12,200 yuan from its 188,000 yuan pricing on December 16 when presales started.</p><p>Based on the company’s Sustainable Experience Architecture (SEA), the E8 is also its first full-electric car, following two plug-in hybrid vehicles – the L7 sport-utility vehicle and the L6 sedan – launched in 2023.</p><p>The company plans to manufacture and sell a total of seven models under the Galaxy brand by 2025. The cars will be more affordable for mainland consumers than the company’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3239497/search-engine-baidu-and-carmaker-geelys-venture-starts-delivery-self-driving-ev-compete-teslas-model" target="_self" title="">Zeekr-branded EVs</a>, which compete against premium models built by companies like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a>, Gan said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247229/short-sellers-target-byd-worlds-top-ev-maker-rivalry-intensifies" title="">Short sellers target BYD, world’s top EV maker, as rivalry intensifies</a></h3><p>Its parent, Zhejiang Geely Holding Group, also owns marquees including Volvo, Lotus and Lynk. Geely Holding has a nearly 6 per cent share of mainland China’s EV market.</p><p>The E8 uses a Qualcomm Snapdragon 8295 chip to support its intelligent features such as voice-activated controls. A 45-inch screen, the biggest in a Chinese-made smart vehicle, is supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology.</p><p>At present, the Class B sedan category in China is dominated by petrol-powered models from foreign carmakers such as Volkswagen and Toyota.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>BYD, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest EV maker</a>, backed by Warren Buffett’s Berkshire Hathaway, delivered a total of 228,383 <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3217091/china-ev-war-how-byd-grew-elon-musks-ridicule-berkshire-hathaways-ridiculous-us98-billion-success-12" target="_self" title="">Han sedans</a> to Chinese customers in 2023, up 59 per cent on year.</p><p>Sales of battery-powered vehicles in mainland China are seen as growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from a 37 per cent rise last year, according to the China Passenger Car Association.</p><p>China is the world’s largest automotive and EV market, with sales of electric cars accounting for about 60 per cent of the global total. But only a few makers, including BYD and Li Auto, are profitable.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>A new round of price cuts is in effect, with top players like BYD and Xpeng offering discounts to lure buyers.</p><p>In November, Geely’s parent company formed a partnership with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246154/chinas-nio-unveils-et9-executive-sedan-its-most-expensive-ev-yet-flexes-tech-muscle-luxury-sector" target="_self" title="">Shanghai-based Nio</a>, a premium EV maker, to promote battery swapping technology as the two companies try to overcome the problem of inadequate charging infrastructure.</p><p>Battery-swapping technology allows owners of electric cars to quickly exchange a spent battery pack for a fully charged one.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei teardown shows 5-nm laptop chip made in Taiwan, not China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247568/huawei-teardown-shows-5-nm-laptop-chip-made-taiwan-not-china</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei's latest laptop, the Qingyun L540, was found to contain a 5-nanometer chip made by Taiwan's TSMC, dispelling rumors of a major breakthrough by Huawei's Chinese chipmaking partner, SMIC.</li>    <li>The discovery of the TSMC chip in the L540 contradicts earlier claims that SMIC had achieved a significant leap in fabrication technology.</li>    <li>Huawei's procurement of a three-year-old TSMC processor raises questions about how the company managed to obtain the chip despite US sanctions.</li>    <li>Huawei has been investing heavily in chip research and stockpiling in recent years, while also building a domestic network of suppliers and manufacturers.</li>    <li>The L540 laptop is part of Huawei's efforts to expand its product offerings beyond networking equipment and become a major player in the mobile and computing devices market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>华为最新款笔记本电脑青云 L540 被发现搭载了由台积电于 2020 年生产的 5 纳米芯片，打破了有关华为的中国芯片制造合作伙伴中芯国际取得重大突破的传言。</li>    <li>在 L540 中发现台积电芯片的事实与之前声称中芯国际在制造技术方面取得重大飞跃的说法相矛盾。</li>    <li>华为采购到三年前的台积电芯片引发了人们的疑问，即该公司是如何设法在遭受美国制裁的情况下获得该芯片的。</li>    <li>近年来，华为一直在加大对芯片研发的投入，并进行囤积，同时也在构建一个由供应商和制造商组成的国内网络。</li>    <li>L540 笔记本电脑是华为努力扩展其产品种类，从网络设备领域扩展到移动和计算设备市场，并成为主要参与者的举措之一。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>dispel (v.) - /dɪˈspel/ 消除，驱散，打消。    <p>原文例句：The discovery of the TSMC chip in the L540 contradicts earlier claims that SMIC had achieved a significant leap in fabrication technology. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语dispello（驱散，消除），表示“消除，驱散，打消”。在这个例句中，它是指发现L540中的台积电芯片与此前声称中芯国际在制造技术方面取得重大飞跃的说法相矛盾。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fabrication (n.) - /ˌfæbrɪˈkeɪʃən/ 制造，制造过程。    <p>原文例句：The discovery of the TSMC chip in the L540 contradicts earlier claims that SMIC had achieved a significant leap in fabrication technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语fabrica（制作，制造），表示“制造，制造过程”。在这个例句中，它是指发现L540中的台积电芯片与此前声称中芯国际在制造技术方面取得重大飞跃的说法相矛盾。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>procure (v.) - /prəˈkjʊər/ 采购，获得，取得。    <p>原文例句：It is unclear how Huawei managed to procure a three-year-old processor, though the Chinese company has been stockpiling vital semiconductors since the US began cutting off its access to components and gear globally.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语procurare（照顾，获得），表示“采购，获得，取得”。在这个例句中，它是指不清楚华为是如何设法采购到三年前的处理器的，尽管这家中国公司一直在囤积重要的半导体，因为美国已经开始在全球范围内切断其对组件和设备的访问。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sensitive environments - 敏感环境，即对数据安全或国家安全至关重要的环境，如政府机关、军事基地、关键基础设施等。    <p>原文例句：Its emergence coincides with a growing call from Beijing to replace foreign technology in sensitive environments, from mandates to stop using iPhones in the workplace to replacing Dell and HP computers. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组指的是对数据安全或国家安全至关重要的环境，如政府机关、军事基地、关键基础设施等。在这个例句中，它是指北京方面日益呼吁在敏感环境中取代外国技术，从禁止在工作场所使用iPhone到更换戴尔和惠普计算机等。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei’s procurement of a three-year-old TSMC processor raises questions about how the company managed to obtain the chip despite US sanctions. - 华为采购到三年前的台积电芯片引发了人们的疑问，即该公司是如何设法在遭受美国制裁的情况下获得该芯片的。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Huawei’s procurement of a three-year-old TSMC processor raises questions，其中主语是Huawei’s procurement of a three-year-old TSMC processor，谓语是raises questions。about how the company managed to obtain the chip despite US sanctions是一个介词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示华为是如何设法在遭受美国制裁的情况下获得该芯片的。这个句子的意思是说，华为采购到三年前的台积电芯片引发了人们的疑问，即该公司是如何设法在遭受美国制裁的情况下获得该芯片的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Huawei has been investing heavily in chip research and stockpiling in recent years, while also building a domestic network of suppliers and manufacturers. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示华为近年来一直在加大对芯片研发的投入，并进行囤积，同时也在构建一个由供应商和制造商组成的国内网络。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Qingyun L540 notebook contains a 5-nm chip made by TSMC in 2020, around the time US sanctions cut off Huawei’s access to the chip maker</li>
<li>Huawei caused a stir in the US and China last August when it released a smartphone with a 7-nm processor made by Shanghai-based SMIC</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/07/c9380a71-e793-48d8-862d-3a8e754b72f5_e6e9a731.jpg" /><figcaption>A Chinese flag flutters near a Huawei store in Shanghai,  September 8, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies’ newest laptop runs on a chip made by Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), a teardown of the device showed, quashing talk of another Chinese technological breakthrough.</p><p>The Qingyun L540 notebook contains a 5-nanometre chip made by the Taiwanese company in 2020, around the time US sanctions cut off Huawei’s access to the chip maker, research firm TechInsights found after dismantling the device for Bloomberg News. That counters speculation that Huawei’s mainland Chinese chipmaking partner, Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC), may have achieved a major leap in fabrication technique.</p><p>Huawei caused a stir in the US and China last August when it released a smartphone with a 7-nm processor made by Shanghai-based SMIC. A teardown by the Canada-based research outfit for Bloomberg News showed the Mate 60 Pro’s chip was only a few years behind the cutting edge, a feat that US trade curbs were meant to prevent. That revelation spurred celebration across the Chinese tech scene, and a debate in the US about the effectiveness of sanctions.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" title="">Huawei sees 9 per cent sales growth in 2023, boosted by Mate 60 Pro 5G comeback</a></h3><p>In the latest teardown, TechInsights discovered a Kirin 9006C processor fabricated via TSMC’s 5-nm method, which was assembled and packaged around the third quarter of 2020. Industry experts had previously speculated that SMIC achieved that milestone by developing workarounds to US sanctions, which would have marked a second technological triumph for the Chinese national champion in the span of months.</p><p>Representatives for Huawei and TSMC did not provide comment when reached by Bloomberg News.</p><p>The advances encapsulated in the Mate 60 smartphone in 2023 cemented Huawei’s role as the standard-bearer for Chinese efforts to wean itself off Western technologies and create domestic alternatives. Chinese consumers snapped up the smartphone in the final quarter, helping the company regain the symbolically important US$100 billion revenue threshold – eroding Apple’s iPhone dominance along the way.</p><p>A foray into 5-nm territory would have represented a big leap for the Shenzhen conglomerate, bringing it closer to the most-advanced processes currently in use, mostly centred around 3-nm nodes. Before TSMC cut off ties with Huawei, it was supplying chips as advanced as 5-nm to the Chinese firm.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246414/huawei-and-xiaomi-launch-new-ev-models-china-reigniting-worries-about-price-wars-worlds-largest-ev" title="">New EVs from Huawei, Xiaomi could renew price wars in China’s car market</a></h3><p>It is unclear how Huawei managed to procure a three-year-old processor, though the Chinese company has been stockpiling vital semiconductors since the US began cutting off its access to components and gear globally. While Huawei has been on Washington’s Entity List since 2019, it was only in 2020 that TSMC stopped taking orders from Huawei to comply with elevated US trade restrictions.</p><p>Huawei has since sunk billions into chip research and stockpiling in past years, while also building a domestic network of suppliers and manufacturing partners, in some cases with government backing.</p><p>The L540 is the latest in a line of laptops that Huawei began selling around 2016, when the then-networking leader developed ambitions to get into mobile and computing devices and round out its offerings.</p><p>Its emergence coincides with a growing call from Beijing to replace foreign technology in sensitive environments, from mandates to stop using iPhones in the workplace to replacing Dell and HP computers.</p><p>Some online retailers touted that the new laptop was designed specifically to comply with recent, stringent requirements in China on data security across sensitive government organs. Huawei’s official site highlights the device’s security features, but did not go into that detail.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>This year, prepare for the magic wand of generative AI to transform our world</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3247183/year-prepare-magic-wand-generative-ai-transform-our-world</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Generative AI is rapidly developing and becoming more multimodal, embedding itself into personal computers and smartphones, significantly impacting our daily lives.</li>    <li>Governments must address ethical, privacy, and copyright concerns to ensure the technology's positive growth, avoiding potential misuse.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>生成式人工智能正在迅速发展，变得更加多模态，嵌入个人电脑和智能手机，对我们的日常生活产生重大影响。</li>    <li>政府必须解决伦理、隐私和版权问题，以确保技术的积极发展，避免潜在的滥用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词汇：</h2>  <ul>    <li>proliferate (v.) - /prəʊˈlɪfəˌreɪt/ 迅速增长，繁殖。    <p>原文例句：The output of generative AI in these domains has proliferated, presenting a diverse array of creative work. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词的词根是proles（后代），加上-fer（产生）构成了proliferate，表示“迅速增长，繁殖”。在这个例句中，它描述了生成式人工智能在这些领域中的应用成果增长迅速，呈现出各式各样的创意作品。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>multi-modal (adj.) - /ˈmʌltiˌmōdəl/ 多模态的，多方式的。    <p>原文例句：Last year, most generative AI tools, algorithms and large language models were primarily focused on a single media type: text, images, speech or video, with limited emphasis on the simultaneous processing of multiple media. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由词根multi-（多）和modal（模式）构成的，表示“多模态的，多方式的”。在这个例句中，它描述了去年大多数生成式人工智能工具、算法和大语言模型主要专注于单一媒体类型，例如文本、图像、语音或视频，而较少关注多种媒体的同步处理。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>federated learning - 联合学习。    <P>原文例句：Generative AI applications that operate locally on personal computers and smartphones are built upon the concept of “federated learning”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由federated（联合的）和learning（学习）构成的，表示“联合学习”。在这个例句中，它指的是生成式人工智能的应用在个人电脑和智能手机上本地运行时所采用的概念。在这种概念下，平台无需将用户数据发送到云端进行搜索或信息组织等任务，从而为消费者提供更高的隐私保护和安全性。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The goal is to develop AutoGPT into a large-scale open-source AI platform, serving various industries. - 目标是将AutoGPT发展成一个服务于各行各业的大型开源人工智能平台。<p>句子分析：这个句子是一个复杂句，包含一个主句和一个目的状语从句。主句是The goal is to develop AutoGPT into a large-scale open-source AI platform，其中主语是The goal，谓语是is to develop，宾语是AutoGPT into a large-scale open-source AI platform。目的状语从句是serving various industries，其中serving是现在分词，作状语，修饰主句中的谓语动词develop，表示目的或意图。这个句子的意思是说，目标是将AutoGPT发展成一个服务于各行各业的大型开源人工智能平台。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>非谓语动词在句中作宾语或补语 - 非谓语动词可以在句中作宾语或补语，从而使句子的结构更加紧凑，表达更加简洁。    <p>原文例句：This year, work to set and agree on 6G standards will continue with the anticipation that the first standards could be introduced between 2027 and 2028, and the technology could reach commercialisation by 2030. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，work to set and agree on 6G standards是一个非谓语动词短语，作主语will continue的宾语，表示“制定和同意6G标准的工作将继续进行”。同时，could be introduced和could reach commercialisation都是非谓语动词短语，作主句中的补语，分别表示“可能被推出”和“可能达到商业化”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>主语从句 - 主语从句是用来修饰主语的名词性从句，它在句中充当主语。    <p>原文例句：Otherwise, there is a risk of unintended consequences, allowing malicious individuals to exploit generative AI’s capabilities. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，Otherwise, there is a risk of unintended consequences是一个主语从句，其中Otherwise是状语，表示“否则”，there is a risk of unintended consequences是一个主谓结构，其中there is a risk是谓语，of unintended consequences是宾语，意为“存在意外后果的风险”。这个主语从句用来修饰主语allowing malicious individuals to exploit generative AI’s capabilities，表示“否则，存在意外后果的风险，这将允许恶意的人利用生成式人工智能的功能”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Generative AI is becoming active, multimodal and being embedded in PCs and smartphones, penetrating our daily lives in profound ways</li>
<li>Governments must pay attention to ethical, privacy and copyright issues to ensure the positive development of the technology</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/993c33b7-d303-46f3-9fa7-b02b2516d087_73af80ad.jpg" /><figcaption>Customs inspector Hui Ka-hei explains how XiaoHui, a virtual ambassador introduced at Hong Kong’s airport and three control points, works to to handle public enquiries, on December 29. Photo: Dickson Lee</figcaption></figure><p>Since the debut of ChatGPT at the end of 2022, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243449/chatgpt-one-year-how-openais-chatbot-brought-generative-artificial-intelligence-public-consciousness" target="_self" title="">generative artificial intelligence</a> (AI) has gained popularity globally. Various industries are eagerly adopting generative AI for diverse applications including the creation of text, images, videos, computer codes and more.</p><p>The output of generative AI in these domains has proliferated, presenting a diverse array of creative work. According to Gartner, an information technology (IT) research and consulting company in the United States, use of generative AI will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245217/chinese-generative-ai-account-third-industrys-economic-value-2035-beijing-think-tank-says" target="_self" title="">increase substantially</a> by 2026. It projects that more than 80 per cent of businesses will have integrated generative AI application programming interfaces (APIs), models and/or applications into their operations by then, from less than 5 per cent now.</p><p>IT experts believe that generative AI will play a transformative role this year, akin to a magic wand that changes the world. In light of these developments, what major trends in generative AI can we expect this year?</p><p>Last year, most generative AI tools, algorithms and large language models were primarily focused on a single media type: text, images, speech or video, with limited emphasis on the simultaneous processing of multiple media. But with the emergence of models like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238197/baidu-says-ai-chatbot-ernie-now-matches-openais-gpt-4-unveils-new-enterprise-tools" target="_self" title="">GPT-4</a>, generative AI is shifting towards multi-modal expression, enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data.</p><p>This suggests that human-machine communication will one day effortlessly incorporate mixed media, as ChatGPT is starting to do. Users can input non-textual cues, such as images, making the conversation more convenient and natural.</p><p>Furthermore, multi-modal generative AI is poised to enhance the creative capabilities of artists and improve the efficiency of professionals in fields such as writing, journalism and music. When appropriately used, multi-modal generative AI can spark artistic inspiration, generate work drafts or even fully automate content creation.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>In 2024, there is likely to be a proliferation of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224924/ai-challenging-us-rethink-distinction-between-real-and-fake" target="_self" title="">AI-generated art</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3227291/ai-generated-hits-hong-kong-stars-surprise-fans-bring-dead-singers-back-life-and-raise-questions" target="_self" title="">music</a>, videos and stories. Experts believe that through generative AI’s artistic contributions, content will become more diverse, innovative and distinctive, ushering in a new era for creative industries.</p><p>Last year, generative AI operated primarily through user-driven prompts. Taking <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> as an example, interactions were conducted in a “question and answer” format and were purely passive. In response to this limitation, scientists are researching “auto agent” technology.</p><p>Auto agents can both generate and respond to prompts, performing tasks more rapidly and efficiently. A recent example is the AutoGPT system, which recently raised US$12 million in a funding round. The goal is to develop AutoGPT into a large-scale open-source AI platform, serving various industries.</p><p>Also set to thrive is the development of personalised generative AI systems. Computer companies are researching and developing AI personal computers capable of running generative AI applications locally, while chip companies have developed AI-embedded mobile processors, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236845/google-unveils-pixel-8-smartphones-pixel-watch-2-new-ai-features-mobile-processor" target="_self" title="">enabling smartphones</a> to execute generative AI models.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>A plethora of intelligent devices with diverse generative AI functionalities is emerging.</p><p>Generative AI applications that operate locally on personal computers and smartphones are built upon the concept of “federated learning”. This approach can afford consumers higher levels of privacy protection and security since these platforms do not need to send user data to the cloud for tasks such as searches or information organisation.</p><p>Meanwhile, by analysing user-specific data such as preferences, behaviours and conversations, this type of generative AI can optimise its performance based on individual characteristics and requirements, providing tailored content and task execution. This not only addresses concerns regarding privacy and security but also saves consumers time and effort.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3213160/how-ai-could-free-us-return-pursuit-wisdom" title="">Could AI free us to return to the pursuit of wisdom?</a></h3><p>Generative AI is also expected to play a significant role in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/6g" target="_self" title="">6G mobile technology</a>. This year, work to set and agree on 6G standards will continue with the anticipation that the first standards could be introduced between 2027 and 2028, and the technology could reach commercialisation by 2030. Generative AI can be applied to various aspects of 6G, such as network resource management, spectrum allocation and network topology optimisation.</p><p>It is also capable of meeting the demands of “connective intelligence” for new technologies. Connective intelligence is a key force driving the development of the 6G network, enabling real-time, reliable and ubiquitous interaction and communication between humans, the physical world and the digital world. This results in the creation of a decentralised and continually evolving intelligence, making it easier for users to share their discoveries and experiences with each other.</p><p>In summary, by the end of 2024, generative AI will become an invaluable assistant, providing support and help across different industries. Its powerful analysis and predictive capabilities will enable people to handle complex tasks and problems more efficiently, offering real-time solutions and recommendations.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3242417/fears-over-ai-dangers-are-hindering-chance-create-better-future" title="">How cooperation on AI governance can curb risks and create a better future</a></h3><p>Whether in fielding queries about professional knowledge or optimising and automating business processes, generative AI will play a crucial role. It will also become the ideal companion in consumption, leisure and entertainment.</p><p>Through personalised recommendation systems and intelligent assistant features, generative AI will gain a deep understanding of user preferences and needs, providing customised product and service suggestions. Whether in shopping, travel, music, film and television entertainment or social interaction, generative AI will enhance our experiences.</p><p>Generative AI has become an irreversible trend, penetrating our daily lives in profound ways. Governments must pay attention to ethical, privacy and copyright issues to ensure the positive development of the technology. Otherwise, there is a risk of unintended consequences, allowing malicious individuals to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246612/chatgpt-aided-ransomware-china-results-four-arrests-ai-raises-cybersecurity-concerns" target="_self" title="">exploit</a> generative AI’s capabilities.</p><p><strong>Wong Kam-fai is a legislative councillor, associate dean (external affairs) of the Faculty of Engineering at Chinese University and vice-president of the Hong Kong Professionals And Senior Executives Association</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
