<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>ChatGPT CEO Altman wants to raise billions of dollars to build AI chip factories, sources say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249291/chatgpt-ceo-altman-wants-raise-billions-dollars-build-ai-chip-factories-sources-say</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  OpenAI首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼正致力于从全球投资者那里筹集数十亿美元资金，用于建设一个芯片工厂网络，以生产半导体。阿尔特曼认为，随着人工智能变得更加普遍，用于广泛部署的芯片将不足够。筹集资金的谈判仍在早期阶段，涉及的合作伙伴和资助者的完整名单尚未确定。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: OpenAI CEO Sam Altman raises funds to build a network of chip factories.</li>    <li>Theme: The concern about the shortage of chips for widespread AI deployment.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The necessity of building a chip manufacturing network to meet the growing demand for AI.</li>    <li>Main information: Altman's conversations with potential investors; the involvement of G42, SoftBank, and other companies; the focus on working with top chip manufacturers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  OpenAI首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼正在努力从全球投资者那里筹集数十亿美元资金，用于建设一个芯片工厂网络，以生产半导体。阿尔特曼认为，随着人工智能变得更加普遍，用于广泛部署的芯片将不足够。筹集资金的谈判仍在早期阶段，涉及的合作伙伴和资助者的完整名单尚未确定。  <ul>    <li>摘要：OpenAI首席执行官萨姆·阿尔特曼筹集资金建设芯片工厂网络。</li>    <li>主题：对广泛的人工智能部署中芯片短缺的担忧。</li>    <li>观点：为满足人工智能日益增长的需求而建立芯片制造网络的必要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：阿尔特曼与潜在投资者的对话；G42、软银和其他公司的参与；专注于与顶级芯片制造商合作。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>deployment (n.) - /dɪˈplɔɪmənt/ 部署，配置。    <p>原文例句：Altman is concerned that as AI becomes more pervasive, there will not be enough chips for widespread deployment. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Deployment是指将人员、设备或资源部署到特定位置或任务中。在这个例句中，它指的是将芯片部署到广泛的人工智能应用中。</p></li>    <li>venture (n.) - /ˈvɛntʃər/ 风险事业，冒险。    <p>原文例句：Altman has been working to raise billions of dollars from global investors for a chip venture. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Venture是指一项涉及风险和不确定性的商业或金融活动。在这个例句中，它指的是阿尔特曼筹集资金用于建设芯片工厂网络的项目。</p></li>    <li>fabrication (n.) - /ˌfæbrɪˈkeɪʃən/ 制造，加工。    <p>原文例句：Altman aims to use the funds to set up a network of factories to manufacture semiconductors. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Fabrication是指制造或加工产品或材料的过程。在这个例句中，它指的是阿尔特曼计划使用筹集的资金来建立一个芯片工厂网络，以制造半导体。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>state-of-the-art (adj.) - 最先进的，最现代化的。    <p>原文例句：Constructing a single state-of-the-art fabrication plant can require tens of billions of dollars. </p>    <p>例句讲解：State-of-the-art是指最先进的或最现代化的。在这个例句中，它指的是建设一个最先进的芯片制造工厂需要花费巨额资金。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Altman has had conversations with several large potential investors in the hopes of raising the vast sums needed for chip fabrication plants, or fabs, as they are known colloquially, said the people, who requested anonymity because the conversations are private. - 阿尔特曼已经与几家大型潜在投资者进行了交谈，希望筹集到建设芯片制造工厂所需的巨额资金，人们这样说道，他们要求匿名，因为这些谈话是私下进行的。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Altman has had conversations，其中主语是Altman，谓语是has had conversations，宾语是with several large potential investors。in the hopes of raising the vast sums needed for chip fabrication plants, or fabs, as they are known colloquially是一个现在分词短语作目的状语，表示阿尔特曼与几家大型潜在投资者进行交谈的目的是为了筹集到建设芯片制造工厂所需的巨额资金。said the people, who requested anonymity because the conversations are private是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示这句话是那些要求匿名的消息人士说的，因为这些谈话是私下的。这个句子的意思是说，阿尔特曼已经与几家大型潜在投资者进行了交谈，希望筹集到建设芯片制造工厂所需的巨额资金，人们这样说道，他们要求匿名，因为这些谈话是私下进行的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 用作句子成分的动词形式。    <p>原文例句：Altman has had conversations with several large potential investors in the hopes of raising the vast sums needed for chip fabrication plants, or fabs, as they are known colloquially, said the people, who requested anonymity because the conversations are private.</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语是用作句子成分的动词形式，它是由一个分词和一个或多个修饰语组成的。在上面的例句中，in the hopes of raising the vast sums needed for chip fabrication plants, or fabs, as they are known colloquially是一个现在分词短语，作目的状语，表示阿尔特曼与几家大型潜在投资者进行交谈的目的是为了筹集到建设芯片制造工厂所需的巨额资金。said the people, who requested anonymity because the conversations are private是一个现在分词短语，作状语，表示这句话是那些要求匿名的消息人士说的，因为这些谈话是私下的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Altman is concerned that as AI becomes more pervasive, there will not be enough chips for widespread deployment</li>
<li>The talks with Abu Dhabi AI firm G42 alone had focused on raising US$8 billion to US$10 billion, sources say</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/22/38d8c516-680b-40f4-9046-a65efee4ba04_77370fb1.jpg" /><figcaption>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the World Economic Forum meeting in Davos, Switzerland last week. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">OpenAI</a> chief executive officer Sam Altman, who has been working to raise billions of dollars from global investors for a chip venture, aims to use the funds to set up a network of factories to manufacture semiconductors, according to several people with knowledge of the plans.</p><p>Altman has had conversations with several large potential investors in the hopes of raising the vast sums needed for chip fabrication plants, or fabs, as they are known colloquially, said the people, who requested anonymity because the conversations are private.</p><p>Firms that have held discussions with Altman include Abu Dhabi-based G42, people told Bloomberg last month, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/softbank" target="_self" title="">SoftBank Group</a>, some of the people said. The project would involve working with top chip manufacturers, and the network of fabs would be global in scope, some of the people said.</p><p>While efforts to raise funds for a chip venture were earlier reported by Bloomberg, the scope of the project and the focus on manufacturing was not previously known. The talks are still early and a full list of involved partners and funders has not been established, the people said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3238354/tech-war-us-ban-tailor-made-nvidia-and-intel-chips-hits-beijings-ai-ambitions" title="">US ban on tailor-made Nvidia and Intel chips hits Beijing’s AI ambitions</a></h3><p>Altman’s fundraising push reflects his concern that as AI becomes more pervasive, there will not be enough chips for widespread deployment, some of the people said. Some current forecasts for production of AI-related chips fall short of projected demand.</p><p>Building and maintaining fabs that manufacture semiconductors is far more expensive than the approach favoured by many of OpenAI’s AI industry peers. Amazon.com, Alphabet’s Google and Microsoft – OpenAI’s largest investor – typically focus on designing their own custom silicon and then farm out manufacturing to outside companies.</p><p>Constructing a single state-of-the-art fabrication plant can require tens of billions of dollars, and creating a network of such facilities would take years. The talks with G42 alone had focused on raising US$8 billion to US$10 billion, people told Bloomberg previously, although the current status of the discussions are unclear.</p><p>Altman believes the industry needs to act now to ensure there is sufficient supply near the end of the decade, according to people familiar with his thinking.</p><p>Since OpenAI released ChatGPT more than a year ago, interest in artificial intelligence applications has skyrocketed among companies and consumers. That in turn has spurred massive demand for the computing power and processors needed to build and run those AI programs. Altman has said repeatedly that there already are not enough chips for his company’s needs.</p><p>Intel, Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company and Samsung Electronics lead the chip fabrication market and are potential partners for OpenAI.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3246736/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-industry-weathers-tough-year-amid-tighter-us-sanctions" title="">China’s semiconductor industry weathers tough year amid tighter US sanctions</a></h3><p>Altman had been hard at work on the chips project until he was temporarily ousted as OpenAI CEO in November. Upon his return, he rekindled the efforts. Altman has also sounded out Microsoft on the plan, and the software giant is interested, according to two people.</p><p>OpenAI, G42, Intel, Microsoft, SoftBank and TSMC declined to comment. Samsung officials were not immediately available to comment.</p><p>G42, which focuses on artificial intelligence, has been the subject of calls this month by a key US lawmaker for greater scrutiny and trade restrictions.</p><p>US House China Select Committee chairman Mike Gallagher, a Republican from Wisconsin, raised concerns about G42’s relationships with blacklisted Chinese companies including Huawei Technologies and Beijing Genomics Institute, as well as risks to research at US universities.</p><p>Gallagher urged Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo to consider sanctions on G42 and 13 of its subsidiaries and affiliates.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>UK delivery firm DPD suspends AI chat function after bot swears at customer and writes poem disparaging company</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249284/uk-delivery-firm-dpd-suspends-ai-chat-function-after-bot-swears-customer-and-writes-poem-disparaging</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  英国包裹递送公司DPD暂停其在线聊天系统中的AI功能，起因是一名懊丧的用户诱使该系统创作了一首诗，描述了该公司客户服务的糟糕状况。“曾经有一个名为DPD的聊天机器人，它无法提供帮助，”在Ashley Beauchamp放弃试图获取客服电话号码后，它写道，他反而要求它写一首关于聊天机器人服务糟糕的诗。“DPD浪费时间，是客户最可怕的噩梦，”机器人继续写道，最后总结道：“有一天，DPD终于关门了，每个人都欢欣鼓舞。他们终于可以从一个知道自己在做什么的真人那里获得所需的帮助。”  <ul>    <li>Abstract: DPD的AI客服被用户诱导写诗吐槽服务差，引发公司暂停AI功能。</li>    <li>Theme: 由客户诱导的AI客服诗歌创作事件反映了DPD公司客户服务差的问题。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 此事件凸显了AI技术在客户服务中的局限性，也揭示了DPD公司需要改进客户服务质量。</li>    <li>Main information: 用户与DPD AI客服对话，诱导其写诗吐槽服务差；该诗在社交媒体上广泛传播；DPD公司暂停AI功能并表示正在更新。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  英国包裹递送公司DPD暂停其在线聊天系统中的AI功能，起因是一名懊丧的用户诱使该系统创作了一首诗，描述了该公司客户服务的糟糕状况。“曾经有一个名为DPD的聊天机器人，它无法提供帮助，”在Ashley Beauchamp放弃试图获取客服电话号码后，它写道，他反而要求它写一首关于聊天机器人服务糟糕的诗。“DPD浪费时间，是客户最可怕的噩梦，”机器人继续写道，最后总结道：“有一天，DPD终于关门了，每个人都欢欣鼓舞。他们终于可以从一个知道自己在做什么的真人那里获得所需的帮助。”  <ul>    <li>摘要：DPD的AI客服被用户诱导写诗吐槽服务差，引发公司暂停AI功能。</li>    <li>主题：由客户诱导的AI客服诗歌创作事件反映了DPD公司客户服务差的问题。</li>    <li>观点：此事件凸显了AI技术在客户服务中的局限性，也揭示了DPD公司需要改进客户服务质量。</li>    <li>主要信息：用户与DPD AI客服对话，诱导其写诗吐槽服务差；该诗在社交媒体上广泛传播；DPD公司暂停AI功能并表示正在更新。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>frustrated (adj.) - /ˈfrʌstreɪtɪd/ 沮丧的，懊恼的。    <p>原文例句：Ashley Beauchamp gave up trying to get it to share a phone number for customer services and asked it to write a poem about bad chatbot service instead.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由frustrate（使沮丧，使懊恼）构成的，表示“感到沮丧，感到懊恼”。在这个例句中，它描述了Ashley Beauchamp在试图获取客服电话号码失败后 cảm thấy沮丧，并要求聊天机器人写一首关于聊天机器人服务差的诗。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>nightmare (n.) - /ˈnaɪtmɛər/ 噩梦，可怕的事情。    <p>原文例句：“DPD was a waste of time, And a customer’s worst nightmare,” the bot continued before concluding: “One day, DPD was finally shut down and everyone rejoiced. Finally they could get the help they needed, From a real person who knew what they were doing.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由night（夜晚）和mare（母马）构成的，表示“噩梦，可怕的事情”。在这个例句中，它描述了DPD公司的客户服务是客户最可怕的噩梦，让客户感到非常不满和懊恼。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>be viewed - 被观看。    <P>原文例句：Beauchamp’s exchange with the bot has been viewed 1.1 million times since he posted it on social media platform X on Thursday.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由be（是）和viewed（观看）构成的，表示“被观看，被浏览”。在这个例句中，它表示自周四博尚在社交媒体平台 X 上发布以来，他与机器人的对话已被觀看 110 万次。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>be used to - 习惯于，被用来。    <P>原文例句：DPD UK said it had used an AI element within its chat system successfully for a number of years alongside its human customer service but an error had occurred after a system update.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由be（是）和used to（习惯于，被用来）构成的，表示“习惯于，被用来”。在这个例句中，它表示DPD UK 表示，在一段时间里，他们已经成功地在聊天系统中使用了 AI 元素，与人工客服一起工作，但在系统更新后出现了一个错误。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>A parcel delivery firm in Britain has disabled the artificial intelligence (AI) function in its online chat systems after a frustrated user coaxed the system into composing a poem about how bad the company’s customer service was. - 英国一家包裹递送公司在一名沮丧的用户诱使该系统创作了一首诗，描述了该公司客户服务的糟糕状况后，禁用了其在线聊天系统中的人工智能 (AI) 功能。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是A parcel delivery firm has disabled the artificial intelligence (AI) function in its online chat systems，其中主语是A parcel delivery firm，谓语是has disabled，宾语是the artificial intelligence (AI) function in its online chat systems。after a frustrated user coaxed the system into composing a poem about how bad the company’s customer service was是一个过去分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示在一名沮丧的用户诱使该系统创作了一首诗，描述了该公司客户服务的糟糕状况后。这个句子的意思是说，英国一家包裹递送公司在一名沮丧的用户诱使该系统创作了一首诗，描述了该公司客户服务的糟糕状况后，禁用了其在线聊天系统中的人工智能 (AI) 功能。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作状语 - 表示动作或事件发生在主句动作或事件之前。    <p>原文例句：A parcel delivery firm in Britain has disabled the artificial intelligence (AI) function in its online chat systems after a frustrated user coaxed the system into composing a poem about how bad the company’s customer service was. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示动作或事件发生在主句动作或事件之前。结构是：过去分词 + 其他。其中过去分词是动词的过去分词形式，其他是状语。在这个例句中，过去分词短语是after a frustrated user coaxed the system into composing a poem about how bad the company’s customer service was，表示在一名沮丧的用户诱使该系统创作了一首诗，描述了该公司客户服务的糟糕状况后。这个句子的意思是说，英国一家包裹递送公司在一名沮丧的用户诱使该系统创作了一首诗，描述了该公司客户服务的糟糕状况后，禁用了其在线聊天系统中的人工智能 (AI) 功能。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话者对某件事的看法或态度。    <p>原文例句：Beauchamp told ITV television he had still not received the parcel. “I think they might hold it hostage now. I wouldn’t blame them,” he said. “That’s totally on me.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示说话者对某件事的看法或态度。结构是：虚拟语气动词 + 其他。其中虚拟语气动词是动词的虚拟语气形式，其他是宾语、状语等。在这个例句中，虚拟语气动词是might hold，表示说话者认为他们可能会扣押包裹。这个句子的意思是说，博尚告诉 ITV 电视台，他仍然没有收到包裹。“我认为他们现在可能会扣押它。我不会责怪他们，”他说。“这完全是我的错。”</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>‘DPD was a waste of time, And a customer’s worst nightmare,’ wrote the bot, which failed to deliver information about the status of a parcel</li>
<li>DPD says the AI function was immediately disabled and is currently being updated</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/22/59fb55a4-30aa-4800-a0ff-424dfb499322_6785f53d.jpg" /><figcaption>British parcel delivery firm DPD has paused the AI function in its online chatbot over a service failure. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>A parcel delivery firm in Britain has disabled the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence (AI) function</a> in its online chat systems after a frustrated user coaxed the system into composing a poem about how bad the company’s customer service was.</p><p>“There was once a chatbot named DPD, Who was useless at providing help,” the bot wrote after Ashley Beauchamp gave up trying to get it to share a phone number for customer services and asked it to write a poem about bad chatbot service instead.</p><p>“DPD was a waste of time, And a customer’s worst nightmare,” the bot continued before concluding: “One day, DPD was finally shut down and everyone rejoiced. Finally they could get the help they needed, From a real person who knew what they were doing.”</p><p>Beauchamp, a pianist and conductor, posted his exchange with the bot on social media platform X on Thursday, since when it has been viewed 1.1 million times.</p><p>He said he initially asked the bot to tell him a joke after failing to get information about the status of a parcel and when it did he asked it to write the poem about automated customer service failings. He also encouraged the bot to swear.</p><p>Beauchamp told ITV television he had still not received the parcel. “I think they might hold it hostage now. I wouldn’t blame them,” he said. “That’s totally on me.”</p><p>DPD UK said it had used an AI element within its chat system successfully for a number of years alongside its human customer service but an error had occurred after a system update.</p><p>“The AI element was immediately disabled and is currently being updated,” the company said in a statement reported by ITV.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia chief visits China for the first time in 4 years as Chinese market headwinds mount</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3249258/nvidia-chief-visits-china-first-time-four-years-chinese-market-headwinds-mount</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang visited China for the first time in four years to attend company annual meetings amid intensified technology rivalry and trade tensions between the US and China.</li>    <li>Huang met with executives from Chinese tech companies and participated in a folk dance performance during his trip.</li>    <li>Nvidia faces challenges in the Chinese market due to US chip export restrictions, which have significantly impacted its data center revenues.</li>    <li>The company is developing new products that comply with US regulations to regain access to the Chinese market.</li>    <li>Nvidia's founder emphasized the importance of balancing national security and competitiveness while conducting business in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>英伟达首席执行官黄仁勋时隔四年再次访问中国，出席公司年度会议，正值中美科技竞争加剧和贸易紧张局势升级之际。</li>    <li>黄仁勋在访问期间会见了中国科技公司的高管，并参加了民间舞蹈表演。</li>    <li>由于美国芯片出口限制，英伟达在中国市场面临挑战，导致其数据中心收入大幅下降。</li>    <li>该公司正在开发符合美国法规的新产品，以重新进入中国市场。</li>    <li>英伟达创始人强调，在对华开展业务时，平衡国家安全和竞争力非常重要。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>founder (n.) - /ˈfaʊndə/ 创始人。    <p>原文例句：The billionaire founder’s first visit to China in more than four years, as the US chip giant remains in the cross hairs of intensified technology rivalry and escalated tensions between the US and China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由found（建立，发现）和-er（人，做事的人）构成，表示“建立者，创始人”。在这个例句中，它指的是英伟达的创始人黄仁勋。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>escalate (v.) - /ˈeskəˌleɪt/ 加剧，升级。    <p>原文例句：Huang’s latest visit came as Nvidia faces increasing headwinds in the Chinese market. Last October the US government further tightened chip export restrictions, blocking China’s access to graphics processing units (GPU) that Nvidia had specifically designed for Chinese clients in response to earlier curbs.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由ex-（出，离开）和scala（阶梯）构成，表示“升级，加剧”。在这个例句中，它指的是美国政府进一步收紧芯片出口限制，导致英伟达在中国市场面临越来越大的阻力。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in view of - 鉴于，考虑到。    <P>原文例句：Nvidia rolls out new chips, claims leadership of 'AI PC' race</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），view（视图，视野）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“考虑到，鉴于”。在这个例句中，它表示英伟达在考虑到美国芯片限制的情况下，推出新芯片，宣称在“人工智能电脑”领域处于领先地位。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia chief executive Jensen Huang Jen-hsun visited China for the first time in four years to attend company annual meetings, according to local media reports, as mainland Chinese market challenges mount for the US chip giant amid Washington’s moves to tighten export rules. - 英伟达首席执行官黄仁勋时隔四年再次访问中国，出席公司年度会议，正值中美科技竞争加剧和贸易紧张局势升级之际，据当地媒体报道，由于美国政府收紧出口规则，这家美国芯片巨头正面临着中国大陆市场的挑战。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Nvidia chief executive Jensen Huang Jen-hsun visited China for the first time in four years to attend company annual meetings，其中主语是Nvidia chief executive Jensen Huang Jen-hsun，谓语是visited，宾语是China，状语是for the first time in four years to attend company annual meetings。according to local media reports是一个状语，表示这一消息来自当地媒体报道。as mainland Chinese market challenges mount for the US chip giant amid Washington’s moves to tighten export rules是一个定语从句，修饰main clause，表示中美科技竞争加剧和贸易紧张局势升级之际，由于美国政府收紧出口规则，这家美国芯片巨头正面临着中国大陆市场的挑战。这个句子的意思是说，英伟达首席执行官黄仁勋时隔四年再次访问中国，出席公司年度会议，正值中美科技竞争加剧和贸易紧张局势升级之际，据当地媒体报道，由于美国政府收紧出口规则，这家美国芯片巨头正面临着中国大陆市场的挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态    <p>原文例句：Huang’s last public appearance in China was in December 2019, when he spoke about the adoption of artificial intelligence (AI) in the automotive, gaming and healthcare sectors.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是由have/has + 过去分词构成的，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。在这个例句中，现在完成时用来表示黄仁勋上一次在中国的公开露面是在2019年12月，当时他谈到了人工智能(AI)在汽车、游戏和医疗保健行业的应用。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>并列结构 - 同时包含两个或两个以上的成分，这些成分在句法上和意义上是对等的。    <p>原文例句：Huang visited China to “celebrate new year with employees”, an Nvidia spokesperson told the South China Morning Post in a statement on Sunday, declining to disclose more details of his trip.    <p>语法讲解：并列结构是指在句子中并列使用两个或两个以上结构相同、意义对等的词、词组或句子成分。在这个例句中，并列结构是由“celebrate new year with employees”和“declining to disclose more details of his trip”组成的，它们在句法上和意义上是对等的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In video clips circulating online, Huang, dressed in a floral-patterned vest, participates in Yangge, a type of folk dance from northern China</li>
<li>Huang’s last public appearance in China was in December 2019, when he spoke about the adoption of AI in the car, gaming and healthcare sectors</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/21/3a442763-f732-4b9d-8ca8-c8d47609d337_2066f9aa.jpg" /><figcaption>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang attends a media roundtable meeting in Singapore December 6, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia chief executive Jensen Huang Jen-hsun visited China for the first time in four years to attend company annual meetings, according to local media reports, as mainland Chinese market challenges mount for the US chip giant amid Washington’s moves to tighten export rules.</p><p>The Taiwan-born American entrepreneur visited Nvidia’s offices in Beijing, Shanghai and Shenzhen over the past week, and appeared on stage at the company’s annual meetings, according to reports by Chinese media outlets.</p><p>In video clips circulating online, Huang, 60, appeared on stage at one meeting dressed in a floral-patterned vest and participated in a programme of Yangge, a type of folk dance from northern China.</p><p>Huang visited China to “celebrate new year with employees”, an Nvidia spokesperson told the South China Morning Post in a statement on Sunday, declining to disclose more details of his trip.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247936/tsmc-halts-revenue-drop-beats-expectations-brisk-demand-ai-chips-nvidia-advanced-micro-devices" title="">Chip-making giant TSMC halts revenue drop on brisk AI demand</a></h3><p>The trip was the billionaire founder’s first visit to China in more than four years, as the US chip giant remains in the cross hairs of intensified technology rivalry and escalated tensions between the US and China.</p><p>Huang’s last public appearance in China was in December 2019, when he spoke about the adoption of artificial intelligence (AI) in the automotive, gaming and healthcare sectors.</p><p>In June last year, the Nvidia chief reportedly planned to visit Shanghai where he had planned to meet executives from Chinese technology companies including Tencent Holdings, TikTok owner ByteDance and smartphone giant Xiaomi. However, Huang ended up cancelling the trip.</p><p>Huang’s latest visit came as Nvidia faces increasing headwinds in the Chinese market. Last October the US government further tightened chip export restrictions, blocking China’s access to graphics processing units (GPU) that Nvidia had specifically designed for Chinese clients in response to earlier curbs.</p><p>Nvidia expects its sales to China and other US-restricted destinations, which together contributed about 20 to 25 per cent of its data-centre revenues in the past several quarters, to “decrease significantly” in the fourth quarter because of the new rules, the company said in financial statements released in November.</p><p>The company is now developing new products for the Chinese market that would not trigger US restrictions, but <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3242429/tech-war-nvidia-warns-sales-hit-china-us-chip-curbs-tailor-made-products-take-time-develop" target="_self" title="">warned</a> that it was a “significant process” that would take time, as the firm tries “finding the right balance” for its customers in China in view of the US chip restrictions.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247752/nvidia-rolls-out-new-chips-claims-leadership-ai-pc-race" title="">Nvidia rolls out new chips, claims leadership of 'AI PC' race</a></h3><p>“We have to come up with new chips that comply with the regulation, and once we comply with the regulation, we’ll go back to China,” Huang said in November at The New York Times’ DealBook conference in New York. “We try to do business with everybody we can. On the other hand, our national security matters. Our national competitiveness matters.”</p><p>The founder said in December that the company has been “<a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3244031/nvidia-working-closely-us-ensure-new-chips-china-are-compliant-curbs" target="_self" title="">working very closely</a>” with the US government to create compliant products. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3244739/nvidia-talks-biden-administration-about-ai-chip-sales-china-us-commerce-chief-gina-raimondo-says" target="_self" title="">US Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo said last month</a> that Nvidia “can, will and should sell AI chips to China because most AI chips will be for commercial applications”, but emphasised that the firm cannot sell its most advanced semiconductors to Chinese firms.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Shanghai delivery worker’s ‘yuan millionaire’ claim sparks heated debate amid China’s bleak jobs outlook</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249238/shanghai-delivery-workers-yuan-millionaire-claim-sparks-heated-debate-amid-chinas-bleak-jobs-outlook</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In China, a food delivery worker named Chen made headlines after claiming to have earned more than 1 million yuan in three years, an amount that is significantly higher than the average monthly wage. However, his claims have been met with skepticism, with many questioning whether it is possible to earn that much money in such a short time.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Food delivery rider's claim of earning over a million yuan in three years sparks debate.</li>    <li>Theme: The challenges and realities of gig work in China, including low wages, long hours, and job insecurity.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The need for better protections and support for gig workers in China, as well as more transparency and accountability from platform companies.</li>    <li>Main information: Chen's claims of earning 1 million yuan in three years; skepticism and doubts about his claims; the average monthly wage of food delivery riders in China; the rise of gig work in China and the challenges faced by gig workers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在中国，一位名叫陈某的外卖配送员因声称三年内赚取百万余元而成为新闻热点，这笔收入远高于平均月工资水平。然而，他的说法遭到了质疑，许多人怀疑在如此短的时间内赚到这么多钱是否可行。  <ul>    <li>摘要：外卖配送员三年内赚百万的言论引发热议。</li>    <li>主题：中国零工经济的挑战和现实，包括低工资、长时间工作和工作不稳定。</li>    <li>观点：需要加强对中国零工经济的保护和支持，以及提高平台公司的透明度和责任感。</li>    <li>主要信息：陈某声称三年内赚取百万余元；对其说法的质疑和怀疑；中国外卖配送员的平均月工资；中国零工经济的兴起和零工经济工作者面临的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>employed (v.) - /ɪmˈplɔɪd/ 雇用；使就业。    <p>原文例句：The average monthly wage of people employed by private firms in cities was only 5,436 yuan in 2022. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于Middle English，由em-（使……变成）和ploy（折叠；雇用）组成，意为“使……就业”。在这个例句中，它表示2022年城市私人企业雇用人员的平均月工资只有5,436元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>lay-offs (n.) - /ˈleɪˌɔːf/ 裁员。    <p>原文例句：After the youth unemployment rate hit a record high of 21.3 per cent last June, authorities stopped releasing the data, citing a need to reassess the calculation methodology.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词是由lay（放置；使……躺下）和off（离开；关掉）组成的，表示“使……下岗”。在这个例句中，它指的是青年失业率在去年6月达到创纪录的21.3%后，当局停止发布数据，理由是需要重新评估计算方法。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>across a wide range of - 涉及广泛的；在很广的范围内。    <P>原文例句：After the youth unemployment rate hit a record high of 21.3 per cent last June, authorities stopped releasing the data, citing a need to reassess the calculation methodology. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由across（横过）, range（范围）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“涉及到或影响到广泛的”。在这个例句中，它表示青年失业率在去年6月达到创纪录的21.3%后，当局停止发布数据，理由是需要重新评估计算方法。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chen said that his fitness “based on practising martial arts when he was young”, coupled with a dose of good luck, helped him achieve the result. - 陈说他的体能来自年轻时习武和一点好运气帮助他取得的这一成就。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Chen said，其中主语是Chen，谓语是said，宾语是that his fitness “based on practising martial arts when he was young”, coupled with a dose of good luck, helped him achieve the result。based on practising martial arts when he was young是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰fitness，表示陈的体能来自年轻时习武。coupled with a dose of good luck是一个过去分词短语作状语，修饰helped him achieve the result，表示再加上一点好运气。这个句子的意思是说，陈说他的体能来自年轻时习武和一点好运气帮助他取得的这一成就。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 用于比较两个对象或事物。    <p>原文例句：The average monthly wage of people employed by private firms in cities was only 5,436 yuan in 2022. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子的比较级是only，表示“仅仅，只有”。它修饰了average monthly wage，强调了城市私人企业雇用人员的平均月工资水平非常低。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：He told the Hunan-based newspaper Xiaoxiang Chenbao that he wakes at 5:50am daily and works until midnight, and that he hardly took any time off, even during the Lunar New Year festival when most workers stop work to celebrate with their families.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个复合句，主句是He told，其中主语是He，谓语是told，宾语是the Hunan-based newspaper Xiaoxiang Chenbao that he wakes at 5:50am daily and works until midnight, and that he hardly took any time off, even during the Lunar New Year festival when most workers stop work to celebrate with their families。He wakes at 5:50am daily and works until midnight是一个现在完成进行时态的句子，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示陈每天早上5点50分起床工作到午夜。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In a video on Douyin, Chen, wearing his Meituan uniform, said his failed restaurant business in his home province left him with a debt of 800,000 yuan (US$112,274)</li>
<li>Based on Chen’s claims, he would need to earn an average of 28,000 yuan a month, delivering 107 orders per day consistently over a span of 1,000 days</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/21/3a4413d3-b37b-4219-9ee0-63d0b1302528_b039a533.jpg" /><figcaption>A group of Meituan couriers waits for order in Beijing on November 16, 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Claims by a food delivery worker in Shanghai that he made more than 1 million yuan (US$140,343) in three years, a story widely reported by state media and debated on social media, has offered hope to the unemployed amid China’s sputtering economic recovery and bleak job market outlook.</p><p>Chen Si, a 26-year-old from the central province of Jiangxi, suggested in a series of videos posted on Douyin, the Chinese sibling of ByteDance’s TikTok, that he made a total of 1.02 million yuan from three years of delivering meals in the Chinese financial hub.</p><p>In one video, Chen, wearing his Meituan courier uniform, said his failed restaurant business in his home province left him with a debt of 800,000 yuan. This prompted him to come to Shanghai where he landed a food courier gig to help pay off his debts.</p><p>“I work 18 hours every day … worked over 1,000 days in three years, barely taking leave,” Chen said, adding that he has paid off all his debt.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247829/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-offers-shoppers-us-grouped-delivery-service-cutting-shipping-times" title="">Cainiao offers shoppers in US grouped delivery service, cutting shipping times</a></h3><p>Chen’s videos were highlighted by Chinese state media, sparking heated online debate across the country, where the average monthly wage of people employed by private firms in cities was only 5,436 yuan in 2022, according to data compiled by the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).</p><p>While some have endorsed Chen’s diligence, many questioned whether he was telling the truth. Based on Chen’s claims, he would need to earn an average of 28,000 yuan each month, delivering an average of 107 orders everyday consistently over a span of 1,000 days.</p><p>One food delivery rider surnamed Yang, who worked for Meituan in Beijing for five years, told the South China Morning Post that he averaged between 40 and 50 orders a day, earning more than 10,000 yuan a month, by putting in a minimum of 12 hours per day.</p><p>While his best performance was delivering 108 orders in one day, according to a screenshot of the Meituan ranking he shared with the Post, Yang said it would be almost impossible for anyone to maintain that pace for more than 1,000 days in a row.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A food delivery courier for Meituan in Beijing, on September 1, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" class="image-inline caption" height="1445" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/21/0ec90034-33b8-40bb-a342-1af3cfb45f3d_7c1d99ea.jpg" title="A food delivery courier for Meituan in Beijing, on September 1, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" width="2000" /><figcaption>A food delivery courier for Meituan in Beijing, on September 1, 2023. Photo: Simon Song</figcaption></figure></div><p>Online job listings published by a Shanghai-based recruitment agency show salaries of between 9,000 yuan and 15,000 yuan for food delivery riders in the city, with the average daily order rate being between 40 and 70.</p><p>Meituan did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Sunday.</p><p>In interviews with state media, Chen said that his fitness “based on practising martial arts when he was young”, coupled with a dose of good luck, helped him achieve the result.</p><p>He told the Hunan-based newspaper Xiaoxiang Chenbao that he wakes at 5:50am daily and works until midnight, and that he hardly took any time off, even during the Lunar New Year festival when most workers stop work to celebrate with their families.</p><p>The inspirational story of a self-made millionaire comes as China is being challenged by an uneven economic recovery that has seen lay-offs across a wide range of industries, with new graduates facing a bleak job market.</p><p>After the youth unemployment rate hit a record high of 21.3 per cent last June, authorities stopped releasing the data, citing a need to reassess the calculation methodology.</p><p>When the reporting recently resumed, the NBS figures pegged the unemployment rate for the 16 to 24 year old age bracket at 14.9 per cent for last December, but the number excluded students still in school. Overall, China’s urban unemployment rate was 5.1 per cent in December.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3238995/dont-worry-ill-deliver-it-caring-china-police-officer-helps-food-courier-finish-round-after-bike" title="">‘Don’t worry, I’ll deliver it’: cop completes food dispatch for rider after crash</a></h3><p>Food delivery couriers like Chen, as well as ride-share drivers and parcel couriers, make up China’s army of flexible employment workers, which numbered more than 200 million at the end of 2021.</p><p>Starting early 2023, internet platforms like Meituan and ride-sharing service Didi Chuxing began to emerge from years of strict oversight by Beijing, but now face the prospect of a challenging economic environment. In a reversal of policy, Beijing is now openly praising the role of such platforms in bolstering growth and creating jobs.</p><p>However, compared with full-time employment, gig workers face job insecurity and a lack of benefits.</p><p>“I don’t want people to follow my work style, as it is not suitable for everyone. I also don’t want people to think delivering meals is a good job just because of how much I’ve made,” Chen said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Goldman Sachs doubles loan facility to Hong Kong fintech start-up FundPark to US$500 million</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3249220/goldman-sachs-doubles-loan-facility-hong-kong-fintech-start-fundpark-us500-million</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  FundPark, a Hong Kong-based fintech startup, secures US$500 million from Goldman Sachs to provide loans to small and medium enterprises (SMEs), mainly in the cross-border e-commerce sector. The investment reflects FundPark's successful track record and capability in deploying capital rapidly. The company aims to use the funding to bridge the trade finance gap for SMEs and expand its technology and data analytics capabilities. It also plans to expand beyond its existing 15 markets, with a focus on exporters and importers in China's e-commerce space.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: FundPark secures US$500 million to provide trade finance to SMEs, addressing the trade financing gap and expanding its services.</li>    <li>Theme: FundPark's partnership with Goldman Sachs and its mission to bridge the trade finance gap for SMEs through technological innovation.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of digital footprint, AI technology, and data analytics in assessing creditworthiness and capturing business potential.</li>    <li>Main information: FundPark's track record, use of AI-driven credit model, expansion plans, partnerships with e-commerce platforms and logistics providers, and focus on China's e-commerce space.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  FundPark，一家香港金融科技初创企业，从高盛获得了5亿美元的资金，用于向中小型企业（SME）提供贷款服务，这些中小型企业主要集中在跨境电子商务领域。这笔投资反映了FundPark在迅速部署资金方面的成功记录和能力。该公司计划利用这笔资金缩小中小型企业的贸易融资缺口，并进一步提升其技术和数据分析能力。它还计划将其业务拓展至15个现有市场之外，重点关注中国电子商务空间的出口商和进口商。  <ul>    <li>摘要：FundPark获5亿美元资金，为中小型企业提供贸易融资，缩小贸易融资缺口，并拓展服务。</li>    <li>主题：FundPark与高盛的合作，以及其通过技术创新缩小中小型企业贸易融资缺口的使命。</li>    <li>观点：数字足迹、人工智能技术和数据分析在评估信誉和把握商业潜力方面的意义。</li>    <li>主要信息：FundPark的成功记录、人工智能驱动的信贷模型的使用、扩张计划、与电子商务平台和物流供应商的合作关系，以及对中国电子商务领域的关注。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>underserved (adj.) - 服务不足的，缺乏服务的。    <p>原文例句：FundPark will continue to extend loans to the underserved and unserved digital SMEs. - FundPark将继续向服务不足和未服务的数字中小型企业发放贷款。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由under（不足的）和served（服务的）组成，表示“服务不足的，缺乏服务的”。在这个例句中，它指的是那些得不到足够金融服务的数字中小型企业。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>scale (v.) - 扩大，扩展。    <p>原文例句：Our solution does not require traditional collateral such as property, etc. That means our solution does not require what a traditional bank requires, which allows our digital SME clients to scale. - 我们的解决方案不需要传统的抵押品，如房产等。这意味着我们的解决方案不需要传统银行所要求的，这使得我们的数字中小企业客户能够扩大规模。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古诺斯语，表示“称重，平衡”，引申为“扩大，扩展”。在这个例句中，它指的是数字中小型企业利用FundPark的解决方案来扩大规模。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>trade finance - 贸易融资。    <p>原文例句：FundPark, a Hong Kong-based fintech start-up that provides trade finance for small and medium enterprises (SMEs). - FundPark是一家提供贸易融资的小型和中型企业金融科技初创企业。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由trade（贸易）和finance（融资）组成，表示“贸易融资”。在这个例句中，它指的是FundPark为中小企业提供的贸易融资服务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company plans to use the investment to provide loans to SMEs, which often have their requests for trade finance rejected by banks, creating a trade financing gap of US$2.5 trillion globally for small business, according to the Asian Development Bank. - 该公司计划利用这笔投资为中小企业提供贷款，据亚洲开发银行称，中小企业经常被银行拒绝提供贸易融资，在全球范围内造成高达2.5万亿美元的小企业贸易融资缺口。</p><p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是The company plans to use the investment to provide loans to SMEs，其中主语是The company，谓语是plans to use，宾语是the investment，to provide loans to SMEs是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示该公司的计划或目的。which often have their requests for trade finance rejected by banks是一个定语从句，修饰前面的SMEs，表示这些中小企业经常被银行拒绝提供贸易融资。creating a trade financing gap of US$2.5 trillion globally for small business是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示该公司的计划或目的，即造成高达2.5万亿美元的小企业贸易融资缺口。according to the Asian Development Bank是一个介词短语，表示该信息的来源或出处。这个句子的意思是说，该公司计划利用这笔投资为中小企业提供贷款，据亚洲开发银行称，中小企业经常被银行拒绝提供贸易融资，在全球范围内造成高达2.5万亿美元的小企业贸易融资缺口。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：FundPark provides loans to SMEs secured by their underlying cashflows, inventory or receivables. - FundPark向中小型企业提供以其基本现金流、库存或应收账款担保的贷款。</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在进行时态的结构是：be + 动词的现在分词（-ing）。这种时态表示动作或状态正在进行或发生，强调动作或状态的持续性。在这个例句中，be动词是provides，动词的现在分词是secured，表示FundPark正在向中小型企业提供以其基本现金流、库存或应收账款担保的贷款。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>不定式短语 - 可以充当句子成分的非限定性从句。    <p>原文例句：The company plans to use the investment to provide loans to SMEs, which often have their requests for trade finance rejected by banks, creating a trade financing gap of US$2.5 trillion globally for small business, according to the Asian Development Bank. - 该公司计划利用这笔投资为中小企业提供贷款，据亚洲开发银行称，中小企业经常被银行拒绝提供贸易融资，在全球范围内造成高达2.5万亿美元的小企业贸易融资缺口。</p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式短语由to + 动词原形构成。它可以充当句子成分，但不是限定性从句。在这个例句中，to provide loans to SMEs是一个不定式短语，充当company的宾语，表示该公司的计划或目的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Goldman Sachs’ decision to upsize its asset-backed securitisation facility is a testament to FundPark’s capability and track record, CEO Anson Suen says</li>
<li>The start-up has disbursed US$2 billion to 16,500 SMEs, mainly in the cross-border e-commerce sector since its inception in 2016</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/21/7b7f197a-0696-471d-956e-863040047853_f4106d42.jpg" /><figcaption>FundPark CEO and co-founder Anson Suen said the company will continue to upgrade its technological capabilities. Photo: Xiaomei Chen</figcaption></figure><p>FundPark, a Hong Kong-based fintech start-up that provides trade finance for small and medium enterprises (SMEs), has secured US$500 million from Goldman Sachs, the second funding facility from the US investment bank in two years.</p><p>Goldman recently doubled the asset-backed securitisation facility to up to US$500 million, from what it provided FundPark in 2022, CEO and co-founder Anson Suen Wai-loi said, adding that it was one of the largest of its kind received by a fintech firm in Asia.</p><p>“Goldman Sachs’ decision to upsize up to US$500 million is a combination of how it looks at FundPark’s track record in the past 18 months and how FundPark has the capability to deploy the capital rapidly,” he said.</p><p>The company plans to use the investment to provide loans to SMEs, which often have their requests for trade finance rejected by banks, creating a trade financing gap of US$2.5 trillion globally for small business, according to the Asian Development Bank.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="FundPark provides loans to SMEs secured by their underlying cashflows, inventory or receivables. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/21/f732afd8-15c7-4f7c-be7a-f842c1d4f48d_1638767f.jpg" title="FundPark provides loans to SMEs secured by their underlying cashflows, inventory or receivables. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>FundPark provides loans to SMEs secured by their underlying cashflows, inventory or receivables. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Since its inception in 2016, the company has disbursed US$2 billion to 16,500 SMEs, mainly in the cross-border e-commerce sector with US dollar working capital needs. Around half of the loan disbursements happened last year.</p><p>Suen said the performance of its underlying portfolio is “sustainable and healthy” and “beat the market benchmark for banks and non-banks”, but did not provide a number.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3244450/bochk-backed-virtual-lender-livi-eyes-further-sme-business-growth-after-strong-2023" title="">Virtual lender Livi eyes further SME business growth after strong 2023</a></h3><p>FundPark provides loans without typical collateral, such as property, but those are secured by SMEs’ underlying cashflows, inventory or receivables. It employs a proprietary AI-driven credit model to assess borrowers and provide financing solutions based on their needs and credit grading.</p><p>The AI credit model can predict clients’ business performance, such as future cashflows and repayment capability.</p><p>“Empowered by our in-house built credit model, it is able to continue to evolve itself and better understand a client’s creditworthiness,” Suen said. “That means our solution does not require what a traditional bank requires – traditional collateral or security such as property, etc.”</p><p>With the new funding, FundPark will continue to extend loans to the underserved and unserved digital SMEs, aiming for growth similar to last year, he said. It will also continue to invest in its technology and data analytics capabilities and look to provide data insights to clients as a value-added service other than lending.</p><p>In addition, the company is eyeing expansion beyond the 15 markets, such as Greater China, Southeast Asia, Europe and the US, where it serves clients. Exporters and importers in China’s e-commerce space will be a focus.</p><p>Apart from its Hong Kong headquarters in Kwun Tong, FundPark has offices in Shenzhen and Chengdu.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3211408/hong-kong-fintech-employs-ai-technology-promise-collateral-free-loans-citys-small-businesses" title="">Hong Kong fintech start-up offers collateral-free SME loans using AI power</a></h3><p>FundPark said it will maintain partnerships with e-commerce platforms such as Amazon and Walmart Marketplace and logistics service providers such as Cainiao to gain more access to SME merchants.</p><p>Suen expects the market for trade finance to keep growing as business activities increasingly go online.</p><p>“Digital footprint, together with AI technology and data analytics, will allow us to get the data online and respond quickly, and help our digital SME clients scale and capture their future potential.”</p><p>“This kind of scalability is exactly something we are eyeing to bridge the huge funding gap.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nokia set to exit telecommunications joint venture with Huawei amid US-China tensions</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249181/nokia-set-exit-telecommunications-joint-venture-huawei-amid-us-china-tensions</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nokia has found new buyers for its majority stake in TD Tech, a joint venture with Huawei.</li>    <li>The new buyers include state-owned entities and a venture capital firm.</li>    <li>Huawei and TD Tech jointly control no more than 10% of China's smartphone market.</li>    <li>TD Tech has been selling rebranded Huawei phones under its own brand since 2021.</li>    <li>Huawei likely did not want to lose control of TD Tech, which could help it circumvent US sanctions.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>诺基亚已为其与华为合资公司 TD Tech 的多数股权找到了新买家。</li>    <li>新买家包括国有企业和一家风投公司。</li>    <li>华为和 TD Tech 在中国智能手机市场的份额不超过 10%。</li>    <li>自 2021 年以来，TD Tech 一直在以自有品牌销售经过重新贴牌的华为手机。</li>    <li>华为可能不想失去对 TD Tech 的控制权，因为这有助于其规避美国的制裁。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>majority (n.) - /məˈdʒɒrɪti/ 多数，多数的。    <p>原文例句：Finnish telecoms equipment giant Nokia has found new buyers for its majority stake in a Beijing-based joint venture with Huawei Technologies, after a proposed deal fell through last year following strong protest by the Chinese partner. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，由major（较大的）和-ity（性）组成，表示“超过一半的数量或比例”。在这个例句中，它指的是诺基亚在这家合资企业中的大多数股权。</p></li>    <li>divest (v.) - /daɪˈvɛst/ 出售，转让。    <p>原文例句：In 2007, Siemens sold half of its stake to Nokia. In 2013, Siemens divested all its shares, making Nokia the major shareholder. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，由des-（away）和vestir（dress）组成，表示“剥夺，出售”。在这个例句中，它指的是西门子出售了在合资企业中的所有股份。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>public feedback - 公众反馈，公开意见。    <P>原文例句：Regulators said they had no antitrust concerns on the deal and would solicit public feedback until January 28. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由public（公众的），feedback（反馈）组成，表示“公众反馈，公开意见”。在这个例句中，它指的是监管机构会向公众征求对这项交易的意见，直到1月28日。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TD Tech has been selling rebranded Huawei phones under its own brand. - TD Tech 一直在以自有品牌销售经过重新贴牌的华为手机。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是TD Tech，谓语是has been selling，宾语是rebranded Huawei phones。under its own brand是一个介词短语作状语，修饰has been selling，表示TD Tech使用自己的品牌销售经过重新贴牌的华为手机。这个句子的意思是说，TD Tech一直 在以自有品牌销售经过重新贴牌的华为手机。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Huawei and TD Tech together control no more than 10 per cent of China’s smartphone market, according to the SAMR, which did not specify the time frame for that data.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是由动词的词干加上-ed或-en或-t构成的。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示华为和TDTech在中国的智能手机市场份额不超过10%，监管机构没有具体说明数据的时段。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Finnish company will sell its majority stake in TD Tech to a group that includes state-owned entities, pending final government approval</li>
<li>Huawei has long been considered the de facto controller of TD Tech, which has been selling rebranded phones from the Chinese giant since 2021</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/96782c3a-8a2e-4d29-8e59-79d66ccfe5a6_def6fa44.jpg" /><figcaption>The Nokia headquarters in Espoo, Finland. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Finnish telecoms equipment giant Nokia has found new buyers for its majority stake in a Beijing-based joint venture with Huawei Technologies, after a proposed deal fell through last year following strong protest by the Chinese partner.</p><p>Under the latest agreement, wireless technology firm TD Tech will be jointly controlled by Huawei and a group of entities that include the government-owned Chengdu High-Tech Investment Group and Chengdu Gaoxin Jicui Technology Co, as well as venture capital firm Huagai, according to a disclosure published on Friday by the State Administration for Market Regulation (SAMR).</p><p>The document did not reveal how much equity each of the new participants will hold. Before the sale, Nokia owned 51 per cent of TD Tech, while Huawei held 49 per cent.</p><p>Regulators said they had no antitrust concerns on the deal and would solicit public feedback until January 28. Huawei and TD Tech together control no more than 10 per cent of China’s smartphone market, according to the SAMR, which did not specify the time frame for that data.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/36a09b3c-7803-48e6-a443-6a2cec7d849d_34f54c2a.jpg" title="An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Huawei had a 14 per cent share in the Chinese smartphone market in the third quarter last year, putting it in fifth place behind its spin-off Honor and rivals Oppo, Vivo and Apple, data from market intelligence firm Counterpoint Research showed.</p><p>TD Tech, founded in 2005, had been a joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens until 2007, when Siemens sold half of its stake to Nokia. In 2013, Siemens divested all its shares, making Nokia the major shareholder.</p><p>Known for its wireless communications equipment, including 4G and 5G networking gear, TD Tech has a presence in more than 100 countries serving 8 million industry customers, according to its website.</p><p>While Nokia had been the majority owner of the joint venture, Huawei has been the de facto controller, according to industry observers.</p><p>“The management are former Huawei employees, with product solutions based on Huawei products but fine-tuned for the industry market,” Yang Guang, an analyst covering the telecoms sector at research firm Omdia, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3216677/huawei-opposition-nokia-sale-joint-venture-threatens-finnish-firms-exit-us-china-tensions-weigh-deal" target="_self" title="">said last year</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3216677/huawei-opposition-nokia-sale-joint-venture-threatens-finnish-firms-exit-us-china-tensions-weigh-deal" title="">Huawei opposition to Nokia sale of joint venture threatens Finnish firm’s exit</a></h3><p>When Nokia last year tried to sell its majority stake to Shanghai-listed ink maker New East New Materials, Huawei threatened to stop licensing technology to TD Tech. That deal ultimately collapsed.</p><p>Huawei likely did not want to lose control of TD Tech, which could help the Chinese tech giant circumvent some US sanctions and help it address certain market segments more efficiently, Yang said at the time.</p><p>TD Tech in 2021 started selling what amounted to rebranded Huawei phones under its own brand. They included the M40 5G, which used a 7-nanometre chip from Taiwan-based MediaTek instead of Huawei’s own Kirin processors.</p><p>Sanctions imposed by Washington currently bar companies from selling to Huawei advanced chips made with US-origin technology, which includes MediaTek processors made by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a>, the world’s largest contract chip maker.</p><p>Despite the US restrictions, Huawei last year launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233636/huaweis-mate-60-pro-will-help-it-take-lost-ground-china-can-it-help-smartphone-giant-regain-global" target="_self" title="">its Mate 60 Pro</a>, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G processor.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
