<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Alibaba reduces stake in GoGoX amid Hong Kong logistics services firm’s mounting losses, as it faces cutthroat competition on the mainland</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247308/alibaba-reduces-stake-gogox-amid-hong-kong-logistics-services-firms-mounting-losses-it-faces</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Alibaba has further decreased its stake in Hong Kong-listed logistics service provider GoGoX Holdings, dropping from 12.23% in mid-2023 to 8.89% in late December. GoGoX has faced intense competition in the mainland China market and experienced significant losses since 2018. It operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland and saw its market value plummet by over 90% since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Alibaba cuts its stake in GoGoX Holdings while the company faces challenges.</li>    <li>Theme: Alibaba's decreased stake reflects GoGoX's market struggles and competitive pressures.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The challenging environment for logistics service providers in mainland China and the regulatory scrutiny faced by companies like GoGoX.</li>    <li>Main information: Alibaba's stake reduction, GoGoX's losses and market value decline, and the competitive landscape in the intracity delivery courier market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  阿里巴巴进一步减持在港交所上市的物流服务提供商GoGoX的股份，将持股比例从2023年中期的12.23%下调至12月下旬的8.89%。自2018年以来，GoGoX一直面临着中国大陆市场的激烈竞争，并遭受了重大损失。它在大陆以Kuaigou Dache运营，自2022年6月在香港交易所首次亮相以来，其市值已缩水超过90%。  <ul>    <li>摘要：阿里巴巴削减对GoGoX控股的股份，而该公司正面临挑战。</li>    <li>主题：阿里巴巴减持反映了GoGoX的市场困境和竞争压力。</li>    <li>观点：中国大陆物流服务提供商面临的严峻环境以及GoGoX等公司面临的监管审查。</li>    <li>主要信息：阿里巴巴减持股份，GoGoX亏损和市值下降，以及同城配送快递市场的竞争格局。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>intracity (adj.) - /ˈɪntrəsɪti/ 城内的, 本市内的。    <p>原文例句：GoGoX competes in a crowded on-demand cargo delivery services market on the mainland, where its hometown rival Lalatech Holdings operates Huolala. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由intra-（在~以内）和city（城市）组成，表示“在城市之内”。在这个例句中，它指的是GoGoX在大陆一个拥挤的按需货物配送服务市场中展开竞争，而在这片市场中，GoGoX的本土竞争对手Lalatech控股运营着货拉拉。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>regulatory (adj.) - /ˈrɛɡjʊlətɔːri/ 有关规章的, 有关管制的。    <p>原文例句：That “cash-burning” business model, however, has faced increased scrutiny from regulators, which recently summoned Lalatech for talks regarding drivers’ rights and unfair price cuts.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于regulate（调整，调节），表示“有关规章的，有关管制的”。在这个例句中，它指的是这种“烧钱”的商业模式最近受到监管机构的严格审查，监管机构最近传唤了货拉拉，就司机的权利和不公平的降价问题进行谈判。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>initial public offering (IPO) - 首次公开募股    <p>原文例句：Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由initial（初始的），public（公开的）和offering（发售）组成，表示“首次公开募股”。在这个例句中，它指的是菜鸟网络的的目标是筹集至少10亿美元，具体情况将取决于市场条件，根据本月一篇邮报报道中引用的消息来源。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Following those moves, the biggest shareholder of GoGoX remains billionaire Yao Jinbo – the founder, chairman and chief executive of mainland Chinese online classifieds giant 58.com – with a 38.69 per cent share. - 继这些举措之后，GoGoX的最大股东仍然是亿万富翁姚劲波——中国大陆在线分类广告巨头58.com的创始人、董事长兼首席执行官——其持股比例为38.69%。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是the biggest shareholder of GoGoX，谓语是remains，宾语是billionaire Yao Jinbo。The founder, chairman and chief executive of mainland Chinese online classifieds giant 58.com是一个由The founder，chairman和chief executive of mainland Chinese online classifieds giant 58.com三个并列短语构成的定语，修饰姚劲波，表示姚劲波是58.com的创始人、董事长兼首席执行官。with a 38.69 per cent share是一个介词短语，表示姚劲波持有GoGoX 38.69%的股份。这个句子的意思是说，继这些举措之后，GoGoX的最大股东仍然是亿万富翁姚劲波——中国大陆在线分类广告巨头58.com的创始人、董事长兼首席执行官——其持股比例为38.69%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 表示强调。强调句有两种形式，一种是将句子中要强调的部分放在句首，另一种是在句子中使用最高级、形容词、副词等。    <p>原文例句：GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子采用了第一种形式的强调句型，即将要强调的部分has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent放在句首。这样可以突出强调GoGoX的市场价值自2022年6月在香港交易所以来已经缩水了90%以上。    另一种常见的强调句是使用最高级、形容词、副词等。这种强调句型通常将形容词、副词或最高级放在句子中适当的位置，以强调某个部分。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示比较    <p>原文例句：Alibaba aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是形容词或副词的一种形式，用于比较两个或两个以上的事物。比较级通常在形容词或副词后加上-er或more，如果形容词或副词以辅音字母+元音字母+辅音字母结尾，则通常需要在形容词或副词前加上more。在这个例句中，at least是比较级的形式，表示至少。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Alibaba has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, leaving it with an 8.89 per cent equity holding as of December</li>
<li>GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/2c781207-f507-4907-bf84-a2425ae1e9fa_2a843a15.jpg" /><figcaption>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022. Image: GoGoX</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> has further reduced its stake in Hong Kong-listed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/transport-and-logistics" target="_self" title="">logistics</a> service provider <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/gogovan" target="_self" title="">GoGoX Holdings</a>, which is facing cutthroat competition and regulatory pressure in the mainland’s intracity delivery courier market.</p><p>Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, slashing its equity holding to 8.89 per cent as of late December from 12.23 per cent in mid-2023, according to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong-stock-market" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong stock exchange</a> records.</p><p>Following those moves, the biggest shareholder of GoGoX remains billionaire Yao Jinbo – the founder, chairman and chief executive of mainland Chinese online classifieds giant 58.com – with a 38.69 per cent share. GoGoX co-founder Chen Xiaohua, with a 5.95 per cent stake, retains his position as the company’s third-biggest shareholder.</p><p>Founded as GoGoVan in Hong Kong in 2013, GoGoX <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/china-tech/article/2108658/gogovan-become-hong-kongs-first-us1-billion-start-after-merger-58" target="_self" title="">became the city’s first unicorn in 2017</a> after its merger with short-distance freight service platform operator 58 Suyun. Still, GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/ab59b907-e9a0-49bd-b7d8-bd576851c04c_8a6158cb.jpg" title="GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX" width="2000" /><figcaption>GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX</figcaption></figure></div><p>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3182875/gogox-shares-rise-hkex-trading-debut-listing-hong-kongs" target="_self" title="">its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022</a>. Its share price closed up 6.8 per cent to HK$0.63 on Thursday.</p><p>The company – which expects to remain in the red this year, according to its 2022 prospectus – narrowed its losses to 642.9 million yuan (US$90.37 million) in the first half of 2023, from 1.05 billion yuan in the same period in 2022.</p><p>GoGoX also went through a major management reshuffle in December, as founder Chen resigned from his chairman role. The company tapped Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, another co-founder and the co-chief executive of GoGoX, as its new chairman.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hangzhou" target="_self" title="">Hangzhou</a>-based Alibaba’s partial divestment initiative at GoGoX comes amid its preparations for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3235860/alibabas-cainiao-files-us1-billion-ipo-helping-hong-kong-land-worlds-second-biggest-listing-2023" target="_self" title="">initial public offering (IPO) of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network</a>, which submitted its A1 filing to the Hong Kong stock exchange last September.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee" class="image-inline caption" height="1298" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/daae0416-e269-4485-a0b4-cb91724c76ec_051879a6.jpg" title="Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee" width="2000" /><figcaption>Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee</figcaption></figure></div><p>Alibaba is trying to stop the bleeding with its stake cut, as its initial goal with the GoGoX investment was to gain financial returns through the listing and create synergy with its own services, according to Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangdong-based consultancy iiMedia.</p><p>“This is still a market with huge demand and many opportunities even with the price wars, similar to those in the bike-sharing and ride-hailing sectors,” Zhang said. “So the bigger problem is more likely to lie within the operation of GoGoX, which will need revolutionary measures to reverse its losses.”</p><p>At present, GoGoX is competing in a crowded on-demand cargo delivery services market on the mainland, where its hometown rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246071/chinese-tech-ipos-watch-2024-global-fast-fashion-online-retailer-shein-leads-pack" target="_self" title="">Lalatech Holdings</a> operates Huolala. Competition has become more intense in recent years after traditional logistics firms and ride-hailing companies also set up similar app-based courier delivery operations.</p><p>Chinese ride-hailing giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/didi-chuxing" target="_self" title="">Didi Chuxing</a>, for example, started its own intracity freight service in 2020 and launched its autonomous trucking business Kargobot in April last year. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3137463/full-truck-chinas-uber-trucks-raise-us157-billion-us" target="_self" title="">Full Truck Alliance</a>, known as China’s “Uber for trucks” and focused on long-haul logistics services, in April launched its Sheng Sheng brand dedicated to same-city delivery.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240676/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-will-enhance-its-overseas-presence-proposed-buyout-local-rival-best" title="">Alibaba logistics spin-off Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout</a></h3><p>Huolala currently leads the mainland’s intracity courier delivery services market with a 61 per cent share, according to Frost &amp; Sullivan data cited in the prospectus of Lalatech, which is eyeing a Hong Kong IPO.</p><p>Similar to on-demand services like ride hailing, the early stage of competition in intracity freight services has relied heavily on subsidies for users.</p><p>That “cash-burning” business model, however, has faced increased scrutiny from regulators, which recently summoned Lalatech for talks regarding drivers’ rights and unfair price cuts.</p><p>GoGoX and other courier delivery services providers have also received “reminders” from regulators about their operations in the past year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Amid US tech war, Premier Li Qiang urges China to focus on application of core technologies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese Premier Li Qiang visited Hubei province, emphasizing the need for improved collaboration between academia and businesses to drive technological innovation amid the ongoing tech war with the United States. He called for increased market applications of core technologies and highlighted the importance of self-reliance in developing key industries.<ul>    <li>Abstract: Premier Li's visit to Hubei focused on promoting technological innovation and addressing challenges in the tech sector.</li>    <li>Theme: Collaboration between academia and businesses is crucial for China's technological advancement and economic growth.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: China aims to reduce its reliance on foreign technology and foster domestic innovation to counter US containment efforts.</li>    <li>Main information: Premier Li visited various facilities, including universities, manufacturers, and research labs, emphasizing the need for stronger ties between academia and industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国总理李强访问湖北省，强调了在与美国持续不断的技术战中，需要改善学术界和企业之间的合作，以推动技术创新。他呼吁加强核心技术的市场应用，并强调在发展关键产业中自力更生的重要性。  <ul>    <li>摘要：李克强总理访问湖北，重点关注促进技术创新和应对科技领域的挑战。</li>    <li>主题：学术界与企业之间的合作对中国的技术进步和经济增长至关重要。</li>    <li>观点：中国旨在减少对外国技术的依赖，并培养国内创新，以应对美国的遏制努力。</li>    <li>主要信息：李克强总理走访了包括大学、制造商和研究所在内的多个机构，强调了加强学术界与产业界紧密联系的必要性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sanction (v./n.)  - /ˈsæŋkʃən/ 制裁（动词/名词）。    <p>原文例句：But unlike China’s leading memory chip maker, YMTC, HGLaser has not been sanctioned by the US. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词意思是“制裁”，既可以作为动词，也可以作为名词使用。在这个例句中，它用作动词，指美国对中国领先的存储芯片制造商长江存储实施制裁。</p></li>    <li>navigation (n.) - /ˌnævɪˈgeɪʃən/ 航行，导航。    <p>原文例句：During his two-day tour, Li also inspected Wuhan University’s laboratory on high-resolution Earth observation and the BeiDou navigation system.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词意思是“航行，导航”。在这个例句中，它指的是李克强总理在武汉大学视察了高分辨率地球观测实验室和北斗导航系统。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>be continually seeking - 不断寻求。    <p>原文例句：Given the escalating containment efforts by the United States, Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组的意思是“不断寻求”。在这个例句中，它指的是鉴于美国不断升级的遏制努力，中国不断寻求用国产技术解决关键问题。</p></li>    <li>play a role in - 发挥作用。    <p>原文例句：The home-grown BeiDou system, which is China’s equivalent to the US’ Global Positioning System (GPS), can be applied to agriculture, forestry and meteorology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组的意思是“发挥作用”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国自主研发的北斗系统，相当于美国的全球定位系统（GPS），可以应用于农业、林业和气象等领域。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central province of Hubei this week. 李克强总理本周对湖北省进行了为期两天的访问，期间参观了一所大学以及半导体、激光和化工制造商。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Premier Li Qiang，谓语是visited，宾语是a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers。介词短语during a two-day visit to the central province of Hubei this week表示访问的时间和地点。这个句子的意思是说，李克强总理本周对湖北省进行了为期两天的访问，期间参观了一所大学以及半导体、激光和化工制造商。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列结构 - 用and, or, but等连接两个或多个结构相似的成分。    <p>原文例句：He called for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个并列结构，用and连接了两个分句：He called for improved collaboration between academia and business，amid the ongoing tech war with the United States。这两个分句结构相似，都具有主语和谓语。这个句子的意思是说，李克强总理呼吁在与美国持续不断的技术战中，改善学术界和企业之间的合作。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central province of Hubei this week</li>
<li>He called for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/3a8be64d-f864-409e-859c-0eef4d4f4ae3_9e966ee7.jpg" /><figcaption>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central Hubei province this week.</figcaption></figure><p>Premier Li Qiang pushed for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive during a two-day tour of Hubei province this week, with the world’s second-largest economy in urgent need of stabilisation to quell investor concerns and lift market confidence.</p><p>“We must expedite the development of productivity driven by emerging technology, and kick-start a robust economic start of the year,” he said in a statement following the tour of the central province on Tuesday and Wednesday, according to the official Xinhua News Agency.</p><p>Hubei is a key part of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3237870/xi-jinping-tells-chinas-biggest-economic-zone-balance-growth-and-security-and-no-more-mega-projects" target="_self" title="">Yangtze River Economic Belt,</a> which is one of President Xi Jinping’s key regional development strategies. It includes 11 provinces and municipalities, and accounts for over 40 per cent of China’s population and economic size.</p><p>“We need to improve collaboration between academia and business, by introducing more precise and supportive measures, thus fluidly turning scientific research into market production,” the premier said after visiting HGLaser Engineering and semiconductor manufacturer Yangtze Memory Technologies Corporation (YMTC) in the provincial capital of Wuhan.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245242/amid-us-tech-war-china-stuck-middle-technology-trap-it-time-open-its-doors-wider" title="">Time to open its doors wider, or will China fall into a middle-technology trap?</a></h3><p>Given the escalating <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245242/amid-us-tech-war-china-stuck-middle-technology-trap-it-time-open-its-doors-wider" target="_self" title="">containment efforts by the United States,</a> Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology.</p><p>Development was also mentioned as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3244856/chinas-development-biggest-political-priority-key-econ-meeting-leaders-vow-counter-risks-lift" target="_self" title="">China’s biggest priority</a> for 2024 at the tone-setting central economic work conference in mid-December.</p><p>HGLaser introduced China’s first fully domestically produced chip-cutting machine in July, according to the WeChat account of Donghu New Technology Development Zone in Wuhan.</p><p>But unlike China’s leading memory chip maker, YMTC, HGLaser has not been sanctioned by the US. YMTC was added to the US trade blacklist <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3203494/us-adds-36-chinese-companies-export-blacklist-including-countrys-top-flash-memory-chip-maker?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">in December 2022.</a></p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>During his two-day tour, Li also inspected Wuhan University’s laboratory on high-resolution Earth observation and the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3241788/chinas-gps-beidou-navigation-system-recognised-global-standard-commercial-aviation-important" target="_self" title="">BeiDou navigation system.</a></p><p>The home-grown BeiDou system, which is China’s equivalent to the US’ Global Positioning System (GPS), can be applied to agriculture, forestry and meteorology.</p><p>China, though, has long suffered from loose cooperation between academia, including universities and research institutes, and enterprises focused on market applications.</p><p>The cooperation issues include poor communication and insufficient resource sharing, which creates obstacles affecting the transformation of inventions in China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3241788/chinas-gps-beidou-navigation-system-recognised-global-standard-commercial-aviation-important" title="">‘Important milestone’: China’s GPS-like BeiDou navigation system hits new height</a></h3><p>As of the end of 2022, only 3.9 per cent of inventions at Chinese universities were industrialised, according to the latest data available by the China National Intellectual Property Administration, compared to around 50 per cent in the US.</p><p>Li also visited water conservancy projects and a chemical company focusing on green development in Yichang, as well as a battery industrial estate set up by Guangdong Brunp Recycling Technology, a subsidiary under China’s leading lithium battery maker, Contemporary Amperex Technology (CATL).</p><p>CATL is a supplier to several carmakers, including Tesla, BMW and Volkswagen.</p><p>The premier also encouraged companies to promote China’s sustainability by focusing on the circular economy to drive companies up the value chain.</p><p>The circular economy model seeks to minimise wasting resources and environmental impact by extending the life cycle of products.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>PDD halts development of local services offering to avoid head-on competition with Meituan and Ele.me, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247286/pdd-halts-development-local-services-offering-avoid-head-competition-meituan-and-eleme-report-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese e-commerce giant PDD has halted its local life services offering, avoiding competition with rivals Meituan, Alibaba and ByteDance.</li>    <li>This decision comes as PDD looks to focus on its international expansion, particularly with its Temu app, which has seen success in markets like the United States and Japan.</li>    <li>PDD's local life services unit, Duoduo Maicai, had struggled to achieve profitability due to low gross margins.</li>    <li>Meituan currently leads the local services market in China, followed by Alibaba and ByteDance.</li>   </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国电商巨头拼多多已暂停其本地生活服务业务，以避免与美团、阿里巴巴和字节跳动等竞争对手竞争。</li>    <li>这一决定正值拼多多寻求聚焦国际扩张之际，特别是其在 Temu 应用上，该应用已在美国、日本和其他几个市场取得成功。</li>    <li>拼多多本地生活服务部门多多买菜由于毛利率低而难以实现盈利。</li>    <li>美团目前在中国本地服务市场处于领先地位，其次是阿里巴巴和字节跳动。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>halt (v.) - /hɔːlt/ 停止，中止。    <p>原文例句：PDD had halted work on its local life services offering, avoiding head-to-head rivalry with Meituan, Alibaba Group Holding and ByteDance, whose Douyin short video app has also dipped a toe into the sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：halt 作动词，意为“停止、使停止、中止”。在这个例句中，PDD 停止了本地生活服务业务，以避免与美团、阿里巴巴和字节跳动正面竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rival (n.) - /ˈraɪvəl/ 竞争者，对手。    <p>原文例句：PDD had planned to launch local services offering in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, report saysChinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in local services market</p>    <p>例句讲解：rival 作名词，意为“竞争者、对手”。在这个例句中，美团、阿里巴巴和字节跳动是拼多多的竞争者。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>aggressive (adj.) - /əˈɡrɛsɪv/ 积极的，激进的。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance’s Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has leveraged its more than 600 million daily active users to make aggressive moves in segments of on-demand e-commerce. </p>    <p>例句讲解：aggressive 作形容词，意为“积极的、激进的”。在这个例句中，抖音积极开拓按需电商细分市场。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>avoid competition with - 避免与……竞争。    <p>原文例句：PDD has halted work on its local life services offering, avoiding head-to-head rivalry with Meituan, Alibaba Group Holding and ByteDance.</p>    <p>例句讲解：avoid competition with 作词组，意为“避免与……竞争”。在这个例句中，拼多多暂停了本地生活服务业务，以避免与美团、阿里巴巴和字节跳动正面竞争。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>PDD has “completely halted [development of] the local services business”, according to Chinese media outlet LatePost. - 据中国媒体 LatePost 报道，拼多多已“完全停止了本地服务业务的开发”。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是 PDD has halted the development of the local services business，主语是 PDD，谓语是 has halted，宾语是 the development of the local services business。completely 是一个副词，修饰 halted，表示完全地、彻底地。according to Chinese media outlet LatePost 是一个介词短语，表示根据中国媒体 LatePost 的报道。这个句子的意思是说，据中国媒体 LatePost 报道，拼多多已经完全停止了本地服务业务的开发。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Abandoning the local services market comes as PDD continues to expand aggressively overseas with its Temu app. - 放弃本地服务市场之际，拼多多正继续通过其 Temu 应用程序积极向海外扩张。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是 PDD continues to expand aggressively overseas with its Temu app，主语是 PDD，谓语是 continues to expand，宾语是 aggressively overseas with its Temu app。Abandoning the local services market 是一个现在分词短语，作状语，表示放弃本地服务市场。comes 是一个连词，表示之际。这个句子的意思是说，放弃本地服务市场之际，拼多多正继续通过其 Temu 应用程序积极向海外扩张。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>完成时 - 表示一个动作或状态在过去某个时间之前就已经完成。    <p>原文例句：PDD had planned to launch the service – which facilitates in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets – in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个完成时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词形式。这种时态表示一个动作或状态在过去某个时间之前就已经完成。在这个例句中，had planned表示拼多多过去已经计划推出这项服务。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>PDD had planned to launch local services offering in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, report says</li>
<li>Chinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in local services market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/416b82eb-4e16-46af-8cd9-c30d0a415c2f_5ba32be4.jpg" /><figcaption>Chinese Big Tech firms have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025. Photo: AFP </figcaption></figure><p>E-commerce giant PDD Holdings has halted work on its local life services offering, avoiding head-to-head rivalry with Meituan, Alibaba Group Holding and ByteDance, whose Douyin short video app has also dipped a toe into the sector.</p><p>PDD has “completely halted [development of] the local services business”, according to Chinese media outlet LatePost. PDD did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p>PDD, whose market cap overtook Alibaba in November after the firm beat revenue estimates, had planned to launch the service – which facilitates in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets – in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, LatePost reported. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>PDD had leveraged Duoduo Maicai’s business development team of around 3,000 people to sign up bricks-and-mortar outlets, such as restaurants and tourist attractions, the report said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244976/amazon-doubles-down-china-e-commerce-strategy-rivals-shein-temu-gain-traction" title="">Amazon doubles down on China e-commerce strategy as Shein, Temu gain traction</a></h3><p>However, PDD’s management has not been completely satisfied with the performance of Duoduo Maicai, which was established in 2020 in the midst of the Covid-19 pandemic. It enables residents in a community to purchase groceries and other daily essentials in bulk, bringing prices down.</p><p>Although the unit has become an industry leader, it is not profitable due to low gross margins, according to the LatePost report, which cited a PDD executive. Duoduo Maicai is nevertheless expected to remain operational despite the halting of local life services, according to Chinese news portal Sina.</p><p>Chinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan (US$4.9 trillion) by 2025, according to estimates by market intelligence firm iResearch.</p><p>Meituan, which merged with restaurant review site Dianping and bike-sharing start-up Mobike, currently leads the sector with a range of food delivery, taxi-ride and hotel reservation services.</p><p>Alibaba has been seeking to catch up with the merger of its Koubei restaurant rating service and navigation app Amap. Alibaba’s local services segment also runs food delivery unit <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3048045/chinas-eleme-deliver-food-100-restaurants-frontline-medical-staff?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Ele.me</a>, grocery delivery service Taoxianda, and online travel platform Fliggy.</p><p>ByteDance’s Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has leveraged its more than 600 million daily active users to make <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3207434/bytedance-primes-short-video-app-douyin-challenge-meituan-demand-local-services-amid-chinas-push?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">aggressive moves in segments of on-demand e-commerce</a>. The company set up a centre dedicated to developing local services in 2020.</p><p>Abandoning the local services market comes as PDD continues to expand aggressively overseas with its Temu app, now available in the United States, Japan and several other markets. The budget shopping platform helped drive an almost doubling of PDD’s third-quarter revenue to 68.8 billion yuan.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Microsoft to show off Copilot AI key for Windows keyboards at CES, in first change to layout since 1994</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247280/microsoft-show-copilot-ai-key-windows-keyboards-ces-first-change-layout-1994</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In an effort to integrate AI into its products, Microsoft is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards. This button will allow users to directly access the company's AI assistant for tasks such as creating images, writing emails, and summarizing text. Microsoft believes that 2024 will be the year of the AI PC and has been revamping its products around AI technology. The Copilot key is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since the addition of the Start key in 1994. Microsoft sees this as a way to seamlessly integrate AI into the Windows experience.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Microsoft introduces the Copilot key to Windows keyboards for easy access to its AI assistant.</li>    <li>Theme: Microsoft's commitment to integrating AI into its products, particularly in the Windows operating system.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Microsoft's efforts to make AI more accessible and user-friendly through dedicated hardware features.</li>    <li>Main information: The Copilot key's location to the right of the spacebar, its role in activating the Copilot AI assistant, and Microsoft's goal of weaving AI into the entire Windows experience.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  为了把AI集成到产品中，微软正在给Windows键盘增加一个Copilot键。这个按键能让用户直接调用微软的人工智能助理，用于生成图片、写电子邮件和总结文本等工作。微软认为2024年将成为人工智能电脑之年，并一直在AI技术上改造其产品。这个Copilot键是自1994年增加开始键以来Windows键盘布局的首次改变。微软认为这是一个将人工智能无缝集成到Windows体验中的方法。  <ul>    <li>摘要：微软为Windows键盘引入Copilot键，方便用户轻松访问其人工智能助理。</li>    <li>主题：微软致力于将人工智能集成到其产品中，尤其是在Windows操作系统中。</li>    <li>观点：微软努力通过专用硬件功能使人工智能更易于访问和使用。</li>    <li>主要信息：Copilot键位于空格键右侧，用于激活Copilot人工智能助手，微软的目标是将人工智能融入整个Windows体验中。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>leverage (v.) - 利用，发挥。（杠杆原理）    <p>原文例句：The work heavily leverages the GPT-4 technology from OpenAI, in which Microsoft has invested US$13 billion. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于法语lever（举起），指的是“利用杠杆作用来举起或移动物体，利用机会或优势来达到目的”。在这个例句中，它表示微软大力利用OpenAI的GPT-4技术来提高其产品的AI能力，OpenAI是一家专注于人工智能研究的公司，而GPT-4则是其开发的最新一代人工智能语言模型。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>seamless (adj.) - 无缝的，无中断的。    <p>原文例句：“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于seam（接缝），指的是“没有接缝，平滑的，连续的”。在这个例句中，它表示微软将把人工智能无缝地融入到Windows系统、芯片和硬件中。Yusuf Mehdi是微软的消费者首席营销官，他在一篇博文中宣布了这个消息。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take into account - 考虑到，把……考虑进去。    <P>原文例句：Mehdi’s promise of weaving AI into hardware and silicon may signal more pressure on consumers to upgrade as Microsoft evolves and improves its AI proposition. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，取），into（进入，里面），account（账户，帐目）组成的，表示“考虑到，把……考虑进去”。在这个例句中，它表示微软把人工智能融入硬件和芯片的承诺可能会对消费者造成升级的压力，因为微软在不断发展和改进其人工智能产品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The tech giant sees 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’ and has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content. - 科技巨头认为2024年是“人工智能电脑之年”，并花费过去一年时间围绕能够产生新内容的人工智能技术调整其主要产品。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The tech giant sees 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’，其中主语是The tech giant，谓语是sees，宾语是2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’。has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content是一个现在完成时态的句子，其中has spent是spend的现在完成时态，主语是The tech giant，谓语是has spent，宾语是the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content。这个句子的意思是说，科技巨头认为2024年是“人工智能电脑之年”，并花费过去一年时间围绕能够产生新内容的人工智能技术调整其主要产品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句型 - 为了强调句子中的某个成分，将句子中正常顺序中的谓语动词提前至主语之前。    <p>原文例句：For device makers, Microsoft’s push into AI services has not yet translated into a boost for sales, as the novel Copilot features are being rolled out to new and existing devices alike.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，把谓语动词has not yet translated提前到了主语For device makers之前，目的是为了强调For device makers这个成分。这个句子的意思是说，对于设备制造商来说，微软进军人工智能服务还没有转化为销量的增长，因为新推出的Copilot功能正在向新设备和现有设备同时推出。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>名词性从句 - 在复合句中充当名词成分的从句。    <p>原文例句：Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves, but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个名词性从句，在复合句中充当宾语。这个从句是由that can generate new content from massive data sets引导的，其中that是连接词，can generate new content from massive data sets是谓语动词。这个从句的意思是说，能够从海量数据集中生成新内容的人工智能技术。这个句子的意思是说，这些标签本身没有多大意义，但微软在过去一年中一直围绕能够从海量数据集中生成新内容的人工智能技术改造其最大产品。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Start key</li>
<li>The tech giant sees 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’ and has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/e31b152f-c194-4f64-8148-b14c9b1dd6e5_1adc5e70.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft said it is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to allow users to immediately call up its artificial intelligence assistant. Photo: YouTube / Windows</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft</a> is adding a button to the Windows keyboard to activate its AI Copilot service, with the first devices to sport the new key available this month.</p><p>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Windows/Start key in 1994, underscoring the company’s commitment to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a>. Microsoft’s hardware partners will show off Windows 11 computers with the Copilot button over the coming days at the CES technology conference and, over time, it will become a required feature.</p><p>The short cut will help users create images, write emails and summarise text with the help of AI.</p><p>“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234530/microsoft-sees-booming-enterprise-ai-demand-hong-kong-amid-us-china-tech-war-threatens-cloud" title="">Microsoft touts booming enterprise AI demand in Hong Kong amid cloud push</a></h3><p>The Redmond, Washington-based company sees 2024 as “the year of the AI PC”, according to Mehdi, mirroring the budding trend among smartphone makers to tout their latest models as “AI phones”. Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves, but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets. That list now includes Windows, Office, Bing search, security software and customer and finance products. The work heavily leverages the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">GPT-4 technology</a> from OpenAI, in which Microsoft has invested US$13 billion.</p><p>For device makers, Microsoft’s push into AI services has not yet translated into a boost for sales, as the novel Copilot features are being rolled out to new and existing devices alike. Mehdi’s promise of weaving AI into hardware and silicon may signal more pressure on consumers to upgrade as Microsoft evolves and improves its AI proposition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese search engine giant Baidu to donate quantum computing facility to state-backed lab in similar move to Alibaba</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247255/chinese-search-engine-giant-baidu-donate-quantum-computing-facility-state-backed-lab-similar-move</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In the AI race in China, internet giants Baidu and Alibaba are donating their quantum computing research facilities to academic institutions. Baidu is donating its facility to the Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences (BAQIS), while Alibaba donated its lab to Zhejiang University last year. This move aims to foster collaboration and innovation in the field of quantum computing.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's tech giants contribute to quantum computing research through donations of facilities to academic institutions.</li>    <li>Theme: Baidu and Alibaba's strategic moves to advance quantum computing research in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of collaboration between industry and academia in推动推进推动推动推动 innovation.</li>    <li>Main information: Baidu's donation of its quantum computing facility to BAQIS; Alibaba's earlier donation to Zhejiang University; the goal of facilitating IP cross-licensing and innovation.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在中国的人工智能竞赛中，互联网巨头百度和阿里巴巴正将其量子计算研究设施捐赠给学术机构。百度将自己的设施捐赠给了北京量子信息科学研究院（BAQIS），而阿里巴巴去年将其实验室捐赠给了浙江大学。此举旨在促进量子计算领域的合作和创新。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国科技巨头通过向学术机构捐赠设施来为量子计算研究做出贡献。</li>    <li>主题：百度和阿里巴巴在推进中国量子计算研究方面的战略举措。</li>    <li>观点：产学研合作在推动创新中的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：百度将量子计算设施捐赠给 BAQIS；阿里巴巴早先向浙江大学捐赠；促进知识产权交叉许可和创新的目标。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>harness (v.) - /ˈhɑːnɪs/ 利用，驾驭。    <p>原文例句：Quantum computing is an emerging field of science that harnesses the principles of fundamental physics to solve problems too complex for traditional computers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：harness 是一个动词，意思是“利用，驾驭”，通常用于描述控制或利用自然力或资源。在这个句子中，它表示量子计算利用了基本物理学的原理来解决传统计算机无法处理的复杂问题。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>simultaneous (adj.) - /ˌsɪməlˈteɪnɪəs/ 同时的，同步的。    <p>原文例句：While quantum computers are not designed to replace traditional computers, they are able to solve very complex statistical problems via simultaneous multiple calculations, making them much faster.</p>    <p>例句讲解：simultaneous 是一个形容词，意思是“同时的，同步的”，表示两个或多个事件或动作在相同的时间发生。在这个句子中，它描述了量子计算机能够同时进行多个计算，从而更快地解决非常复杂的统计问题。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：In terms of computing power, the new quantum computer is 100 times faster than the previous model. </p>    <p>例句讲解：in terms of 是一个介词短语，意思是“就……而言，从……方面来说”。在这个句子中，它表示在计算能力方面，新的量子计算机比以前的型号快 100 倍。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese scientists use quantum computing to simulate black hole - 中国科学家利用量子计算来模拟黑洞<p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是Chinese scientists，谓语是use quantum computing to simulate，宾语是black hole。use quantum computing to simulate 是一个动词短语，意思是“利用量子计算来模拟”。在这个句子中，它表示中国科学家利用量子计算来模拟黑洞。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直延续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Baidu has been an early investor in AI applications including autonomous driving, and established its quantum computing facility in early 2018.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是一种时态，表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直延续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。它的结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。在这个句子中，Baidu has been an early investor in AI applications including autonomous driving 表示百度一直是自动驾驶等人工智能应用的早期投资者，并且established its quantum computing facility in early 2018 表示百度在 2018 年初建立了其量子计算设施。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物执行或引起的。    <p>原文例句：The new quantum computer is said to be 100 times faster than the previous model.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是一种语态，表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物执行或引起的。它的结构是：be + 过去分词。在这个句子中，is said to be 100 times faster than the previous model 表示据说是比以前的型号快 100 倍。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Last March, Baidu and BAQIS jointly launched the country’s first quantum computing intellectual property alliance, with the goal of facilitating easier IP cross-licensing</li>
<li>In 2023, Alibaba’s in-house research institution Damo Academy announced it was donating its own quantum lab to Zhejiang University</li>
</ul><p>Chinese search engine giant Baidu is donating its quantum computing research facility to the Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences (BAQIS), in a move similar to one made last year by e-commerce giant Alibaba Group Holding, as both firms lock horns in the country’s artificial intelligence (AI) race.</p><p>Baidu said on Thursday it would donate its Baidu Institute for Quantum Computing and associated experiment apparatus to BAQIS, a government-backed laboratory. The two parties are currently discussing details of the donation, according to a company statement.</p><p>Beijing-based Baidu, which was an early Chinese investor in AI applications including autonomous driving, established its quantum computing facility in early 2018.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3230671/tech-war-new-us-investment-curbs-have-limited-impact-chinas-targeted-semiconductors-quantum" title="">New US investment curbs to have limited impact on China’s targeted tech sectors</a></h3><p>It was launched with a mission to “become a top-tier global quantum computing research institution in five years”, with a focus on several areas including quantum AI, quantum algorithms and quantum architecture, according to local media the Paper.</p><p>In March last year, Baidu and BAQIS jointly launched the country’s first quantum computing intellectual property (IP) alliance, with the goal of facilitating easier IP cross-licensing and innovation in the industry.</p><p>Quantum computing is an emerging field of science that harnesses the principles of fundamental physics to solve problems too complex for traditional computers.</p><p>While quantum computers are not designed to replace traditional computers, they are able to solve very complex statistical problems via simultaneous multiple calculations, making them much faster.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3224737/chinese-scientists-use-quantum-computing-simulate-black-hole" title="">Chinese scientists use quantum computing to simulate black hole</a></h3><p>China and the US have been competing for supremacy in this field in recent years, although the technology is still in its early stage of development. Beijing did not define the area as a national priority until late 2020.</p><p>Last November, Alibaba’s in-house research institution Damo Academy announced it was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242956/alibaba-donates-its-quantum-lab-local-university-shifts-focus-ai-agriculture-healthcare" target="_self" title="">donating its own quantum lab to Zhejiang University.</a> Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Damo Academy said at the time that it would become more focused on fundamental research in AI and its application in areas such as agriculture and healthcare.</p><p>While quantum computing is still a long way from achieving large-scale commercialisation, the new trend of generative AI has been spreading rapidly around the world.</p><p>OpenAI, which unleashed a new era of AI with its conversational bot ChatGPT, was reported to be generating annual revenues of US$1.6 billion, according to US digital media outlet The Information. The San-Francisco-based start-up’s rival Anthropic was forecast to rake in over US$850 billion in annualised revenue by the end of 2024.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TikTok eyes US$17.5 billion shopping business on Amazon’s turf</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247219/tiktok-eyes-us175-billion-shopping-business-amazons-turf</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  TikTok, the popular short-video platform, aims to significantly expand its US e-commerce business in 2024, targeting a tenfold increase in merchandise sales to reach US$17.5 billion. This ambitious goal positions TikTok as a formidable competitor to Amazon and other budget retail rivals like Temu and Shein, which are gaining traction among younger shoppers in the US.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: TikTok's e-commerce ambitions in the US pose a challenge to dominant players like Amazon.</li>    <li>Theme: TikTok's strategic expansion into e-commerce, leveraging its social media reach and viral content to drive sales.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The growing popularity of Chinese e-commerce platforms, including TikTok Shop, among American consumers.</li>    <li>Main information: TikTok's target of US$17.5 billion in US e-commerce sales in 2024; its strategy of combining social media entertainment with impulse buying; and its intent to attract merchants and generate revenue from its e-commerce platform.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  抖音，这个颇受欢迎的短视频社交平台，计划在 2024 年显著拓展其美国电商业务，以十倍的增长达到 175 亿美元的商品销售额。这个雄心勃勃的目标让抖音成为亚马逊和其他像 Temu 和希音这样的预算零售商的强劲竞争对手，这些平台正受到美国年轻一代购物者的青睐。  <ul>    <li>摘要：抖音在美国的电商野心给亚马逊等龙头企业带来挑战。</li>    <li>主题：抖音将社交媒体影响力和病毒式传播内容变现，进军电商领域的战略扩张。</li>    <li>观点：包括抖音小店在内的中国电商平台在美国消费者间日益流行。</li>    <li>主要信息：2024 年抖音在美国电商销售额目标为 175 亿美元；结合社交媒体娱乐和冲动购买的策略；以及吸引商家、其电商平台创收的意图。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>subsidy (n.) - /ˈsʌbsɪdɪ/ 补贴。    <p>原文例句：In the US, TikTok is offering free shipping and subsidies to influencers who peddle gadgets, clothes and make-up in videos and live streams. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词派生自拉丁语subsidium（援助），指的是“政府或其他组织提供的经济援助”。在这个例句中，它特指TikTok在美国向兜售小工具、服装和化妆品的视频博主提供的免费送货和补贴。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>commission (n.) - /kəˈmɪʃn/ 手续费，佣金。    <p>原文例句：TikTok on Wednesday announced it will increase fees imposed on merchants to 6 per cent of each sale beginning in April and to 8 per cent in July in most product categories, marking an end to promotions used to entice sellers. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词最初源于拉丁语，意为“委托”，在此处表示“代理人或经纪人为提供服务而收取的费用，又称佣金、手续费”。在这个例句中，它特指TikTok于周三宣布自4月起将对商家收取每笔销售额的6%作为手续费，并在7月增加至8%，结束了此前为吸引商家而进行的促销活动。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>free shipping - 免运费。    <P>原文例句：In the US, TikTok is offering free shipping and subsidies to influencers who peddle gadgets, clothes and make-up in videos and live streams. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由free（免费的）和shipping（运送）组成，表示“不需要收取运费”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok在美国为兜售小工具、服装和化妆品的视频博主提供的免运费。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TikTok is now seeking to expand sales across the US and Latin America, where it is planning to launch the e-commerce operation in coming months, two people familiar with the matter said. - TikTok 现正寻求在美国和拉丁美洲扩张销售，根据两位知情人士透露，计划将在未来几个月内启动电商业务。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是 TikTok，谓语是 is seeking to expand sales，宾语是 across the US and Latin America。where it is planning to launch the e-commerce operation in coming months 是一个定语从句，修饰 TikTok，表示 TikTok 计划将在未来几个月内启动电商业务。这个句子的意思是说，TikTok 现正寻求在美国和拉丁美洲扩张销售，计划将在未来几个月内启动电商业务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>将来时 - 表示未来将要发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams within its main social media app, hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这种时态由will/shall + 动词原形构成，表示说话人对未来将要发生的动作或状态的预测或打算。在这个例句中，it lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams within its main social media app, hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee是一个将来时的句子，表示TikTok Shop允许用户在滚动其主要社交媒体应用程序中的短视频和直播时购买商品，希望消费者将其用作亚马逊或虾皮的替代品。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物承受的。    <p>原文例句：TikTok Shop is one of the fastest-growing features for the Beijing-based, closely held company, which is seeking a new growth driver beyond social-media advertising. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这种语态由be + 过去分词构成，表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物承受的。在这个例句中，is seeking a new growth driver beyond social-media advertising是一个被动语态句子，表示该公司正在寻求除了社交媒体广告之外的新增长动力。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon, but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein</li>
<li>TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales</li>
</ul><p>TikTok, the global hit short-video platform owned by ByteDance, aims to grow the size of its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, according to people familiar with the matter, posing a bigger threat to Amazon.com.</p><p>The 2024 merchandise volume goal for the US version of TikTok Shop – which melds online entertainment with impulse buying – was discussed in internal meetings in recent weeks and may still change depending on how the business goes, said the people, who asked not to be named discussing private information.</p><p>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon but also fellow Chinese-owned budget retail outfits Temu and Shein, which have been making big strides among younger American shoppers.</p><p>Unlike its two rival discounters, TikTok is counting on its social media reach and the appeal of viral videos to hook buyers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales through its platform, Bloomberg News reported. The company is now seeking to expand sales across the US and Latin America, where it is planning to launch the e-commerce operation in coming months, two people familiar with the matter said.</p><p>“The speculated US merchandise sales figures represented by Bloomberg are inaccurate,” TikTok said in a statement.</p><p>ByteDance, founded more than a decade ago by Zhang Yiming and Liang Rubo, grew into an internet leader worth more than US$200 billion thanks to the virality of short-video platforms TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin. TikTok Shop is one of the fastest-growing features for the Beijing-based, closely held company, which is seeking a new growth driver beyond social-media advertising. ByteDance’s revenue surged roughly 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing the projected growth of far more established social media rivals Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings.</p><p>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams within its main social media app, hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee. That format – an effort to combine the ease of shopping on Amazon with the product discovery afforded by apps like Meta’s Instagram – has already helped Douyin snatch a significant portion of Chinese consumer spending from Alibaba Group Holding and JD.com, particularly after lockdown rules during the pandemic drove people to spend more time online. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/80b40a96-5660-44d3-a756-f6c48d3cb312_1126e908.jpg" title="TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>ByteDance is intent on exporting its e-commerce model globally. In the US, TikTok is offering free shipping and subsidies to influencers who peddle gadgets, clothes and make-up in videos and live streams. In November, boosted by Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals, more than 5 million new US customers bought something on TikTok, the company said. It has roughly 150 million users in the country.</p><p>TikTok on Wednesday announced it will increase fees imposed on merchants to 6 per cent of each sale beginning in April and to 8 per cent in July in most product categories, marking an end to promotions used to entice sellers. Those commissions are still significantly lower than Amazon seller fees, which are typically about 15 per cent, but the boost signals TikTok is quickly moving to generate revenue from its e-commerce platform.</p><p>Americans are increasingly comfortable shopping on Chinese e-commerce apps, including the popular fashion site Shein and PDD Holdings' Temu, which has exploded in popularity since airing a Super Bowl ad in February.</p><p>It is unclear what sales targets TikTok Shop has set globally or for other markets. In Indonesia, TikTok has taken control of GoTo Group’s e-commerce unit Tokopedia in a US$1.5 billion deal, which allowed the company to restart its online retail service after months of scrutiny by the local government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247211/apple-leads-us383-billion-tech-rout-reversal-groups-2023-rally</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Apple, Amazon, Alphabet, Microsoft, Meta Platforms, Tesla, and Nvidia, also known as the "Magnificent Seven," had impressive gains in 2023, driven by the craze for AI. However, the second half of the year saw a decline in these gains due to concerns about the US economy, with Nvidia and Apple facing specific challenges.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tech giants' rally cooled in 2023's second half.</li>    <li>Theme: Market downturn after tech stocks' surge in 2023.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Investors' doubts about the rally's sustainability; the need for tech companies to deliver profitable technology.</li>    <li>Main information: Magnificent Seven's stock performance; the impact of AI, the Federal Reserve's policies, and company-specific challenges.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  苹果、亚马逊、Alphabet、微软、Meta Platforms、特斯拉和英伟达，也被称为“科技七巨头”，在2023年受人工智能狂潮的推动而大幅上涨。然而，由于对美国经济的担忧，下半年这些收益有所下降，英伟达和苹果面临着特定的挑战。  <ul>    <li>摘要：科技巨头在2023年下半年的涨势降温。</li>    <li>主题：科技股2023年激增后市场下滑。</li>    <li>观点：投资者对这次上涨可持续性的怀疑；科技公司需要提供有利可图的技术。</li>    <li>主要信息：科技七巨头的股票表现；人工智能、美联储政策和公司特定挑战的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>frenzy (n.) - /ˈfrɛnzi/ 狂热，疯狂。    <p>原文例句：Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于Old French，由frenetique（狂热的）而来，意为“疯狂，狂热”。在这个例句中，它指的是对电动汽车的疯狂。这个词带有强烈的负面色彩，表示一种不理性的、不受控制的兴奋或热情。    </p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>recoup (v.) - /rɪˈkuːp/ 弥补，挽回。    <p>原文例句：Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于Latin，由re-（重新）和capere（采取，抓住）组成，意为“重新获得，弥补”。在这个例句中，它指的是2023年的大部分收益弥补了前一年的损失。这个词通常用于表示在经历了损失或失败之后，又重新获得了部分或全部的损失，也用于表示在经历了一段时间的低迷之后，又重新恢复了增长或活力。    </p>    </li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>have one's work cut out for them - 面临一项艰巨的任务。    <p>原文例句：The companies need to continue to deliver not only solid technology, but profitable technology going forward, according to Sosnick.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由have（有），work（工作），cut out（切断），for them（为他们）构成的，表示“面临一项艰巨的任务”。在这个例句中，它指的是这些公司面临着在未来继续提供不仅是可靠的技术，而且是盈利的技术这一艰巨的任务。这个词组通常用于表示某人或某机构面临着困难的挑战或任务。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD. - 尽管特斯拉表示其在第四季度交付的电动汽车数量超过分析师预期，但该公司却将电动汽车销量冠军的位置输给了中国的比亚迪。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是the company lost its place as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD，其中主语是the company，谓语是lost，宾语是its place as top seller of EVs。Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected是一个让步状语从句，表示尽管特斯拉表示其在第四季度交付的电动汽车数量超过分析师预期，后面逗号的作用是分隔主句和让步状语从句。这个句子的意思是说，尽管特斯拉表示其在第四季度交付的电动汽车数量超过分析师预期，但该公司却将电动汽车销量冠军的位置输给了中国的比亚迪。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、愿望或可能性。    <p>原文例句：Though the Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023 as investors mulled the Federal Reserve’s ability to execute a soft landing for the US economy, which would likely mean fewer interest rate cuts than expected.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气结构，表示如果美联储能够实现经济软着陆，那么加息的次数就会比预期少。这个结构由if（如果）引导，后面是虚拟语气动词（如could、would、should等）。在这个例句中，虚拟语气动词是would，表示可能或假设。这个句子的意思是说，尽管科技七巨头在去年上涨了超过100%，这主要是受人工智能的狂潮推动，但随着投资者猜测美联储能否让美国经济实现软着陆，2023年下半年的涨幅有所降温。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023</li>
<li>Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD</li>
</ul><p>The largest technology stocks that lifted the broader market last year are having a less-rosy start to 2024.</p><p>The so-called Magnificent Seven, which includes Apple, Amazon.com, Alphabet, Microsoft, Meta Platforms, Tesla and Nvidia, slipped for the last four trading days, the longest losing streak in a month, according to the Bloomberg Magnificent 7 Price Return Index.</p><p>Shares of Apple, down 4.6 per cent in the time period, lead the slump that has erased US$383 billion in market value. The Nasdaq 100 Index has also fallen in the last four trading days.</p><p>“We don’t know if last year’s rally has fully ended, but it is completely normal to expect markets will pull back after a rally like we saw,” said Steve Sosnick, chief strategist at Interactive Brokers Group. “Without the year-end factors that turbocharged the rally, I think we’re seeing the party winding down.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" title="">Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets</a></h3><p>It is a signal that investor doubts over the sticking power of the 2023 rally were well-placed.</p><p>Though the Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023 as investors mulled the Federal Reserve’s ability to execute a soft landing for the US economy, which would likely mean fewer interest rate cuts than expected.</p><p>“You’re not going to get high-single-digit or double-digit earnings growth if we get something worse than a soft landing,” Sosnick said. “But we’re not going to get six cuts with a soft landing.”</p><p>A few members of the group have also seen specific stock pressure early this year. Apple shares have been weighed down after gaining a new bear; Barclays analysts early this week downgraded shares of the tech giant to underweight, saying they expect soft demand for iPhones going forward.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" title="">Apple hits 7-week low after Barclays downgrade on demand concerns</a></h3><p>Tesla has shed 8.8 per cent in the last four days, its longest streak of losses in more than four weeks. Though Tesla reported on Tuesday that it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as the top seller of electric cars to China’s BYD.</p><p>To be sure, it is likely too early to say the tech-focused rally is over. Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier, and some of the group – Amazon, Alphabet, Meta and Tesla – are still below their all-time highs, signalling they could have room to run.</p><p>But, the largest tech names also have their work cut out for them in 2024. The companies need to continue to deliver not only solid technology, but profitable technology going forward, according to Sosnick.</p><p>“In December everyone bought the sizzle,” he said. “Now we have to see if the steak is any good.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>New refund policies from Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com spark fears of customer abuse among merchants</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247168/new-refund-policies-alibabas-taobao-and-jdcom-spark-fears-customer-abuse-among-merchants</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese e-commerce platforms Taobao and JD.com have introduced new "refund only" policies, allowing customers to keep the product while receiving a refund, sparking concerns among merchants about potential abuse. Merchants fear that some consumers may exploit these policies, leading to increased costs and unfair competition for sellers who prioritize high-quality products.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: New "refund only" policies in Chinese e-commerce raise concerns over potential abuse.</li>    <li>Theme: The introduction of "refund only" policies and the potential for abuse by consumers.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The debate over whether consumer rights or merchant interests should be prioritized in e-commerce.</li>    <li>Main information: The implementation of the new policies by Taobao and JD.com, concerns expressed by merchants, and the potential for increased costs and unfair competition.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国电子商务平台淘宝和京东推出了新的“仅退款”政策，允许消费者在保留商品的同时获得退款，这引发了商家对潜在滥用的担忧。商家担心，一些消费者可能会利用这些政策，导致成本增加，并对优先考虑高品质产品的卖家造成不公平的竞争。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国电子商务的新“仅退款”政策引发了对潜在滥用的担忧。</li>    <li>主题：引入“仅退款”政策和消费者可能滥用的潜力。</li>    <li>观点：在电子商务中是消费者权益还是商家利益更重要。</li>    <li>主要信息：淘宝和京东实施新政策、商家表达的担忧以及成本增加和不公平竞争的可能性。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>spark (v.) - /spɑːrk/ 点燃，激发。    <p>原文例句：New “refund only” policies introduced by Chinese e-commerce players including Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao and JD.com have sparked concern among some sellers about potential abuse of the terms, according to merchants and analysts.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语spærca，意思是“火花”。它可以作为名词或动词使用。作为动词时，意为“点燃，激发”。在这个例句中，它表示新的“仅退款”政策引起了商家的担忧。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>retribution (n.) - /rɛtrɪˈbjuːʃn/ 报应，报复。    <p>原文例句：The 33-year-old online shop owner, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of retribution from the platforms, said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products, because they will bear higher costs in the event of more claims.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语retribuere，意思是“偿还，报答”。它通常被用作名词，表示“报应，报复”。在这个例句中，它表示该网店老板担心来自平台的报复。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>run a business - 经营生意，开店。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba, whose company mission is “to make it easy to do business anywhere”, had a long internal debate over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo, which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由run（经营，管理）和business（生意，店面）构成的，表示“经营生意，开店”。在这个例句中，它表示阿里巴巴一直在内部争论是否要效仿拼多多，而拼多多是第一个提供不退货退款政策的公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba, whose company mission is “to make it easy to do business anywhere”, had a long internal debate over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo, which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it. - 阿里巴巴的企业使命是“让天下没有难做的生意”，该公司内部就是否效仿竞争对手拼多多进行了长时间的争论，拼多多是第一家提供消费者可以对不满意商品退款而不退货的政策的公司。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Alibaba had a long internal debate，其中主语是Alibaba，谓语是had，宾语是a long internal debate。whose company mission is “to make it easy to do business anywhere”是一个定语从句，修饰Alibaba，表示阿里巴巴的企业使命是“让天下没有难做的生意”。over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo, which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it是一个介词短语作状语，修饰Alibaba had a long internal debate，表示阿里巴巴内部争论是否要效仿竞争对手拼多多，而拼多多是第一家提供消费者可以对不满意商品退款而不退货的政策的公司。这个句子的意思是说，阿里巴巴的企业使命是“让天下没有难做的生意”，该公司内部就是否效仿竞争对手拼多多进行了长时间的争论，拼多多是第一家提供消费者可以对不满意商品退款而不退货的政策的公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动名词作主语 - 动名词可以作主语，表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse under new refund policies. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某些人对新退款政策下的潜在滥用行为表示担忧。结构是：Some + 动名词 + have/has + 其他。其中Some是限定词，动名词是动词的-ing形式，have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，其他是其他成分。在这个例句中，动名词是concerns，表示担忧，主语是Some merchants，谓语是have raised，宾语是potential abuse under new refund policies，表示新退款政策下的潜在滥用行为。这个句子的意思是说，一些商家对新退款政策下的潜在滥用行为表示担忧。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Taobao and JD.com have introduced policies that allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it</li>
<li>Some merchants have raised concerns that consumers may look to exploit the terms of these ‘refund only’ policies, hitting their operations</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/85b29bec-f2e3-42ad-ba41-d20ec559a707_664d3160.jpg" /><figcaption>Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse under new refund policies. Photo: SCMP</figcaption></figure><p>New “refund only” policies introduced by Chinese e-commerce players including Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao and JD.com have sparked concern among some sellers about potential abuse of the terms, according to merchants and analysts.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com in late December introduced new policies that – in certain circumstances – allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it. This may occur when a consumer complains about the poor quality of a product, or about an inaccurate and misleading description on the platform. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Alibaba, whose company mission is “to make it easy to do business anywhere”, had a long internal debate over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo, which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it.</p><p>Even though some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse, Alibaba came down on the side of consumer rights in such a situation as merchants are ultimately dependent on buyer confidence, according to a person briefed on the discussions who asked not to be identified.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>However, since the policy went into effect last week there has been an increased number of claims under the “refund but keep the purchase” policy, according to one merchant who runs apparel shops on both Taobao and JD.com, adding that some consumers were looking to exploit the situation.</p><p>The 33-year-old online shop owner, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of retribution from the platforms, said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products, because they will bear higher costs in the event of more claims.</p><p>“This refund terms only works for merchants who sell dirt-cheap goods,” she said, adding that the policy clearly favoured consumers.</p><p>Meanwhile, some merchants took to social media platforms such as Douyin and Weibo to express anger at the potential for policy abuse.</p><p>One user with the handle “PengqiangweiVerna” posted on Weibo that the practice will “foster a group of online freeloaders”. Another Douyin user called “Xinzhouxiaohuolang” posted a dozen videos denouncing such refund requests.</p><p>Both Taobao and JD.com have said that any decisions on refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments.</p><p>A person familiar with the situation at Taobao, who asked not to be identified as they are not authorised to talk to the media, said that the platform has offered merchants an appeal option if they think they have been wronged.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Wednesday.</p><p>Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice was initially launched in 2021 and is seen as a key factor behind the Shanghai-based budget-shopping platform’s rise to prominence.</p><p>Tang Guangyao, a 38-year-old Beijing software developer, said he has shifted from other e-commerce platforms to Pinduoduo as a primary shopping channel owing to its robust consumer protection, even though it focuses on budget prices.</p><p>But some analysts say simply following Pinduoduo’s lead may not work for rival platforms.</p><p>“This [new refund policy] isn’t very practical for platforms such as Taobao, Tmall and JD.com,” said Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangzhou-based iiMedia, pointing out that Pinduoduo’s focus on rock-bottom prices means that the costs of the scheme are more bearable than for merchants on rival sites.</p><p>“By following this [Pinduoduo] refund policy … [rival platforms] will give their merchants a dilemma,” he added.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei’s HarmonyOS to beat Apple’s iOS as the No. 2 smartphone operating system in China in 2024: TechInsights report</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Huawei's return to the 5G smartphone segment is predicted to drive the increased adoption of its HarmonyOS operating system in China, surpassing Apple's iOS as the second-biggest platform. The Mate 60 series launch facilitated this comeback despite US sanctions and chipset shortages. Huawei's self-developed HarmonyOS aims to gain market share from Android and iOS.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: HarmonyOS poised to become the second-largest mobile OS in China.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's HarmonyOS gains traction in China due to Mate 60 series and upcoming HarmonyOS Next.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: HarmonyOS's potential to challenge Android and iOS dominance in China; Huawei's resilience in overcoming supply challenges.</li>    <li>Main information: Huawei's successful launch of Mate 60 series despite US sanctions; HarmonyOS Next launch plans; partnerships with major Chinese companies for native app development.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  德勤预计，得益于华为重返5G智能手机领域，其鸿蒙操作系统将在中国市场的份额超越苹果的iOS，成为第二大操作系统。Mate60系列的发布促成了这一复出，尽管受到了美国的制裁和芯片短缺的影响。华为自研的鸿蒙操作系统旨在从安卓和iOS手中夺取市场份额。  <ul>    <li>摘要：鸿蒙操作系统有望成为中国第二大移动操作系统。</li>    <li>主题：华为鸿蒙操作系统在中国市场获得关注，得益于Mate60系列手机和即将推出的HarmonyOS Next。</li>    <li>观点：鸿蒙操作系统挑战安卓和iOS在华统治地位的潜力；华为在应对供应挑战方面的韧性。</li>    <li>主要信息：华为成功发布Mate60系列手机，尽管受到美国制裁；HarmonyOS Next发布计划；与中国各大企业合作开发原生应用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>adoption (n.) - /əˈdɒpʃ(ə)n/ 收养，采用。    <p>原文例句：Increased HarmonyOS adoption is expected to be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语adoptare，意思是“收养，采用”。在这个例句中，它指的是HarmonyOS操作系统的采用率，预计随着华为重返5G智能手机市场而增加。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>platform (n.) - /ˈplætfɔːm/ 平台，讲台。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year driven by the US-sanctioned firm’s comeback with the Mate 60 series.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古法语plateforme，意思是“平台，讲台”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为的移动平台HarmonyOS，预计今年将超越苹果的iOS成为中国第二大操作系统。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>to ease - 缓解，减轻。    <P>原文例句：TechInsights also expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由to（向……）和ease（缓解）构成的，意思是“缓解，减轻”。在这个例句中，它表示TechInsights还预计，在未来几个月内，华为的供应挑战将得到缓解，这主要是由于麒麟9000芯片组的短缺。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>to make a comeback - 卷土重来，重新流行。    <P>原文例句：Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由make和comeback构成，make表示使，comeback表示回来，引申为“卷土重来，重新流行”，常用来形容曾经流行过的事物又重新受到欢迎。在这个例句中，它表示华为重返5G智能手机领域。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei’s smartphones are all powered by HarmonyOS, its self-developed Android alternative launched in August 2019.- 华为的所有智能手机都搭载了HarmonyOS，这是其于2019年8月推出的自研安卓替代系统。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Huawei’s smartphones，谓语是are powered by HarmonyOS。all是限定词，修饰HarmonyOS，表示所有的华为智能手机都搭载了HarmonyOS。its self-developed Android alternative是一个定语从句，修饰HarmonyOS，表示HarmonyOS是华为自研的安卓替代系统。launched in August 2019是一个过去分词短语，作状语，修饰HarmonyOS，表示HarmonyOS是在2019年8月推出的。这个句子的意思是说，华为的所有智能手机都搭载了HarmonyOS，这是其于2019年8月推出的自研安卓替代系统。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去进行时 - 表示过去某个时间正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TechInsights also expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，结构是：was/were + 现在分词。其中was/were要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间正在进行，强调动作或状态的持续性。在这个例句中，它表示TechInsights还预计，在未来几个月内，华为的供应挑战将得到缓解，这主要是由于麒麟9000芯片组的短缺。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Increased HarmonyOS adoption is expected to be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment</li>
<li>TechInsights also expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/83c4b156-87f3-4acb-b3f4-8cb885281387_c0009114.jpg" /><figcaption>Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year driven by the US-sanctioned firm’s comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to a report by TechInsights.</p><p>While Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, Canadian research firm TechInsights said in a report released on Wednesday.</p><p>Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment, which started with the surprise launch in late August of its Mate 60 Pro, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology.</p><p>TechInsights also expects Huawei to make a solid recovery in 2024, according to the report.</p><p>Huawei’s smartphones are all powered by HarmonyOS, its self-developed Android alternative launched in August 2019, three months after the US government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">added the firm to its Entity List</a>. Under this trade blacklist, Huawei is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>On its release, the Mate 60 Pro inspired <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">a wave of patriotic fervour</a> among Chinese consumers, and the Shenzhen-based firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241541/huawei-has-big-problem-popular-mate-60-5g-smartphones-theres-not-enough-supply-meet-growing-demand" target="_self" title="">faced supply issues as it scrambled to crank up production to meet demand</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" title="">Huawei sees 9 per cent sales growth in 2023, boosted by Mate 60 Pro 5G comeback</a></h3><p>TechInsights expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months. Huawei’s product portfolio further expanded last week when it launched new smartphone models under its mid-range Nova series.</p><p>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p><p>Huawei is expected to launch a developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next in the first quarter of 2024, and is already working with China’s major companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p><p>Last month, Chinese financial technology giant Ant Group, the fintech affiliate of South China Morning Post owner <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, said it is building a new version of mobile payment app Alipay based on HarmonyOS, after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242703/alibaba-develops-native-dingtalk-app-harmonyos-huawei-aims-end-support-android-apps?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba started development on a new version of DingTalk</a>, its workplace collaboration app, for the platform.</p><p>Other major Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> companies – including e-commerce firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>, video gaming giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netease?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">NetEase</a> and food delivery market leader <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> – in November already started to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241371/chinese-big-tech-firms-jdcom-netease-and-meituan-rush-hire-harmonyos-based-app-developers-huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">recruit developers to build native apps for HarmonyOS</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mcdonalds?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">McDonald’s</a> China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year – became <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244236/mcdonalds-china-pushes-development-native-apps-based-harmonyos-adoption-huaweis-mobile-operating?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239589/xiaomi-launches-home-grown-cross-device-system-hyperos-us-sanctioned-huawei-moves-further-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS Next</a>.</p><p>It remains to be seen whether these efforts will have a halo effect on other smartphone makers and make HarmonyOS a default operating system for not just smartphones but also laptops and cars in China, TechInsights said.</p><p>More than 700 million devices currently run on HarmonyOS, with more than 2.2 million third-party developers creating apps for the platform, according to Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group, speaking at the company’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230293/tech-war-huawei-revive-smartphone-business-back-fresh-ai-powered-operating-system-even-us-sanctions?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">annual developer conference in August</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple dominates global premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground on the back of its new 5G handsets</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Apple continued its dominance in the premium smartphone market in 2023 with a 71% share, despite facing tough competition from Huawei and Samsung.<br>  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple maintains its lead in the premium smartphone segment despite Huawei's comeback and Samsung's gains.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's resilience in the premium smartphone market amidst competition from Huawei and Samsung.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of the premium smartphone segment and changing consumer buying patterns.</li>    <li>Main information: Apple's leading position, Huawei's strong comeback, Samsung's gains, and the growth of the premium smartphone segment.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果公司在 2023 年继续主导着高端智能手机市场，市场份额达到 71%，尽管面临着来自华为和三星的激烈竞争。<br>  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果在高端智能手机领域保持领先地位，尽管华为强势回归，三星市场份额有所增加。</li>    <li>主题：苹果在高端智能手机市场保持韧性，面临华为和三星的竞争。</li>    <li>观点：高端智能手机领域的意义和消费者购买模式的变化。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果的领先地位，华为的强势回归，三星的收益以及高端智能手机领域的发展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>resilience (n.) - /rɪˈzɪljəns/ 恢复力，适应力。    <p>原文例句：The premium segment, meanwhile, was expected to account for nearly one-fourth of global smartphone market sales and 60 per cent of the industry’s revenue in 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由re-（重新）和silience（跳跃）构成的，表示“恢复力，适应力”。在这个例句中，它指的是高端智能手机市场预计将占全球智能手机市场销量的近四分之一，占行业收入的 60%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>underscoring (v.) - /ˌʌndəˈskɔːrɪŋ/ 强调，突出。    <p>原文例句：Apple opened its first retail store in India last April, underscoring the US tech titan’s increasing focus on the South Asian nation as a key sales market and alternative manufacturing hub to China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由under-（下面）和score（刻痕）构成的，表示“强调，突出”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果去年 4 月在印度开设了第一家零售店，凸显了这家美国科技巨头对南亚国家作为主要销售市场和中国替代制造中心的日益关注。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>despite the - 尽管，不顾。    <p>原文例句：Apple continued its dominance in the premium smartphone market in 2023 with a 71% share, despite facing tough competition from Huawei and Samsung.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由despite（不顾）和the（冠词）构成的，表示“尽管，不顾”。在这个例句中，它表示苹果在 2023 年继续主导着高端智能手机市场，市场份额达到 71%，尽管面临着来自华为和三星的激烈竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in the meantime - 同时，与……同时。    <p>原文例句：The premium segment, meanwhile, was expected to account for nearly one-fourth of global smartphone market sales and 60 per cent of the industry’s revenue in 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……中）和the meantime（同时）构成的，表示“同时，与……同时”。在这个例句中，它表示高端智能手机市场预计将占全球智能手机市场销量的近四分之一，占行业收入的 60%。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple opened its first retail store in India last April, underscoring the US tech titan’s increasing focus on the South Asian nation as a key sales market and alternative manufacturing hub to China. - 苹果去年 4 月在印度开设了第一家零售店，凸显了这家美国科技巨头对南亚国家作为主要销售市场和中国替代制造中心的日益关注。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Apple opened its first retail store in India last April，其中主语是Apple，谓语是opened，宾语是its first retail store，状语是last April。underscoring the US tech titan’s increasing focus on the South Asian nation as a key sales market and alternative manufacturing hub to China是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰Apple opened its first retail store in India last April，表示苹果去年 4 月在印度开设第一家零售店这一行为是为了凸显该公司对南亚国家作为主要销售市场和中国替代制造中心的日益关注。这个句子的意思是说，苹果去年 4 月在印度开设了第一家零售店，凸显了这家美国科技巨头对南亚国家作为主要销售市场和中国替代制造中心的日益关注。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 强调句型是通过在句首或句中插入特定词语来强调句子中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：Owning the latest and greatest flagships has also become a status symbol for many consumers, especially in emerging markets where they are jumping directly from the mid-price band to the premium band.</p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句型的基本结构是：It is/was + 被强调成分 + that/who + 其他。在这个例句中，被强调成分是Owning the latest and greatest flagships，that引导了一个句子，说明了拥有最新最好的旗舰手机如何成为一种身份象征，尤其是对那些直接从普通手机市场转向高端手机市场的新兴市场消费者而言。这个句子的意思是说，拥有最新最好的旗舰手机也已成为许多消费者的身份象征，尤其是在新兴市场，消费者直接从普通手机市场转向高端手机市场。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示苹果的份额从2022年的75%下降，这是华为复苏的结果。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple remained the world’s top vendor of premium smartphones in 2023, with a 71 per cent market share, according to research firm Counterpoint</li>
<li>The US firm’s lead, however, declined year on year amid Huawei’s 5G comeback with its Mate 60 series and the gains made by Samsung’s foldable phones</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/64d88f21-13d4-47d7-a021-0a71facc64d7_e98ebaba.jpg" /><figcaption>Apple’s iPhone 15 Pro and Pro Max models are seen on display at a store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 22, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> continued to lead the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> industry’s premium segment in 2023, but saw its worldwide share decline mainly because of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-sanctioned</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>’ strong <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/5g/news" target="_self" title="">5G</a> handset market comeback with its Mate 60 series.</p><p>The global premium smartphone market, where handsets are priced from US$600, saw Apple remain the “undisputed leader” last year with a dominant 71 per cent share, according to the latest industry report released on Tuesday by Counterpoint Research.</p><p>Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei, which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020</a>, as well as the gains made by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a>’ Galaxy S23 series and its latest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foldable-phones" target="_self" title="">foldable phones</a>.</p><p>Samsung retained the global No 2 spot in the premium segment with a share of 17 per cent, compared to 16 per cent in 2022. Still, No 3 Huawei captured more new ground year on year with a 5 per cent share, up from 3 per cent in 2022, according to the Counterpoint report.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/cb3a9a4b-0ce5-45f4-91e6-798c2c4c40f0_5babf532.jpg" title="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> last year took the fourth and fifth spots in the premium smartphone segment with a 2 per cent and 1 per cent share, respectively.</p><p>The latest market data shows the resilience of the premium segment, despite the projected decrease in the overall global smartphone market in 2023 – global handset shipments are forecast to hit their lowest level in almost a decade with a 5 per cent decline, according to an earlier Counterpoint report.</p><p>The premium segment, meanwhile, was expected to account for nearly one-fourth of global smartphone market sales and 60 per cent of the industry’s revenue in 2023. Counterpoint data shows that the so-called ultra-premium segment, where smartphones cost more than US$1,000, accounted for one-third of total premium handset sales last year.</p><p>Over the past few years, the premium segment has emerged as a growth area in the otherwise weak worldwide smartphone market. Counterpoint projected the premium segment sales share to triple to 24 per cent in 2023, compared to 6 per cent in 2016.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3246457/ranked-top-5-smartphones-2023-iphone-15-pro-max-and-google-pixel-8-pro-two-foldable-phones-and-best" title="">Top 5 smartphones of 2023, from iPhone 15 Pro Max to the best camera phone</a></h3><p>“There has been a shift in consumer buying patterns in the smartphone market,” Counterpoint senior analyst Varun Mishra said in the premium segment report. “Considering the importance a smartphone holds, consumers are willing to spend more to get a high-quality device that they can use for a longer period.”</p><p>Much of the global premium segment’s growth last year was driven by China, western Europe, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/india" target="_self" title="">India</a>, and the Middle East-and-Africa regions, according to Counterpoint.</p><p>India is already the world’s fastest-growing market for premium smartphones, the Counterpoint report said. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217435/apple-opens-first-retail-store-india-us-tech-giant-sharpens-focus-south-asian-nation-major-market" target="_self" title="">Apple opened its first retail store in India</a> last April, underscoring the US tech titan’s increasing focus on the South Asian nation as a key sales market and alternative manufacturing hub to China.</p><p>“Owning the latest and greatest flagships has also become a status symbol for many consumers, especially in emerging markets where they are jumping directly from the mid-price band to the premium band,” Mishra said. “Further, these devices are increasingly becoming more affordable due to promotion seasons and financing options.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
