<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China’s video gaming market ended 2023 battered and bruised, but can world-beating titles and innovation save the day?</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248249/chinas-video-gaming-market-ended-2023-battered-and-bruised-can-world-beating-titles-and-innovation</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>英语摘要：</h2>  2023年对于中国的视频游戏行业来说充满挑战。行业监管机构出台游戏规则草案，旨在遏制消费者在游戏内物品上的过度支出，导致中国游戏股票市值损失约800亿美元。尽管如此，中国游戏行业在全球继续保持强劲势头，并受到分析师的看好。中国游戏公司努力平衡股东收益最大化与保护未成年人免受游戏成瘾的双重目标。虽然腾讯、网易等公司都受到了不同程度的影响，但也有像米哈游这样的公司在全球市场上取得了成功。2024年，中国游戏行业预计将继续保持增长势头，更多优质游戏有望推出。业内人士认为，人工智能和虚拟现实等新技术将推动中国游戏行业的创新和发展。  <ul>    <li>摘要：2023年中国游戏业界挑战与机遇并存，规则草案出台遏制过度消费，中国游戏在全球表现强劲，多家公司平衡收益与保护未成年人，米哈游全球市场获成功，2024年预计持续增长，新技术将推动游戏业发展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  2023年对于中国的视频游戏行业来说充满挑战。行业监管机构出台游戏规则草案，旨在遏制消费者在游戏内物品上的过度支出，导致中国游戏股票市值损失约800亿美元。尽管如此，中国游戏行业在全球继续保持强劲势头，并受到分析师的看好。中国游戏公司努力平衡股东收益最大化与保护未成年人免受游戏成瘾的双重目标。虽然腾讯、网易等公司都受到了不同程度的影响，但也有像米哈游这样的公司在全球市场上取得了成功。2024年，中国游戏行业预计将继续保持增长势头，更多优质游戏有望推出。业内人士认为，人工智能和虚拟现实等新技术将推动中国游戏行业的创新和发展。  <ul>    <li>摘要：2023年中国游戏业界挑战与机遇并存，规则草案出台遏制过度消费，中国游戏在全球表现强劲，多家公司平衡收益与保护未成年人，米哈游全球市场获成功，2024年预计持续增长，新技术将推动游戏业发展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rout (n.) - /raʊt/ - 溃败，大败。    <p>原文例句：The timing and severity of the proposed rule change dealt a fresh blow to already-fragile investor confidence in Chinese stocks. NetEase, the country’s No. 2 gaming operator, fell by nearly a quarter in a single trading day, with Tencent dropping over 12 per cent. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自古法语，意思是“溃败，大败”。在这个例句中，它指的是拟议的规则变更对中国股市投资者的信心造成了新的打击。网易，中国第二大游戏运营商，在单个交易日中下跌了近四分之一，腾讯下跌了超过12%。</p></li>    <li>incentive (n.) - /ɪnˈsɛntɪv/ - 激励，诱因。    <p>原文例句：The rule change – if passed in its present form – is expected to hit titles that rely heavily on loot boxes for monetisation or incentives for user acquisition, and those that have a large number of high spenders.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自拉丁语，意思是“激励，诱因”。在这个例句中，它指的是拟议的规则变更预计将打击那些严重依赖战利品箱来实现货币化或用户获取激励的游戏，以及那些有大量高额消费者的游戏。</p></li>    <li>immersive (adj.) - /ɪˈmɜːsɪv/ - 沉浸式的，身临其境的。    <p>原文例句：Zhang says that in terms of innovation, local developers are likely to “leverage augmented and virtual reality equipment and software” as well as “artificial intelligence (AI) to make the same game playable across different platforms – mobile, desktop and consoles – for a more immersive gameplay experience”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自拉丁语，意思是“沉浸式的，身临境的”。在这个例句中，它指的是张说，在创新方面，当地开发商可能会“利用增强现实和虚拟现实设备和软件”以及“人工智能 (AI) 使同一款游戏可以在不同平台上玩——手机、桌面和游戏机——以获得更具沉浸感的游戏体验”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>crack down on - 打击，严厉打击。    <P>原文例句：Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由crack（打破）和down（向下）组成的，意思是“打击，严厉打击”。在这个例句中，它指的是北京打击视频游戏行业以防止未成年人沉迷游戏。</p></li>    <li>be at odds with - 与……不一致，与……发生冲突。    <P>原文例句：Meanwhile, the companies need to maintain an uneasy balance between maximising revenue for shareholders and protecting minors from gaming addiction.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由be（是），at（在），和odds（与……不一致，与……发生冲突）组成的，意思是“与……不一致，与……发生冲突”。在这个例句中，它指的是与此同时，各公司必须在为股东实现最大收益和保护未成年人不沉迷于游戏之间保持一种不稳定的平衡。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The total number of video game players in China has been peaking. - 中国的视频游戏玩家总数一直在达到顶峰。<p>句子分析：这是一个现在完成时态的句子，主语是The total number of video game players in China，谓语是has been peaking，表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示中国视频游戏玩家总数一直处于高峰状态。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>形容词作表语 - 形容词作表语时，用来描述或修饰主语。    <p>原文例句：The rule change – if passed in its present form – is expected to hit titles that rely heavily on loot boxes for monetisation or incentives for user acquisition, and those that have a large number of high spenders.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，形容词heavily和large分别作表语，修饰名词loot boxes和spenders，表示战利品箱和高额消费者的数量很多。</p></li>  </ul><ul>    <li>反义疑问句 - 反义疑问句是用肯定或否定的形式对前面的陈述进行反问，以寻求对方的证实。    <p>原文例句：Chinese mobile game user spending in 2023 remained at a level similar to that of 2022, as the market saw an influx of new titles with more games obtaining licences from authorities, according to Nan Lu, director of Asia-Pacific marketing at research firm Sensor Tower. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，反义疑问句是didn’t it?，是对前面陈述Chinese mobile game user spending in 2023 remained at a level similar to that of 2022的肯定形式的反问，以寻求对方的证实。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Industry regulator ended the year with a draft rule change designed to curb excessive consumer spending on in-game items, sparking market rout</li>
<li>China-backed games continue to make headlines around the world, and many analysts see overseas opportunities for domestic video game firms</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/94beb22e-5bd3-49df-8e52-6405f925421a_939b4d96.jpg" /><figcaption>China-backed games continue to win awards and analysts see more overseas opportunities for domestic developers in 2024. Illustration: SCMP/Lau Ka-kuen</figcaption></figure><p>Although 2023 started with new hope, the year was not filled with fun for Chinese video gaming companies and players.</p><p>ByteDance, the deep-pocketed owner of TikTok that had aggressively acquired gaming operations, decided to throw in the towel and Blizzard Entertainment left the Chinese market after its 14-year-old partnership with NetEase ended.</p><p>Last but not least, the country’s video games regulator ended the year with a draft rule change designed to curb excessive consumer spending on items such as avatars and in-game weapons, wiping out around US$80 billion in market value from Chinese gaming stocks.</p><p>The total number of video game players in China has been peaking.</p><p>By the end of 2023 there were 668 million gamers in China, a tiny increase from the 666 million at the end of 2022. They jointly spent 303 billion yuan (US$42 billion) on games, or about US$63 per gamer last year – roughly a quarter of the amount spent by US gamers.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
<div>
</div>
</div><p>The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained <em>Honour of Kings</em>, released by Tencent Holdings in 2015.</p><p>Amid an increase in regulatory oversight in recent years, China’s video gaming market has, in some ways, become walled off like the country’s television market.</p><p>Censors scrutinise content and control licence approvals, and domestic gaming studios – including Tencent and NetEase – are increasingly expected to deliver Chinese “social values” with their titles. Meanwhile, the companies need to maintain an uneasy balance between maximising revenue for shareholders and protecting minors from gaming addiction.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/310b9ccf-967e-4db1-9a3a-f0047ea1bb08_cda5d6ab.jpg" title="Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Video gaming, once seen as a gold mine in China’s internet sector, was also hard hit by lay-offs and closures in the past year, according to industry insiders and executives.</p><p>“Every studio that I know is cutting costs, even industry leader Tencent,” said Mark Wu, who works for a gaming studio in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p><p>But does this herald another barren year for China’s video game market or is it just a much-needed bout of consolidation and recalibration for an industry that has been subject to wild swings of investment in recent years?</p><p>Earlier this month, the gaming unit of Tencent launched a “spring bamboo shoots” initiative to support low- and medium-budget projects, in a change from a previous focus on projects with heavy production costs, according to industry blog Youxiputao. Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246197/china-approves-105-video-games-christmas-miracle-does-not-revive-stocks-after-suggested-spending" title="">China’s Christmas gift to game developers: 105 approved titles, the most all year</a></h3><p>However, China-backed games continue to make headlines around the world.</p><p>In December The Game Awards (TGA) named <em>Baldur’s Gate 3, c</em>reated and published by Tencent-backed Belgian developer Larian Studios, as video game of the year. Another nominee for the award was <em>Alan Wake 2</em>, from Remedy Entertainment and published by Epic Games, both backed by Tencent.</p><p>Shanghai-based miHoYo – which cracked the global video games market with its hit title <em>Genshin Impact</em> in 2021 – saw its <em>Honkai: Star Rail</em> win TGA’s best mobile game and Apple’s iPhone game of the year in 2023.</p><p>Analysts expect Chinese studios to roll out more hits in 2024, although it remains to be seen whether the content will match up with Beijing’s desire for “excellent” video games that promote socialist values, highlight Chinese culture and demonstrate the country’s advanced technology.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Honkai: Star Rail has delivered another set of game awards for Shanghai-based studio miHoYo. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/37809897-88de-484d-a18e-024f1aadca30_a18f5966.jpg" title="Honkai: Star Rail has delivered another set of game awards for Shanghai-based studio miHoYo. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Honkai: Star Rail has delivered another set of game awards for Shanghai-based studio miHoYo. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>“In coming years, China’s gaming industry will be focused on producing premium titles and overseas expansion,” said Zhang Shule, an analyst with CBJ Think Tank. “Local developers are expected to step up R&amp;D efforts to make quality games, drawing on their experience and success in the domestic market.”</p><p>In another bright spot, it appears China is set to welcome the massively-popular <em>World of Warcraft</em> back, after developer Blizzard struck a new deal with old partner NetEase, according to a report by domestic media outlet 36Kr.</p><p>CBJ’s Zhang said that while there is still uncertainty about the “remarriage”, NetEase “does stand out in a crowd of options”. “Its experience from the last tie-up and operational edge will be a strong draw.”</p><p>Chinese mobile game user spending in 2023 remained at a level similar to that of 2022, as the market saw an influx of new titles with more games obtaining licences from authorities, according to Nan Lu, director of Asia-Pacific marketing at research firm Sensor Tower.</p><p>Similar spending levels have been recorded in overseas markets, such as the US, South Korea and Southeast Asia in the past year. Still, Sensor Tower has observed a gradual increase in global user spending since the Christmas and 2024 New Year holiday. “Overall, the overseas market continues to offer opportunities for Chinese developers in the coming years, especially those focused on hybrid casual genres,” added Lu.</p><p>According to data from the Game Publishing Committee of the China Audio-Video and Digital Publishing Association, the semi-official industry association, overseas revenue from China video game titles dropped 5.7 per cent in 2023 to US$16.3 billion.</p><p>Meanwhile, China’s video games industry is not an island and faces the same headwinds as the wider economy – namely weak domestic consumption amid an unsteady, post-pandemic recovery.</p><p>Matthew Chen, co-founder and chief operating officer of Chengdu-based Zencat Gaming in southwestern Sichuan province, said that players in China “are not spending that much money amid a slowing economy”.</p><p>UBS analyst Christine Peng said this week that heightened fears among consumers about salary cuts and job security have dragged down retail sales growth in the world’s second-largest economy. The Swiss bank expects China’s retail sales to climb 5.5 per cent in 2024, one percentage point lower than the estimated 6.5 per cent rise last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" title="">China to curb excess spending on video games in blow for world’s biggest market</a></h3><p>Wu, the Guangzhou-based video games worker, said that the end of strict pandemic controls in late 2022 led to some good signs in the first few months, but added “demand for gaming [subsequently] gave way to the need [to spend] on necessities”.</p><p>Meanwhile, the overall tone of policy towards the industry remains uncertain. As things stand, all online video games must go through rigorous screening to obtain licences before being released to the public and monetised, and all players are required to have real-name registration.</p><p>Earlier this week, Tencent announced its winter policy for players aged under 18 – they can only play its games online for a combined 16 hours between January 22 and February 24. The rule is designed to comply with Beijing’s 2021 move to impose a play time ceiling for minors.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings , released by Tencent Holdings in 2015. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1503" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/bc900708-65b5-4106-977a-84409ccb6f9e_f9f7aaf5.jpg" title="The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings , released by Tencent Holdings in 2015. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings , released by Tencent Holdings in 2015. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>But while Beijing has toned down its overall view of video games as “spiritual opium”, the industry was rocked at the end of last year when regulator the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) proposed in a draft rule that games must not offer rewards that entice people to spend excessively, such as for daily logins and funding top-ups.</p><p>The timing and severity of the proposed rule change dealt a fresh blow to already-fragile investor confidence in Chinese stocks. NetEase, the country’s No. 2 gaming operator, fell by nearly a quarter in a single trading day, with Tencent dropping over 12 per cent.</p><p>Zeng Xiaofeng, vice-president of industry research firm Niko Partners, expects the rule change – if passed in its present form – to hit titles that rely heavily on loot boxes for monetisation or incentives for user acquisition, and those that have a large number of high spenders.</p><p>Popular games like Tencent’s <em>Honour of Kings</em> and NetEase’s <em>Eggy Party</em> are less likely to be impacted, as both have relatively low average revenue per user, according to Niko Partners.</p><p>Around 26 per cent of China’s mobile game users are payers, while high spenders – which refers to players that spend 300 yuan (US$42) monthly – only account for 2.5 per cent of mobile gamers in China, according to Niko Partners.</p><p>However, in the wake of the market rout triggered by the NPPA’s action, Beijing attempted to limit the damage by stating its desire for “healthy” development of the industry.</p><p>Meanwhile, Feng Shixin, a key figure overseeing the industry, subsequently stepped down from his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, according to a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes" target="_self" title="">Post report</a> citing sources.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245240/bytedance-throws-towel-video-games-chinese-studio-mihoyo-claims-global-wins-honkai" title="">As ByteDance retreats in video games, miHoYo claims global wins with new title</a></h3><p>And Beijing approved 105 new video game licences in December, the most in 17 months. In 2023 the regulator issued 1,075 licences for domestic and foreign games, more than double the number in 2022. 98 imported titles also received the greenlight in 2023, up from 44 in 2022, and Niko Partners expects another increase this year.</p><p>CBJ’s Zhang says that in terms of innovation, local developers are likely to “leverage augmented and virtual reality equipment and software” as well as “artificial intelligence (AI) to make the same game playable across different platforms – mobile, desktop and consoles – for a more immersive gameplay experience”.</p><p>Meanwhile, many of the industry workers the Post interviewed have used generative AI, the technology popularised by OpenAI’s ChatGPT, to produce various gaming content, including text, images and video.</p><p>Zencat Gaming’s Chen said that the use of AI tools to modify pictures, generate video and dub animated characters can cut the costs of overall video game development by roughly 20 per cent.</p><p>This can be a double-edged sword though. As Wu, the Guangzhou-based industry worker pointed out, while the new technology can be a “great assistant” it may very well kill entry-level jobs.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech war: China chip imports fall in 2023 but semiconductors remain country’s largest item ahead of crude oil</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248269/tech-war-china-chip-imports-fall-2023-semiconductors-remain-countrys-largest-item-ahead-crude-oil</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Chinese semiconductor imports experienced a notable decline in 2023. Despite this, chips remained the country's top import, surpassing crude oil. The import drop reflects economic challenges and efforts to localize chip production. China's goal is to reduce reliance on imported chips, and it is making progress in producing legacy chips domestically. This localization strategy may have contributed to the decline in imported chips.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's semiconductor imports fell in 2023 due to economic headwinds and localization efforts.</li>    <li>Theme: China's chip imports fell in 2023 due to economic headwinds and localization efforts.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: China's efforts to reduce reliance on imported chips and boost local production.</li>    <li>Main information: China's chip imports declined in volume and value; localization efforts to reduce reliance on imported chips; US export controls impacting advanced chip purchases.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  中国半导体进口在2023年经历了显著下降。尽管如此，芯片仍是中国进口额最高的项目，超过了原油。进口下降反映了经济挑战和本地化芯片生产的努力。中国旨在减少对进口芯片的依赖，并在国内生产旧式芯片方面取得了进展。这种本地化策略可能导致进口芯片的减少。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国半导体进口在2023年下降，原因是经济的不利因素和本地化的努力。</li>    <li>主题：中国半导体进口在2023年下降，原因是经济的不利因素和本地化的努力。</li>    <li>观点：中国努力减少对进口芯片的依赖并促进本地生产。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国芯片进口在数量和价值上有所下降；减少对进口芯片依赖的本地化工作；美国出口管制影响了先进芯片的购买。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>integrated circuit (n.) - /ˌɪntɪˈɡreɪtɪd ˈsɜːkjuːt/ 集成电路。    <p>原文例句：China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023, although semiconductors remained the mainland’s largest import item ahead of crude oil, according to customs data released on Friday.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由integrate（整合）和circuit（电路）组成，表示“集成电路”。在这个例句中，它指的是集成电路，即由半导体器件组成的电子电路。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fabless (adj.) - /ˈfæblɪs/ 无晶圆厂的。    <p>原文例句：The US intensified its export controls on China in October 2022, which caused widespread disruption for global fabless and semiconductor tools companies in their China-related businesses.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由fabe（工厂）和less（缺乏）组成，表示“无晶圆厂的”。晶圆厂是生产半导体芯片的工厂，通常使用硅晶片作为材料制造芯片。这个例句描述了对中国出口管制的加强造成全球无晶圆厂和半导体工具公司的广泛中断。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>by volume - 按体积。    <P>原文例句：In 2023, China imported a total of 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion, down 10.8 per cent by volume and 15.4 per cent in value from 2022, official data showed. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由by（按）和volume（体积）组成，表示“按体积”。在这个例句中，它表示按照体积计算，中国在2023年进口的集成电路数量下降了10.8%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023, although semiconductors remained the mainland’s largest import item ahead of crude oil, according to customs data released on Friday. - 中国集成电路（IC）进口在2023年大幅下降，但半导体仍然是继原油之后中国大陆最大的进口商品，海关公布的数据显示。<p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023，表示中国的集成电路进口在2023年大幅下降。从句是although semiconductors remained the mainland’s largest import item ahead of crude oil，表示半导体仍然是继原油之后中国大陆最大的进口商品。according to customs data released on Friday是一个介词短语作状语，表示根据周五公布的海关数据。这个句子的意思是说，根据周五公布的海关数据，中国集成电路进口在2023年大幅下降，但半导体仍然是继原油之后中国大陆最大的进口商品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The massive expansion, which has caused alarm in the US and EU, will see China’s global share of mature process capacity reach 39 per cent by 2027, up from 31 per cent in 2023, with room for further growth if equipment procurement proceeds smoothly, the TrendForce note said.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：had + been + 过去分词。其中had根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示到2027年，中国成熟工艺产能的全球份额将从2023年的31%上升到39%，如果设备采购顺利进行，还有进一步增长的空间。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>一般现在时 - 表示现在正在发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：According to the customs data, China’s imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices, a proxy of garden-variety commodity chips, were also down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：主语+谓语（动词原形）。其中谓语如果是be动词，要用am/is/are。这种时态表示现在正在发生的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性。在这个例句中，它表示根据海关数据，去年中国二极管和类似半导体器件的进口量按数量计算也下降了23.8%。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In 2023, China imported a total of 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion</li>
<li>Under rigid US export measures, China is unable to directly purchase advanced chips such as Nvidia’s H100 and A100 GPUs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/7a87b40d-bebc-417b-9aa1-baaa805bde8c_3c46d64f.jpg" /><figcaption>China chip imports fall in 2023 on economic headwinds and localisation efforts. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023, although semiconductors remained the mainland’s largest import item ahead of crude oil, according to customs data released on Friday.</p><p>In 2023, China imported a total of 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion, down 10.8 per cent by volume and 15.4 per cent in value from 2022, official data showed. By comparison, the country spent US$337.5 billion importing crude oil last year, a fall of 7.7 per cent.</p><p>The weaker imports of ICs and semiconductor devices reflect economic headwinds in the world’s second-largest economy last year, in particular China’s weak smartphone and laptop sales. Meanwhile, the data was also affected by China’s efforts to boost local output to cut reliance on imported chips.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248095/nvidia-reveals-progress-chinas-self-driving-chip-market-setting-competition-domestic-players" title="">Nvidia reveals progress in China’s self-driving chip market as competition revs up</a></h3><p>Under rigid US export control measures, China is unable to directly buy advanced chips, such as the H100 and A100 graphics processing units designed by US-based Nvidia. However, the country is making solid progress in boosting local output of legacy chips, including those being used in cars and home appliances, to satisfy domestic demand.</p><p>According to the customs data, China’s imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices, a proxy of garden-variety commodity chips, were also down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year.</p><p>The US intensified its export controls on China in October 2022, which caused widespread disruption for global fabless and semiconductor tools companies in their China-related businesses. In October last year, the US further tightened the noose, cutting China’s access to workaround chips that Nvidia had tailor-made for mainland customers.</p><p>In a state-backed drive to build a more resilient domestic chip supply chain, China’s semiconductor players have upped their localisation efforts with closer cooperation between the biggest companies. These efforts may also have contributed to the decline of imported chips as China added mature capacity to enable production of the vast majority of chips locally.</p><p>China currently has 44 semiconductor wafer fabs in operation and a further 22 under construction, Taiwan-based IC research company TrendForce said in a recent note. By the end of 2024, the capacity for mature chip production – defined as 28-nanometre and older technologies – will be expanded at 32 Chinese fabs.</p><p>The massive expansion, which has caused alarm in the US and EU, will see China’s global share of mature process capacity reach 39 per cent by 2027, up from 31 per cent in 2023, with room for further growth if equipment procurement proceeds smoothly, the TrendForce note said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tencent’s e-commerce drive takes off in 2023 on the back of super app WeChat’s short video and live streaming function</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248254/tencents-e-commerce-drive-takes-2023-back-super-app-wechats-short-video-and-live-streaming-function</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  WeChat's short video and live streaming function, Channels, has experienced significant growth in its e-commerce business in 2023, with a 244% increase in orders compared to the previous year. This growth has contributed to Tencent's overall e-commerce GMV and advertising revenue, highlighting the success of WeChat's efforts to enter the live-streaming e-commerce market.  <ul>    <li>Channels has enabled WeChat to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023.</li>    <li>The number of orders made through Channels grew more than 244% year-over-year.</li>    <li>WeChat's advertising business also saw a 20% year-over-year growth in the third quarter.</li>    <li>Tencent has set a target of reaching 100 billion yuan in e-commerce GMV through Channels.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  微信的短视频和直播功能「频道」于2023年在其电子商务业务中取得显着增长，与去年相比，订单量增加了244%。这种增长提升了腾讯的整体电子商务GMV和广告收入，突出了微信进军直播电商市场的成功。  <ul>    <li>「频道」使微信在2023年记录了几乎三倍的商品交易总额（GMV）。</li>    <li>通过「频道」下的订单数量同比增长超过244%。</li>    <li>微信的广告业务在第三季度也同比增长了20%。</li>    <li>腾讯的目标是通过「频道」实现1000亿元的电子商务GMV。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>livestreaming (n.) - /ˈlaɪvˌstriːmɪŋ/ 实时流媒体。    <p>原文例句：WeChat’s short video and livestreaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023, according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是从live（直播的）和stream（流）组成的，意为“实时流媒体”。在这个例句中，它指的是微信的短视频和实时流媒体功能，该功能使该平台在2023年记录了几乎三倍的商品交易总额（GMV）。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>short video (n.) - /ˌʃɔːrt ˈvɪdi.əʊ/ 短视频。    <p>原文例句：WeChat’s short video and livestreaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023, according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是从short（短的）和video（视频）组成的，意为“短视频”。在这个例句中，它指的是微信的短视频和实时流媒体功能，该功能使该平台在2023年记录了几乎三倍的商品交易总额（GMV）。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take on - /teɪk ɔːn/ 承担；接手。    <p>原文例句：腾讯悄悄进军直播电商市场，与字节跳动的抖音和快手科技——中国两大最大的短视频平台——展开竞争。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿）和on（承担，接手）构成的，意为“承担，接手”。在这个例句中，它表示腾讯悄悄进军直播电商市场，与字节跳动的抖音和快手科技——中国两大最大的短视频平台——展开竞争。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>WeChat’s short video and livestreaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023, according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province. - 根据周四在该应用程序的年度Open Class Pro开发者大会上发布的信息，微信的短视频和直播功能使该平台在2023年记录了几乎三倍的商品交易总额（GMV）。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是WeChat’s short video and livestreaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV)，其中主语是WeChat’s short video and livestreaming function，谓语是enabled，宾语是the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV)。according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province是一个介词短语作状语，表示根据在周四在该应用程序的年度Open Class Pro开发者大会上发布的信息。这个句子的意思是说，根据周四在该应用程序的年度Open Class Pro开发者大会上发布的信息，微信的短视频和直播功能使该平台在2023年记录了几乎三倍的商品交易总额（GMV）。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设或不真实的情况。    <p>原文例句：They are great to have for when you have that stubborn screw that just won't turn.</p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种语气，用于表示假设的情况或不真实的情况。在英语中，虚拟语气通常通过在句子中使用虚拟语气动词来表示。虚拟语气动词有两种形式：现在式和过去式。现在式虚拟语气动词通常用在表示现在或将来时态的句子中，而过去式虚拟语气动词通常用在表示过去时态的句子中。在这个例句中，虚拟语气动词是have，它表示假设的情况或不真实的情况。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>祈使句 - 表示请求、命令或建议。    <p>原文例句：Visit our site today to learn more.</p>    <p>语法讲解：祈使句是一种句子，用于表示请求、命令或建议。在英语中，祈使句通常通过使用动词的基本形式来表示，动词的基本形式就是动词的原型。在祈使句中，主语通常被省略，但有时也可以使用you或let's来表示主语。在这个例句中，祈使句是Visit our site today to learn more，它表示请求或建议人们访问他们的网站以了解更多信息。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Online orders made through WeChat’s short video and live streaming function, Channels, grew more than 244 per cent in 2023 over the previous year</li>
<li>WeChat Channels has also become a major driver of Tencent’s advertising business, which grew 20 per cent year on year in the third quarter</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/424841e5-a3ac-4b8a-ae91-51168cfa301a_99a90435.jpg" /><figcaption>The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s internet industry, as Tencent Holdings quietly made inroads into the live-streaming e-commerce market. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>, China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> giant, saw its ubiquitous super <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">app</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> achieve significant growth in its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/live-streaming" target="_self" title="">live-streaming</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce business</a> last year, thanks to the popularity of its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a>-style short video function.</p><p>WeChat’s short video and live streaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023, according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/guangzhou-0" target="_self" title="">Guangzhou</a>, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p><p>While the platform’s exact GMV figures were not released, conference attendees were told that the number of orders made through WeChat’s video function – marketed as Channels – grew more than 244 per cent in 2023 over the previous year, according to a report by Chinese online media outlet Thepaper.cn.</p><p>A number of attendees at the conference, which was held as a closed-door event exclusive to industry partners, on Friday confirmed the reported growth rate. Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="2408" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/382a2415-7317-4bb1-8359-257715bbe26b_8190c8e6.jpg" title="Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>WeChat’s high GMV performance last year showed how prescient Tencent founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/abacus/who-what/who/article/3028219/pony-ma-tycoon-behind-chinas-social-media-and-gaming-giant" target="_self" title="">Pony Ma Huateng</a> was in December 2022, when he told an internal town hall meeting that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3204291/tencents-pony-ma-says-cost-cutting-will-continue-2023-and-pins-hope-short-video-major-growth-driver" target="_self" title="">short video was key to the company’s future</a>.</p><p>The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> industry, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244790/tencent-set-hit-e-commerce-sales-milestone-2023-closing-short-video-rivals-bytedance-kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Tencent quietly made inroads</a> into the live-streaming e-commerce market to take on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Kuaishou Technology</a> – the country’s two largest short video platforms.</p><p>Tencent was expected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244790/tencent-set-hit-e-commerce-sales-milestone-2023-closing-short-video-rivals-bytedance-kuaishou" target="_self" title="">hit 100 billion yuan (US$13.9 billion) in e-commerce GMV</a>, a measure of the total value of goods sold online, through WeChat Channels last year, according to a report last month by Chinese media outlet LatePost.</p><p>While the e-commerce turnover on WeChat Channels is small compared with those of Kuaishou and TikTok’s Chinese sibling Douyin, Tencent has bet on swiftly building its online retail business on the back of the country’s vast number of WeChat users, estimated at 1.34 billion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/648b1380-6ea8-4522-b681-e27f1eb67183_1126e908.jpg" title="WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Tencent also plans to expand its live-streaming e-commerce-related headcount and broaden its product categories, as the WeChat Pay team builds the vital transaction infrastructure to facilitate online payments, according to the LatePost report.</p><p>WeChat Channels has already become a major driver of Tencent’s advertising business, which increased 20 per cent year on year in the third quarter, the fastest growth achieved by all of the company’s business segments in that period. During the second quarter, WeChat Channels raked in 3 billion yuan (US$421 million) in advertising revenue.</p><p>Launched in 2020, Channels has been growing rapidly and had about 813 million active users as of June 2022. That number was ahead of Douyin’s 680 million users and the 390 million on Kuaishou, according to estimates by Chinese data analytics firm QuestMobile.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tesla cuts prices in China on Model 3 and Model Y EVs to keep commanding lead in premium segment of fast-growing market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tesla cuts prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6% to maintain its leading position in China's premium EV market.</li>    <li>The move comes after Tesla reported 15.7% month-on-month sales growth in December.</li>    <li>Tesla's Chinese rivals have launched new intelligent electric cars, challenging Tesla's dominance.</li>    <li>Tesla's price cuts are seen as a strategic move to maintain market share in the highly competitive Chinese EV market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>特斯拉下调上海生产汽车价格，最高降幅达6%，以维持在中国高端电动汽车市场的领先地位。</li>    <li> 此举是在特斯拉报告12月份月度销售额增长15.7％之后做出的。</li>    <li>特斯拉的中国竞争对手推出了新的智能电动汽车，挑战特斯拉的统治地位。</li>    <li>特斯拉的降价被视为保持在中国竞争激烈的电动汽车市场份额的战略举措。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Premium (n.) - /ˈpriːmiəm/ 高价，优等品，报酬。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6% to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Premium在这里是指高价、优等品的意思。特斯拉将旗下上海生产的汽车价格下调了最高6%，以保持其在全球最大电动汽车市场中高端细分市场的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Segment (n.) - /ˈsɛɡmənt/ 阶段，部分，领域。      <p>原文例句：Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6% to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Segment在这里是指领域、细分市场的意思。特斯拉将旗下上海生产的汽车价格下调了最高6%，以保持其在全球最大电动汽车市场中高端细分市场的领先地位。</p>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>price cut - 降价。 <p>原文例句：Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6% to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market. </p>      <p>例句讲解：Price cut在这里是降价的意思。特斯拉将旗下上海生产的汽车价格下调了最高6%，以保持其在全球最大电动汽车市场中高端细分市场的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>market share - 市场份额。      <p>原文例句：Tesla apparently hopes to maintain its market share in the highly competitive market.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Market share在这里是市场份额的意思。特斯拉希望保持其在竞争激烈的市场中的市场份额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>  <li>Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6% to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market. - 特斯拉将旗下上海生产的汽车价格下调了最高6%，以保持其在全球最大电动汽车市场中高端细分市场的领先地位。</li>  <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Tesla has cut，其中主语是Tesla，谓语是has cut，宾语是the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles。to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market是一个不定式短语作目的状语，表示特斯拉降价的目的是为了保持其在全球最大电动汽车市场中高端细分市场的领先地位。整个句子的意思是：特斯拉将旗下上海生产的汽车价格下调了最高6%，以保持其在全球最大电动汽车市场中高端细分市场的领先地位。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Tesla’s Chinese rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是英语中的一种时态，用于表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。其结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。在这个例句中，have been launched表示特斯拉的中国竞争对手已经推出了许多新的智能电动汽车，一直持续到现在。这个时态的使用表明，特斯拉的中国竞争对手一直在努力挑战特斯拉的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Carmaker cut prices by up to 6 per cent after reporting 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December</li>
<li>‘Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder,’ analyst says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/7e2c041a-9f88-4d42-864b-ea64912c8bf0_9e3fcf96.jpg" /><figcaption>People look at a Tesla Model 3 at a showroom in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p><a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest <a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> market.</p><p>The Texas-based company announced on Friday that the price of the entry-level edition of its Model 3 will be reduced from 261,400 yuan (US$36,814) to 245,900 yuan, while the starting price of the Model Y is now 258,900 yuan, down from 266,400 yuan.</p><p>The price cuts come after Tesla reported 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December, according to data released by the China Passenger Car Association.</p><p>“Tesla apparently hopes to maintain its market share in the highly competitive market,” said Phate Zhang, founder of Shanghai-based EV data provider CnEVPost. “Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua" class="image-inline caption" height="1618" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/eb3603e2-9af8-4fa3-8ecc-aae102cfa6f6_a8c0939e.jpg" title="Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua" width="2000" /><figcaption>Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure></div><p>Tesla also lowered the price of the dual-motor version of the Model 3 by 3.9 per cent to 285,900 yuan and offered a 2.1 per cent discount on the dual-motor Model Y, which now sells for 299,900 yuan.</p><p>The front-runner in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3241811/chinas-premium-ev-segment-set-cutthroat-competition-huawei-baidu-and-xiaomi-join-fray" target="_self" title="">China’s premium electric vehicle (EV) segment</a> delivered 603,664 EVs made in its Shanghai Gigafactory to buyers in China last year, up 37.3 per cent from 2022. The growth was nearly unchanged from the 37 per cent sales rise recorded in 2022 when it delivered about 440,000 vehicles.</p><p>The company’s domestic rivals are not exactly nipping at its heels. Its closest competitor in the premium segment, <a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a>, delivered about 376,000 cars in 2023.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Tesla adjusts the prices of its locally built vehicles regularly based on production costs, Grace Tao, Tesla’s head of communications and government affairs in China, said on the microblogging site Weibo last January. Since January 2020, Tesla China cut prices on its Chinese-made models six times. This is the first reduction since August 2023; Tesla slightly raised prices between October and November when growth of deliveries in China slowed.</p><p>The Gigafactory, Tesla’s largest production hub worldwide, has an annual capacity of about 1 million units.</p><p>Aside from deliveries to mainland customers, the Shanghai factory also shipped 344,078 vehicles to markets like Japan and Germany in 2023, up 26.9 per cent year on year, according to data compiled by the CnEVPost.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" title="">Chinese EV maker shows off flying car but admits urban use is far off</a></h3><p>Sales of electric cars in China jumped 37 per cent last year, with deliveries of pure EVs and plug-in hybrids hitting 8.9 million units. At present, mainland China accounts for about 60 per cent of global EV sales.</p><p>But sales growth of battery-powered vehicles in mainland China is expected to slow to 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November.</p><p>Intensifying competition is piling pressure on the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3237078/chinas-ev-war-only-strongest-will-survive-byd-xpengs-dominance-knock-out-15-pretenders-amid-supply" target="_self" title="">200-plus Chinese EV makers</a> this year, with some leading players spearheading price cuts to lure customers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247906/vw-and-gm-lose-ground-chinese-ev-makers-petrol-heavy-line-ups-fall-out-favour-worlds-largest-car" title="">VW and GM lose ground to Chinese EV makers as petrol-heavy line-ups lose favour</a></h3><p>A new round of price cuts is in effect, with BYD, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest EV maker</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> offering discounts to bolster sales.</p><p>Early last month, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a> cut the price of its Han luxury car by as much as 20,000 yuan to meet its annual sales target. Xpeng followed by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3245621/china-evs-xpeng-cuts-price-bestselling-g6-suv-maintain-high-sales-volume-amid-intensifying" target="_self" title="">cutting the price of its bestselling G6 SUV</a> by 10,000 yuan, or about 5 per cent.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US$3 billion top Asia fund bets on Tencent again despite China gaming rules, favours Samsung over TSMC in chip market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248169/us3-billion-top-asia-fund-bets-tencent-again-despite-china-gaming-rules-favours-samsung-over-tsmc</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  The Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which has outperformed its peers, recently added Tencent Holdings back to its portfolio, despite China's new guidelines on excessive spending on online gaming. The fund manager believes the gaming company's valuation is attractive, trading at less than 16 times forward earnings. The fund also prefers Samsung Electronics over TSMC in the Asia semiconductor space due to Samsung's stronger earnings outlook and position in the memory chip sector.  <ul>    <li>Tencent Holdings was added to the portfolio of the Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund due to its attractive valuation.</li>    <li>The fund manager believes the valuation of Tencent shares is incredibly low, at less than 16 times forward earnings.</li>    <li>Samsung Electronics is preferred over TSMC in the Asia semiconductor space due to its stronger earnings outlook and position in the memory chip sector.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund 是一只表现优于同行的大部分基金，最近将其投资组合中增加了腾讯控股，原因是该游戏公司的估值具有吸引力，其远期市盈率低于 16 倍。该基金还更青睐三星电子，而不是亚洲半导体领域的台积电，因三星电子的盈利前景更加强劲，并在存储芯片领域处于有利地位。  <ul>    <li>投资组合中增加了腾讯控股，因为其估值具有吸引力。</li>    <li>基金经理认为腾讯股票的估值非常低，远期市盈率低于 16 倍。</li>    <li>在亚洲半导体领域中，三星电子更受青睐，因为它具有更强的盈利前景，并在存储芯片领域处于有利地位。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>curb (v.) - 抑制，限制。    <p>原文例句：China released draft guidelines on December 22, 2023, aimed at curbing excessive spending on online gaming. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语curbe，意思是“限制，抑制”。在这个例句中，它被用作动词，表示中国于2023年12月22日发布的旨在抑制过度花费在网络游戏上的指导草案。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>portfolio (n.) - 投资组合。    <p>原文例句：The Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词起源于意大利语portafoglio，意思是“携带文件夹”。在这个例句中，它被用作名词，表示Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund，这只基金在过去三年中表现优于其83%的同行，即使在中国于12月发布了关于游戏限制的指导草案后，这只基金在新年期间也进行了购买。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>valuation (n.) - 估值。    <p>原文例句：Tencent yielded its position as Asia’s second-most valuable company after China’s new rules on online gaming erased US$53 billion off its market value in 2023, capping a third year of losses. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是value的派生词，意思是“估值，价值”。在这个例句中，它被用作名词，表示腾讯在亚洲第二大最有价值公司的排名，在中国2023年新的网络游戏规则下，由于市值损失530亿美元，导致连续三年亏损，因此退出了该排名。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>outperform sb. - 表现优于某人。    <p>原文例句：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which outperformed most of its peers has added Tencent Holdings back to its portfolio recently, betting on the gaming company’s attractive valuation despite further industry curbs by the Chinese government. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由outperform（表现优于）和sb.（某人）组成，表示某人或某事在绩效或表现上优于另一个人或另一件事。在这个例句中，它被用来描述Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund，该基金的表现优于其大部分同行，即使中国政府进一步限制该行业，它也因游戏公司的估值具有吸引力而将其重新纳入投资组合。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>make a purchase - 进行购买。    <p>原文例句：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由make（制作，制造）和purchase（购买）组成，表示进行购买或采购。在这个例句中，它被用来描述Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund，这只基金在过去三年中表现优于其83%的同行，即使在中国于12月发布了关于游戏限制的指导草案后，这只基金在新年期间也进行了购买。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now.台积电即将面临周期性衰退，其股票交易价格接近账面价值的五倍，而三星的收益有望复苏，派恩斯表示，并补充称，这家韩国公司在存储芯片领域的领先地位使其目前更具吸引力。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn，其中主语是TSMC，谓语是is due for，宾语是a cyclical downturn。while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示三星收益即将复苏。Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示派恩斯说，并补充称，这家韩国公司在存储芯片领域的领先地位使其目前更具吸引力。这个句子的意思是说，台积电即将面临周期性衰退，其股票交易价格接近账面价值的五倍，而三星的收益有望复苏，派恩斯表示，并补充称，这家韩国公司在存储芯片领域的领先地位使其目前更具吸引力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式 - 表示动词的非限定形式，可以用作名词、形容词或副词。    <p>原文例句：The Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，不定式短语to outperform sb.（表现优于某人）用作形容词修饰fund，表示这只基金在过去三年中表现优于其83%的同行。不定式短语to make a purchase（进行购买）用作名词，表示该基金在新年期间进行的购买。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Investment reflects fund’s optimism over beaten-down market, where valuations are ‘absolutely incredible’, says fund manager</li>
<li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund also prefers Samsung Electronics over TSMC in the semiconductor market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/b3633bc7-a417-4b09-b1bb-2156486982fa_cf3478d7.jpg" /><figcaption>A man plays an online game from Tencent on a train. China released draft guidelines on December 22, 2023, aimed at curbing excessive spending on online gaming. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>A fund that outperformed most of its peers has added Tencent Holdings back to its portfolio recently, betting on the gaming company’s attractive valuation despite further industry curbs by the Chinese government.</p><p>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246161/chinas-video-gaming-watchdog-speaks-out-after-draft-spending-rules-roil-market" target="_self" title="">draft rule on gaming restrictions in December</a>. The investment reflects the fund’s optimism over the nation’s beaten-down market, where valuations are “absolutely incredible”, said Jonathan Pines, who manages the US$3.1 billion fund.</p><p>“We are buying it now because of its very cheap value,” he said in an interview Wednesday, referring to Tencent’s shares. Pines’ fund sold most of its shares in Tencent as well as in Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) about a year ago.</p><p>Tencent yielded its position as Asia’s second-most valuable company after China’s new rules on online gaming erased US$53 billion off its market value in 2023, capping a third year of losses. The shares trade at less than 16 times forward earnings, or about half the 10-year average, making them attractive, Pines said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations" title="">ByteDance confirms talks with Tencent, other buyers for video game operations</a></h3><p>While China currently is not the preferred investment destination for many, a combination of ultra-cheap valuations and low allocations outweighs the risks of investing in the nation’s stocks, according to Pines.</p><p>“We think the risks of investing in China are worth taking because the stocks are so cheap,” he said.</p><p>The fund, which is also overweight on South Korea, prefers Samsung Electronics to TSMC in the Asia semiconductor space.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" title="">China to curb excess spending on video games in blow for world’s biggest market</a></h3><p>TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now.</p><p>While Korea’s largest company this week reported a steeper-than-expected 35 per cent drop in operating income, reflecting weak demand for consumer electronics globally, Pines said the results would not prevent him from being positive on its earnings trajectory. “Things are going to improve from here,” he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
