<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Chinese EV maker Geely introduces first pure electric Galaxy model, to woo mainstream buyers from BYD, foreign brands</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247567/chinese-ev-maker-geely-introduces-first-pure-electric-galaxy-model-woo-mainstream-buyers-byd-foreign</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Geely Automobile Group launched the Galaxy E8, a pure electric sedan, to compete with BYD's Han model in the growing electric vehicle (EV) market in China. The E8, priced at 175,800 yuan (US$24,752), is more affordable than BYD's Han EV, which starts at 209,800 yuan. Geely plans to offer seven models under the Galaxy brand by 2025, targeting budget-conscious consumers. The E8 features a 45-inch screen, a Qualcomm Snapdragon 8295 chip, and voice-activated controls. Geely aims to capture a share of the Chinese EV market, which is the largest in the world but is dominated by a few profitable players like BYD and Li Auto.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Geely launches Galaxy E8 sedan to challenge BYD in China's EV market.</li>    <li>Theme: Competition intensifies in China's EV market as Geely unveils a new sedan with attractive features and pricing.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Geely's strategy to target budget-conscious consumers and its focus on intelligent features in the E8.</li>    <li>Main information: Launch of the Galaxy E8, comparison with BYD's Han model, pricing and features, plans for future models.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  吉利汽车集团推出了一款纯电动轿车Galaxy E8，以在激烈的中国电动汽车市场与比亚迪的汉车型竞争。E8的售价为175,800元（24,752美元），低于比亚迪汉EV的起售价209,800元。到2025年，吉利计划在Galaxy品牌下提供七款车型，目标是注重性价比的消费者。E8配备45英寸屏幕、高通骁龙8295芯片和语音控制功能。吉利的目标是在全球规模最大但仅有比雅迪和理想汽车等少数盈利车企主导的中国电动汽车市场中占领一席之地。  <ul>    <li>摘要：吉利推出Galaxy E8轿车，挑战比亚迪在中国电动汽车市场的地位。</li>    <li>主题：随着吉利推出搭载了极具吸引力的功能且定价合理的全新轿车，中国电动汽车市场的竞争日益激烈。</li>    <li>观点：吉利专注于以极具性价比的产品目标价格敏感的消费者，以及专注于E8的智能化功能。</li>    <li>主要信息：Galaxy E8的推出、与比亚迪汉车型的比较、定价和功能、未来车型的规划。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>mass-market (adj.) - 面向大众市场的。    <p>原文例句：Geely Automobile Group has launched a pure electric sedan under its mass-market brand Galaxy to take on BYD’s bestselling models amid intensified competition.</p>    <p>例句讲解：mass-market是指适合或针对普通消费者的大众市场。在这个例句中，mass-market brand是指面向大众市场的品牌，即Galaxy品牌。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>budget-sensitive (adj.) - 对预算敏感的，注重性价比的。    <p>原文例句：Hangzhou-based Geely will begin delivering the Class B sedan in February, hoping to target budget-sensitive mainland motorists, according to the company’s CEO Gan Jiayue.</p>    <p>例句讲解：budget-sensitive是指对预算敏感的，注重性价比的。在这个例句中，budget-sensitive mainland motorists是指对预算敏感的大陆车主，即那些注重性价比的消费者。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take on - 挑战，竞争。    <p>原文例句：Geely Automobile Group has launched a pure electric sedan under its mass-market brand Galaxy to take on BYD’s bestselling models amid intensified competition.</p>    <p>例句讲解：take on是指挑战，竞争。在这个例句中，take on BYD’s bestselling models是指挑战比亚迪最畅销的车型，即与比亚迪的畅销车型竞争。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>"In terms of safety, design, performance and intelligence, E8 proves to be superior to all blockbuster models,” he said during a media briefing after a launch ceremony on Friday.</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是E8 proves to be superior to all blockbuster models。其中主语是E8，谓语是proves to be superior to all blockbuster models。In terms of safety, design, performance and intelligence是一个介词短语作状语，表示在安全、设计、性能和智能方面。during a media briefing after a launch ceremony on Friday是一个介词短语作时间状语，表示在周五发布会后的媒体简报会上。这个句子的意思是说，在安全、设计、性能和智能方面，E8被证明优于所有大片车型，这是他在周五发布会后的媒体简报会上说的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示现在正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Geely is also developing other models under the Galaxy brand.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在进行时的句子，结构是：be + 现在分词（-ing形式）。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态现在正在进行，强调动作或状态的进行性。在这个例句中，is developing是现在进行时，表示吉利正在开发其他Galaxy品牌车型，强调开发动作正在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Galaxy E8 sells for almost about US$25,000, nearly US$5,000 less than BYD’s Han model</li>
<li>Geely plans to offer seven models under the affordable Galaxy brand by 2025, while its Zeekr brand targets more affluent buyers</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/07/fe08d875-eae8-4f43-a06b-0f78505b4ace_faa77576.jpg" /><figcaption>Geely Automobile Group’s Galaxy E8 sells for 175,800 yuan (US$24,752). Photo: Geely</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/geely" target="_self" title="">Geely Automobile Group</a>, one of China’s largest private carmakers, has launched a pure electric sedan under its mass-market brand Galaxy to take on BYD’s bestselling models amid intensified competition.</p><p>The basic edition of the E8, with a driving range of 550 kilometres, sells for 175,800 yuan (US$24,752), 34,000 yuan lower than the Han <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> built by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a>, which has a range of 506km.</p><p>Hangzhou-based Geely will begin delivering the Class B sedan in February, hoping to target budget-sensitive mainland motorists, according to the company’s CEO Gan Jiayue.</p><p>“In terms of safety, design, performance and intelligence, E8 proves to be superior to all blockbuster models,” he said during a media briefing after a launch ceremony on Friday. “We expect it to be an ideal model to replace both existing petrol and electric cars.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The E8 features a 45-inch screen supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology. Photo: Geely" class="image-inline caption" height="1275" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/07/d39c782a-7ceb-4ed9-8296-284ba2472139_c5eb9682.jpg" title="The E8 features a 45-inch screen supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology. Photo: Geely" width="2000" /><figcaption>The E8 features a 45-inch screen supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology. Photo: Geely</figcaption></figure></div><p>Geely lowered the price of the model by 12,200 yuan from its 188,000 yuan pricing on December 16 when presales started.</p><p>Based on the company’s Sustainable Experience Architecture (SEA), the E8 is also its first full-electric car, following two plug-in hybrid vehicles – the L7 sport-utility vehicle and the L6 sedan – launched in 2023.</p><p>The company plans to manufacture and sell a total of seven models under the Galaxy brand by 2025. The cars will be more affordable for mainland consumers than the company’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3239497/search-engine-baidu-and-carmaker-geelys-venture-starts-delivery-self-driving-ev-compete-teslas-model" target="_self" title="">Zeekr-branded EVs</a>, which compete against premium models built by companies like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a>, Gan said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247229/short-sellers-target-byd-worlds-top-ev-maker-rivalry-intensifies" title="">Short sellers target BYD, world’s top EV maker, as rivalry intensifies</a></h3><p>Its parent, Zhejiang Geely Holding Group, also owns marquees including Volvo, Lotus and Lynk. Geely Holding has a nearly 6 per cent share of mainland China’s EV market.</p><p>The E8 uses a Qualcomm Snapdragon 8295 chip to support its intelligent features such as voice-activated controls. A 45-inch screen, the biggest in a Chinese-made smart vehicle, is supplied by display panel ­manufacturer BOE Technology.</p><p>At present, the Class B sedan category in China is dominated by petrol-powered models from foreign carmakers such as Volkswagen and Toyota.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>BYD, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest EV maker</a>, backed by Warren Buffett’s Berkshire Hathaway, delivered a total of 228,383 <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3217091/china-ev-war-how-byd-grew-elon-musks-ridicule-berkshire-hathaways-ridiculous-us98-billion-success-12" target="_self" title="">Han sedans</a> to Chinese customers in 2023, up 59 per cent on year.</p><p>Sales of battery-powered vehicles in mainland China are seen as growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from a 37 per cent rise last year, according to the China Passenger Car Association.</p><p>China is the world’s largest automotive and EV market, with sales of electric cars accounting for about 60 per cent of the global total. But only a few makers, including BYD and Li Auto, are profitable.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>A new round of price cuts is in effect, with top players like BYD and Xpeng offering discounts to lure buyers.</p><p>In November, Geely’s parent company formed a partnership with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246154/chinas-nio-unveils-et9-executive-sedan-its-most-expensive-ev-yet-flexes-tech-muscle-luxury-sector" target="_self" title="">Shanghai-based Nio</a>, a premium EV maker, to promote battery swapping technology as the two companies try to overcome the problem of inadequate charging infrastructure.</p><p>Battery-swapping technology allows owners of electric cars to quickly exchange a spent battery pack for a fully charged one.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei teardown shows 5-nm laptop chip made in Taiwan, not China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247568/huawei-teardown-shows-5-nm-laptop-chip-made-taiwan-not-china</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>After Dismantling the device, TechInsights discovered that the Qingyun L540 notebook contains a 5-nm chip made by the Taiwanese company TSMC, which was manufactured in 2020.</li>    <li>The revelation quashed talking of another Chinese technological breakthrough and suggested that Huawei did not develop new processors since its access to TSMC chips was cut off in 2020.</li>    <li>Huawei relies on chips manufactured by TSMC and has beenstockpiling the components since the US imposed sanctions on the company in 2020.</li>    <li>The latest development comes amid a growing call from Beijing to replace foreign technology in sensitive environments, including government offices, with domestic alternatives.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>拆解后发现青云L540笔记本搭载的是2020年由台积电制造的5nm芯片。</li>    <li>这一发现令关于中国再次取得技术突破的传言不攻自破，并表明华为自2020年无法获得台积电芯片后便没有研发出新处理器。</li>    <li>华为使用的芯片仍然依赖于台积电的制造，而这家中国公司自美国于2020年对其实施制裁以来便开始囤积这些组件。</li>    <li>最新进展与北京方面日益高涨的呼声不谋而合，即用国产替代品取代包括政府办公机构在内的敏感环境中的外国技术。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>teardown (n.) - 拆卸，分解。    <p>原文例句：The Qingyun L540 notebook contains a 5-nm chip made by TSMC in 2020, around the time US sanctions cut off Huawei’s access to the chip maker, research firm TechInsights found after dismantling the device for Bloomberg News. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由tear（撕裂）和down（向下）构成的，表示“拆卸，分解”。在这个例句中，它指的是研究公司TechInsights拆卸青云L540笔记本电脑，发现其搭载的是由台积电制造的5nm芯片。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>counter (v.) - 反驳，抵消。    <p>原文例句：That counters speculation that Huawei’s mainland Chinese chipmaking partner, Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC), may have achieved a major leap in fabrication technique. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，表示“反驳，抵消”。在这个例句中，它表示关于华为的中国大陆芯片制造合作伙伴中芯国际可能在制造技术方面取得重大突破的传言不攻自破。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>stockpiling (v.) - 储存，囤积。    <p>原文例句：While Huawei has been on Washington’s Entity List since 2019, it was only in 2020 that TSMC stopped taking orders from Huawei to comply with elevated US trade restrictions.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由stock（储存，库存）和pile（堆，积累）构成的，表示“储存，囤积”。在这个例句中，它指的是虽然华为自2019年以来就被列入美国实体清单，但台积电直到2020年才停止接受华为的订单，以遵守更加严格的美国贸易限制。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>coincides (v.) - 同时发生。    <p>原文例句：Its emergence coincides with a growing call from Beijing to replace foreign technology in sensitive environments, from mandates to stop using iPhones in the workplace to replacing Dell and HP computers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，表示“同时发生”。在这个例句中，它指的是随着北京方面日益高涨的呼声，要求用国产替代品取代包括政府办公机构在内的敏感环境中的外国技术，该款笔记本的发布应运而生。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>cut off - 断绝，切断。    <p>原文例句：US sanctions cut off Huawei’s access to the chip maker</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“断绝，切断”。在这个例句中，它表示美国制裁切断了华为与芯片制造商的联系。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>develop ambition - 野心勃勃。    <p>原文例句：Its emergence coincides with a growing call from Beijing to replace foreign technology in sensitive environments, from mandates to stop using iPhones in the workplace to replacing Dell and HP computers.Some online retailers touted that the new laptop was designed specifically to comply with recent, stringent requirements in China on data security across sensitive government organs.Huawei’s official site highlights the device’s security features, but did not go into that detail.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“野心勃勃”。在这个例句中，它表示一些网络零售商宣称这款新笔记本专为符合中国最近对敏感政府机构数据安全提出的严格要求而设计。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei Technologies’ newest laptop runs on a chip made by Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), a teardown of the device showed, quashing talk of another Chinese technological breakthrough. - 华为最新款笔记本电脑搭载台积电制造的芯片，拆机结果显示，有关中国再次取得技术突破的传言不攻自破。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Huawei Technologies’ newest laptop runs on a chip made by Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC)，其中主语是Huawei Technologies’ newest laptop，谓语是runs，宾语是on a chip made by Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC)。a teardown of the device showed是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示拆机结果显示。quashing talk of another Chinese technological breakthrough是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示有关中国再次取得技术突破的传言不攻自破。这个句子的意思是说，华为最新款笔记本电脑搭载台积电制造的芯片，拆机结果显示，有关中国再次取得技术突破的传言不攻自破。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去式 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：While Huawei has been on Washington’s Entity List since 2019, it was only in 2020 that TSMC stopped taking orders from Huawei to comply with elevated US trade restrictions.</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去式是动词的一种时态，用于表示过去发生的动作或状态。英语中过去式的构成方法有很多种，包括在动词原形后面加-ed、-d或不规则变化。在这个例句中，stopped和taking都是过去式动词，分别表示停止和接受。</p></li>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或直到现在为止的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Huawei has since sunk billions into chip research and stockpiling in past years, while also building a domestic network of suppliers and manufacturing partners, in some cases with government backing.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是动词的一种时态，用于表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或直到现在为止的动作或状态。英语中现在完成时的构成方法是：have/has + been + 现在分词。在这个例句中，sunk、building和backing都是现在完成时态动词，分别表示投入、建立和支持。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Qingyun L540 notebook contains a 5-nm chip made by TSMC in 2020, around the time US sanctions cut off Huawei’s access to the chip maker</li>
<li>Huawei caused a stir in the US and China last August when it released a smartphone with a 7-nm processor made by Shanghai-based SMIC</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/07/c9380a71-e793-48d8-862d-3a8e754b72f5_e6e9a731.jpg" /><figcaption>A Chinese flag flutters near a Huawei store in Shanghai,  September 8, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies’ newest laptop runs on a chip made by Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), a teardown of the device showed, quashing talk of another Chinese technological breakthrough.</p><p>The Qingyun L540 notebook contains a 5-nanometre chip made by the Taiwanese company in 2020, around the time US sanctions cut off Huawei’s access to the chip maker, research firm TechInsights found after dismantling the device for Bloomberg News. That counters speculation that Huawei’s mainland Chinese chipmaking partner, Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC), may have achieved a major leap in fabrication technique.</p><p>Huawei caused a stir in the US and China last August when it released a smartphone with a 7-nm processor made by Shanghai-based SMIC. A teardown by the Canada-based research outfit for Bloomberg News showed the Mate 60 Pro’s chip was only a few years behind the cutting edge, a feat that US trade curbs were meant to prevent. That revelation spurred celebration across the Chinese tech scene, and a debate in the US about the effectiveness of sanctions.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" title="">Huawei sees 9 per cent sales growth in 2023, boosted by Mate 60 Pro 5G comeback</a></h3><p>In the latest teardown, TechInsights discovered a Kirin 9006C processor fabricated via TSMC’s 5-nm method, which was assembled and packaged around the third quarter of 2020. Industry experts had previously speculated that SMIC achieved that milestone by developing workarounds to US sanctions, which would have marked a second technological triumph for the Chinese national champion in the span of months.</p><p>Representatives for Huawei and TSMC did not provide comment when reached by Bloomberg News.</p><p>The advances encapsulated in the Mate 60 smartphone in 2023 cemented Huawei’s role as the standard-bearer for Chinese efforts to wean itself off Western technologies and create domestic alternatives. Chinese consumers snapped up the smartphone in the final quarter, helping the company regain the symbolically important US$100 billion revenue threshold – eroding Apple’s iPhone dominance along the way.</p><p>A foray into 5-nm territory would have represented a big leap for the Shenzhen conglomerate, bringing it closer to the most-advanced processes currently in use, mostly centred around 3-nm nodes. Before TSMC cut off ties with Huawei, it was supplying chips as advanced as 5-nm to the Chinese firm.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246414/huawei-and-xiaomi-launch-new-ev-models-china-reigniting-worries-about-price-wars-worlds-largest-ev" title="">New EVs from Huawei, Xiaomi could renew price wars in China’s car market</a></h3><p>It is unclear how Huawei managed to procure a three-year-old processor, though the Chinese company has been stockpiling vital semiconductors since the US began cutting off its access to components and gear globally. While Huawei has been on Washington’s Entity List since 2019, it was only in 2020 that TSMC stopped taking orders from Huawei to comply with elevated US trade restrictions.</p><p>Huawei has since sunk billions into chip research and stockpiling in past years, while also building a domestic network of suppliers and manufacturing partners, in some cases with government backing.</p><p>The L540 is the latest in a line of laptops that Huawei began selling around 2016, when the then-networking leader developed ambitions to get into mobile and computing devices and round out its offerings.</p><p>Its emergence coincides with a growing call from Beijing to replace foreign technology in sensitive environments, from mandates to stop using iPhones in the workplace to replacing Dell and HP computers.</p><p>Some online retailers touted that the new laptop was designed specifically to comply with recent, stringent requirements in China on data security across sensitive government organs. Huawei’s official site highlights the device’s security features, but did not go into that detail.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>This year, prepare for the magic wand of generative AI to transform our world</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3247183/year-prepare-magic-wand-generative-ai-transform-our-world</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Generative AI has recently become popular, and various industries see it as a transformational tool.</li>    <li>It is moving towards multi-modal expression, able to handle different media forms simultaneously, resulting in more natural human-machine communication.</li>    <li>Multi-modal generative AI can enhance creativity, accelerate content creation, and automate tasks.</li>    <li>Personalized generative AI systems are being developed to offer tailored content and efficient task execution.</li>    <li>Generative AI is expected to play a role in 6G technology, enabling real-time interaction and communication between humans and the digital world.</li>    <li>It has the potential to become an invaluable assistant across industries, offering solutions, recommendations, and enhancing user experiences.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>生成式人工智能风靡一时，许多行业认为它具有变革潜能。</li>    <li>它正朝着多模态表达方向转变，可同时处理多种媒体形式，实现更为自然的“人机”交互。</li>    <li>多模态生成式人工智能可以增强创造力，加速内容创作和自动执行任务。</li>    <li>Personalized generative AI systems 正在开发中，将提供定制内容和高效的任务执行能力。</li>    <li>预计生成式人工智能将在6G技术中发挥作用，实现人与数字世界之间的实时交互和交流。</li>    <li>它有潜力成为各行各业的宝贵助手，为用户提供解决方案、建议，并改善用户体验。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>debut (n.) - /ˈdeɪbjuː/ 首次登台，处女作。    <p>原文例句：Since the debut of ChatGPT at the end of 2022, generative artificial intelligence (AI) has gained popularity globally. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于法语，意思是“开始，开端”。在这个例句中，它指的是ChatGPT在2022年末首次推出。</p></li>    <li>proliferate (v.) - /prəˈlɪfərˌeɪt/ 迅速增长，繁殖，蔓延。    <p>原文例句：In 2024, there is likely to be a proliferation of AI-generated art, music, videos and stories. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由pro-（向前）和ferre（带，拿）组成，意思是“快速增长，繁殖，蔓延”。在这个例句中，它表示2024年可能会出现大量人工智能生成的艺术、音乐、视频和故事。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>multi-modal expression - 多模态表达。    <p>原文例句：But with the emergence of models like GPT-4, generative AI is shifting towards multi-modal expression, enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由multi-（多）和modal（模式）构成，表示“多模态表达”。在这个例句中，它指的是随着GPT-4等模型的出现，生成式人工智能正向多模态表达转变，能够同时处理多种形式的数据。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>This suggests that human-machine communication will one day effortlessly incorporate mixed media, as ChatGPT is starting to do. - 这表明人类和机器的交流终有一天将轻松地包含混合媒体，正如ChatGPT开始做的那样。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是human-machine communication will one day effortlessly incorporate mixed media，其中主语是human-machine communication，谓语是will incorporate，宾语是mixed media。as ChatGPT is starting to do是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示人类和机器的交流终有一天将轻松地包含混合媒体的具体方式，即正如ChatGPT开始做的那样。这个句子的意思是说，这表明人类和机器的交流终有一天将轻松地包含混合媒体，正如ChatGPT开始做的那样。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人对某事的看法或态度。    <p>原文例句：It is also capable of meeting the demands of “connective intelligence” for new technologies. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气的句子，表示说话人对新技术对“连接情报”的需求的看法或态度。虚拟语气一般用在条件句、愿望句、目的句和让步句中，表示说话人的主观想法或愿望。在这个例句中，它表示新技术能够满足新技术对“连接情报”的需求。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Generative AI is becoming active, multimodal and being embedded in PCs and smartphones, penetrating our daily lives in profound ways</li>
<li>Governments must pay attention to ethical, privacy and copyright issues to ensure the positive development of the technology</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/993c33b7-d303-46f3-9fa7-b02b2516d087_73af80ad.jpg" /><figcaption>Customs inspector Hui Ka-hei explains how XiaoHui, a virtual ambassador introduced at Hong Kong’s airport and three control points, works to to handle public enquiries, on December 29. Photo: Dickson Lee</figcaption></figure><p>Since the debut of ChatGPT at the end of 2022, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243449/chatgpt-one-year-how-openais-chatbot-brought-generative-artificial-intelligence-public-consciousness" target="_self" title="">generative artificial intelligence</a> (AI) has gained popularity globally. Various industries are eagerly adopting generative AI for diverse applications including the creation of text, images, videos, computer codes and more.</p><p>The output of generative AI in these domains has proliferated, presenting a diverse array of creative work. According to Gartner, an information technology (IT) research and consulting company in the United States, use of generative AI will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245217/chinese-generative-ai-account-third-industrys-economic-value-2035-beijing-think-tank-says" target="_self" title="">increase substantially</a> by 2026. It projects that more than 80 per cent of businesses will have integrated generative AI application programming interfaces (APIs), models and/or applications into their operations by then, from less than 5 per cent now.</p><p>IT experts believe that generative AI will play a transformative role this year, akin to a magic wand that changes the world. In light of these developments, what major trends in generative AI can we expect this year?</p><p>Last year, most generative AI tools, algorithms and large language models were primarily focused on a single media type: text, images, speech or video, with limited emphasis on the simultaneous processing of multiple media. But with the emergence of models like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238197/baidu-says-ai-chatbot-ernie-now-matches-openais-gpt-4-unveils-new-enterprise-tools" target="_self" title="">GPT-4</a>, generative AI is shifting towards multi-modal expression, enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data.</p><p>This suggests that human-machine communication will one day effortlessly incorporate mixed media, as ChatGPT is starting to do. Users can input non-textual cues, such as images, making the conversation more convenient and natural.</p><p>Furthermore, multi-modal generative AI is poised to enhance the creative capabilities of artists and improve the efficiency of professionals in fields such as writing, journalism and music. When appropriately used, multi-modal generative AI can spark artistic inspiration, generate work drafts or even fully automate content creation.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>In 2024, there is likely to be a proliferation of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224924/ai-challenging-us-rethink-distinction-between-real-and-fake" target="_self" title="">AI-generated art</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3227291/ai-generated-hits-hong-kong-stars-surprise-fans-bring-dead-singers-back-life-and-raise-questions" target="_self" title="">music</a>, videos and stories. Experts believe that through generative AI’s artistic contributions, content will become more diverse, innovative and distinctive, ushering in a new era for creative industries.</p><p>Last year, generative AI operated primarily through user-driven prompts. Taking <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> as an example, interactions were conducted in a “question and answer” format and were purely passive. In response to this limitation, scientists are researching “auto agent” technology.</p><p>Auto agents can both generate and respond to prompts, performing tasks more rapidly and efficiently. A recent example is the AutoGPT system, which recently raised US$12 million in a funding round. The goal is to develop AutoGPT into a large-scale open-source AI platform, serving various industries.</p><p>Also set to thrive is the development of personalised generative AI systems. Computer companies are researching and developing AI personal computers capable of running generative AI applications locally, while chip companies have developed AI-embedded mobile processors, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236845/google-unveils-pixel-8-smartphones-pixel-watch-2-new-ai-features-mobile-processor" target="_self" title="">enabling smartphones</a> to execute generative AI models.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>A plethora of intelligent devices with diverse generative AI functionalities is emerging.</p><p>Generative AI applications that operate locally on personal computers and smartphones are built upon the concept of “federated learning”. This approach can afford consumers higher levels of privacy protection and security since these platforms do not need to send user data to the cloud for tasks such as searches or information organisation.</p><p>Meanwhile, by analysing user-specific data such as preferences, behaviours and conversations, this type of generative AI can optimise its performance based on individual characteristics and requirements, providing tailored content and task execution. This not only addresses concerns regarding privacy and security but also saves consumers time and effort.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3213160/how-ai-could-free-us-return-pursuit-wisdom" title="">Could AI free us to return to the pursuit of wisdom?</a></h3><p>Generative AI is also expected to play a significant role in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/6g" target="_self" title="">6G mobile technology</a>. This year, work to set and agree on 6G standards will continue with the anticipation that the first standards could be introduced between 2027 and 2028, and the technology could reach commercialisation by 2030. Generative AI can be applied to various aspects of 6G, such as network resource management, spectrum allocation and network topology optimisation.</p><p>It is also capable of meeting the demands of “connective intelligence” for new technologies. Connective intelligence is a key force driving the development of the 6G network, enabling real-time, reliable and ubiquitous interaction and communication between humans, the physical world and the digital world. This results in the creation of a decentralised and continually evolving intelligence, making it easier for users to share their discoveries and experiences with each other.</p><p>In summary, by the end of 2024, generative AI will become an invaluable assistant, providing support and help across different industries. Its powerful analysis and predictive capabilities will enable people to handle complex tasks and problems more efficiently, offering real-time solutions and recommendations.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3242417/fears-over-ai-dangers-are-hindering-chance-create-better-future" title="">How cooperation on AI governance can curb risks and create a better future</a></h3><p>Whether in fielding queries about professional knowledge or optimising and automating business processes, generative AI will play a crucial role. It will also become the ideal companion in consumption, leisure and entertainment.</p><p>Through personalised recommendation systems and intelligent assistant features, generative AI will gain a deep understanding of user preferences and needs, providing customised product and service suggestions. Whether in shopping, travel, music, film and television entertainment or social interaction, generative AI will enhance our experiences.</p><p>Generative AI has become an irreversible trend, penetrating our daily lives in profound ways. Governments must pay attention to ethical, privacy and copyright issues to ensure the positive development of the technology. Otherwise, there is a risk of unintended consequences, allowing malicious individuals to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246612/chatgpt-aided-ransomware-china-results-four-arrests-ai-raises-cybersecurity-concerns" target="_self" title="">exploit</a> generative AI’s capabilities.</p><p><strong>Wong Kam-fai is a legislative councillor, associate dean (external affairs) of the Faculty of Engineering at Chinese University and vice-president of the Hong Kong Professionals And Senior Executives Association</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
