<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Samsung to kick off year of AI phones with new launch this month</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247104/samsung-kick-year-ai-phones-new-launch-month</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Samsung is shifting its focus to artificial intelligence (AI) as a key strategy to boost sales in 2024. The company plans to launch its next flagship device, the Galaxy S24, on January 17, emphasizing advanced AI capabilities. This marks a departure from previous years, where improvements in camera technology and flexible displays were the primary selling points. Counterpoint Research estimates that over a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI will be shipped by the end of 2027. AI integration is seen as the next step in advancing smartphone technology, with companies like Samsung and Qualcomm leading the way. Samsung aims to capture a significant market share in the AI smartphone segment, similar to its success with foldable devices.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung's strategic shift towards AI-powered smartphones.</li>    <li>Theme: The growing significance of AI in the smartphone industry, with Samsung leading the charge.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: AI integration is the key to unlocking greater sales potential and driving innovation in the smartphone market.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's upcoming Galaxy S24 launch; Counterpoint Research's projections for AI smartphone shipments; AI training accelerators provided by Nvidia; Samsung's market share aspirations.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  三星正在将重点转向人工智能（AI）作为其在 2024 年提振销售的关键战略。该公司计划在 1 月 17 日发布其下一款旗舰设备 Galaxy S24，重点是先进的人工智能功能。这标志着与往年不同，往年主要卖点集中在摄像头技术和柔性显示屏的改进上。Counterpoint Research 估计，到 2027 年底，将出货超过 10 亿部内置生成式人工智能的智能手机。人工智能集成被视为智能手机技术进步的下一步，三星和高通等公司引领着这一趋势。三星的目标是在人工智能智能手机领域占据相当大的市场份额，就像其在可折叠设备方面取得的成功一样。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星战略性地转向人工智能驱动的智能手机。</li>    <li>主题：人工智能在智能手机行业日益重要，三星引领潮流。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能集成是释放更大销售潜力和推动智能手机市场创新的关键。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星即将推出的 Galaxy S24；Counterpoint Research 对人工智能智能手机出货量的预测；英伟达提供的人工智能训练加速器；三星的市场份额目标。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rely on - /rɪˈlaɪ ɑːn/ 依赖于，依靠。    <p>原文例句：In past years, Samsung and fellow mobile makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由rely（依靠）和on（在……上）构成，表示“依赖于，依靠”。在这个例句中，它表示三星和其他手机制造商在过去几年依靠相机技术和柔性显示屏的改进脱颖而出。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>flagship device - /ˈflæɡʃɪp dɪˈvaɪs/ 旗舰设备。    <p>原文例句：Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device on January 17 in San Jose, California.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由flagship（旗舰）和device（设备）构成，表示“旗舰设备”。在这个例句中，它表示三星电子宣布计划于 1 月 17 日在加利福尼亚州圣何塞推出其下一款旗舰设备。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>generative AI - /ˈdʒɛnərətɪv aɪ/ 生成式人工智能。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由generative（生成式的）和AI（人工智能）构成，表示“生成式人工智能”。在这个例句中，它表示根据 Counterpoint Research 的估计，到 2027 年底，预计将出货超过 10 亿部内置生成式人工智能的智能手机。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>added AI capabilities - /ˈædɪd aɪ ˈkeɪpəbɪlətɪz/ 添加的人工智能功能。    <p>原文例句：2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由added（添加的）和AI capabilities（人工智能功能）构成，表示“添加的人工智能功能”。在这个例句中，它表示 2024 年有望成为添加的人工智能功能占据中心舞台的一年。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>take center stage - /teɪk ˈsɛntər steɪdʒ/ 成为焦点，成为中心。    <p>原文例句：but 2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由take（采取）和center stage（中心舞台）构成，表示“成为焦点，成为中心”。在这个例句中，它表示但 2024 年有望成为添加的人工智能功能占据中心舞台的一年。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>capture market share - /ˈkæptʃər ˈmɑːrkɪt ʃɛər/ 占领市场份额。    <p>原文例句：“Similar to what it did with foldables, Samsung is likely to capture almost 50 per cent share for the next two years, followed by key Chinese OEMs like Xiaomi, Vivo, Honor and Oppo.”    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由capture（占领）和market share（市场份额）构成，表示“占领市场份额”。在这个例句中，它表示类似于其在可折叠智能手机方面的表现，三星预计将在未来两年内占领近 50% 的市场份额，随后是中国主要原始设备制造商，如小米、Vivo、荣耀和 Oppo。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The world’s most prolific smartphone maker is leaning into artificial intelligence as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.- 世界上最多产的智能手机制造商今年正依赖人工智能作为释放更大销量的关键。<p>句子分析：这是一个主动语态的现在进行时句子，主语是The world’s most prolific smartphone maker，谓语是is leaning into artificial intelligence，宾语是greater sales。as the key to unlocking是介词短语作状语，表示人工智能作为释放更大销量的关键。this year是时间状语，表示今年。这个句子的意思是说，世界上最多产的智能手机制造商今年正依赖人工智能作为释放更大销量的关键。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Huawei launches new Nova smartphones without giving details on chip.- 华为推出新的 Nova 智能手机，但未提供有关芯片的详细信息。<p>句子分析：这是一个主动语态的现在时句子，主语是Huawei，谓语是launches。new Nova smartphones是宾语，without giving details on chip是介词短语作状语，表示华为推出新的 Nova 智能手机，且未提供有关芯片的详细信息。这个句子的意思是说，华为推出新的 Nova 智能手机，但未提供有关芯片的详细信息。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Samsung has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示三星已经连续好几年在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、愿望、建议或可能性的语气。    <p>原文例句：“Similar to what  <ul><li>In past years, Samsung and fellow mobile makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out</li>
<li>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/7ec45056-5dac-41c9-9c8d-90ebe51417b8_a1a0985b.jpg" /><figcaption>Samsung employees show models of the Galaxy S23 Fan Edition during its rollout in Seoul, South Korea, December 8, 2023. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>The world’s most prolific smartphone maker is leaning into artificial intelligence as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.</p><p>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device on January 17 in San Jose, California – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – with a livestreamed event. The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming.” In past years, Samsung and fellow mobile makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out, but 2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246310/huawei-launches-new-nova-smartphones-without-giving-details-chip-attention-remains-fixed-its" title="">Huawei launches new Nova smartphones without giving details on chip</a></h3><p>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates. OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Dall-E tools, which generate text or visual responses to users’ queries, are at the forefront of a generative-AI wave that is swept across the tech industry – and helped make Nvidia a trillion-dollar company by providing the key AI-training accelerators. The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices, as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year.</p><p>“Samsung and Qualcomm are immediate leaders as current product offerings and capabilities position them as first movers,” the Counterpoint researchers wrote in December. “Similar to what it did with foldables, Samsung is likely to capture almost 50 per cent share for the next two years, followed by key Chinese OEMs like Xiaomi, Vivo, Honor and Oppo.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
