<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: Hong Kong start-ups attract interest from Microsoft, Best Buy amid overseas push</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248382/ces-2024-hong-kong-start-ups-attract-interest-microsoft-best-buy-amid-overseas-push</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>   <ul>    <li>At CES 2024, the Hong Kong pavilion attracted significant attention, with Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella showing interest in AI Guided's belt for guiding the blind.</li>    <li>Other Hong Kong start-ups also received interest from retailers like Best Buy, showcasing their innovative products.</li>    <li>Companies like Invisible Tech and XOXO Beverages highlighted their commitment to sustainability and the expansion of their markets beyond Hong Kong.</li>    <li>The focus of the Hong Kong pavilion was on selecting start-ups with market-ready products, aiming to facilitate business deals at CES.</li>    <li>The participation of start-ups like Sitan Semiconductor International and Raysolve Technology reflects the growing importance of micro-LED displays.</li>    <li>Hong Kong's efforts to establish itself as a tech hub received positive feedback from start-ups and industry experts.</li></ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2> <ul>    <li>在2024年的CES展会上，香港馆吸引了大量关注，微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉对AI Guided的盲人导航腰带表现出兴趣。</li>    <li>其他香港初创企业也收到了百思买等零售商的兴趣，展示了他们的创新产品。</li>    <li>Invisible Tech和XOXO Beverages等公司强调了他们对可持续发展的承诺，并计划将市场拓展到香港以外地区。</li>    <li>香港馆的重点是选择拥有市场就绪产品的初创企业，旨在促进CES的商业交易。</li>    <li>像Sitan Semiconductor International和Raysolve Technology这样的初创企业的参与反映了微型LED显示屏日益增长的重要性。</li>    <li>香港将自己打造成科技中心的努力得到了初创企业和行业专家的积极反馈。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2> <ul>    <li>navigate (v.) - /ˈnævɪɡeɪt/ 导航，驾驶，控制。    <p>原文例句：The dream of our company is that in three to five years … visually impaired people can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world.” - 我们公司的梦想是在三到五年内……视障人士能够拥有一些便捷的体验来探索世界。”    <p>例句讲解：这是由拉丁词根navig（船只）和-ate（使……）组成的动词，指“驾驶，操纵”。在这个例句中，它指“引导盲人在充满障碍的世界中，为其导航。”</p></li>  </ul> <ul>    <li>accessibility (n.) - /ˌæksɛsɪˈbɪləti/ 可访问性，无障碍性。    <p>原文例句：“Microsoft really supports accessibility technology,” said Steve Kong, co-founder and chief technology officer of AI Guided.     <p>例句讲解：是由access和-ibility组成的名词，意为“可访问性，无障碍性”。在这个例句中，它指“微软公司非常支持辅助技术。”</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2> <ul> <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：We had to make some selection of companies that have more of a mature level of readiness in terms of being ready to sell,     <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示“就（符合）准备销售的成熟程度而言”。</p></li></ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>   <ul>    <li>“The dream of our company is that in three to five years … visually impaired people can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world.” - 我们公司的梦想是在三到五年内……视障人士能够拥有一些便捷的体验来探索世界。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The dream of our company is…，其中主语是The dream of our company，谓语是is，宾语是some hands-free experience to navigate the world。that in three to five years … visually impaired people can…是一个宾语从句，表示我们的公司在三到五年内的梦想是……视障人士能够……，“in three to five years”，“visually impaired people”和“can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world”是三个并列成分。这个句子的意思是说，我们公司的梦想是在三到五年内，视障人士能够拥有一些便捷的体验来探索世界。</p></li></ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达虚拟、假设、意愿、可能性、建议等。    <p>原文例句：The dream of our company is that in three to five years … visually impaired people can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world.” - 我们公司的梦想是在三到五年内……视障人士能够拥有一些便捷的体验来探索世界。    <p>语法讲解：这是虚拟语气的使用，结构是：should/could/would/might等情态动词+动词原形。在这个例句中，它表示一种希望或愿望，即在未来三到五年内，视障人士能够拥有一些便捷的体验来探索世界。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>非谓语动词 - 在句中不起谓语作用的动词。    <p>原文例句：The company said its tech has already found its way into products from big brands like TCL, Huawei Technologies, Oppo and Meizu – although not all of these products have been released. - 该公司表示，他们的技术已经出现在TCL、华为、OPPO和魅族等大品牌的产品中，尽管并非所有这些产品都已发布。    <p>语法讲解：这是一个非谓语动词的用法，由现在完成分词found作定语，修饰products，表示这些产品已经使用了该公司的技术。这个句子的意思是说，该公司表示，他们的技术已经出现在TCL、华为、OPPO和魅族等大品牌的产品中，尽管并非所有这些产品都已发布。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella stopped by the booth of a start-up at the Hong Kong pavilion that makes an AI-powered belt to guide blind people</li>
<li>Other start-ups say they have received interest at the show from retailers and other potential partners as Hong Kong firms look overseas</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/c4aa2f7b-bda4-4f1d-8d18-95ebfe7901e8_6e29421c.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella meets with Steve Kong, co-founder and chief technology officer of AI Guided, at CES to learn more about the Hong Kong start-up’s belt for guiding the blind. Photo: Handout </figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft">Microsoft</a> and Best Buy expressed interest in Hong Kong <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups">start-ups</a> at CES 2024, after the city’s pavilion at the world’s largest consumer electronics show saw the most interest there in years.</p><p>Last Tuesday, the first day of the trade show in Las Vegas, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella swung by the Tech Hong Kong pavilion to chat with AI Guided, a company that makes a belt with haptic feedback for obstacle detection, helping to guide the blind.</p><p>“Microsoft really supports accessibility technology,” said Steve Kong, co-founder and chief technology officer of AI Guided. “The dream of our company is that in three to five years … visually impaired people can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world.”</p><p>AI Guided is one of 20 Hong Kong-based companies exhibiting with the city’s start-up pavilion this year, a big improvement over the eight that exhibited last year because of the last-minute lifting of Covid-19 restrictions.</p><p>Even leading up to the show, Hong Kong Science and Technology Park (HKSTP) said 40 companies applied to exhibit in the Eureka Park start-up area, a marked improvement over previous years, according to H L Yiu, corporate development officer for HKSTP, which runs the pavilion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248116/ces-2024-china-smartphone-brand-realme-unveils-new-handset-sidelines-trade-show-its-biggest-rivals" title="">Realme unveils 12 Pro series smartphone in parallel event to CES</a></h3><p>“We had to make some selection of companies that have more of a mature level of readiness in terms of being ready to sell,” Yiu said in an interview. “We really mean to help them get new business.”</p><p>With limited space, HKSTP focused on picking companies that were closer to having products ready to go, or even already in the market, with the goal of picking up business deals at CES.</p><p>For some, that could pan out in a big way.</p><p>Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology, aka Invisible Tech, which builds speakers into furniture, said it has received interest from Best Buy. A representative from the largest electronics retail chain in the US told Invisible Tech that it had not seen other products like its cabinet with an embedded speaker in the base, according to the start-up’s co-founder Patrick Lee.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1507" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/8c535fe2-a0b7-472a-a511-c0de39fad1c7_cffec5fe.jpg" title="Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Best Buy always wants to source something new,” said Lee. “Furniture is a very traditional thing that [has not had] much disruptive design or link with technology.”</p><p>Invisible Tech also uses recycled materials in some parts of its products. Henry Cheung, the company’s other co-founder, said the company wants to “help Hong Kong fulfil its carbon neutral mission”. The city aims to be carbon neutral by 2050.</p><p>The Hong Kong pavilion at this year’s CES, which concluded on Friday, featured a variety of start-ups that make products ranging from the quirky to the practical.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" title="">Chinese EV maker shows off flying car but admits urban use is far off</a></h3><p>XOXO Beverages already has its cocktail-making machine in about 10 bars and restaurants in Hong Kong, but it has not expanded to home use yet. Co-founder Peter Yau said CES was the best show the company has been to.</p><p>“People from all around the world come by and are very interested in the product,” Yau said. “[We got] a lot of contacts, and we’re looking to see what we can do after [the show] with those guys.”</p><p>Two of the participating companies, Sitan Semiconductor International and Raysolve Technology, make micro-LED displays, something that has become more important amid rising interest in augmented reality glasses.</p><p>Sitan was started at the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, and the company said its tech has already found its way into products from big brands like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tcl" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tcl">TCL</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo">Oppo</a> and Meizu – although not all of these products have been released.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1613" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/2b040077-b3ac-4878-bb0e-daa1b2414354_75a0b9ef.jpg" title="XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>For most of the start-ups, though, CES was about getting leads and looking for ways to expand beyond their home market. Getting the attention of a tech giant like Microsoft is one way to achieve that.</p><p>Asked about the prospects of Microsoft investing, AI Guided’s Kong said, “I hope so … I will still have another discussion with them, so we’ll see.”</p><p>This kind of attention also may help the Hong Kong government justify its efforts to turn the city into a tech hub, which has had mixed results in a city better known as a regional financial hub.</p><p>“From a tech area standpoint, I think the opportunity to come to Hong Kong is surging,” said HKSTP’s Yiu. “The number of start-ups that we nurture every year is an increasing trend.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Elon Musk’s Tesla loses US$94 billion in market valuation as winter sets in for global electric vehicle market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248400/elon-musks-tesla-loses-us94-billion-market-valuation-winter-sets-global-electric-vehicle-market</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tesla's market value has experienced a significant decline in the first two weeks of 2024, losing over $94 billion.</li>    <li>The downturn is attributed to a series of negative factors, including price cuts in China, labor cost increases, and slowing demand for electric vehicles.</li>    <li>The pressure on Tesla is further compounded by the rise of competitors like BYD, which overtook Tesla in global electric car sales.</li>    <li>Tesla's CEO, Elon Musk, has seen his personal wealth decrease significantly due to the company's stock performance.</li>    <li>Tesla remains a key player in the transition to electric vehicles, but its high valuation makes it vulnerable to negative news.</li>    <li>The company's long-term success hinges on its ability to deliver on promises of self-driving technology and artificial intelligence.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>特斯拉在今年前两周的市场价值大幅下跌，损失超过940亿美元。</li>    <li>这种下滑归因于一系列负面因素，包括中国降价、劳动力成本上升和电动汽车需求放缓。</li>    <li>特斯拉还面临着比亚迪等竞争对手的崛起带来的压力，比亚迪在全球电动汽车销量上超过了特斯拉。</li>    <li>特斯拉首席执行官埃隆·马斯克的个人财富因公司股票表现而大幅缩水。</li>    <li>特斯拉仍然是向电动汽车转型过程中的关键参与者，但其高估值使其容易受到负面新闻的影响。</li>    <li>该公司的长期成功取决于其兑现自动驾驶技术和人工智能承诺的能力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>barrage (n.) - /ˈbærɪdʒ/ 弹幕，猛烈的攻击。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古法语barrage，意思是“阻碍，障碍”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉为了提振需求而对其汽车采取的积极降价行动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>erosion (n.) - /ɪˈroʊʒən/ 侵蚀，腐蚀。    <p>原文例句：The result has been a steady erosion of its once-hefty profit margin.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语erodere，意思是“吃掉，腐蚀”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉曾经丰厚的利润率不断被侵蚀的过程。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>stagnate (v.) - /ˈstæɡneɪt/ 停滞，不发展。    <p>原文例句：“Investors’ main concern on Tesla is stagnating growth,” Cowen analyst Jeffrey Osborne said in an interview. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语stagnum，意思是“池塘，沼泽”。在这个例句中，它指的是投资者对特斯拉增长的担忧，即特斯拉的增长已经停滞不前。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>race to the bottom - 恶性竞争，价格战。    <P>原文例句：The price cuts in China only fan those concerns, because it is starting to look like “a race to the bottom for the EV industry given intense competition in that market”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指在激烈的竞争中，各方为了赢得市场份额而不断压低价格，最终导致价格水平大幅下降的情况。在这个例句中，它指的是中国市场上激烈的竞争导致特斯拉和其他电动汽车制造商陷入价格战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand. - 自去年年初以来，特斯拉一直大力削减汽车价格，以提振需求。<p>句子分析：这是一个主动语态的现在完成时句子，主语是Tesla，谓语是has been cutting，宾语是prices on its cars，介词短语in an effort to boost demand作目的状语。这个句子的意思是，自去年年初以来，特斯拉一直大力削减汽车价格，以提振需求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>情态动词can的用法 - 表示能力、可能性或许可。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand.</p>    <p>语法讲解：情态动词can有三种主要用法：表示能力、可能性或许可。在这个例句中，它表示能力，意思是特斯拉有能力大幅削减汽车价格，以提振需求。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Tesla’s losses in the first two weeks of this year have come from a barrage of negative news, including another price cut for its made-in-China cars</li>
<li>The US carmaker has been cutting prices on its vehicles aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/83cb01fa-622e-4130-b271-fd9276597c55_850fb60a.jpg" /><figcaption>Tesla chief executive Elon Musk applauds the roll-out of new electric vehicles at the opening of the firm’s Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant  in Germany on March 22, 2022. Photo:  AP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> had a blockbuster 2023, as its shares more than doubled in 12 months. But 2024 is starting on a different note, with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/elon-musk" target="_self" title="">Elon Musk</a>’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle</a> (EV) maker off to its worst start to any year – ever.</p><p>The company has lost more than US$94 billion in market valuation in just the first two weeks of this year. It is not hard to figure out why, as the Austin, Texas-based EV maker has been pounded by a barrage of negative news: an about-face on EVs from the car rental giant Hertz Global Holdings, yet another price cut for its cars <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-manufacturing" target="_self" title="">made in China</a>, and signs of rising labour costs.</p><p>All of this comes in the face of slowing growth in demand for EVs, especially in the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>.</p><p>“Investors’ main concern on Tesla is stagnating growth,” Cowen analyst Jeffrey Osborne said in an interview. The price cuts in China only fan those concerns, because it is starting to look like “a race to the bottom for the EV industry given intense competition in that market”.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/b52c250b-b6c8-47e5-91ec-7f2278c772c1_a66cec46.jpg" title="A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The hit to Tesla’s market capitalisation to start the year is the biggest the company has seen over a similar period since it went public in 2010. In percentage terms, Tesla’s 12 per cent drop since the start of January is the worst since 2016, when the stock fell 14 per cent over the first nine trading days of the year.</p><p>To make matters worse, the odds of an imminent turnaround for the EV maker do not look good.</p><p>Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early 2023 in an effort to boost demand. But the result has been a steady erosion of its once-hefty profit margin. Tesla’s automotive gross margin ex-regulatory credits for the third quarter fell to 16.3 per cent from 27.9 per cent a year ago. And the pressure is only mounting, now that production workers at Tesla’s US plants are getting pay rises.</p><p>“We are going through a cyclical downturn for EVs, but competitive dynamics are exacerbating the cyclical pressures,” Ivana Delevska, chief investment officer at Spear Invest, said in an interview. “Price cuts and plummeting margins are all a function of these unfavourable competitive dynamics.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing" title="">Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</a></h3><p>Adding to the woes, Tesla has had to divert shipments destined for its Berlin plant after Western military actions and security concerns in the Red Sea, and is suspending most production at its plant near the German capital from January 29 to February 11, according to a person familiar with the matter.</p><p>Tesla first warned about the deceleration in EV demand during its October third-quarter earnings report. Almost immediately after, carmakers and suppliers across the globe chimed in with their own downbeat forecasts. Many carmakers dialled back their plans for expansion.</p><p>Then, earlier this month, Tesla reported its fourth-quarter delivery numbers. While they were better than what analysts expected, they put the company behind China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD Co</a> in global electric-car sales.</p><p>The result has been a rude awakening for Tesla investors. Last year, the stock was the eighth best performer in the S&amp;P 500. So far this year, it is the eighth worst.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa" class="image-inline caption" height="1201" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/47b22035-65d8-46f4-a5cf-8ceaf3d20b48_c243b8f2.jpg" title="Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa" width="2000" /><figcaption>Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Naturally, Musk is taking a big hit personally. The world’s richest person, who gained more wealth last year than anyone else on the planet, has seen his net worth shrink by US$23 billion so far this year, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index.</p><p>Musk regained the top spot on Bloomberg’s wealth index last year, overtaking LVMH Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton founder and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226276/lvmh-boss-bernard-arnaults-visit-highlights-growing-importance-huge-mainland-chinese-market-luxury" target="_self" title="">Bernard Arnault</a>, but now <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon.com</a> founder and executive chairman <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jeff-bezos" target="_self" title="">Jeff Bezos</a> is rapidly closing in, with US$179 billion to Musk’s US$206 billion as of Friday’s close.</p><p>The bulk of Musk’s net worth comes from his 13 per cent stake in Tesla and about 304 million exercisable stock options. He also owns about 42 per cent of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/spacex" target="_self" title="">Space Exploration Technologies</a>, which is valued at about US$53 billion, according to Bloomberg’s wealth index.</p><p>With all that being said, Tesla remains a key player in the global transition from petrol-powered vehicles to largely electric ones. The reason: the company is so far ahead of its potential rivals. China’s BYD may have surpassed Tesla in the number of units sold, but it still lags in revenue and profits. And BYD does not sell cars in the US, where Tesla remains the market leader.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>In many ways, Tesla’s biggest problem may be its past success and the hope it generated. As investors piled into the stock, Tesla’s market capitalisation ballooned, making it way larger than any other car company in the world. However, with the shares priced for perfection, that also made them highly vulnerable to big reactions to any negative news.</p><p>That is why so many Tesla proponents argue that it should not be compared to regular car companies. To them, the ultimate true value of the company rests in the future and it is hope to develop the first truly <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/self-driving-cars-autonomous-vehicles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">self-driving vehicles</a>. The only problem is Tesla has been promising this for years, and most experts say the technology is still years, maybe even decades, away.</p><p>“Tesla has not been able to deliver on fully autonomous driving and AI promises, which are already embedded in the valuation,” Spear’s Delevska said. “Being simply another automotive manufacturer is not going to cut it for a US$750 billion valuation.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese etching tools giant AMEC sees 2023 sales rise more than 30% on strong demand from mainland semiconductor fabs</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248391/chinese-etching-tools-giant-amec-sees-2023-sales-rise-more-30-strong-demand-mainland-semiconductor</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div><h2>English Summary:</h2><ul><li>AMEC, a Shanghai-based company, anticipates a 32.1% revenue growth in 2023, reaching $879 million due to strong domestic demand.</li><li>New orders increased by 32.3%, totaling 8.36 billion yuan.</li><li>Improved core technologies boosted the sales of etching tools, now accounting for 75% of AMEC's revenue.</li><li>Replacing foreign-sourced components with domestic parts, AMEC aims to achieve 100% domestic production by 2024.</li><li>Amid US export controls, Chinese semiconductor foundries increasingly adopt domestically produced equipment.</li></ul></div><div><h2>中文总结：</h2><ul><li>位于上海的 AMEC 公司预计 2023 年的收入将增长 32.1%，达到 8.79 亿美元，这得益于强劲的国内需求。</li><li>新订单增加了 32.3%，总计 83.6 亿元人民币。</li><li>改进的核心技术推动了蚀刻工具的销售，如今占 AMEC 收入的 75%。</li><li>AMEC 旨在通过将外购组件替换为国产零件来实现 100% 的国产化生产，目标在 2024 年实现。</li><li>在受到美国出口管制的情况下，中国半导体代工厂越来越多地采用国产设备。</li></ul></div><div><h2>Words:</h2><ul><li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.njuː/ 收入，收益。<p>Example: The company's revenue grew by 32.1% in 2023.</p><p>例句讲解：这个单词的意思是“收入，收益”。在这个例句中，它指的是该公司在 2023 年的收入增长了 32.1%。</p></li><li>etching (n.) - /ˈetʃ.ɪŋ/ 刻蚀，腐蚀。<p>Example: AMEC's core etching tools saw increased adoption by domestic foundry clients.</p><p>例句讲解：这个单词的意思是“蚀刻，腐蚀”。在这个例句中，它指的是 AMEC 的核心蚀刻工具被国内代工厂客户广泛采用。</p></li><li>semiconductor (n.) - /ˌsem.i.kənˈdʌk.tər/ 半导体。<p>Example: AMEC is China's leading provider of process technologies, tools, and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors.</p><p>例句讲解：这个单词的意思是“半导体”。在这个例句中，它指的是 AMEC 是中国领先的半导体制造商的工艺技术、工具和专业知识提供商。</p></li></ul></div><div><h2>Phrases:</h2><ul><li>on the back of - 得益于，依靠。<p>Example: AMEC's revenue growth in 2023 is expected to reach 32.1% on the back of strong domestic demand.</p><p>例句讲解：这个词组的意思是“得益于，依靠”。在这个例句中，它指的是 AMEC 在 2023 年的收入增长预计将达到 32.1%，这得益于强劲的国内需求。</p></li><li>year-on-year - 同比。<p>Example: Net profit last year is projected to be from 1.7 billion yuan to 1.85 billion yuan, representing year-on-year growth of between 45 per cent and 58 per cent.</p><p>例句讲解：这个词组的意思是“同比”。在这个例句中，它指的是去年的净利润预计将在 17 亿至 18.5 亿元人民币之间，同比增长 45% 至 58%。</p></li><li>state-backed - 由国家支持的。<p>Example: With state-backed efforts to localise great swathes of China's semiconductor supply chain, mainland semiconductor foundries have accelerated adoption of locally made equipment.</p><p>例句讲解：这个词组的意思是“由国家支持的”。在这个例句中，它指的是在中国国家支持的努力下，本土化了大批半导体供应链，从而促进了中国大陆半导体代工厂加速采用国产设备。</p></li></ul></div><div><h2>Sentences:</h2><ul><li>The company said sales of its core etching tools will account for 75 per cent of its total revenue last year.</li><p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是The company，谓语是said，宾语是sales of its core etching tools will account for 75 per cent of its total revenue last year。这个句子说的是，该公司表示其核心蚀刻工具的销售额将占其去年总收入的 75%。</p></li><li>Yin had said 80 per cent of US-restricted components that AMEC used would be replaced with domestic parts by the end of last year.</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Yin had said，其中主语是Yin，谓语是had said。第一个分句是80 per cent of US-restricted components that AMEC used would be replaced with domestic parts，其中主语是80 per cent of US-restricted components that AMEC used，谓语是would be replaced，宾语是domestic parts。第二个分句是by the end of last year，其中主语是Yin，谓语是had said。这个句子说的是，尹曾表示，到去年年底，AMEC 使用的 80% 的受美国限制的组件将由国产零件替换。</p></li></ul></div><div><h2>Grammar:</h2><ul><li>To be going to + infinitive - 表示即将发生的事情。<p>Example: AMEC expects sales of its core etching tools to account for 75 per cent of its total revenue last year.</p><p>语法讲解：to be going to + infinitive 表示即将发生的事情。在这个例句中，it指的是 AMEC 预计其核心蚀刻工具的销售额将占其去年总收入的 75%。</p></li><li>The passive voice - 被动语态。<p>Example: Net profit last year is projected to be from 1.7 billion yuan to 1.85 billion yuan.</p><p>语法讲解：被动语态是指句子中的宾语是动作的承受者。在这个例句中，net profit 是动作的承受者，所以句子用了被动语态。</p></li></ul></div>  <ul><li>Shanghai-based AMEC expects its 2023 revenue to reach US$879 million, up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic orders</li>
<li>The company said sales of its core etching tools will account for 75 per cent of its total revenue last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/977166e1-00b7-4d05-941a-ada3e90b90d0_07dcf1ac.jpg" /><figcaption>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment workers at the company’s main production site in Shanghai. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese etching tools giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3232334/tech-war-china-chip-tool-firm-amecs-profit-boosted-strong-local-demand-it-reshuffles-tech-board-wake" target="_self" title="">Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment</a> (AMEC) expects revenue last year to grow more than 30 per cent from 2022, as core <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> breakthroughs enabled the firm to deploy more chip-making gear to domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> fabrication plants.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a>-based AMEC said in a regulatory filing on Sunday that its 2023 revenue is expected to reach 6.26 billion yuan (US$879 million), up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic demand. The company said it recorded 8.36 billion yuan worth of new orders, a 32.3 per cent year-on-year increase.</p><p>Net profit last year is projected to be from 1.7 billion yuan to 1.85 billion yuan, representing year-on-year growth of between 45 per cent and 58 per cent.</p><p>AMEC’s positive earnings guidance reflects its successful strategy to expand sales on the mainland, months after founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230803/us-wants-chinas-chip-industry-5-generations-behind-cutting-edge-head-equipment-maker-amec-says-wuxi" target="_self" title="">Gerald Yin Zhiyao</a> said the firm had devised a detailed road map to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy" target="_self" title="">tightened US semiconductor sanctions</a>.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/8dc83513-a48d-478e-9d86-f625246bf8fe_ada0205e.jpg" title="Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Yin had said 80 per cent of US-restricted components that AMEC used would be replaced with domestic parts by the end of last year. He expected the company to achieve a 100-per cent replacement rate in 2024.</p><p>AMEC shares in Shanghai closed down 2.07 per cent to 134.66 yuan last Friday.</p><p>With state-backed efforts to localise great swathes of China’s semiconductor supply chain, mainland semiconductor foundries have accelerated adoption of locally made equipment since October 2022, when Washington <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3195461/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-self-sufficiency-drive-under-siege-new" target="_self" title="">first tightened export controls</a> to cut off the country’s access to advanced chip-making gear from the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">US</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netherlands" target="_self" title="">the Netherlands</a>.</p><p>AMEC expects sales of its core etching tools, including so-called capacitively coupled plasma (CCP) and inductive coupled plasma (ICP), to account for 75 per cent of the firm’s total revenue last year, which would be up nearly 50 per cent to 4.7 billion yuan.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1414" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/646d3f0c-dcc0-4e3c-87fa-0e91b99b21a2_bfef4330.jpg" title="Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>AMEC said that its CCP and ICP equipment saw increased adoption by domestic foundry clients on the strength of the firm’s breakthroughs in core technologies last year.</p><p>Etching tools are some of the most important processing equipment used by semiconductor foundries. It is an area where China has strong players such as AMEC and state-backed Naura Technology Group.</p><p>AMEC’s domestic CCP equipment market share is projected to hit 60 per cent in the near future, up from 24 per cent in October 2022. The firm’s share in ICP gear sales on the mainland is predicted to reach 75 per cent from almost zero, according to company chief executive Yin, after once-dominant US chip equipment maker Lam Research saw its mainland sales drop sharply.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China price wars help spark US$157 billion rout in mainland consumer stocks, as firms including Alibaba, Yum China and BYD drag the market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248377/china-price-wars-help-spark-us157-billion-rout-mainland-consumer-stocks-firms-including-alibaba-yum</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese consumer stocks have been suffering from a lack of positive drivers, leading to a decline in the stock market.</li>    <li>Companies are offering big discounts to lure customers amidst tepid consumer demand, impacting corporate earnings and share prices.</li>    <li>The EV industry has been hit by intense competition, with BYD and other Chinese makers lowering prices to boost sales.</li>    <li>Internet giants like Alibaba and JD.com have also been affected by the price war, impacting their stock prices.</li>    <li>Fund managers and economists are looking to interest-rate cuts and government spending to prevent deflation and boost consumer confidence.</li>    <li>Factors such as salary cuts, job losses, and slowing economic recovery continue to weigh on consumer sentiment and spending.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国消费类股票因缺乏利好驱动而表现不佳，导致股市低迷。</li>    <li>由于消费者需求疲软，企业为吸引客户而提供巨额折扣，影响公司收益和股价。</li>    <li>电动汽车行业受到激烈竞争的打击，比亚迪和其他中国制造商降低价格以提振销量。</li>    <li>阿里巴巴、京东等互联网巨头也受到价格战的影响，导致股价下跌。</li>    <li>基金经理和经济学家希望降息和政府支出能够防止通货紧缩并提振消费者信心。</li>    <li>减薪、失业和经济复苏放缓等因素继续影响消费情绪和支出。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tepid (adj.) - 不温不火的。    <p>原文例句：The seemingly relentless decline in prices of Chinese goods amid tepid consumer demand is denting expectations that corporate earnings can revive the flagging stock market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Tepid指不热烈、不热情，常用于形容经济、市场等。在这个例句中，它表示消费者需求不温不火，这使得人们对企业收益能否提振低迷股市的预期受到打击。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>gauge (n.) - 衡量标准，标尺。    <p>原文例句：Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Gauge作为名词时，可以表示衡量标准、标尺。在这个例句中，它表示消费者股票的衡量指标，即衡量消费者股票表现的标准。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>dint (n.) - 凹痕，痕迹。    <p>原文例句：The seemingly relentless decline in prices of Chinese goods amid tepid consumer demand is denting expectations that corporate earnings can revive the flagging stock market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Dent表示凹痕、痕迹，常比喻对声誉、经济等造成的损害或影响。在这个例句中，它表示价格持续下跌对人们对企业收益能否提振低迷股市的预期的打击。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The EV industry has been among the worst hit by intense competition as growth slows, with Chinese makers following the lead of Tesla in lowering prices to boost sales. - 电动汽车行业受到激烈竞争的打击，随着增长放缓，中国制造商效仿特斯拉降低价格以提振销量。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The EV industry has been hit by intense competition，其中主语是The EV industry，谓语是has been hit，宾语是intense competition。as growth slows是一个时间状语，表示随着增长放缓。with Chinese makers following the lead of Tesla in lowering prices to boost sales是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示中国制造商效仿特斯拉降低价格以提振销量。这个句子的意思是说，随着增长放缓，电动汽车行业受到激烈竞争的打击，中国制造商效仿特斯拉降低价格以提振销量。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时态 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include Alibaba, Yum China Holdings and BYD, which have all been offering big discounts.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态的句子，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示阿里巴巴、Yum China Holdings和BYD这三家公司从过去的某个时间开始一直持续到present提供大折扣，强调动作的持续性和未完成性。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023</li>
<li>The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include Alibaba, Yum China Holdings and BYD, which have all been offering big discounts</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/b3e8597a-be7a-4197-85aa-c1a7be1f6626_e063aefc.jpg" /><figcaption>People fly dragon-shaped kites on the Bund in front of buildings in Pudong’s Lujiazui Financial District in Shanghai on January 9, 2024. China’s stock market suffers from a lack of positive drivers ahead of the Lunar New Year. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>The seemingly relentless decline in prices of Chinese goods amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247712/chinas-retail-sales-weaken-year-falling-home-prices-jobs-outlook-feed-consumer-insecurity-ubs" target="_self" title="">tepid consumer demand</a> is denting expectations that corporate earnings can revive the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-stock-market" target="_self" title="">flagging stock market</a>.</p><p>From <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicles</a> (EVs) to fast food, companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3244649/china-inflation-4-takeaways-novembers-data-deflationary-pressure-heightened" target="_self" title="">Consumer prices</a> fell for a third-straight month in December, the longest streak since 2009, deepening concerns about companies’ profits and share prices.</p><p>“That’s all symbolic of a very weak consumption environment that includes lack of consumer confidence and weak income growth,” said Ng Xin-yao, an investment director for Asian equities at abrdn. “We are cautious on fourth-quarter earnings across most sectors, and would assume that continues in the first quarter unless the government starts doing something massive to support the economy.”</p><p>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/msci" target="_self" title="">MSCI China Index</a> since the end of September, after the real estate measure. The aggregate market value of companies included in the two consumer indexes has fallen by about US$157 billion since.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/c17c04b3-1a34-4b5f-9767-75f9273ed6e5_8a6158cb.jpg" title="Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include e-commerce giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, restaurant operator <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3209531/kfc-pizza-hut-operator-yum-china-open-1300-stores-worst-over-posts-earnings-decline-2022" target="_self" title="">Yum China Holdings</a> and EV maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD Co</a> – which have all been offering big discounts. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>The world’s second-largest stock market has started 2024 on a dismal note, with the MSCI China gauge already down more than 4 per cent so far this year. It capped a third straight annual decline in 2023.</p><p>“The bigger picture is that the weak demand is leading to a deflationary environment, which particularly bodes ill for businesses that cannot achieve higher volumes with lower prices,” said Daisy Li, a fund manager at EFG Asset Management HK.</p><p>The EV industry has been among the worst hit by intense competition as growth slows, with Chinese makers following the lead of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> in lowering prices to boost sales. BYD and local peers including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a> have shed billions of dollars in market value in the past few months.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing" title="">Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</a></h3><p>“Retail prices are falling fast,” Morgan Stanley analysts wrote in their 2024 outlook report for the Chinese EV sector. “While local brands, in general, have fared better than luxury and foreign brands in terms of widening discounts, we expect discounts to further widen into the first quarter this year on the back of seasonality effects.”</p><p>Even China’s vaunted <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants have been impacted, with Alibaba and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> seeing their stock prices tumble, as they wage a fierce battle for market share. The price war has made US-listed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247286/pdd-halts-development-local-services-offering-avoid-head-competition-meituan-and-eleme-report-says" target="_self" title="">PDD Holdings</a>, operator of discount sites <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="">Pinduoduo</a> on the mainland and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>, one of the rare bright spots in China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> industry.</p><p>Many economy and market observers are hoping for interest-rate cuts and government spending to help prevent the nation from entering a deflationary spiral.</p><p>Fund managers have said the next catalyst they are watching is pricing and sales data around the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/lunar-new-year" target="_self" title="">Lunar New Year</a> in February, which will offer more clues on consumer confidence.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>The next few weeks may also be key for policy action, given Chinese leaders will soon gear up for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/national-peoples-congress" target="_self" title="">National People’s Congress</a>. That annual legislative session, held in March, is where the government is expected to announce its official growth target for 2024.</p><p>A Morgan Stanley survey conducted late last month suggests seasonally better consumer sentiment ahead of the holidays. However, “sustainability is in doubt amid slowing economic recovery”, analysts including Lillian Lou wrote in a note.</p><p>Salary cuts and job losses have remained among the top concerns of households, they wrote, adding that the number of consumers anticipating the economy to worsen ticked up by two percentage points from November to 13 per cent.</p><p>In all, there is little hope for a quick fix. Citigroup expects consensus estimates to fall for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-ning-company-ltd" target="_self" title="">Li Ning</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3217413/anta-sports-seeks-us15-billion-equity-placement-market-discount-triggering-stocks-worst-sell-six" target="_self" title="">Anta Sports Products</a> around the upcoming results season, hurt by foreign competition and pushes into lower-tier cities with cheaper products.</p><p>Fast-food companies are still locked in a protracted fight for customers, with some offering full meals for around US$3. It is difficult to make money at such low prices.</p><p>“We expect industry margins to erode until the irrational price war ends,” Kevin Yin, an analyst at JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co., wrote in a note, while cutting estimates for Yum China. “No player is immune” to the headwinds created by the nation’s slowing demand growth, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Stanford students win hearts in China with US$32,000 household robot that can cook shrimp and wash pans</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248330/stanford-students-win-hearts-china-us32000-household-robot-can-cook-shrimp-and-wash-pans</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  A two-handed robot, called Mobile Aloha, developed by researchers at Stanford University, can be remotely controlled or operate autonomously through imitation learning. It can perform various tasks with a success rate of at least 80%, including cooking, cleaning, and wiping spills.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Two-handed robot cooks and performs household chores autonomously.</li>    <li>Theme: Mobile Aloha, a versatile two-handed robot, showcases advanced robotic capabilities.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Potential of two-handed robots in domestic tasks, as demonstrated by Mobile Aloha.</li>    <li>Main information: Tasks performed by Mobile Aloha; development process and challenges; potential applications in smart homes.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  由斯坦福大学研究人员开发的双臂机器人Mobile Aloha能够通过远程控制或自主模仿学习方式进行操作。它能够完成各种任务，成功率至少为80%，包括烹饪、清洁和擦拭溢出物。  <ul>    <li>摘要：双手机器人自主烹饪和完成家务。</li>    <li>主题：Mobile Aloha，一款多功能双臂机器人，展示了先进的机器人功能。</li>    <li>观点：双手机器人在家务任务中的潜力，Mobile Aloha就是证明。</li>    <li>主要信息：Mobile Aloha执行的任务；开发过程和面临的挑战；在智能家居中的潜在应用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>autonomously (adv.) - /ɔːˈtɒnəməsli/ 自主地，自动地。    <p>原文例句：Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于Greek，由auto-（自我）和nomos（法律）组成，表示“按照自己的法律或规则行事，自主地”。在这个例句中，它指的是Mobile Aloha可以自主地通过模仿学习的方式工作。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>demonstration (n.) - /ˌdemənˈstreɪʃən/ 示范，演示。    <p>原文例句：After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, according to the project’s website.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词来源于Latin，由demonstrare（展现）构成，表示“展现，演示”。在这个例句中，它指的是Mobile Aloha通过50次人类的演示和数据集合的共同训练，成功率至少达到80%地学会了烹饪虾、清洗锅子、端起酒杯和擦拭溢出的液体。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>at least - 至少。    <P>原文例句：After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, according to the project’s website. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由at（在）和least（至少）构成的，表示“至少，最少”。在这个例句中，它表示Mobile Aloha通过50次人类的演示和数据集合的共同训练，成功率至少达到80%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Fu and Zhao are also student researchers at Google DeepMind, an artificial intelligence (AI) research laboratory. - Fu和Zhao也是Google DeepMind的人工智能（AI）研究实验室的学生研究员。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Fu和Zhao，谓语是are，宾语是student researchers at Google DeepMind, an artificial intelligence (AI) research laboratory。Fu和Zhao是主语，表示两个人；are是谓语，表示“是”；student researchers at Google DeepMind, an artificial intelligence (AI) research laboratory是宾语，表示Google DeepMind人工智能（AI）研究实验室的学生研究员。这个句子的意思是说，Fu和Zhao也是Google DeepMind人工智能（AI）研究实验室的学生研究员。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语 - 由现在分词和其修饰语构成的短语，作状语或定语。    <p>原文例句：After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, according to the project’s website.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在分词短语是由现在分词和其修饰语构成的短语，在句中作状语或定语。现在分词是动词的-ing形式，修饰语可以是形容词、副词、介词短语等。在这个例句中，After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets是一个现在分词短语，作状语，表示在经历了50次人类演示和在数据集上进行共同训练之后；with a success rate of at least 80 per cent是一个现在分词短语，作状语，表示成功率至少达到80%。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 把句子中某些成分的位置颠倒，以达到某种修辞效果。    <p>原文例句：The robot can walk at 1.42 metres per second, roughly equivalent to human speed, reach as high as 2 metres and extend one metre beyond its base, the team said.</p>    <p>语法讲解：倒装句是把句子中某些成分的位置颠倒，以达到某种修辞效果。常见的倒装句有：强调句、疑问句、祈使句、感叹句等。在这个例句中，The robot can walk at 1.42 metres per second, roughly equivalent to human speed, reach as high as 2 metres and extend one metre beyond its base, the team said是一个倒装句，把主语The robot放在了谓语can walk之后，以强调主语The robot。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Mobile Aloha, a two-handed system, can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning</li>
<li>It is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, the inventors say</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/a5391667-ecfe-41e0-ba55-d4bcc8573340_5eb9826c.jpg" /><figcaption>Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning. Photo: Screenshot</figcaption></figure><p>A US$32,000 robot developed by a team at Stanford University has caught the attention of Chinese online users, after a video showing the two-handed robot cooking a three-course meal went viral.</p><p>Mobile Aloha, built by two computer-science PhD candidates from China, is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p><p>After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, according to the project’s website.</p><p>It took three months to develop the robot, according to Zipeng Fu, who co-leads the project with Tony Zhao, advised by Stanford assistant professor Chelsea Finn. Fu and Zhao are also student researchers at Google DeepMind, an artificial intelligence (AI) research laboratory.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Fu said they had to tackle both hardware and software challenges. To save cost, they assembled the machine on their own. The goal was to make a robot that could “complete complex home or office tasks that were not shown to be possible previously”.</p><p>The robot can walk at 1.42 metres per second, roughly equivalent to human speed, reach as high as 2 metres and extend one metre beyond its base, the team said.</p><p>When it comes to the software, the duo took a “data-driven AI approach using human demonstration data to teach the robot” instead of the traditional way of “tons of programming and manual tuning” that is not scalable, Fu said.</p><p>The robot cost US$32,000 to build, including on-board power and computing. Fu said he and Zhao, who have open-sourced the whole system, “don’t have any business plan at the moment”.</p><p>As the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ageing-society" target="_self" title="">global population gets older</a>, domestic robots are expected to play a critical role in the smart home ecosystem. The market is estimated to grow at an annual rate of nearly 20 per cent from US$8.6 billion this year to US$22.5 billion by 2029, according to market research firm Mordor Intelligence.</p><p>Global tech giants have been betting big on the sector. In 2021, American online retailer Amazon.com unveiled Astro, a nearly US$1,000 household robot designed for home monitoring. Japanese electronics giant Sony launched the latest generation of its Aibo robot dog in 2018, priced at around US$2,900.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s Big Tech firms from Tencent to Alibaba cut external investments further in 2023 amid troubled economy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248311/chinas-big-tech-firms-tencent-alibaba-cut-external-investments-further-2023-amid-troubled-economy</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  2023年，互联网巨头阿里巴巴、腾讯和百度去年总投资交易额下降近40%，根据IT桔子数据显示。其中，智能手机制造商小米以投资数量成为其同行中的トップ投资者，2023年投资82笔。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 中国互联网巨头去年的投资大幅减少。</li>    <li>Theme: 阿里巴巴、腾讯和百度等中国互联网巨头在经济放缓、监管逆风和地缘政治紧张局势下，去年大幅削减了外部投资。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 中国互联网巨头投资减少的原因和影响。</li>    <li>Main information: 阿里巴巴、腾讯和百度的投资交易总额下降近40%至102笔；腾讯投资数量降幅最大，去年与37家公司签订了39份投资合同；百度去年参与了24笔投资交易，低于2021年的52笔；阿里巴巴去年参与了39笔交易，低于2021年的91笔；小米以82笔投资成为投资数量最多的公司。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023年，互联网巨头阿里巴巴、腾讯和百度去年总投资交易额下降近40%，根据IT桔子数据显示。其中，智能手机制造商小米以投资数量成为其同行中的トップ投资者，2023年投资82笔。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国互联网巨头去年的投资大幅减少。</li>    <li>主题：阿里巴巴、腾讯和百度等中国互联网巨头在经济放缓、监管逆风和地缘政治紧张局势下，去年大幅削减了外部投资。</li>    <li>观点：中国互联网巨头投资减少的原因和影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：阿里巴巴、腾讯和百度的投资交易总额下降近40%至102笔；腾讯投资数量降幅最大，去年与37家公司签订了39份投资合同；百度去年参与了24笔投资交易，低于2021年的52笔；阿里巴巴去年参与了39笔交易，低于2021年的91笔；小米以82笔投资成为投资数量最多的公司。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>counterpart (n.) - /ˈkaʊntəpɑːrt/ 相对应的，对应物。    <p>原文例句：Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由counter（相反的，对立的）和part（部分，份额）组成的，表示“相对应的，对应物”。在这个例句中，它指的是“与美国同行相对应的中国互联网巨头”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>watershed (n.) - /ˈwɔːtərʃɛd/ 分水岭，转折点。    <p>原文例句：2021 was a watershed year for Chinese internet firms, as Beijing kicked off a campaign to rein in the “disorderly expansion of capital”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语，由water（水）和shed（分离，分开）组成，表示“分水岭，转折点”。在这个例句中，它指的是2021年中国政府开始整顿互联网行业的资本扩张，成为中国互联网行业的一个转折点。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rein in - 使节制，使收敛。    <P>原文例句：Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由rein（缰绳）和in（向内）组成的，表示“拉紧缰绳，使节制，使收敛”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国政府通过一系列监管措施来抑制互联网行业的扩张。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo - 阿里巴巴的标识出现在北京的一栋建筑外。照片：美联社。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是The Alibaba logo，谓语是is seen，宾语是outside a building in Beijing。Photo: AP Photo是一个插入语，用来解释或说明The Alibaba logo is seen的具体情况，表示这张照片是美联社拍摄的。这个句子的意思是说，阿里巴巴的标识出现在北京的一栋建筑外，这张照片是美联社拍摄的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Total investment deals made by Alibaba, Tencent and Baidu plunged by nearly 40 per cent last year, data from ITJuzi shows</li>
<li>Smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor among its peers by number of investments, with 82 deals made in 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/44791123-3b25-419d-83ab-8b90abaff588_62f5b773.jpg" /><figcaption>The Tencent headquarters in Shenzhen. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>China’s internet giants from Alibaba Group Holding to Tencent Holdings slashed external investments last year amid an economic slowdown, regulatory headwinds and geopolitical tensions, according to data compiled by a Chinese consultancy.</p><p>Total investment deals made by Alibaba, Tencent and Baidu plunged by nearly 40 per cent to 102 in 2023, with Tencent – known for its expansive holdings in China’s internet sector – seeing the largest reduction in deals, data from ITJuzi showed.</p><p>The social media and video gaming titan struck 39 investment contracts with 37 companies last year, a sharp decline from the 95 and 299 deals it made in 2022 and 2021, respectively.</p><p>Web search and artificial intelligence (AI) firm Baidu participated in 24 investment deals last year, down from 52 in 2021. E-commerce giant Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, took part in 39 deals, a fall from 91 in 2021, according to ITJuzi.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/7597aa81-09a5-4a11-9eec-a437d76b7f0a_d667e456.jpg" title="The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Alibaba logo is seen outside a building in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure></div><p>2021 was a watershed year for Chinese internet firms, as Beijing kicked off a campaign to rein in the “disorderly expansion of capital”. Amid a series of regulatory tightening moves, the country’s internet champions - whose market sizes were once on a par with their American counterparts - have virtually stopped expanding.</p><p>Tencent’s investments last year were mainly related to corporate services, healthcare and video games. Advanced manufacturing firms were Alibaba’s top picks, with eight related deals being struck by the Hangzhou-based company and its affiliates during the year.</p><p>Alibaba, which is grappling with anaemic consumer spending at home, made four investment deals in the e-commerce sector, three of them outside China.</p><p>AI was another investment favourite among Chinese tech giants last year, as they raced to build and promote their local rivals to OpenAI’s ChatGPT.</p><p>Tencent and Alibaba each backed seven and four AI start-ups developing large language models (LLMs), the technology which underpins chatbots like ChatGPT, which can understand complex questions and give humanlike responses.</p><p>Last year, Alibaba’s in-house research facility Damo Academy also launched a research laboratory to recruit more than a hundred postdoctoral candidates to work on cutting-edge areas, including AI and semiconductors.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1325" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/5991da2b-d385-4951-b2a1-8a232f9ce1c4_bc1c8442.jpg" title="Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Baidu’s headquarters in Beijing. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Other major Chinese tech companies made even fewer investments.</p><p>TikTok owner ByteDance struck five external investment deals last year, while online shopping platform operator JD.com made just two.</p><p>ByteDance’s largest deal in 2023 was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244634/tiktok-restarts-e-commerce-indonesia-us15-billion-investment-goto-gojek-tokopedia-unit" target="_self" title="">a US$1.5 billion investment into Indonesia’s biggest e-commerce firm Tokopedia</a>, which allows the Beijing-based company to restart its local online shopping business after Indonesian regulators banned TikTok Shop.</p><p>Meanwhile, Chinese smartphone maker Xiaomi emerged as the top investor by number of investments, with 82 deals made during the year.</p><p>The company, also based in Beijing, in December launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246558/xiaomi-unveils-its-first-ev-su7-setting-its-sights-tesla-highly-competitive-china-market" target="_self" title="">its first electric vehicle, the SU7</a>, designed to compete against the likes of Tesla and Porsche in China’s hotly contested car market.</p><p>In that same month, Xiaomi invested in three start-ups in the vehicle and transport industry, according to ITJuzi.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong needs to speed up approval of spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds after US launch, industry insiders say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248282/hong-kong-needs-speed-approval-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-after-us-launch-industry</link>
<description><![CDATA[ ```html###<div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Hong Kong is urged to expedite its authorization of spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs) to boost its competitiveness in the global cryptocurrency market. The successful launch of spot bitcoin ETFs in the US is seen as a positive step, and leading to a potential boost in the crypto industry and its collaboration with mainstream finance. Industry Insiders urge Hong Kong regulators to follow suit and approve similar cryptocurrency funds, enhancing the city's position as a virtual-asset hub.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Hong Kong faces calls to accelerate the approval of spot cryptocurrency ETFs, following the US's lead, to maintain its competitive edge in the global crypto market.</li>    <li>Theme: Hong Kong's efforts to establish itself as a major virtual-asset hub by authorizing spot cryptocurrency ETFs.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of spot cryptocurrency ETFs in boosting Hong Kong's competitiveness in the global crypto market and facilitating collaboration with mainstream finance.</li>    <li>Main information: The US's approval of spot bitcoin ETFs, the potential impact on Hong Kong regulators, the readiness of fund management firms in Hong Kong, and China's stance on cryptocurrencies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  业内人士呼吁香港加快认可现货加密货币交易所交易基金（ETF），以提高其在全球加密货币市场的竞争力。美国现货比特币ETF的成功推出被视为积极的一步，有可能提振加密货币行业及其与主流金融的合作。业内人士敦促香港监管机构效仿并批准类似的加密货币基金，以提升香港作为虚拟资产中心的地位。  <ul>    <li>摘要：香港面临着加速审批现货加密货币ETF的呼吁，效仿美国，以保持其在全球加密货币市场上的竞争优势。</li>    <li>主题：香港通过授权现货加密货币ETF来确立其作为主要虚拟资产中心的努力。</li>    <li>观点：现货加密货币ETF在提升香港在全球加密货币市场竞争力以及促进其与主流金融合作上的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：美国批准现货比特币ETF、对香港监管机构的潜在影响、香港基金管理公司的准备情况以及中国对加密货币的立场。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>bolster (v.) - /ˈboʊlstər/ 支撑，加强，提升。    <p>原文例句：Hong Kong should soon follow the United States’ lead in authorising spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs), bolstering the city’s ambition to become a major virtual-asset hub in Asia, according to industry insiders. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由bolster（支撑物，垫子）演变而来，表示“支撑，加强，提升”。在这个例句中，它表示香港应该尽快效仿美国，授权现货加密货币交易所交易基金（ETF），以巩固香港成为亚洲主要虚拟资产中心的目标。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>legitimacy (n.) - /lɪˈdʒɪtɪməsi/ 合法性，正当性。    <p>原文例句：Spot cryptocurrency ETFs enable investors to gain exposure to virtual assets without directly buying any crypto tokens. These funds “give the crypto industry more legitimacy and also opens up more collaboration opportunities with mainstream finance”, said RJ Ke, a researcher with ethereum scaling start-up Taiko. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语legitimus（合法的），表示“合法性，正当性”。在这个例句中，它表示现货加密货币ETF使投资者能够接触虚拟资产，而无需直接购买任何加密货币代币。这些基金“赋予加密货币行业更多的合法性，也为与主流金融的合作提供了更多机会”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take suit - 采取法律行动。    <P>原文例句：However, each country and region has its own independent stance and regulatory objectives,” he said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由take（采取）和suit（诉讼）组成，表示“采取法律行动”。在这个例句中，它表示每个国家和地区都有自己独立的立场和监管目标。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The successful launch of spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds in the US is expected to help move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city. - 美国现货比特币交易所交易基金的成功推出预计将推动香港监管机构迈向授权类似加密货币基金在该市运营。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是US is expected to help move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city，其中主语是US，谓语是expected to help，宾语是move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city。The successful launch of spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds in the US是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰US，表示美国现货比特币交易所交易基金的成功推出。这个句子的意思是说，美国现货比特币交易所交易基金的成功推出预计将推动香港监管机构迈向授权类似加密货币基金在该市运营。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示虚拟的情境、愿望或可能性。    <p>原文例句：Hong Kong should soon follow the United States’ lead in authorising spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds (ETFs), bolstering the city’s ambition to become a major virtual-asset hub in Asia, according to industry insiders. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气结构，其中should表示建议或义务，follow表示跟随或效仿。这个结构表示香港应该效仿美国，授权现货加密货币交易所交易基金（ETF），以巩固香港成为亚洲主要虚拟资产中心的目标。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>并列连词 - 用于连接两个或多个词、短语或句子。    <p>原文例句：These funds “give the crypto industry more legitimacy and also opens up more collaboration opportunities with mainstream finance”, said RJ Ke, a researcher with ethereum scaling start-up Taiko. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个并列连词结构，其中and表示连接，也表示。这个结构表示这些基金“赋予加密货币行业更多的合法性，也为与主流金融的合作提供了更多机会”。</p></li>  </ul></div>###```  <ul><li>Hong Kong has fallen behind the US in authorising spot cryptocurrency ETFs, even though regulators in December said the city was prepared to do so</li>
<li>Industry insiders urge local regulators to step up approvals to strengthen the city’s competitiveness in the global cryptocurrency market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/3b2dd50a-a4ac-4010-9e13-b8b9d2dcf87f_4276bf76.jpg" /><figcaption>The successful launch of spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds in the US is expected to help move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong</a> should soon follow the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>’ lead in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">authorising spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a> (ETFs), bolstering the city’s ambition to become a major <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3197838/hong-kong-unveils-policies-develop-virtual-assets-industry-challenging-singapore-hub-status" target="_self" title="">virtual-asset hub in Asia</a>, according to industry insiders.</p><p>While the city’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/sfc" target="_self" title="">Securities and Futures Commission</a> (SFC) in December said it was prepared to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" target="_self" title="">authorise retail access to spot virtual asset ETFs</a>, the actual launch of such products has already fallen behind the US, according to Wang Yi, the head of quantitative investment at CSOP Asset Management, which currently runs two <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/digital-currencies" target="_self" title="">cryptocurrency</a> futures ETFs.</p><p>US-listed spot <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bitcoin" target="_self" title="">bitcoin</a> ETFs saw US$4.6 billion worth of shares trade hands on Thursday, according to a Reuters report that cited LSEG data, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248152/us-bitcoin-etfs-trades-soar-us46-billion-first-day-after-landmark-sec-approval" target="_self" title="">investors jumped into the landmark products</a> approved by the US securities regulator on Wednesday.</p><p>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust, Grayscale Bitcoin Trust and ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF, among others – began trading on Thursday, following the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">US Securities and Exchange Commission’s landmark approval</a> that is expected to help bring the cryptocurrency industry closer to the more regulated world of traditional finance.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/9cebdb57-e859-4c52-8114-95780d50fca8_a66cec46.jpg" title="Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Blackrock representatives ring the opening bell with guests at the Nasdaq MarketSite in New York on January 11, 2024, as bitcoin spot exchange-traded funds began trading. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The successful US launch of spot bitcoin ETFs is expected to help move Hong Kong regulators closer to authorising similar cryptocurrency funds to operate in the city.</p><p>Spot cryptocurrency ETFs enable investors to gain exposure to virtual assets without directly buying any crypto tokens.</p><p>These funds “give the crypto industry more legitimacy and also opens up more collaboration opportunities with mainstream finance”, said RJ Ke, a researcher with ethereum scaling start-up Taiko. “Hong Kong is likely to accelerate bitcoin ETF applications in the coming months.”</p><p>Around 10 fund management firms are preparing to launch spot virtual asset-backed ETFs in Hong Kong, according to Chinese media Caixin’s interview on Wednesday of Livio Weng, chief operating officer at <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239953/hong-kongs-hashkey-launches-first-crypto-trading-app-retail-investors-gives-away-new-token" target="_self" title="">crypto trading app operator HashKey Group</a>. Weng said that up to eight companies were at an “advanced stage” to launch.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" title="">US regulator SEC authorises spot bitcoin ETFs in cryptocurrency breakthrough</a></h3><p>Bitcoin jumped about 3.4 per cent to US$47,500, following the spot crypto ETF approvals in the US. That was nearly three times the level that the original cryptocurrency reached in November 2022, when <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3199385/crypto-exchange-giant-ftx-collapses-files-bankruptcy-protection-global-digital-currency-market-posts" target="_self" title="">failed crypto exchange FTX filed for bankruptcy</a> to send bitcoin’s price below US$17,000.</p><p>Hong Kong needs to launch spot virtual asset ETFs as soon as possible to “ensure that the city remains competitive in the global cryptocurrency market and strengthen its position as a global financial centre”, said Mao Shixing, also known as “Discus Fish”, who is the co-founder and chief executive of digital asset custody solutions provider Cobo.</p><p>Mao said the US approvals could impact other jurisdictions because “the SEC is one of the most influential and reputable financial regulators in the world”, adding that the agency’s initiatives “often serve as important references for financial regulators in other countries and regions”.</p><p>“However, each country and region has its own independent stance and regulatory objectives,” he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" title="">Hong Kong to push retail access to spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a></h3><p>Echoing the Cobo head’s view, Donald Day, chief operating officer at digital asset platform VDX, said the SEC’s decision would make its peers “seriously consider whether similar ETFs would be permissible and desirable”.</p><p>Day pointed out that the SFC’s statement in December about being prepared to authorise such funds has “in principle opened a pathway for issuers to launch spot crypto ETFs in Hong Kong”.</p><p>With the US, there are now nine markets around the world that have allowed the operation of spot crypto ETFs. The other markets include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/canada?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Canada</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/germany?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Germany</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/switzerland?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Switzerland</a>, and tax havens such as the Cayman Islands in the Caribbean and Jersey near the coast of northwestern France, according to market analytics firm CoinGecko.</p><p>Mainland China, however, is unlikely to follow suit.</p><p>In December, China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology said it will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" target="_self" title="">draft a national Web3 development plan</a> to suit the country’s needs. But the announcement did not mention cryptocurrencies even though Beijing maintains its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3216894/chinese-officials-pledge-support-hong-kongs-tech-web3-ambitions-digital-economy-summit?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">support for Hong Kong’s ambition to become a major virtual-asset hub</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" title="">Beijing to draft national Web3 development plan amid strict cryptocurrency ban</a></h3><p>The Chinese government banned banks from handling bitcoin in 2013 and forced cryptocurrency exchanges to move offshore in 2017. In 2021, the country’s regulators reiterated the state’s prohibition on all financial institutions from engaging in crypto-related activities.</p><p>China’s state media recently emphasised the risks involved in spot cryptocurrency ETFs.</p><p>The US approval of spot bitcoin ETFs “would make the cryptocurrency market even more frantic, providing fertile ground for illegal transactions such as money laundering”, according to a report by the International Financial News, a newspaper under the People’s Daily, which cited Shanghai Jiao Tong University assistant professor Li Nan.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
