<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Apple’s China price cuts on iPhones, MacBooks ‘cancel out’ pressure from rivals chasing premium segment, say analysts</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248529/apples-china-price-cuts-iphones-macbooks-cancel-out-pressure-rivals-chasing-premium-segment-say</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Apple is offering discounts of up to 800 yuan (US$113) on a range of products in China, including iPhones, iPads, MacBook Air laptops, the Apple Watch, and AirPods. Apple is facing intense competition from Chinese rivals like Huawei, and the discounts are meant to boost sales and clear out older models of products.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple offers discounts on products in China to boost sales amid competition from Chinese rivals.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's strategy to tackle competition from Chinese smartphone brands in the Chinese market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Apple's price cuts are a strategic move to counteract competition and boost sales during the Lunar New Year shopping season.</li>    <li>Main information: Products covered by the discounts; timing of the discounts; competitive pressure from Chinese rivals; sales performance of Apple and Huawei in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  苹果在中国推出了力度高达 800 元（合 113 美元）的促销活动，涉及 iPhone、iPad、MacBook Air 笔记本电脑、Apple Watch 和 AirPods 等产品。苹果正面对来自华为等中国竞争对手的激烈竞争，此次降价旨在提振销量，并清理旧款产品。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果在中国提供产品折扣，旨在提振销量，以应对来自中国竞争对手的竞争压力。</li>    <li>主题：苹果在中国市场应对来自中国智能手机品牌的竞争所采取的策略。</li>    <li>观点：苹果的降价是一种战略举措，旨在抵消竞争对手的影响并在春节购物季提振销量。</li>    <li>主要信息：折扣涵盖的产品范围；折扣的时间安排；来自中国竞争对手的竞争压力；苹果和华为在中国市场的销售业绩。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>compete (v.) - /kəmˈpiːt/ 竞争，争夺。    <p>原文例句：In a sales promotion covering iPhones, iPads, MacBook Air laptops, the Apple Watch and AirPods, which will run until the end of the coming weekend, consumers can receive up to 500 yuan off from the 13 model up to the latest 15 version, while the subsidy for MacBook Air is up to 800 yuan, according to the firm’s mainland China website.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由com-（共同）和petere（追求）组成，意为“共同追求，竞争，争夺”。在这个例句中，it describes how Apple is offering discounts on its products in China in order to compete with other brands and boost sales.</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>surge (v.) - /ˈsɜːdʒ/ 猛增，激增。    <p>原文例句：Lam said the timing of Apple’s price cuts in China would take advantage of the typical consumer spending surge around the Lunar New Year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于French，意为“激增，猛增”。在这个例句中，it used to describe the typical increase in consumer spending during the Lunar New Year holiday.</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>face mounting competitive pressure - 面临日益增长的竞争压力。    <P>原文例句：Apple has been facing mounting competitive pressure from Chinese rivals, especially Huawei, as they inch towards the premium smartphone segment.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由face（面临），mounting（日益增长的），competitive（竞争的），pressure（压力）构成，表示“面临日益增长的竞争压力”。在这个例句中，it means that Apple is facing increasing competition from Chinese brands like Huawei in the premium smartphone market.</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>According to Counterpoint Research, Apple’s iPhone sales in mainland China dropped by 3 percent year over year in 2023, resulting in a 0.4 percent decline in its market share. - 据市场咨询公司Counterpoint Research的数据，2023年苹果在中国的iPhone销量同比下降3%，导致其市场份额下降0.4%。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Apple’s iPhone sales dropped by 3 percent，其中主语是Apple’s iPhone sales，谓语是dropped，宾语是by 3 percent。year over year in 2023是一个时间状语，表示“在2023年同比”。resulting in a 0.4 percent decline in its market share是一个现在分词短语作结果状语，表示“导致其市场份额下降0.4%”。这个句子的意思是说，据市场咨询公司Counterpoint Research的数据，2023年苹果在中国的iPhone销量同比下降3%，导致其市场份额下降0.4%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示比较。    <p>原文例句：The sale, coming several weeks ahead of the Lunar New Year, the most important annual festival for Chinese people, is expected to boost revenue for Apple amid increasing competition from local players, according to Ivan Lam, senior analyst at market consultancy Counterpoint Research.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个比较句，比较的是两个名词Lunar New Year和most important annual festival。其中Lunar New Year是比较的主语，most important annual festival是比较的对象，比较级是more important。这个句子的意思是说，据Counterpoint Research公司的资深分析师Ivan Lam说，这次促销活动预计将在农历新年到来前几周举行，农历新年是中国最重要的年度节日，这有望提振苹果的收入，因为该公司正面临来自本地竞争对手日益激烈的竞争。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在分词短语 - 表示一种正在进行或持续的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The sale, coming several weeks ahead of the Lunar New Year, the most important annual festival for Chinese people, is expected to boost revenue for Apple amid increasing competition from local players, according to Ivan Lam, senior analyst at market consultancy Counterpoint Research.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在分词短语，由coming修饰名词sale。coming表示正在进行或持续的动作或状态。在这个例句中，it describes when the sale is taking place, which is several weeks before the Lunar New Year.</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Consumers can receive up to 500 yuan off from the 13 model up to the latest 15 version, while the subsidy for MacBook Air is up to 800 yuan</li>
<li>Apple has been facing mounting competitive pressure from Chinese rivals, especially Huawei, as they inch towards the premium smartphone segment</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/cff0e2a7-e348-487c-ad3e-6880e3e4599e_a97e6f8e.jpg" /><figcaption>This photo taken on October 30, 2023 shows people visiting an Apple store in Shenyang, in China’s northeastern Liaoning province. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>US consumer electronics giant Apple is offering Chinese consumers discounts of up to 800 yuan (US$113) on a range of products, from iPhones to MacBooks, in a move to fend off intensifying competition from local rivals such as Huawei Technologies ahead of the Lunar New Year.</p><p>In a sales promotion covering iPhones, iPads, MacBook Air laptops, the Apple Watch and AirPods, which will run until the end of the coming weekend, consumers can receive up to 500 yuan off from the 13 model up to the latest 15 version, while the subsidy for MacBook Air is up to 800 yuan, according to the firm’s mainland China website.</p><p>The sale, coming several weeks ahead of the Lunar New Year, the most important annual festival for Chinese people, is expected to boost revenue for Apple amid increasing competition from local players, according to Ivan Lam, senior analyst at market consultancy Counterpoint Research.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247961/can-beethoven-bach-and-mozart-help-iphone-sales-china-apple-launch-classical-music-app-mainland-amid" title="">Apple to launch classical music app in China amid weak iPhone sales</a></h3><p>Lam said the timing of Apple’s price cuts in China would take advantage of the typical consumer spending surge around the Lunar New Year.</p><p>“The strategic price adjustment will cancel out competitive pressure but will also boost sales growth, especially around the Lunar New Year season,” Lam said in a research note on Monday, adding that the move will also help Apple clear out older models from its inventory.</p><p>Apple has been facing mounting competitive pressure from Chinese rivals, especially Huawei, as they inch towards the premium smartphone segment once ruled over by the Cupertino, California-based company, according to Lam.</p><p>Chinese smartphone brands have rolled out a series of middle to high-end devices over the last few months, many of which are competitively priced from 3,999 yuan, and equipped with functions that rival higher-priced phones, he noted.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247941/foxconn-pushes-electric-vehicle-production-near-its-biggest-iphone-plant-amid-slow-smartphone-sales" title="">Foxconn pushes into car production near its biggest iPhone plant</a></h3><p>These models, representing efforts made by Chinese vendors to vie for the premium smartphone segment, are posing challenges to Apple’s older iPhone models as well as the basic versions of its new iPhone 15 line.</p><p>Total 2023 sales volume for the iPhone in mainland China dropped 3 per cent year on year, which translated to a 0.4 per cent decline in Apple’s market share, according to equity research firm Jefferies.</p><p>Jefferies estimated that Huawei saw its mainland market share in the December quarter gain 2 per cent from the previous quarter, and 6 per cent year on year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Internet titans bury the hatchet as Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos amid ByteDance retreat</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance and Tencent end their online spats and collaborate on video game distribution.</li>    <li>Honour of Kings, Tencent's hit mobile game, will return to ByteDance's Douyin platform.</li>    <li>Tencent is now a potential buyer for ByteDance's gaming operations.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>字节跳动和腾讯结束网络争端，就视频游戏分发展开合作。</li>    <li>腾讯的热门手游《王者荣耀》将重返字节跳动的抖音平台。</li>    <li>腾讯现在是字节跳动游戏业务的潜在买家。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>collaborate (v.) - /kəˈlæbəreɪt/ 合作，协作。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance and Tencent end their online spats and collaborate on video game distribution.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由拉丁语单词“collaborare”演变而来，意思是“共同参与”。它表示团队或个人共同努力完成某事。在这个例句中，it指的是ByteDance和腾讯在网络争议结束后的合作，以分发视频游戏。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>return (v.) - /rɪˈtɜːn/ 返回，回返。    <p>原文例句：Honour of Kings, Tencent's hit mobile game, will return to ByteDance's Douyin platform.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由拉丁语单词“revertere”演变而来，意思是“转身，返回”。它表示某人或某物从一个地方或状态重新回到以前的地方或状态。在这个例句中，it指的是《王者荣耀》这款热门手游重新回到字节跳动的抖音平台。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>potential (n.) - /pəˈtenʃ(ə)l/ 潜力，可能性。    <p>原文例句：Tencent is now a potential buyer for ByteDance's gaming operations.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语单词“potentialis”，意思是“潜在的，有能力的”。它表示某人或某物具有发展或实现的能力或可能性。在这个例句中，it指的是腾讯现在是字节跳动游戏业务的潜在买家。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>online spat - 网络争端，网上纠纷。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance and Tencent end their online spats and collaborate on video game distribution.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由“online”和“spat”组成，分别表示“在线的”和“争吵，纠纷”。它指的是发生在网络上的争吵或纠纷。在这个例句中，it指的是字节跳动和腾讯之间结束的网络争端。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TikTok owner ByteDance has also confirmed it is in talks with multiple potential buyers, including Tencent, for its video game operations. - 抖音所有者字节跳动还确认，正在与包括腾讯在内的多个潜在买家就其视频游戏业务进行谈判。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是ByteDance has confirmed it is in talks，其中主语是ByteDance，谓语是has confirmed，宾语是it is in talks。with multiple potential buyers, including Tencent, for its video game operations是一个介词短语作状语，修饰has confirmed，表示字节跳动正在与包括腾讯在内的多个潜在买家就其视频游戏业务进行谈判。这个句子的意思是说，抖音所有者字节跳动还确认，正在与包括腾讯在内的多个潜在买家就其视频游戏业务进行谈判。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Tencent's eight-year-old Honour of Kings, however, continues to lead as the world’s highest-grossing mobile game in November, according to data from Sensor Tower.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示腾讯的八岁手游王者荣耀，根据Sensor Tower的数据，仍然在11月继续保持着世界最高收入的手机游戏的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Shenzhen-based social media and gaming giant and Beijing-based ByteDance have fought years of bidding wars over Chinese studios</li>
<li>ByteDance’s retreat from the mainstay of Tencent’s business is likely to bring the curtain down on a series of online spats</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/156cf82e-d3ad-47b5-924d-78918b1b7ecc_090eef7e.jpg" /><figcaption>A man plays the popular Honour of Kings online game from Chinese gaming platform Tencent. Photo: AP

</figcaption></figure><p><em>Honour of Kings</em>, the blockbuster video game from market leader Tencent Holdings, will return to ByteDance’s short video app Douyin as the two internet giants bury the hatchet following the TikTok owner’s decision to exit the sector.</p><p>The Shenzhen-based social media and gaming giant and Beijing-based ByteDance have fought years of bidding wars over Chinese video game studios and court battles over copyright, but that has ceased with Tencent now seen as a potential buyer of ByteDance’s gaming operations.</p><p><em>Honour of Kings</em>, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3116088/honour-kings-became-worlds-most-popular-game-it-was-desperate?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">world’s most popular mobile game</a>, will be officially streamed on Douyin’s live-streaming platform from January 21, according to an announcement by the title’s official account on social media platform Weibo.</p><p>Before the official return, live-streaming sessions featuring Chinese esports team XYG began on Douyin on Sunday, and another three-day session with Zhang Daxian, a popular <em>Honour of Kings</em> streamer with over 50 million followers on the video platform, is slated to start on Thursday.</p><p>The game’s return to the ByteDance platform comes five years after a court in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province, banned the streaming of <em>Honour of Kings</em> on Xigua Video, another video streaming site run by the Douyin operator, in 2019.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="FILE PHOTO: A child plays the game Honour of Kings by Tencent at home in Dezhou, Shandong province, China. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/f996b64f-11d5-4a3d-9281-c8c6b150a47f_7eab980c.jpg" title="FILE PHOTO: A child plays the game Honour of Kings by Tencent at home in Dezhou, Shandong province, China. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>FILE PHOTO: A child plays the game Honour of Kings by Tencent at home in Dezhou, Shandong province, China. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>The collaboration between ByteDance’s popular Chinese video app and Tencent’s biggest title comes amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248249/chinas-video-gaming-market-ended-2023-battered-and-bruised-can-world-beating-titles-and-innovation" target="_self" title="">regulatory uncertainties for the industry and a weaker macro environment</a> in China. Tencent’s eight-year-old <em>Honour of Kings</em>, however, continues to lead as the world’s highest-grossing mobile game in November, according to data from Sensor Tower.</p><p>TikTok owner ByteDance has also confirmed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations" target="_self" title="">it is in talks with multiple potential buyers, including Tencent, for its video game operations</a>.</p><p>The retreat by ByteDance from the mainstay of Tencent’s business is likely to bring the curtain down on a series of online spats between the two billionaire founders of the respective companies, which saw a freeze in business dealings and dozens of lawsuits between them.</p><p>The feud started in 2018 with the rapid rise of Douyin, the Chinese sister app of TikTok, when <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/china-tech/article/2145334/tencent-bytedance-ceos-online-spat-over-accusations-blocking-and" target="_self" title="">Tencent boss Pony Ma Huateng and ByteDance founder Zhang Yiming engaged in rare online bickering</a>. Zhang accused Tencent of plagiarising Douyin and Ma fired back, calling the comment “slander”.</p><p>ByteDance later sued the Shenzhen-based tech giant for anticompetitive behaviour and Tencent responded with a defamation lawsuit. Tencent also announced that it <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/china-tech/article/2149094/bytedance-hits-back-tencent-law-suit-anti-competitive-behaviour" target="_self" title="">would halt all existing partnerships with ByteDance and its affiliated companies</a>.</p><p>More legal battles followed in the next few years, as ByteDance accused Tencent of blocking links to Douyin in its flagship WeChat app. Tencent sued ByteDance for copyright infringement by streaming video and gaming content without authorisation.</p><p>However, there has been a growing thaw in icy relations in recent years.</p><p>In 2023 <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3216333/tencent-and-douyin-end-years-copyright-disputes-signing-cooperation-agreement-content-distribution" target="_self" title="">Tencent and Douyin ended their copyright disputes by signing a cooperation agreement on content distribution</a>. Under the deal, Tencent will authorise Douyin to distribute its video content and it clarified copyright rules for users to produce modifications and adaptations.</p><p>Users of Douyin, Xigua Video and Jinri Toutiao, all operated by ByteDance, will also be able to produce derivative works based on Tencent-owned videos.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China EVs: CATL, world’s top battery maker, plans first plant in Beijing to supply Li Auto and Xiaomi</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248522/china-evs-catl-worlds-top-battery-maker-plans-first-plant-beijing-supply-li-auto-and-xiaomi</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>CATL is set to build its first plant in Beijing to meet the rising demand for EVs in mainland China.</li>    <li>The Beijing plant will be key in forming a complete supply chain for EV production in Beijing.</li>    <li>CATL has the world's largest share in the global EV battery market, and will be a key vendor to Li Auto and Xiaomi.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>宁德时代计划在北京建设首家工厂，以满足中国大陆对电动汽车不断增长的需求。</li>    <li>北京工厂将在北京电动汽车生产供应链的建立中发挥重要作用。</li>    <li>宁德时代在全球电动汽车电池市场占有率最高，将成为李易汽车和小米的重点供应商。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>gigawatt-hour (n.) - 吉瓦时，即十亿瓦时的能量。</li>    <li>breakthrough (n.) - 突破，重大进展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take the lead - 带头，引领。</li>    <li>form ... chain - 形成...链。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company, which had a 37.4 per cent share of the global market with an output of 233.4 gigawatt-hours of batteries in the first 11 months of 2023, is set to become a key vendor to Li Auto and Xiaomi when the smartphone maker’s Beijing plant becomes operational, according to analysts.</li>    <p><b>句子分析：</b>This sentence is about CATL's market share and its potential to become a key vendor to Li Auto and Xiaomi. The subject is "The company", and the verb is "is set to become". The phrase "with an output of 233.4 gigawatt-hours of batteries in the first 11 months of 2023" is a prepositional phrase modifying "The company", indicating the company's production capacity. The phrase "when the smartphone maker's Beijing plant becomes operational" is a temporal clause modifying "is set to become", indicating the time when CATL will become a key vendor.</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li><b>现在完成时：</b>表示一个动作或状态在某个时间之前已经完成，而且可能持续到目前。</li>    <li><b>被动语态：</b>表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语而不是主语执行的。</li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>CATL, which had a 37.4 per cent share of the global battery market last year, will start construction on the Beijing plant this year, city’s economic planner says</li>
<li>Ningde-based firm plans to deliver its Shenxing battery, which can offer 400km of driving range with just 10 minutes of charging, before the end of the first quarter</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/8315ae92-7ba5-4bd5-a3b6-40fa428e5900_fcacf6e0.jpg" /><figcaption>CATL’s superfast charging battery Shenxing is displayed at the  International Motor Show in Munich, Germany, in September last year. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3231316/catl-produce-worlds-fastest-ev-battery-offers-400km-driving-range-just-10-minutes-charging-keep" target="_self" title="">Contemporary Amperex Technology (CATL)</a>, the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) battery manufacturer, will build its first plant in Beijing to tap the rising demand for battery-powered cars in mainland China.</p><p>CATL’s plant will help China’s capital city form a complete supply-chain for EV production, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243806/li-auto-xpeng-pace-chinese-ev-makers-race-towards-2023-sales-record-amid-all-time-high-monthly" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a>, the country’s top electric-car start-up, and smartphone maker Xiaomi, both based in Beijing, step up the development of new models.</p><p>CATL, based in Ningde, eastern Fujian province, will begin construction on the plant this year, according to a statement by the Beijing Commission of Development and Reform, the city’s economic planning agency, which did not provide details about the plant’s capacity or launch date. CATL declined to comment.</p><p>The company, which had a 37.4 per cent share of the global market with an output of 233.4 gigawatt-hours of batteries in the first 11 months of 2023, is set to become a key vendor to Li Auto and Xiaomi when the smartphone maker’s Beijing plant becomes operational, according to analysts.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="CATL will serve Li Auto, which has a plant in Beijing. Photo: Xinhua" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/168ee68b-067c-492e-9a57-5d9f00ee09fb_32afda76.jpg" title="CATL will serve Li Auto, which has a plant in Beijing. Photo: Xinhua" width="2000" /><figcaption>CATL will serve Li Auto, which has a plant in Beijing. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure></div><p>Li Auto is already a major player in China’s premium EV segment, and Xiaomi has the potential to become one, said Cao Hua, a partner at private-equity firm Unity Asset Management.</p><p>“So it is reasonable for key suppliers like CATL to establish local production lines to serve its major clients,” Cao said.</p><p>Beijing’s economic planning agency said that Li Auto is considering setting up a production base for car parts, without revealing details.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Li Auto is the closest rival to Tesla in China’s premium EV segment, delivering 376,030 intelligent vehicles to mainland buyers in 2023, a jump of 182.2 per cent year on year.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3216314/tesla-might-lose-ground-local-pretenders-likes-xpeng-byd-steal-march-made-china-evs" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> handed 603,664 units made at its Shanghai Gigafactory to Chinese customers last year, an increase of 37.3 per cent year on year.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246558/xiaomi-unveils-its-first-ev-su7-setting-its-sights-tesla-highly-competitive-china-market" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> unveiled its first model, SU7, at the end of 2023. Featuring a sleek look and a sports-car level of performance, the company plans to begin trial production of the electric sedan in the coming months.</p><p>CEO Lei Jun said Xiaomi will strive to become a top five global carmaker in the next 15 to 20 years.</p><p>In China, the EV penetration rate exceeded 40 per cent in late 2023 amid motorists’ rising penchant for environmentally friendly cars featuring autonomous driving technology and digital cockpits.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Xiaomi CEO Lei Jun unveils the SU7 electric vehicle at an event in Beijing on December 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/d878bca9-63dc-4af1-ac20-f003a09e9824_1126e908.jpg" title="Xiaomi CEO Lei Jun unveils the SU7 electric vehicle at an event in Beijing on December 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Xiaomi CEO Lei Jun unveils the SU7 electric vehicle at an event in Beijing on December 28, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Mainland China is now the world’s largest automotive and EV market, with sales of battery-powered cars accounting for about 60 per cent of the global total.</p><p>UBS analyst Paul Gong said last week that only 10 to 12 companies would survive the cutthroat mainland market by 2030, as intensifying competition has been piling pressure on the 200-plus Chinese EV makers.</p><p>Sales of battery-powered vehicles on the mainland are expected to slow to 20 per cent this year, compared with 37 per cent growth recorded in 2023, according to a forecast by Fitch Ratings in November.</p><p>Meanwhile, CATL will start delivering the world’s fastest-charging electric-car battery before the end of the year’s first quarter, another technological breakthrough to speed up the use of battery-powered cars.</p><p>The Shenxing battery, which can offer 400 kilometres of driving range with just 10 minutes of charging and reach 100 per cent capacity in just 15 minutes as a result of the so-called 4C charging capabilities.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Why a Chinese court’s landmark decision recognising the copyright for an AI-generated image benefits creators in this nascent field</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248510/why-chinese-courts-landmark-decision-recognising-copyright-ai-generated-image-benefits-creators</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>A Beijing Internet Court judge explained that granting legal status to AI-generated content aims to promote creativity and support the emerging generative AI industry.</li>    <li>The court's landmark ruling in November recognized an AI-generated image as an artwork protected by copyright due to the creator's intellectual input and original artistic expression.</li>    <li>The decision intends to encourage people to use new AI tools for creative purposes and stimulate growth in the generative AI sector.</li>    <li>While the ruling adds to ongoing debates on copyright protection for AI-generated content, future disputes will be assessed individually based on the creator's personal expression in each case.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>北京互联网法院的法官朱葛表示，赋予生成式人工智能内容法律地位旨在鼓励人们利用新工具进行创作，并为新兴的生成式人工智能产业提供支持。</li>    <li>法院在去年 11 月作出的具有里程碑意义的裁决承认，人工智能生成的图像作为艺术作品受到版权法的保护，因为该作品体现了创作者的智力投入和原创的艺术表达。</li>    <li>此裁决旨在鼓励人们将人工智能工具用于创作目的，并刺激生成式人工智能领域的增长。</li>    <li>虽然该裁决加剧了人们对人工智能生成内容的版权保护的争论，但针对未来有关人工智能辅助创作中作者个人表达的争端，法院将根据具体情况逐案评判。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>prompt (n.) - /prɑːmpt/ 指示，提示。      <p>原文例句：Li used the US start-up StabilityAI’s Stable Diffusion program to create an image of a young Asian woman and posted it on Chinese social media platform Xiaohongshu.</p>      <p>例句讲解：“prompt”在这个句子中作名词，意为“提示，指示”。它指的是李先生使用美国初创公司 StabilityAI 的 Stable Diffusion 程序创建的图片提示。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>emerge (v.) - /ɪˈmɜːrdʒ/ 涌现，出现。      <p>原文例句：Advances in the use of AI are also expected to transform industries and improve people’s daily lives.</p>      <p>例句讲解：“emerge”在这个句子中作动词，意为“涌现，出现，发生”。它指的是人工智能的使用正在取得进展，预计将转变产业并改善人们的日常生活。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>affiliate (v.) - /əˈfɪliˌeɪt/ 加入，使成为会员。      <p>原文例句：CCID Group, a research unit affiliated with Ministry of Industry and Information Technology.</p>      <p>例句讲解：“affiliate”在这个句子中作动词，意为“加入，使成为会员”。它指的是赛迪顾问，一家隶属于工业和信息化部的研究单位。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>grant legal status - 赋予法律地位。      <p>原文例句：Assigning generative AI content a legal status aims to encourage people to create with new tools, Beijing Internet Court judge Zhu Ge said.</p>      <p>例句讲解：“grant legal status”在这个句子中作动词词组，意为“赋予法律地位”。它指的是北京互联网法院法官朱葛表示，赋予生成式人工智能内容法律地位旨在鼓励人们利用新工具进行创作。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>protect by copyright laws - 受版权法保护。      <p>原文例句：The Beijing Internet Court last November ruled that a picture, generated via the text-to-image software Stable Diffusion, should be considered an artwork under the protection of copyright laws, because of the “originality” and intellectual input of its human creator.</p>      <p>例句讲解：“protect by copyright laws”在这个句子中作动词词组，意为“受版权法保护”。它指的是北京互联网法院去年11月裁定，根据文本到图像软件Stable Diffusion生成的一张图片应被视为受版权法保护的艺术品，因为该作品具有人类创作者的“独创性”和智力投入。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Beijing Internet Court last November ruled that an AI-generated image was an artwork, based on how the creator’s prompts and repeated adjustments came up with a picture that reflected his “aesthetic choice and personalised judgment”.</li>      <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是The Beijing Internet Court ruled that an AI-generated image was an artwork，其中主语是The Beijing Internet Court，谓语是ruled，宾语是an AI-generated image was an artwork。based on how the creator’s prompts and repeated adjustments came up with a picture that reflected his “aesthetic choice and personalised judgment”是一个长定语从句，修饰主语The Beijing Internet Court，表示北京互联网法院做出这一裁决的依据。这个句子的意思是说，北京互联网法院去年11月裁定，根据文本到图像软件Stable Diffusion生成的一张图片应被视为受版权法保护的艺术品，因为该作品具有人类创作者的“独创性”和智力投入。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 被动语态表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的，强调动作或状态的承受者。      <p>原文例句：Beijing court rules AI-generated content covered by copyright, eschews US stand.</p>      <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是AI-generated content，谓语是covered by copyright，宾语是US stand。这个句子的意思是说，北京法院裁定，人工智能生成的内容受到版权保护，回避了美国立场。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 现在完成时表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。      <p>原文例句：China’s aspirations for generative AI continue to evolve amid wider use of the technology around the world.</p>      <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态的句子，主语是China’s aspirations for generative AI，谓语是continue to evolve，宾语是amid wider use of the technology around the world。这个句子的意思是说，中国对生成式人工智能的愿景随着该技术在世界范围内的广泛使用而不断演变。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Assigning generative AI content a legal status aims to encourage people to create with new tools, Beijing Internet Court judge Zhu Ge said</li>
<li>The court’s ruling last November has added fuel to heated arguments on whether AI-generated content should be protected by copyright laws</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/620f2c95-34df-42f3-a6c1-cea2cbba303a_586dc832.jpg" /><figcaption>The Beijing Internet Court last November ruled that an AI-generated image was an artwork, based on how the creator’s prompts and repeated adjustments came up with a picture that reflected his “aesthetic choice and personalised judgment”. Illustration: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>A Chinese court’s decision recognising the copyright of an image generated via <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) aims to encourage such creations and provide a boost to this nascent industry, according to the judge who made the landmark ruling.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243570/beijing-courts-ruling-ai-generated-content-can-be-covered-copyright-eschews-us-stand-far-reaching" target="_self" title="">In the first judgment of its kind in mainland China</a>, the Beijing Internet Court last November ruled that a picture, generated via the text-to-image software Stable Diffusion, should be considered an artwork under the protection of copyright laws, because of the “originality” and intellectual input of its human creator.</p><p>Assigning generative AI content a legal status under certain conditions in this case is aimed at encouraging people to create with new tools, presiding judge Zhu Ge said last week at a lecture that was first reported on Monday by Chinese online news outlet The Paper.</p><p>“If no content created with AI models can be considered artwork, this would deal a blow to the industry,” Zhu was quoted as saying in the report.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The original artificial intelligence-generated image of an Asian lady, left, was at the centre of an intellectual property dispute adjudicated by the Beijing Internet Court on November 27, 2023. To the right of the picture are three images generated during the process of creating the final one that was the subject of infringement. Photo: Xiaohongshu/Stable Diffusion AI" class="image-inline caption" height="746" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/9cd86092-fe03-4638-b826-b367c36403eb_bfa18d87.jpg" title="The original artificial intelligence-generated image of an Asian lady, left, was at the centre of an intellectual property dispute adjudicated by the Beijing Internet Court on November 27, 2023. To the right of the picture are three images generated during the process of creating the final one that was the subject of infringement. Photo: Xiaohongshu/Stable Diffusion AI" width="2000" /><figcaption>The original artificial intelligence-generated image of an Asian lady, left, was at the centre of an intellectual property dispute adjudicated by the Beijing Internet Court on November 27, 2023. To the right of the picture are three images generated during the process of creating the final one that was the subject of infringement. Photo: Xiaohongshu/Stable Diffusion AI</figcaption></figure></div><p>Although the ruling has added fuel to heated arguments on whether AI-generated content should be protected by copyright laws, the Beijing Internet Court has asserted that future disputes about an author’s personal expression in images created with AI’s help should be judged on a case-by-case basis.</p><p>The intellectual property infringement lawsuit was initiated in May last year by the plaintiff surnamed Li, who used the US start-up StabilityAI’s Stable Diffusion program to create an image of a young Asian woman and posted it on Chinese social media platform <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3141392/chinese-lifestyle-platform-xiaohongshu-known-little-red?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Xiaohongshu</a>.</p><p>Li sued a blogger surnamed Liu for allegedly using that image without permission in a post on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/2183325/baidu-draws-ire-netizens-promoting-its-own-content-search-results?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Baijiahao</a>, a Chinese content-sharing platform owned by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>.</p><p>The court subsequently ruled in favour of Li. It said Li’s AI-generated image was an artwork, based on how he had continuously added prompts and repeatedly adjusted the parameters to come up with a picture that reflected his “aesthetic choice and personalised judgment”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243570/beijing-courts-ruling-ai-generated-content-can-be-covered-copyright-eschews-us-stand-far-reaching" title="">Beijing court rules AI-generated content covered by copyright, eschews US stand</a></h3><p>The court ordered the defendant Liu to issue a public apology as well as pay the plaintiff 500 yuan (US$70.43) in damages and 50 yuan for court fees.</p><p>Zhu, the presiding judge, said in her lecture that the ruling was made with the potential implications for “emerging industries” in mind, according to The Paper’s report. It said Zhu hoped her decision in the case could serve as a reference for future disputes.</p><p>The court’s ruling has come as China’s aspirations for generative AI continue to evolve amid wider use of the technology around the world. Advances in the use of AI are also expected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3228219/why-many-china-unlike-us-see-ai-force-good?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">transform industries and improve people’s daily lives</a>.</p><p>China’s generative AI industry is forecast to contribute <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245217/chinese-generative-ai-account-third-industrys-economic-value-2035-beijing-think-tank-says" target="_self" title="">30 trillion yuan worth of economic value by 2035</a>, accounting for a third of the industry’s global value of 90 trillion yuan, according to a report by the CCID Group, a research unit affiliated with Ministry of Industry and Information Technology.</p><p>Many <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-technology" target="_self" title="">Chinese tech</a> firms have also ramped up their efforts to grow their businesses using generative AI. Chinese delivery services giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a>, for example, recently launched Wow, a chatbot that purports to respond to user questions with a personal touch.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, owner of the South China Morning Post, featured an online shop for digital products based on Baidu’s virtual assistant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240971/china-big-tech-firms-experiment-personalised-chatbots-amid-push-monetise-generative-ai-technologies" target="_self" title="">Duxiaoxiao</a> during the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/singles-day-1111" target="_self" title="">Singles’ Day</a> campaign last year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba, TikTok woo US with AI and live-streaming e-commerce at CES trade show, setting the tone for 2024</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248469/alibaba-tiktok-woo-us-ai-and-live-streaming-e-commerce-ces-trade-show-setting-tone-2024</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba.com and TikTok showcased their strengths in AI and live-streaming e-commerce at CES 2024.</li>    <li>Alibaba.com's Smart Assistant helps buyers navigate its sourcing website using multiple large language models (LLMs).</li>    <li>TikTok Shop focused on live-streaming e-commerce at CES, inviting influencers to sell products directly from the trade show.</li>    <li>Chinese e-commerce platforms like Shein and Temu benefit from their connections with mainland Chinese suppliers.</li>    <li>Start-ups like Spaceship use AI to help brands manage their own e-commerce shops and optimize logistics.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>阿里巴巴和TikTok分别在2024年CES上展示了他们在人工智能和直播电商方面的实力。</li>    <li>阿里巴巴国际站的智能助手通过多个大型语言模型（LLM）帮助买家在其采购网站上查找产品。</li>    <li>TikTok Shop在CES上专注于直播电商，邀请有影响力的人直接在展会上销售产品。</li>    <li>像希音和拼多多旗下的Temu这样的中国电商平台受益于它们与中国大陆供应商的联系。</li>    <li>像Spaceship这样的初创企业利用人工智能帮助品牌管理自己的电子商务商店并优化物流。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>electronic (n.) - /ˌɛlɪkˈtrɒnɪk/ 电子，电子产品。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba.com, the international business-to-business wholesale marketplace of South China Morning Post owner Alibaba, launched its Smart Assistant feature at the world’s largest consumer electronics show, with computers set up around the centre of its booth to show how the embedded chatbot can help buyers navigate the sourcing website.</p>    <p>例句讲解：electronic在句子中作形容词，修饰show，表示电子产品展。electronic由electro（电的）和-ic（形容词后缀）构成，表示“电子的，电子产品”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>influencer (n.) - /ˈɪnfluənsər/ 有影响力的人，意见领袖。    <p>原文例句：TikTok Shop set up a booth for influencers to sell their wares via live streaming from CES, showing where the platform figures its strengths lie.</p>    <p>例句讲解：influencer在句子中作主语，表示有影响力的人。influencer由influence（影响）和-er（名词后缀）构成，表示“有影响力的人，意见领袖”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>powered by - 由……提供动力，由……驱动。    <p>原文例句：Smart Assistant is powered by multiple large language models (LLMs) – the technology used to train ChatGPT and similar services – including home-grown Tongyi Qianwen, depending on use case, an Alibaba.com representative said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：powered by是固定搭配，表示“由……提供动力，由……驱动”。在这个例句中，powered by表示智能助理由多个大型语言模型提供动力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>live-streaming e-commerce - 直播电商。    <p>原文例句：At the recent CES trade show in Las Vegas, Alibaba.com and TikTok Shop focused on their respective strengths in artificial intelligence and live-streaming e-commerce.</p>    <p>例句讲解：live-streaming e-commerce是名词短语，表示直播电商。live-streaming表示“直播”，e-commerce表示“电子商务”。live-streaming e-commerce是近年来兴起的一种新的电子商务模式，是指通过网络直播平台进行商品销售的电子商务活动。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese internet giants Alibaba Group Holding and TikTok each put their technological prowess on display last week at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, where their respective artificial intelligence (AI) and live-streaming e-commerce products set the tone for how they plan to embed themselves further into daily life in overseas markets. - 中国互联网巨头阿里巴巴集团和TikTok分别在上周举行的2024年拉斯维加斯CES展上展示了各自的技术实力，他们各自的人工智能（AI）和直播电商产品为他们如何进一步融入海外市场人们的日常生活定下了基调。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Chinese internet giants Alibaba Group Holding and TikTok each put their technological prowess on display last week at CES 2024 in Las Vegas，其中主语是Chinese internet giants Alibaba Group Holding and TikTok，谓语是put，宾语是their technological prowess。where their respective artificial intelligence (AI) and live-streaming e-commerce products set the tone for how they plan to embed themselves further into daily life in overseas markets是一个定语从句，修饰主句中的they，说明他们各自的人工智能（AI）和直播电商产品为他们如何进一步融入海外市场人们的日常生活定下了基调。这个句子的意思是说，中国互联网巨头阿里巴巴集团和TikTok分别在上周举行的2024年拉斯维加斯CES展上展示了各自的技术实力，他们各自的人工智能（AI）和直播电商产品为他们如何进一步融入海外市场人们的日常生活定下了基调。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>In its international launch at CES, Alibaba.com’s new AI chatbot showed how it can help buyers with sourcing for merchandise. - 阿里巴巴国际站的新的人工智能聊天机器人展示了它如何帮助买家采购商品。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Alibaba.com’s new AI chatbot，谓语是showed，宾语是how it can help buyers with sourcing for merchandise。这个句子的意思是说，阿里巴巴国际站的新的人工智能聊天机器人展示了它如何帮助买家采购商品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由分词及其修饰语构成的短语，在句中作定语、状语或补语。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba.com, the international business-to-business wholesale marketplace of South China Morning Post owner Alibaba, launched its Smart Assistant feature at the world’s largest consumer electronics show, with computers set up around the centre of its booth to show how the embedded chatbot can help buyers navigate the sourcing website.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，with computers set up around the centre of its booth to show how the embedded chatbot can help buyers navigate the sourcing website是一个分词短语，作状语，修饰主句中的launched，说明了阿里巴巴国际站推出智能助理功能的具体情况。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>定语从句 - 由关系词引导的句子，在句中作定语，修饰先行词。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，including the latest iPhone 15是一个定语从句，修饰先行词other products，说明了公司在印度生产的其他产品包括最新的iPhone 15。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In its international launch at CES, Alibaba.com’s new AI chatbot showed how it can help buyers with sourcing for merchandise</li>
<li>TikTok Shop set up a booth for influencers to sell their wares via live streaming from CES, showing where the platform figures its strengths lie</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/4b4e3c96-5e9f-4a0e-a12a-4b8ebd59c282_e1e0e1d3.jpg" /><figcaption>At the recent CES trade show in Las Vegas, Alibaba.com and TikTok Shop focused on their respective strengths in artificial intelligence and live-streaming e-commerce. Photos: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a> each put their technological prowess on display last week at <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ces" target="_self" title="">CES 2024</a> in Las Vegas, where their respective <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/live-streaming" target="_self" title="">live-streaming</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> products set the tone for how they plan to embed themselves further into daily life in overseas markets.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" target="_self" title="">Alibaba.com</a>, the international business-to-business wholesale marketplace of South China Morning Post owner Alibaba, launched its Smart Assistant feature at the world’s largest consumer electronics show, with computers set up around the centre of its booth to show how the embedded chatbot can help buyers navigate the sourcing website.</p><p>Smart Assistant is powered by multiple large language models (LLMs) – the technology used to train <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> and similar services – including home-grown <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234385/alibaba-opens-ai-model-tongyi-qianwen-public-competition-baidu-tencent-and-other-chinese-big-tech" target="_self" title="">Tongyi Qianwen</a>, depending on use case, an Alibaba.com representative said.</p><p>“With advances in AI, we are ushering in the next generation of sourcing and empowering small businesses to succeed with our Smart Assistant at their side,” Chris Lu, general manager at Alibaba.com North America, said in a statement last week.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Alibaba.com booth features the e-commerce platform’s artificial intelligence-powered Smart Assistant, designed to help users navigate the sourcing website, at the CES trade show in Las Vegas on January 12, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1356" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/7ea9cc8d-352b-43d1-8802-d0195ff7dfbc_4677c949.jpg" title="The Alibaba.com booth features the e-commerce platform’s artificial intelligence-powered Smart Assistant, designed to help users navigate the sourcing website, at the CES trade show in Las Vegas on January 12, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Alibaba.com booth features the e-commerce platform’s artificial intelligence-powered Smart Assistant, designed to help users navigate the sourcing website, at the CES trade show in Las Vegas on January 12, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant showed how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year. No tech giant’s exhibition was complete without showing off its effort in that space.</p><p>By putting generative AI at the centre of its exhibition, Alibaba.com made it clear where it thought the platform’s advantage lies, despite some grumblings from a marketing manager that the product was not quite yet ready for prime time, according to a brand ambassador at the booth.</p><p>A number of CES attendees at the Alibaba.com presentation were made up of select “gold suppliers”, or those that pay for a premium membership on the platform, according to some exhibitors.</p><p>A test of Smart Assistant by the Post showed the all-too-common limitations of new LLM-powered chatbots. When asked about the best options for sourcing a 10,000-milliampere-hour power bank, it offered a link to search results for the product on Alibaba.com. A follow-up query on the best way to determine differences in quality among suppliers resulted in a generic response about checking certifications and standards.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An online influencer is seen at the TikTok Shop booth preparing for a live-streaming session to sell goods directly from CES inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas on January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1256" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/b4f2b04e-92e3-4588-8f81-51fac86ad8ed_ab01d493.jpg" title="An online influencer is seen at the TikTok Shop booth preparing for a live-streaming session to sell goods directly from CES inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas on January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>An online influencer is seen at the TikTok Shop booth preparing for a live-streaming session to sell goods directly from CES inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas on January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned TikTok, already famous for its more traditional recommendation algorithms that have made its short video service so difficult to put down, went in a different direction at CES. Its TikTok Shop booth inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas, was set up with a live-streaming area where some influencers were invited to sell their wares directly from the trade show.</p><p>While TikTok remains best known outside China as a platform to consume bite-sized videos, live-streaming e-commerce is already big business for the app’s Chinese version, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>. E-commerce is seen by Beijing-based parent ByteDance as an important area for future growth.</p><p>TikTok Shop representatives were roaming the CES floor looking for companies they can convince to sell on the platform. That task may have been harder for the US team. A US-based TikTok Shop employee told Shenzhen-based mechanical keyboard maker Keychron that he was not allowed to sign up Chinese companies. Only their team in mainland China can on-board those suppliers.</p><p>Connections with mainland Chinese suppliers are seen as the secret weapon for new e-commerce entrants like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3240612/china-founded-e-commerce-start-shein-said-aim-us90-billion-valuation-us-ipo" target="_self" title="">Shein</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3243140/discount-e-commerce-giant-pdd-nearly-doubles-quarterly-revenue-closing-alibaba-meituan-also-chalks" target="_self" title="">PDD Holdings</a>’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>. These platforms are taking on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon.com</a> on its home turf with dirt-cheap products, which are sold as they roll off the factory floor from their mainland suppliers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>“Temu or Shein can get those very low-cost items and low-cost shipping because they have the volume,” said Stanley Wong, co-founder and chief product officer of Hong Kong-based Spaceship, which exhibited at CES under its Taiwanese entity. “They have very professional teams to do that kind of supply chain management.”</p><p>TikTok Shop is also seeking to take on Shein and Temu. TikTok sees international e-commerce expansion so important to its future that it <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244634/tiktok-restarts-e-commerce-indonesia-us15-billion-investment-goto-gojek-tokopedia-unit" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244634/tiktok-restarts-e-commerce-indonesia-us15-billion-investment-goto-gojek-tokopedia-unit">bought a 75 per cent stake</a> in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/indonesia" target="_self" title="">Indonesia</a>’s largest online shopping platform, enabling the firm restart its local operations which had earlier been suspended by regulators in Southeast Asia’s largest economy.</p><p>Chinese suppliers are also Alibaba.com’s bread and butter. While it is ostensibly a global sourcing platform, the vast majority of companies on Alibaba.com are Chinese, which typically offer big cost advantages owing to the mainland’s vast manufacturing supply chain.</p><p>Even <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups">start-ups</a> are trying to use AI to help companies navigate the changing landscape of e-commerce in the West. Spaceship, for example, uses AI to help brands manage their own shops with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3146298/tiktok-partners-shopify-latest-step-expand-its-e-commerce-efforts" target="_self" title="">Canadian e-commerce firm Shopify</a> to determine the best logistics options for goods manufactured in China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" title="">Alibaba pushes new AI tool to help wholesale merchants manage overseas clients</a></h3><p>“Our focus is to enable individual sellers to” achieve cost-effective supply chain management like Shein and Temu, Spaceship’s Wong said.</p><p>As more merchants try to control their own brands and reduce the money they lose to platforms like Shein, Temu and TikTok Shop by operating their own sites, services like Spaceship make sense when making price comparisons on logistics solutions.</p><p>Still, Spaceship does not have its own generative AI product yet to take on the likes of Alibaba. The company said it is considering one for customer service.</p><p>Many of the underpinnings of AI LLMs are open-source code, making the technology easily accessible to start-ups even if they do not have the data advantage of tech giants. But it could be some time before the kinks are worked out and these start-ups can handle more sophisticated requirements of business users.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: Hong Kong start-ups attract interest from Microsoft, Best Buy amid overseas push</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248382/ces-2024-hong-kong-start-ups-attract-interest-microsoft-best-buy-amid-overseas-push</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  English: Microsoft CEO held discussions with a Hong Kong start-up that makes an AI-powered belt for the visually impaired; this year's CES saw an increase in interest from retailers and partners in Hong Kong start-ups.Chinese: 微软首席执行官与香港一家制造人工智能导盲腰带的初创公司进行了会谈；今年的 CES 展会上，来自零售商和其他潜在合作伙伴对香港初创企业的兴趣有所增加。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Hong Kong start-ups gain attention at CES 2024, including a belt for the visually impaired and furniture with embedded speakers.</li>    <li>Theme: Hong Kong start-ups showcase innovative products at CES, attracting interest from global tech giants and potential partners.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Hong Kong's efforts to become a tech hub see positive results as start-ups secure potential business deals and partnerships.</li>    <li>Main information: Microsoft CEO visits Hong Kong pavilion and meets with AI Guided, a company that makes a belt with haptic feedback for the blind; other start-ups, such as Invisible & Innovation Technology and XOXO Beverages, also receive interest from potential partners.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中文：微软首席执行官与一家制造人工智能导盲腰带的香港初创企业进行了会谈；今年的 CES 展会上，来自零售商和其他潜在合作伙伴对香港初创企业的兴趣有所增加。  <ul>    <li>摘要：香港初创企业在 2024 年的 CES 展上备受关注，其中包括一条专为视觉障碍者设计的腰带和一件带有嵌入式扬声器的家具。</li>    <li>主题：香港初创企业在 CES 展会上展示创新产品，吸引了来自全球科技巨头和潜在合作伙伴的兴趣。</li>    <li>观点：香港努力成为科技中心取得积极成果，因为初创企业获得了潜在的商业交易和合作伙伴关系。</li>    <li>主要信息：微软首席执行官访问香港展馆并会见了 AI Guided，这是一家制造带有触觉反馈腰带以帮助盲人的公司；其他初创企业，如 Invisible & Innovation Technology 和 XOXO Beverages，也引起了潜在合作伙伴的兴趣。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>navigate (v.) - /ˈnævɪgeɪt/ 导航。    <p>原文例句：The dream of our company is that in three to five years … visually impaired people can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world.” - 我们的公司梦想是，在三到五年内……视障人士能够有一些免提体验来导航世界。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由拉丁语中的navigare（航行）演变而来的，意思是“航行，驾驶船只”。在这个例子中，它指的是视障人士使用人工智能导盲腰带在世界中导航，强调了该产品帮助他们自由移动和独立性的能力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>retail chain (n.) - /ˈriːteɪl tʃeɪn/ 零售连锁店。    <p>原文例句：“Best Buy always wants to source something new,” said Lee. “Furniture is a very traditional thing that [has not had] much disruptive design or link with technology.” - 李说：“百思买总是希望采购新产品。” “家具是一种非常传统的东西，[不具备]太多颠覆性设计或与技术的联系。”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组指的是由多个零售店组成的连锁店，这些零售店通常由同一个公司拥有和运营，并销售相同或类似的产品。在这个例子中，它指的是百思买，这是美国最大的电子产品零售连锁店之一。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>carbon neutral (adj.) - /ˈkɑːbən ˈnjuːtrəl/ 碳中和。    <p>原文例句：“From a tech area standpoint, I think the opportunity to come to Hong Kong is surging,” said HKSTP’s Yiu. “The number of start-ups that we nurture every year is an increasing trend.” - 香港科技园的姚说：“从科技领域的角度来看，我认为来到香港的机会正在激增。” “我们每年培育的初创企业数量呈增长趋势。”</p>    <p>例句讲解：carbon neutral（碳中和）是指通过植树、使用可再生能源或减少碳排放等措施，将排放到大气中的二氧化碳和其他温室气体量减少到零。在这个例子中，carbon neutral指的是香港政府的目标，即在 2050 年实现碳中和，强调了该市致力于减少温室气体排放并保护环境的承诺。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>hands-free experience - 解放双手的体验。    <p>原文例句：“The dream of our company is that in three to five years … visually impaired people can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world.” - 我们的公司梦想是，在三到五年内……视障人士能够有一些免提体验来导航世界。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组指的是无需使用双手就能进行某项任务或操作的体验。在这个例子中，它指的是视障人士使用人工智能导盲腰带在世界中导航的体验，强调了该产品帮助他们减少对辅助设备的依赖，提高独立性和自由移动能力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>We really mean to help them get new business.” - 我们的真正目的是帮助他们获得新业务。</p>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是We really mean，其中主语是We，谓语是mean，宾语是to help them get new business。really是一个副词，表示“真正地，实际上”。mean是一个动词，表示“意味着，意指”。to help them get new business是一个不定式短语作宾语，表示帮助他们获得新业务。这个句子的意思是说，我们的真正目的是帮助他们获得新业务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设或不现实的情况。    <p>原文例句：“Best Buy always wants to source something new,” said Lee. “Furniture is a very traditional thing that [has not had] much disruptive design or link with technology.” - 李说：“百思买总是希望采购新产品。” “家具是一种非常传统的东西，[不具备]太多颠覆性设计或与技术的联系。”</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例子中，has not had是一个虚拟语气的过去式，表示家具不具备或者没有过太多颠覆性设计或与技术的联系。这里的虚拟语气是为了表示一个假设或不现实的情况，即家具通常不被认为是具有颠覆性设计或与技术联系的。这种虚拟语气的使用有助于强调家具行业的传统性以及 Invisible Tech 产品的创新性。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella stopped by the booth of a start-up at the Hong Kong pavilion that makes an AI-powered belt to guide blind people</li>
<li>Other start-ups say they have received interest at the show from retailers and other potential partners as Hong Kong firms look overseas</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/c4aa2f7b-bda4-4f1d-8d18-95ebfe7901e8_6e29421c.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella meets with Steve Kong, co-founder and chief technology officer of AI Guided, at CES to learn more about the Hong Kong start-up’s belt for guiding the blind. Photo: Handout </figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft">Microsoft</a> and Best Buy expressed interest in Hong Kong <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups">start-ups</a> at CES 2024, after the city’s pavilion at the world’s largest consumer electronics show saw the most interest there in years.</p><p>Last Tuesday, the first day of the trade show in Las Vegas, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella swung by the Tech Hong Kong pavilion to chat with AI Guided, a company that makes a belt with haptic feedback for obstacle detection, helping to guide the blind.</p><p>“Microsoft really supports accessibility technology,” said Steve Kong, co-founder and chief technology officer of AI Guided. “The dream of our company is that in three to five years … visually impaired people can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world.”</p><p>AI Guided is one of 20 Hong Kong-based companies exhibiting with the city’s start-up pavilion this year, a big improvement over the eight that exhibited last year because of the last-minute lifting of Covid-19 restrictions.</p><p>Even leading up to the show, Hong Kong Science and Technology Park (HKSTP) said 40 companies applied to exhibit in the Eureka Park start-up area, a marked improvement over previous years, according to H L Yiu, corporate development officer for HKSTP, which runs the pavilion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248116/ces-2024-china-smartphone-brand-realme-unveils-new-handset-sidelines-trade-show-its-biggest-rivals" title="">Realme unveils 12 Pro series smartphone in parallel event to CES</a></h3><p>“We had to make some selection of companies that have more of a mature level of readiness in terms of being ready to sell,” Yiu said in an interview. “We really mean to help them get new business.”</p><p>With limited space, HKSTP focused on picking companies that were closer to having products ready to go, or even already in the market, with the goal of picking up business deals at CES.</p><p>For some, that could pan out in a big way.</p><p>Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology, aka Invisible Tech, which builds speakers into furniture, said it has received interest from Best Buy. A representative from the largest electronics retail chain in the US told Invisible Tech that it had not seen other products like its cabinet with an embedded speaker in the base, according to the start-up’s co-founder Patrick Lee.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1507" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/8c535fe2-a0b7-472a-a511-c0de39fad1c7_cffec5fe.jpg" title="Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Best Buy always wants to source something new,” said Lee. “Furniture is a very traditional thing that [has not had] much disruptive design or link with technology.”</p><p>Invisible Tech also uses recycled materials in some parts of its products. Henry Cheung, the company’s other co-founder, said the company wants to “help Hong Kong fulfil its carbon neutral mission”. The city aims to be carbon neutral by 2050.</p><p>The Hong Kong pavilion at this year’s CES, which concluded on Friday, featured a variety of start-ups that make products ranging from the quirky to the practical.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" title="">Chinese EV maker shows off flying car but admits urban use is far off</a></h3><p>XOXO Beverages already has its cocktail-making machine in about 10 bars and restaurants in Hong Kong, but it has not expanded to home use yet. Co-founder Peter Yau said CES was the best show the company has been to.</p><p>“People from all around the world come by and are very interested in the product,” Yau said. “[We got] a lot of contacts, and we’re looking to see what we can do after [the show] with those guys.”</p><p>Two of the participating companies, Sitan Semiconductor International and Raysolve Technology, make micro-LED displays, something that has become more important amid rising interest in augmented reality glasses.</p><p>Sitan was started at the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, and the company said its tech has already found its way into products from big brands like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tcl" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tcl">TCL</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo">Oppo</a> and Meizu – although not all of these products have been released.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1613" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/2b040077-b3ac-4878-bb0e-daa1b2414354_75a0b9ef.jpg" title="XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>For most of the start-ups, though, CES was about getting leads and looking for ways to expand beyond their home market. Getting the attention of a tech giant like Microsoft is one way to achieve that.</p><p>Asked about the prospects of Microsoft investing, AI Guided’s Kong said, “I hope so … I will still have another discussion with them, so we’ll see.”</p><p>This kind of attention also may help the Hong Kong government justify its efforts to turn the city into a tech hub, which has had mixed results in a city better known as a regional financial hub.</p><p>“From a tech area standpoint, I think the opportunity to come to Hong Kong is surging,” said HKSTP’s Yiu. “The number of start-ups that we nurture every year is an increasing trend.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Elon Musk’s Tesla loses US$94 billion in market valuation as winter sets in for global electric vehicle market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248400/elon-musks-tesla-loses-us94-billion-market-valuation-winter-sets-global-electric-vehicle-market</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tesla's stock has dropped significantly in the first two weeks of 2024 due to negative news such as price cuts, rising labor costs, and slowing demand for EVs.</li>    <li>The company's market capitalization has seen its biggest loss since its IPO in 2010, and its shares have experienced their worst start to a year since 2016.</li>    <li>Tesla's aggressive price cuts have eroded its profit margin, and the company is facing increased competition from other EV makers, particularly BYD.</li>    <li>Production disruptions and security concerns have further impacted Tesla's operations. The company's valuation is still high compared to traditional car companies, largely due to expectations of future growth and the development of self-driving vehicles.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>特斯拉今年头两周股价大幅下跌，原因是其陷入一系列负面新闻，包括降价、劳动力成本上升和电动汽车需求放缓。</li>    <li>自2010年上市以来，该公司的市值遭遇最大损失，其股价也创下自2016年以来最糟糕的年度开局。</li>    <li>特斯拉的激进降价行为侵蚀了其利润率，且该公司面临来自其他电动汽车制造商（特别是比亚迪）的激烈竞争。</li>    <li>生产中断和安全问题进一步影响了特斯拉的运营。与传统汽车公司相比，该公司的估值仍然很高，主要原因是对未来增长和自动驾驶汽车发展的预期。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>barrage (n.) - /bəˈrɑːʒ/ 猛烈的炮火。    <p>原文例句：The company has lost more than US$94 billion in market valuation in just the first two weeks of this year. It is not hard to figure out why, as the Austin, Texas-based EV maker has been pounded by a barrage of negative news.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于French，表示“猛烈的炮火”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉在今年头两周内遭受的负面新闻。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>stagnating (adj.) - /ˈstæɡneɪtɪŋ/ 停滞的。    <p>原文例句：“Investors’ main concern on Tesla is stagnating growth,” Cowen analyst Jeffrey Osborne said in an interview.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，表示“停滞的”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉投资者对该公司增长停滞的担忧。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>exacerbating (v.) - /ɪɡˈzæsərbeɪtɪŋ/ 加剧。    <p>原文例句：“We are going through a cyclical downturn for EVs, but competitive dynamics are exacerbating the cyclical pressures,” Ivana Delevska, chief investment officer at Spear Invest, said in an interview.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，表示“加剧”。在这个例句中，它指的是激烈的竞争加剧了电动汽车行业的周期性压力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>woes (n.) - /woʊz/ 灾难，不幸。    <p>原文例句：Adding to the woes, Tesla has had to divert shipments destined for its Berlin plant after Western military actions and security concerns in the Red Sea, and is suspending most production at its plant near the German capital from January 29 to February 11, according to a person familiar with the matter.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，表示“灾难，不幸”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉在柏林工厂的生产问题以及西方军事行动和红海安全问题对特斯拉的影响。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>vulnerable (adj.) - /ˈvʌlnərəbəl/ 脆弱的。    <p>原文例句：Tesla’s biggest problem may be its past success and the hope it generated. As investors piled into the stock, Tesla’s market capitalisation ballooned, making it way larger than any other car company in the world. However, with the shares priced for perfection, that also made them highly vulnerable to big reactions to any negative news.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，表示“脆弱的”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉的股价对负面新闻高度敏感。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>roll out (v.) - /rəʊl aʊt/ 推出。    <p>原文例句：Tesla chief executive Elon Musk applauds the roll-out of new electric vehicles at the opening of the firm’s Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany on March 22, 2022. Photo: AP    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“推出”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉首席执行官埃隆·马斯克在2022年3月22日为柏林-勃兰登堡超级工厂开工。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in an effort to - 为了。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“为了”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉自去年初以来大幅降价是为了提振需求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The hit to Tesla’s market capitalisation to start the year is the biggest the company has seen over a similar period since it went public in 2010.    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是The hit to Tesla’s market capitalisation，谓语是is，宾语是the biggest the company has seen over a similar period since it went public in 2010。这个句子的意思是，特斯拉今年开年的市值损失是自2010年上市以来同期最大的损失。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The pressure is only mounting, now that production workers at Tesla’s US plants are getting pay rises.    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The pressure is only mounting，其中主语是The pressure，谓语是is mounting。now that production workers at Tesla’s US plants are getting pay rises是一个时间状语从句，表示“现在特斯拉美国工厂的生产工人正在涨工资”。这个句子的意思是，随着特斯拉美国工厂的生产工人涨工资，压力只会越来越大。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Past perfect tense - 过去完成时。    <p>原文例句：Tesla had a blockbuster 2023, as its shares more than doubled in 12 months.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。它表示在过去的某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示特斯拉在2023年取得了骄人的业绩，其股价在12个月内上涨了一倍多。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Present perfect continuous tense - 现在完成进行时。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early 2023 in an effort to boost demand.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has been + 现在分词。它表示从过去的某个时间点开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示特斯拉自2023年初以来一直大幅降价，以提振需求。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Tesla’s losses in the first two weeks of this year have come from a barrage of negative news, including another price cut for its made-in-China cars</li>
<li>The US carmaker has been cutting prices on its vehicles aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/83cb01fa-622e-4130-b271-fd9276597c55_850fb60a.jpg" /><figcaption>Tesla chief executive Elon Musk applauds the roll-out of new electric vehicles at the opening of the firm’s Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant  in Germany on March 22, 2022. Photo:  AP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> had a blockbuster 2023, as its shares more than doubled in 12 months. But 2024 is starting on a different note, with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/elon-musk" target="_self" title="">Elon Musk</a>’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle</a> (EV) maker off to its worst start to any year – ever.</p><p>The company has lost more than US$94 billion in market valuation in just the first two weeks of this year. It is not hard to figure out why, as the Austin, Texas-based EV maker has been pounded by a barrage of negative news: an about-face on EVs from the car rental giant Hertz Global Holdings, yet another price cut for its cars <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-manufacturing" target="_self" title="">made in China</a>, and signs of rising labour costs.</p><p>All of this comes in the face of slowing growth in demand for EVs, especially in the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>.</p><p>“Investors’ main concern on Tesla is stagnating growth,” Cowen analyst Jeffrey Osborne said in an interview. The price cuts in China only fan those concerns, because it is starting to look like “a race to the bottom for the EV industry given intense competition in that market”.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/b52c250b-b6c8-47e5-91ec-7f2278c772c1_a66cec46.jpg" title="A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The hit to Tesla’s market capitalisation to start the year is the biggest the company has seen over a similar period since it went public in 2010. In percentage terms, Tesla’s 12 per cent drop since the start of January is the worst since 2016, when the stock fell 14 per cent over the first nine trading days of the year.</p><p>To make matters worse, the odds of an imminent turnaround for the EV maker do not look good.</p><p>Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early 2023 in an effort to boost demand. But the result has been a steady erosion of its once-hefty profit margin. Tesla’s automotive gross margin ex-regulatory credits for the third quarter fell to 16.3 per cent from 27.9 per cent a year ago. And the pressure is only mounting, now that production workers at Tesla’s US plants are getting pay rises.</p><p>“We are going through a cyclical downturn for EVs, but competitive dynamics are exacerbating the cyclical pressures,” Ivana Delevska, chief investment officer at Spear Invest, said in an interview. “Price cuts and plummeting margins are all a function of these unfavourable competitive dynamics.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing" title="">Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</a></h3><p>Adding to the woes, Tesla has had to divert shipments destined for its Berlin plant after Western military actions and security concerns in the Red Sea, and is suspending most production at its plant near the German capital from January 29 to February 11, according to a person familiar with the matter.</p><p>Tesla first warned about the deceleration in EV demand during its October third-quarter earnings report. Almost immediately after, carmakers and suppliers across the globe chimed in with their own downbeat forecasts. Many carmakers dialled back their plans for expansion.</p><p>Then, earlier this month, Tesla reported its fourth-quarter delivery numbers. While they were better than what analysts expected, they put the company behind China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD Co</a> in global electric-car sales.</p><p>The result has been a rude awakening for Tesla investors. Last year, the stock was the eighth best performer in the S&amp;P 500. So far this year, it is the eighth worst.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa" class="image-inline caption" height="1201" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/47b22035-65d8-46f4-a5cf-8ceaf3d20b48_c243b8f2.jpg" title="Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa" width="2000" /><figcaption>Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Naturally, Musk is taking a big hit personally. The world’s richest person, who gained more wealth last year than anyone else on the planet, has seen his net worth shrink by US$23 billion so far this year, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index.</p><p>Musk regained the top spot on Bloomberg’s wealth index last year, overtaking LVMH Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton founder and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226276/lvmh-boss-bernard-arnaults-visit-highlights-growing-importance-huge-mainland-chinese-market-luxury" target="_self" title="">Bernard Arnault</a>, but now <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon.com</a> founder and executive chairman <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jeff-bezos" target="_self" title="">Jeff Bezos</a> is rapidly closing in, with US$179 billion to Musk’s US$206 billion as of Friday’s close.</p><p>The bulk of Musk’s net worth comes from his 13 per cent stake in Tesla and about 304 million exercisable stock options. He also owns about 42 per cent of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/spacex" target="_self" title="">Space Exploration Technologies</a>, which is valued at about US$53 billion, according to Bloomberg’s wealth index.</p><p>With all that being said, Tesla remains a key player in the global transition from petrol-powered vehicles to largely electric ones. The reason: the company is so far ahead of its potential rivals. China’s BYD may have surpassed Tesla in the number of units sold, but it still lags in revenue and profits. And BYD does not sell cars in the US, where Tesla remains the market leader.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>In many ways, Tesla’s biggest problem may be its past success and the hope it generated. As investors piled into the stock, Tesla’s market capitalisation ballooned, making it way larger than any other car company in the world. However, with the shares priced for perfection, that also made them highly vulnerable to big reactions to any negative news.</p><p>That is why so many Tesla proponents argue that it should not be compared to regular car companies. To them, the ultimate true value of the company rests in the future and it is hope to develop the first truly <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/self-driving-cars-autonomous-vehicles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">self-driving vehicles</a>. The only problem is Tesla has been promising this for years, and most experts say the technology is still years, maybe even decades, away.</p><p>“Tesla has not been able to deliver on fully autonomous driving and AI promises, which are already embedded in the valuation,” Spear’s Delevska said. “Being simply another automotive manufacturer is not going to cut it for a US$750 billion valuation.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese etching tools giant AMEC sees 2023 sales rise more than 30% on strong demand from mainland semiconductor fabs</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248391/chinese-etching-tools-giant-amec-sees-2023-sales-rise-more-30-strong-demand-mainland-semiconductor</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese etching tools giant Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment (AMEC) expects its revenue to grow more than 30% in 2023, driven by strong domestic demand and increased adoption of its core etching tools. The company aims to replace 100% of US-restricted components with domestic parts by 2024.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: AMEC expects strong revenue growth in 2023 due to domestic demand and core technology breakthroughs.</li>    <li>Theme: AMEC's strategy to expand sales in China amidst tightened US semiconductor sanctions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of localizing China's semiconductor supply chain.</li>    <li>Main information: AMEC's projected revenue, net profit, and market share; the company's efforts to replace foreign components with domestic parts.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国刻蚀设备巨头中微半导体设备有限公司（AMEC）预计其 2023 年收入将增长超过 30%，这得益于强劲的国内需求及其核心刻蚀设备的日益普及。该公司计划到 2024 年将 100% 的美国限制组件替换为国产部件。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中微半导体依靠国内需求和核心技术突破，预计 2023 年收入将大幅增长。</li>    <li>主题：AMEC 在美国收紧半导体制裁的情况下扩大其在中国销售的策略。</li>    <li>观点：本土化中国半导体供应链的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：AMEC 预计收入、净利润和市场份额；该公司努力用国产部件替换国外部件。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.njuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：Shanghai-based AMEC expects its 2023 revenue to reach US$879 million, up 32.1 per cent from the previous year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Revenue 是收入、收益的意思，在经济学和会计学中，它是指某一特定时期内一个实体（如公司或组织）通过销售商品或提供服务所获得的收入。在这个例句中，它说上海中微半导体预计其 2023 年的收入将达到 8.79 亿美元，比上一年的增长 32.1%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>core technology (n.) - /kɔːr tekˈnɑːlədʒi/ 核心技术。    <p>原文例句：Core technology breakthroughs enabled the firm to deploy more chip-making gear to domestic semiconductor fabrication plants.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Core technology 是核心技术的意思，是指一个行业或领域内最基本、最重要的技术。在这个例句中，它说核心技术突破使该公司能够向国内半导体制造厂部署更多芯片制造设备。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>on the back of - 凭借，依托，依靠。    <p>原文例句：Shanghai-based AMEC said in a regulatory filing on Sunday that its 2023 revenue is expected to reach 6.26 billion yuan (US$879 million), up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic demand. </p>    <p>例句讲解：On the back of 是凭借、依托的意思，常用在经济和金融领域。在这个例句中，它说上海中微半导体在其周日的一份监管文件中表示，预计其 2023 年收入将达到 62.6 亿元人民币（8.79 亿美元），比上一年的增长 32.1%，这得益于强劲的国内需求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Shanghai-based AMEC said in a regulatory filing on Sunday that its 2023 revenue is expected to reach 6.26 billion yuan (US$879 million), up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic demand - 上海中微半导体在其周日的一份监管文件中表示，预计其 2023 年收入将达到 62.6 亿元人民币（8.79 亿美元），比上一年的增长 32.1%，这得益于强劲的国内需求。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是AMEC said its 2023 revenue is expected to reach 6.26 billion yuan，其中主语是AMEC，谓语是said，宾语是its 2023 revenue is expected to reach 6.26 billion yuan。in a regulatory filing on Sunday是一个时间状语，表示这一消息是在周日的一份监管文件中公布的。on the back of strong domestic demand是一个原因状语，表示这一增长的原因是强劲的国内需求。这个句子的意思是说，上海中微半导体在其周日的一份监管文件中表示，预计其 2023 年收入将达到 62.6 亿元人民币（8.79 亿美元），比上一年的增长 32.1%，这得益于强劲的国内需求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式 - 表示动作或状态，但没有具体人称、数或时态。    <p>原文例句：The company said it recorded 8.36 billion yuan worth of new orders, a 32.3 per cent year-on-year increase. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是动词不定式的一种形式，表示动作或状态，但没有具体的人称、数或时态。在这个例句中，它表示该公司表示其记录了价值 83.6 亿元人民币的新订单，同比增长 32.3%。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>介词短语 - 由介词和名词或代词组成的短语，用作状语或补语。    <p>原文例句：Net profit last year is projected to be from 1.7 billion yuan to 1.85 billion yuan, representing year-on-year growth of between 45 per cent and 58 per cent. </p>    <p>语法讲解：介词短语是由介词和名词或代词组成的短语，用作状语或补语。在这个例句中，它表示去年净利润预计为 17 亿至 18.5 亿元人民币，同比增长 45% 至 58%。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Shanghai-based AMEC expects its 2023 revenue to reach US$879 million, up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic orders</li>
<li>The company said sales of its core etching tools will account for 75 per cent of its total revenue last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/977166e1-00b7-4d05-941a-ada3e90b90d0_07dcf1ac.jpg" /><figcaption>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment workers at the company’s main production site in Shanghai. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese etching tools giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3232334/tech-war-china-chip-tool-firm-amecs-profit-boosted-strong-local-demand-it-reshuffles-tech-board-wake" target="_self" title="">Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment</a> (AMEC) expects revenue last year to grow more than 30 per cent from 2022, as core <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> breakthroughs enabled the firm to deploy more chip-making gear to domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> fabrication plants.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a>-based AMEC said in a regulatory filing on Sunday that its 2023 revenue is expected to reach 6.26 billion yuan (US$879 million), up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic demand. The company said it recorded 8.36 billion yuan worth of new orders, a 32.3 per cent year-on-year increase.</p><p>Net profit last year is projected to be from 1.7 billion yuan to 1.85 billion yuan, representing year-on-year growth of between 45 per cent and 58 per cent.</p><p>AMEC’s positive earnings guidance reflects its successful strategy to expand sales on the mainland, months after founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230803/us-wants-chinas-chip-industry-5-generations-behind-cutting-edge-head-equipment-maker-amec-says-wuxi" target="_self" title="">Gerald Yin Zhiyao</a> said the firm had devised a detailed road map to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy" target="_self" title="">tightened US semiconductor sanctions</a>.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/8dc83513-a48d-478e-9d86-f625246bf8fe_ada0205e.jpg" title="Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Yin had said 80 per cent of US-restricted components that AMEC used would be replaced with domestic parts by the end of last year. He expected the company to achieve a 100-per cent replacement rate in 2024.</p><p>AMEC shares in Shanghai closed down 2.07 per cent to 134.66 yuan last Friday.</p><p>With state-backed efforts to localise great swathes of China’s semiconductor supply chain, mainland semiconductor foundries have accelerated adoption of locally made equipment since October 2022, when Washington <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3195461/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-self-sufficiency-drive-under-siege-new" target="_self" title="">first tightened export controls</a> to cut off the country’s access to advanced chip-making gear from the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">US</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netherlands" target="_self" title="">the Netherlands</a>.</p><p>AMEC expects sales of its core etching tools, including so-called capacitively coupled plasma (CCP) and inductive coupled plasma (ICP), to account for 75 per cent of the firm’s total revenue last year, which would be up nearly 50 per cent to 4.7 billion yuan.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1414" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/646d3f0c-dcc0-4e3c-87fa-0e91b99b21a2_bfef4330.jpg" title="Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>AMEC said that its CCP and ICP equipment saw increased adoption by domestic foundry clients on the strength of the firm’s breakthroughs in core technologies last year.</p><p>Etching tools are some of the most important processing equipment used by semiconductor foundries. It is an area where China has strong players such as AMEC and state-backed Naura Technology Group.</p><p>AMEC’s domestic CCP equipment market share is projected to hit 60 per cent in the near future, up from 24 per cent in October 2022. The firm’s share in ICP gear sales on the mainland is predicted to reach 75 per cent from almost zero, according to company chief executive Yin, after once-dominant US chip equipment maker Lam Research saw its mainland sales drop sharply.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
