<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Hong Kong-based AI-driven company sells potential breast cancer drug in deal whose value could exceed US$500 million</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247263/hong-kong-based-ai-driven-company-sells-potential-breast-cancer-drug-deal-whose-value-could-exceed</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Insilico Medicine, an AI-powered drug discovery company, sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy's Menarini Group for a potential value exceeding $500 million. Menarini will pay an upfront fee of $12 million and royalties based on sales. The collaboration aims to develop and market a novel small molecule inhibitor as a treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Insilico and Menarini partner to develop and commercialize a new drug for hormone-sensitive cancers using AI-powered technologies.</li>    <li>Theme: AI's role in revolutionizing drug discovery by enhancing efficiency and reducing research and development time.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The promise of AI-driven drug discovery in identifying potential drugs and enabling precision medicine.</li>    <li>Main information: Insilico's AI-driven drug discovery platform; Menarini's global reach and pharmaceutical expertise; the licensing agreement terms and potential market value of the drug.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  香港人工智能制药公司Insilico Medicine将用于治疗乳腺癌的临床前候选药物以超过5亿美元的潜在估值出售给意大利制药公司Menarini集团。Menarini将支付1200万美元的预付款和基于销售额的版税。此次合作旨在开发和销售一种新型小分子抑制剂，用作激素敏感型癌症的治疗药物。    <ul>    <li>摘要：Insilico和Menarini合作，利用人工智能驱动的技术开发和销售一种治疗激素敏感型癌症的新药。</li>    <li>主题：人工智能在提高效率和减少研发时间方面对药物发现变革的作用。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能驱动的药物发现，在识别潜在药物和实现精准医疗方面的承诺。</li>    <li>主要信息：Insilico的人工智能驱动的药物发现平台；Menarini的全球影响力和制药专业知识；许可协议条款和药物的潜在市场价值。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>pipeline (n.) - /ˈpaɪplaɪn/ 管道，输油管。    <p>原文例句：Insilico, founded by Zhavoronkov in 2014, has a pipeline that consists of 31 programmes for 29 drug targets in cancer, fibrosis, immunity, central nervous system and ageing-related diseases.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由pipe（管道）和-line（线）组成，表示“管道，输油管”，在例句中引申为“一系列的项目或活动”。在这个例句中，pipeline指的是Insilico公司正在进行的31个针对癌症、纤维化、免疫、中枢神经系统和衰老相关疾病的药物靶点项目。</p>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>clinical trial (n.) - /ˈklɪnɪkəl traɪəl/ 临床试验。    <p>原文例句：In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由clinical（临床的）和trial（试验）组成，表示“临床试验”。在这个例句中，它指的是Insilico公司计划使用在香港进行的首次公开募股（IPO）来为其利用人工智能发现和设计的药物的临床试验提供资金。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>on track - 按照计划进行。        <p>原文例句：The combined value of the deal includes all development, regulatory, and commercial milestones.</p>    <p>例句讲解：on track是一个表示“按照计划进行，向前推进”的短语，由on和track（轨道）组成，track表示“轨道，前进的道路”，on track的意思是“在轨道上运行”，比喻事情按照既定计划顺利进行。在这个例句中，on track指的是该交易的总价值包括所有开发、监管和商业里程碑，表明该合作项目正在按照计划顺利进行。</p>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>take into account - 考虑，考虑到。    <p>原文例句：“The partnership at the early stage preclinical trial is truly optimal when the partner is very committed,” said Zhavoronkov.</p>    <p>例句讲解：take into account是一个表示“考虑，考虑到”的短语，由take（拿，采取）和into account（考虑）组成，into account的意思是“考虑到”，take into account的意思是“考虑到，把……当作因素”。在这个例句中，take into account指的是Zhavoronkov表示，当合作伙伴非常有决心时，在早期临床前试验阶段的合作才是真正最佳的，表明在选择合作伙伴时会考虑其承诺和决心程度。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Insilico, founded by Zhavoronkov in 2014, has a pipeline that consists of 31 programmes for 29 drug targets in cancer, fibrosis, immunity, central nervous system and ageing-related diseases. - Insilico由Zhavoronkov于2014年创立，拥有一个由31个项目组成的研发线，针对癌症、纤维化、免疫、中枢神经系统和衰老相关疾病的29个药物靶点。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Insilico，谓语是has，宾语是a pipeline that consists of 31 programmes for 29 drug targets in cancer, fibrosis, immunity, central nervous system and ageing-related diseases。这个句子介绍了Insilico公司的研发线，及其针对的疾病领域和药物靶点。</p></ul>  <ul>    <li>In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence. - 去年6月，该公司在搁置了纽约筹款计划后，披露了在香港进行首次公开募股（IPO）的计划，以资助人工发现和设计的药物的临床试验。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong，其中主语是The company，谓语是revealed，宾语是an IPO plan in Hong Kong。in June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰主句中的The company，该从句介绍了该公司在香港进行首次公开募股（IPO）的原因及其筹集资金的用途。</p></ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句 - 用以强调句子中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：Menarini, an international pharmaceutical and diagnostics company with a turnover of more than US$4.4 billion and operations in 140 countries, sees the collaboration with Insilico as an opportunity to explore new treatment approaches and potentially unlock transformative cancer therapies, according to CEO Elcin Barker Ergun.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句，通过在句首使用it来强调句子中的Menarini，表示Menarini公司看到了与Insilico合作的机会。强调句的结构一般是：It is/was + 被强调的成分 + that/who + 其他部分。在这个例句中，强调的成分是Menarini，that引导的从句说明了Menarini看到了与Insilico合作的机会。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表示说话人的愿望、假设或不真实的情况。    <p>原文例句：“The partnership at the early stage preclinical trial is truly optimal when the partner is very committed,” said Zhavoronkov.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气的句子，使用虚拟语气是为了表示说话人的愿望或假设。虚拟语气的结构一般是：If + 虚拟语气，在这个例句中，If + 虚拟语气表示了Zhavoronkov的愿望或假设，即当合作伙伴非常有决心时，在早期临床前试验阶段的合作才是真正最佳的。</p>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Insilico grants Italy’s Menarini Group, the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule inhibitor, as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers</li>
<li>Breast cancer, a hormone-sensitive cancer, is the most common cancer worldwide, and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the WHO</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/0aa273cd-964f-49d2-be3b-69223d5b9a88_d8bebbd1.jpg" /><figcaption>null</figcaption></figure><p>Insilico Medicine, a Hong Kong-based AI-driven drug discovery company that intends to list in Hong Kong after it unveiled an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3225736/hong-kong-based-biotech-insilico-medicine-shifts-ipo-plan-city-new-york" target="_self" title="">initial public offering plan</a> (IPO) last year, has sold its preclinical drug candidate for breast cancer treatment to Italy-based pharmaceutical company Menarini Group in a deal that could reach a value of over US$500 million.</p><p>Stemline Therapeutics, a wholly owned unit of Menarini, will make a US$12 million upfront payment to Insilico under the agreement, which will be followed by sales royalties worth up to “double digits”. The combined value of the deal includes all development, regulatory, and commercial milestones.</p><p>The agreement comes at a time when cutting-edge technology is playing a greater role in drug discovery. AI has emerged as a catalyst in revolutionising drug discovery by enhancing efficiency and accuracy while reducing the time-consuming aspects of research and development, experts say.</p><p>The AI-driven drug discovery market is projected to grow at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 23.72 per cent from 2023 to 2030, reaching an estimated value of US$7.1 billion by 2030, according to US-based Vantage Market Research.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/8d6c5116-f305-4968-8ef3-f757c1373823_34f54c2a.jpg" title="An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>An AI-run robotic laboratory at the Insilico Medicine research facility in Suzhou, China. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The technology expedites the process of identifying potential drugs, according to Insilico’s founder and co-CEO, Dr Alex Zhavoronkov.</p><p>Under the exclusive licensing agreement, Insilico has granted Stemline the global rights to develop and commercialise a novel small molecule KAT6A inhibitor as a potential treatment for hormone-sensitive cancers and other oncology indications.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3199001/sanofi-signs-research-tie-hong-kongs-insilico-medicine-accelerate-ai-powered-drug-discovery" title="">Sanofi signs with Hong Kong biotech firm Insilico to spur AI drug discovery</a></h3><p>Breast cancer is the most common cancer worldwide and the leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the World Health Organization.</p><p>The global breast cancer market is projected to hit around US$73.68 billion by 2032 with a registered CAGR of 9.9 per cent, according to Precedence Research.</p><p>“The partnership at the early stage preclinical trial is truly optimal when the partner is very committed,” said Zhavoronkov.</p><p>Menarini, an international pharmaceutical and diagnostics company with a turnover of more than US$4.4 billion and operations in 140 countries, sees the collaboration with Insilico as an opportunity to explore new treatment approaches and potentially unlock transformative cancer therapies, according to CEO Elcin Barker Ergun.</p><p>Insilico, founded by Zhavoronkov in 2014, has a pipeline that consists of 31 programmes for 29 drug targets in cancer, fibrosis, immunity, central nervous system and ageing-related diseases.</p><p>In June last year, the company revealed an IPO plan in Hong Kong after shelving a New York fundraising plan, to fund clinical trials of drugs discovered and designed by artificial intelligence.</p><p>Zhavoronkov declined to reveal a timeline for its IPO but said market sentiment was a concern.</p><p>Insilico has a presence in the markets of the US, Greater China, Canada and the Middle East. It launched the Generative AI and Quantum Computing Research and Development Center in Abu Dhabi in February 2023.</p><p>To date, the company has raised more than US$400 million via private markets. In 2022, it secured series D financing of US$95 million from investors such as Prosperity7, a growth venture fund of Saudi Arabia’s Aramco, and others including B Capital Group, Warburg Pincus, and Hong Kong-based Qiming Ventures.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese EV maker Hozon predicts fivefold jump in overseas sales as growth slows in hyper-competitive domestic market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247305/chinese-ev-maker-hozon-predicts-fivefold-jump-overseas-sales-growth-slows-hyper-competitive-domestic</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Hozon New Energy Automobile, a Shanghai-based maker of Neta electric vehicles (EVs), aims to boost its overseas sales to 100,000 units in 60 markets, primarily in Southeast Asia, by the end of 2024. The company, motivated by slowing growth in the domestic market, has begun assembling vehicles at its first overseas plant in Thailand and plans to establish a second facility in the second quarter. Hozon's expansion strategy targets middle- and low-income consumers, offering affordable battery-powered vehicles to compete with gasoline-powered cars. Despite a projected slowdown in the Chinese EV market, the company aims to reach total sales of 1 million units by 2026, including 400,000 vehicles sold outside China.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese EV maker Hozon aims to expand its overseas sales to 100,000 units in 2024, targeting Southeast Asian markets.</li>    <li>Theme: Hozon's strategy to increase international sales as a response to slower domestic growth.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The expansion of Chinese EV makers into global markets amidst domestic competition and the rise of affordable battery-powered vehicles.</li>    <li>Main information: Hozon's overseas sales target, assembly plant operations, focus on middle- and low-income consumers, and planned expansion to the Middle East, Africa, and South America.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary：</h2>  总部位于上海的哪吒汽车制造商 Hozon 新能源汽车计划在今年将 10 万辆汽车运往 60 个海外市场，主要是在东南亚。该公司于 11 月份在泰国的第一家海外工厂开始组装车辆，比原定计划提前了两个月。2022 年 8 月 24 日，表演者在泰国曼谷的发布仪式上展示了一辆哪吒 V。照片：欧洲图片社中国电动汽车 (EV) 初创公司 Hozon 新能源汽车预计，随着中国汽车制造商越来越有信心将汽车销往海外，该公司在中国大陆以外的销售额将在 2024 年增长五倍，以应对国内增长放缓。据副总裁周江介绍，该公司今年的目标是向 60 个海外市场交付 10 万辆汽车，主要是在东南亚，此前该公司已开始在泰国和印度尼西亚运营组装厂。他说，按照这个水平，海外销售将在 2024 年占 Hozon 总交付量的三分之一，届时公司的总交付量可能会达到 30 万辆。“总体而言，中国制造的电动汽车受到世界各地消费者的欢迎，”他周四在媒体发布会上这样说。“此外，我们对公司的全球前景充满信心，我们的目标是为所有人设计和制造电动汽车。”Hozon 新能源汽车的电动汽车正在等待从上海运往海外。照片：微博在 11 月底，Hozon（又称哪吒汽车）比原计划提前约两个月开始在其位于泰国的首个海外工厂组装汽车。该工厂的年产能为 20,000 辆，生产右舵版的哪吒汽车。周说，Hozon 在中国境外的第二家组装厂将于第二季度投入运营。“由于国内市场放缓，那些品牌和汽车能够吸引外国买家的中国电动汽车制造商将在未来几年加大在海外市场的扩张力度，”上海咨询公司 Suolei 的高级经理 Eric Han 说。“事实上，由于国内的价格竞争，他们在其他市场的利润率更高。”卖空者瞄准全球最大的电动汽车制造商比亚迪，竞争加剧哪吒是哪咤的变体，哪咤是中国神话中的保护神。该品牌属于中国的廉价电动汽车，针对的是更喜欢电池动力汽车而不是汽油发动机的汽车的中低收入司机。根据惠誉评级在 11 月发布的报告，预计中国大陆的电动汽车销量在 2024 年将同比增长 20%，低于 2023 年预计的 30% 增幅。由于电动汽车市场挤满了 200 家参与者，新一轮降价正在实施，比亚迪（全球最大的制造商）和小鹏汽车等顶级参与者提供折扣来吸引买家。中国电动汽车：小鹏汽车和理想汽车推出针对富裕买家的微型货车车型Hozon 在 2023 年向国内外客户交付了总计 127,496 辆汽车，同比下降 16%。该公司于 8 月宣布，已通过交叉融资交易筹集了 70 亿元人民币（合 9.86 亿美元），但并未披露投资者的姓名。交叉融资通常为初创公司提供更多时间和资本在其首次公开募股 (IPO) 之前发展其业务。投资者通常以折扣价达成交叉融资交易，同时在潜在的 IPO 中站稳脚跟。比亚迪超越特斯拉成为纯电动汽车的最大制造商据 Hozon 的投资者之一奇虎 360 科技的年度报告显示，Hozon 在 2022 年报告的净亏损为 69 亿元人民币，比前一年的 29 亿元人民币亏损扩大了 138%。周说，这家汽车制造商的目标是到 2026 年实现 100 万辆电动汽车的总销量，其中包括在中国大陆以外销售的 40 万辆。他说，公司还计划在中东、非洲和南美等市场建设工厂。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国电动汽车制造商 Hozon 计划在 2024 年将其海外销售额提高到 10 万辆，目标是东南亚市场。</li>    <li>主题：Hozon 的战略是在国内增长放缓的情况下增加国际销售额。</li>    <li>观点：中国电动汽车制造商向全球市场扩张，背景是国内竞争加剧以及价格适中的电池动力汽车的兴起。</li>    <li>主要信息：Hozon 的海外销售目标、组装厂运营、专注于中低收入消费者以及计划向中东、非洲和南美地区扩张。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>aim (v.) - /eɪm/ 瞄准，目标，志在。    <p>原文例句：The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars, aims to deliver 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia, as it starts operations of assembly plants in Thailand and Indonesia, according to vice-president Zhou Jiang.    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古诺斯语，表示“瞄准，目标，志在”。在这个例句中，它表示上海的哪吒汽车制造商的目标是今年在60个海外市场，主要是在东南亚，交付10万辆汽车。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>consumer (n.) - /kənˈsjuːmə/ 消费者。    <p>原文例句：Hozon’s second assembly facility outside China will be operational by the second quarter, Zhou said.    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，表示“消费者”。在这个例句中，它表示中国以外的第二个组装厂将在第二季度投入运营。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>vehicle (n.) - /ˈviːɪkəl/ 车辆。    <p>原文例句：“Overall, Chinese-made electric cars are well received by customers around the world,” he said in a media briefing on Thursday.     <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，表示“车辆”。在这个例句中，它表示中国制造的电动汽车受到世界各地消费者的欢迎。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>overall - 总的来说，总体上。    <P>原文例句：“Overall, Chinese-made electric cars are well received by customers around the world,” he said in a media briefing on Thursday.     <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“总体来说，总体上”。在这个例句中，它表示总体来说，中国制造的电动汽车受到世界各地消费者的欢迎。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in effect - 生效，有效。    <P>原文例句：A new round of price cuts is in effect, with top players like BYD, the world’s largest maker, and Xpeng offering discounts to lure buyers.    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“生效，有效”。在这个例句中，它表示新一轮降价正在进行中，比亚迪（全球最大的制造商）和小鹏汽车等顶级参与者提供折扣来吸引买家。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars aims to deliver a total 100,00  <ul><li>The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars aims to deliver 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia</li>
<li>Company started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand in November, about two months ahead of schedule</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/2f9a94ae-4006-4789-9e96-32506d8ef0a5_7020747c.jpg" /><figcaption>Performers present a Hozon NETA V during a launch ceremony in Bangkok, Thailand, on August 24, 2022. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> start-up Hozon New Energy Automobile expects its sales outside mainland China to jump five-fold in 2024 as the country’s increasingly confident carmakers look to international sales to counter slowing growth at home.</p><p>The Shanghai-based maker of Neta-branded cars, aims to deliver a total 100,000 units in 60 overseas markets this year, mainly in Southeast Asia, as it starts operations of assembly plants in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3243541/chinese-ev-maker-hozon-kicks-operations-its-first-overseas-factory-thailand-it-steps-push-southeast" target="_self" title="">Thailand</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3230821/hozon-steps-plans-develop-right-hand-drive-neta-electric-cars-indonesia-it-pushes-ahead-its-hong" target="_self" title="">Indonesia</a>, according to vice-president Zhou Jiang.</p><p>At that level, overseas sales would account for a third of Hozon’s total deliveries in 2024, which are likely to hit 300,000 units, he said.</p><p>“Overall, Chinese-made electric cars are well received by customers around the world,” he said in a media briefing on Thursday. “Moreover, we are confident of our company’s global perspective with the goal of designing and manufacturing EVs for all the people.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo" class="image-inline caption" height="1328" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/338ee101-bc2d-48a2-8f3d-5ae81ace116c_515c76ff.jpg" title="Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo" width="2000" /><figcaption>Hozon New Energy Automobile EVs await shipment overseas from Shanghai. Photo: Weibo</figcaption></figure></div><p>At the end of November, Hozon, also known as Neta Auto, started assembling vehicles at its first overseas factory in Thailand, about two months ahead of schedule. The plant, with an annual capacity of 20,000 units, produces right-hand-drive versions of Neta vehicles.</p><p>Hozon’s second assembly facility outside China will be operational by the second quarter, Zhou said.</p><p>“Owing to a slowing domestic market, Chinese EV makers whose brands and vehicles can attract foreign buyers will step up their overseas expansion in the coming years,” said Eric Han, a ­senior ­manager at Suolei, an advisory firm in Shanghai. “Indeed, they enjoy a higher profit margin in other markets because of price competition at home.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3247229/short-sellers-target-byd-worlds-top-ev-maker-rivalry-intensifies" title="">Short sellers target BYD, world’s top EV maker, as rivalry intensifies</a></h3><p>Neta is a variation of the name Nezha, a protection deity in Chinese mythology. The brand falls into the category of budget EVs in China, aimed at middle- and low-income drivers who prefer battery-powered vehicles to cars powered by petrol-guzzling internal combustion engines.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246896/chinese-ev-makers-face-day-reckoning-2024-competition-and-price-war-force-out-underperformers" target="_self" title="">EV sales in mainland China</a> are seen growing 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November, slowing from the projected 30 per cent increase in 2023.</p><p>With the EV market crowded with 200 players, a new round of price cuts is in effect, with top players like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest maker</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3229066/xpeng-gets-volkswagens-us700-million-investment-jointly-develop-evs-worlds-largest-vehicle-market" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> offering discounts to lure buyers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/markets/article/3247151/china-evs-xpeng-and-li-auto-roll-out-x9-and-mega-mpvs-aimed-rich-buyers-bid-dominate-segment" title="">China EVs: Xpeng and Li Auto roll out minivan models with focus on rich buyers</a></h3><p>Hozon delivered a total of 127,496 vehicles to domestic and overseas customers in 2023, down 16 per cent year on year.</p><p>In August, the company announced it had <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3232811/chinese-ev-start-hozon-raises-us960-million-pre-ipo-financing-looks-expand-footprint-home-and-abroad" target="_self" title="">raised 7 billion yuan (US$986 million)</a> in a crossover financing deal, without disclosing the names of the investors.</p><p>Crossover financing typically gives a start-up more time and capital to develop its business before an initial public offering (IPO). Investors normally close cross-financing deals at a discounted price while gaining a foothold in the prospective IPO.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>Hozon reported a net loss of 6.9 billion yuan in 2022, 138 per cent wider than a 2.9 billion yuan loss in the previous year, according to the annual report of 360 Security Technology, one of the EV company’s investors.</p><p>Zhou said the carmaker targets total sales of 1 million EVs in 2026, including 400,000 outside mainland China. It also plans to build plants in markets like the Middle East, Africa and South America, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China is on track to be world AI leader by 2030, with Hong Kong’s help</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3247052/china-track-be-world-ai-leader-2030-hong-kongs-help</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>China's AI market and technology are rapidly growing, and its regulatory framework is developing.</li>    <li>Hong Kong can contribute to China's AI development by providing talent and funding.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国的人工智能市场、企业和技术正在强劲增长，而监管环境日益成熟。</li>    <li>香港可以通过提供人工智能人才和资金来为中国的AI发展做出贡献。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>capacity (n.) - /kəˈpæsɪti/ 容量，能容纳的能力。    <p>原文例句：AI is a foundational technology with the capacity to increase productivity, boost competitiveness and help solve social challenges.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由caput（头部，首级）和ere（在……中）构成的，表示“空间容纳能力，体积，能力，能容纳的数量或数目”。在这个例句中，它指的是人工智能的基本技术能力，能够提高生产力、增强竞争力并帮助解决社会挑战。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>prominent (adj.) - /ˈprɑːmɪnənt/ 突出的，显著的。    <p>原文例句：Hong Kong has a key role to play in China’s AI development. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于 Latin，由pro-（向前，向外）和minere（突出，伸出）构成，表示“伸出，突出，显著的，显眼的”。在这个例    句中，它指的是香港在    中国AI发展中发挥着关键作用。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>contribute (v.) - /kənˈtrɪbjuːt/ 贡献，捐献。    <p>原文例句：Hong Kong can contribute by providing talent and funding.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于 Latin，由con-（共同）和tribuere（分发）构成，表示“共同分摊，分摊，贡献”。在这个例句中，它指的是香港可以通过提供人才和资金来贡献。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases：</h2>  <ul>    <li>global race - 全球竞赛。    <p>原文例句：If we are in the midst of a global race for artificial intelligence (AI) breakthroughs, China is definitely a key player. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由global（全球的）和race（竞赛）构成的，表示“全球竞赛”。在这个例句中，它指的是如果我们正处于全球人工智能（AI）突破的竞赛中，那么中国肯定是一个关键参与者。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>people-centred - 以人为本。    <p>原文例句： The initiative calls for a “people-centred” approach to AI (i.e., developing AI for the good of humanity and its progress), more inclusiveness and fairness in AI development so countries can benefit regardless of their political or economic situation...</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由people（人）和centred（以……为中心的）构成的，表示“以人为本，以人为中心”。在这个例句中，它指的是该倡议呼吁以“以人为本”的方式发展人工智能（即，让人工智能造福于人类及其进步），在人工智能的开发中更加包容和公平，以便各国都能受益，无论其政治或经济状况如何。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Artificial intelligence (AI) is a rapidly developing field that has the potential to revolutionise many aspects of our lives. </li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单的复合句，主句是Artificial intelligence (AI) is a rapidly developing field，其中主语是Artificial intelligence (AI)，谓语是is，表语是a rapidly developing field。That has the potential to revolutionise many aspects of our lives是一个定语从句，修饰Artificial intelligence (AI)，表示人工智能具有彻底改变我们生活的各个方面的潜力。这个句子的意思是说，人工智能是一个快速发展的领域，有可能彻底改变我们生活的各个方面。</p>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>China has made significant investments in AI research and development, and is now a global leader in the field. </li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是China has made significant investments in AI research and development，其中主语是China，谓语是has made，宾语是significant investments。And is now a global leader in the field是一个并列连词，连接两个谓语动词，表示中国在人工智能研究和开发方面进行了大量投资，现在已经成为该领域的全球领导者。这个句子的意思是说，中国在人工智能研究和开发方面进行了大量投资，现在已经成为该领域的全球领导者。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设或愿望。    <p>原文例句：This could be why they chose to stream it through services outside of the mainland, where it is not yet approved, instead of waiting for an official launch in China. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，could be why they chose to stream it through services outside of the mainland, where it is not yet approved是虚拟语气。它表示对原因的猜测หรือการคาดการณ์，因为这里使用的是过去式could be，表示“可能的原因”。在这个句子中，it is not yet approved是一个现在完成时态的被动语态，表示“它还没有被批准”。这个句子的意思是说，这可能就是为什么他们选择通过境外服务来播放它，而不是等待在中国正式上映。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China’s AI market, firms and tech are growing strongly, while the regulatory climate is maturing. Hong Kong can contribute by providing AI talent and funding</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/ccb3683c-5993-48ba-ab9c-122ea06719a8_5241b49e.jpg" /><figcaption>A woman stands in front of a poster during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai on July 6 last year. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>If we are in the midst of a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3236727/expect-chinas-regulators-help-ai-firms-race-against-us-european-peers" target="_self" title="">global race</a> for artificial intelligence (AI) breakthroughs, China is definitely a key player. While 2023 has been a year of AI hype – especially for generative AI, amid the popularity of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> – the industry has been of interest to most countries for years and will only become more important.</p><p>According to the 2023 AI Index Report by the Stanford Institute for Human-Centred Artificial Intelligence, global investment in AI has significantly increased over the last decade. By 2022, private investment in AI had grown to 18 times greater than in 2013.</p><p>Back in 2017, China made AI a national priority, stating its ambition to become “the world’s premier artificial intelligence innovation centre” by 2030.</p><p>According to the State Council’s 2017 guidelines, AI should be used to promote China’s technology, economy and social welfare, maintain national security and contribute to the world. The guidelines also said: “AI should be applied in the public service and social management to build a safer, more comfortable and convenient society.”</p><p>Why are nations racing to achieve AI dominance? One reason is that AI is a foundational technology with the capacity to increase productivity, boost competitiveness and help solve social challenges.</p><p>So what does the AI industry in China look like? According to a recent Nikkei study, “China is the undisputed champion in artificial intelligence research papers … far surpassing the US in both quantity and quality”.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>China’s AI market is projected to reach US$38.89 billion this year, and will grow by a compound annual rate of 18 per cent to reach US$104.7 billion by 2030. This is less than the US market, the world’s largest at a projected US$106.5 billion this year.</p><p>In addition, China has more than 4,300 AI enterprises and at least 238 <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241659/chinese-tech-companies-frenzy-over-ai-large-language-models-huge-waste-resources-baidu-ceo-says" target="_self" title="">large language models</a> (LLMs) – deep-learning AI algorithms based on very large data sets – with tech giants such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3239981/baidu-launches-paid-version-ernie-bot-chinese-firms-rush-make-money-their-generative-ai-chatbots" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3244693/alibaba-research-unit-unveils-llm-tailored-southeast-asia-e-commerce-giant-pushes-ai-fast-growth" target="_self" title="">Alibaba</a> (owner of the South China Morning Post) <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239432/tencent-using-hunyuan-ai-model-180-services-amid-competition-local-rivals-baidu-and-alibaba" target="_self" title="">Tencent</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238698/alibaba-tencent-and-other-major-chinese-backers-invest-us342-million-start-zhipu-ai-tech-sector-sees" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239031/iflytek-says-its-large-language-model-outperforms-chatgpt-chinese-ai-firm-vows-counter-us-chip-curbs" target="_self" title="">iFlyTek</a> all venturing into the field.</p><p>It is fair to say China can indeed become a world leader in AI by 2030. This is especially given its number of AI companies, number of people working in them, advanced AI infrastructure and supportive policies.</p><p>Furthermore, China has 975 million smartphone users, by far the highest in any country, meaning it generates a vast amount of digital information – and data plays a paramount role in developing AI.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>From a regulatory perspective, China has taken a further step towards digitalisation and innovation. At the third Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation, President Xi Jinping proposed the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238360/belt-and-road-forum-china-launches-ai-framework-urging-equal-rights-and-opportunities-all-nations" target="_self" title="">Global AI Governance Initiative</a> for countries participating in the Belt and Road Initiative.</p><p>The initiative calls for a “people-centred” approach to AI (i.e., developing AI for the good of humanity and its progress), more inclusiveness and fairness in AI development so countries can benefit regardless of their political or economic situation, testing and assessment systems based on AI risk levels, and regulation reform to protect privacy and data security.</p><p>Even though Global AI Governance Initiative is not the first multilateral forum on AI, it is undoubtedly one of the bigger ones, with potential implications for the AI regulatory scene across the globe.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3216079/how-hong-kong-can-play-role-preventing-ai-armageddon" title="">How Hong Kong can play a role in preventing AI Armageddon</a></h3><p>Meanwhile, Hong Kong has a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226804/hong-kongs-financial-secretary-tells-waic-city-has-key-role-play-chinas-ai-development" target="_self" title="">key role</a> to play in China’s AI development. Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po has said the city can contribute by providing talent and funding.</p><p>At the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai in July, Chan <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226804/hong-kongs-financial-secretary-tells-waic-city-has-key-role-play-chinas-ai-development" target="_self" title="">said</a> Hong Kong had advantages when it came to attracting talent in the current geopolitical landscape: “Our universities have brought together scientific researchers from the mainland and around the world, and the Hong Kong government has given a lot of policy and financial support in the past few years.”</p><p>Moreover, Chan added, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3241373/guangdong-authorities-unveil-new-data-transfer-guidelines-amid-push-build-greater-bay-area-ai-hub" target="_self" title="">Greater Bay Area</a> has formed “the whole industrial chain of AI from research to market application”.</p><p>To sum up, China will probably become the global AI leader and Hong Kong has a role to play in this. China’s AI industry is powerful and will keep on growing. While it is still too early to say if the Global AI Governance Initiative will be a success, it is relevant that China starts leveraging the Belt and Road Initiative.</p><p><strong>Dr Oriol Caudevilla is an honorary fellow at the Asian Institute of International Financial Law at the University of Hong Kong and a board director at the Global Impact FinTech Forum. The views do not necessarily reflect those of any of the organisations the author collaborates with</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba reduces stake in GoGoX amid Hong Kong logistics services firm’s mounting losses, as it faces cutthroat competition on the mainland</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247308/alibaba-reduces-stake-gogox-amid-hong-kong-logistics-services-firms-mounting-losses-it-faces</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba cut its GoGoX stake again, now only having 8.89% equity.</li>    <li>GoGoX has been operating at a loss since 2018 due to competition and international expansion.</li>    <li>Stiff competition in the intracity delivery market in China has led to the decline of GoGoX's market value.</li>    <li>GoGoX's market value has shrunk by over 90% since its 2022 Hong Kong debut.</li>    <li>The company is prepaired for an IPO of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network after narrowing its losses in the first half of 2023.</li>    <li>Alibaba's stake cut aims to stop the bleeding, but GoGoX still needs revolutionary measures to reverse its losses.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>阿里巴巴再次减持GoGoX股份，目前仅持有8.89%的股权。</li>    <li>GoGoX自2018年以来持续亏损，原因在于竞争激烈和国际扩张。</li>    <li>中国同城即时配送市场的激烈竞争导致了GoGoX市值下跌。</li>    <li>自2022年在港交所上市以来，GoGoX的市值已缩水超过90%。</li>    <li>该公司计划通过首次公开募股（IPO）为菜鸟网络筹集资金，此前该公司在2023年上半年亏损收窄。</li>    <li>阿里巴巴减持旨在止损，但GoGoX仍需要采取革命性措施扭转亏损局面。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stiff (adj.) - /stɪf/ 僵硬的，坚硬的。    <p>原文例句：GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是指“坚硬的，僵硬的，不灵活的”。在这个例句中，它形容了GoGoX自2018年以来持续亏损的原因之一是来自中国大陆激烈的竞争和公司持续的国际扩张。</p>    </li>    <li>cutthroat (adj.) - /ˈkʌtˌθrəʊt/ 激烈的，残酷的。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba Group Holding has further reduced its stake in Hong Kong-listed logistics service provider GoGoX Holdings, which is facing cutthroat competition and regulatory pressure in the mainland’s intracity delivery courier market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是指“残酷的竞争，激烈的竞争”。在这个例句中，它形容了GoGoX面临的激烈竞争和监管压力，导致阿里巴巴集团进一步减持了该公司股份。</p>    </li>    <li>resurgence (n.) - /rɪˈsɜːdʒəns/ 复苏，反弹。    <p>原文例句：GoGoX narrowed its losses to 642.9 million yuan (US$90.37 million) in the first half of 2023, showing signs of resurgence.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是指“复苏，重新兴起”。在这个例句中，它形容了GoGoX在2023年上半年亏损收窄，显示出复苏的迹象。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>intracity delivery - 同城即时配送。    <p>原文例句：GoGoX is competing in a crowded on-demand cargo delivery services market on the mainland, where its hometown rival Lalatech Holdings operates Huolala.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指“同城即时配送服务”。在这个例句中，它指的是GoGoX在中国大陆激烈的按需货运配送服务市场中竞争，其家乡的竞争对手Lalatech Holdings运营着Huolala。</p>    </li>    <li>market value - 市值。    <p>原文例句：GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指“市值，股票或公司的总价值”。在这个例句中，它指的是GoGoX自2022年6月在香港交易所上市以来，其市值缩水了90%以上。</p>    </li>    <li>initial public offering (IPO) - 首次公开募股。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba’s partial divestment initiative at GoGoX comes amid its preparations for the initial public offering (IPO) of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是指“首次公开募股，一家公司首次向公众出售其股票”。在这个例句中，它指的是阿里巴巴在为菜鸟网络首次公开募股做准备期间部分减持了GoGoX的股份。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, slashing its equity holding to 8.89 per cent as of late December from 12.23 per cent in mid-2023, according to Hong Kong stock exchange records. - 阿里巴巴在过去两个月里四次减持GoGoX股份，截至去年年底，其持股比例从2023年中期的12.23%降至8.89%，根据香港证券交易所的记录显示。    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Alibaba has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months，其中主语是Alibaba，谓语是has cut，宾语是its GoGoX stake。slashing its equity holding to 8.89 per cent as of late December from 12.23 per cent in mid-2023是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示阿里巴巴减持GoGoX股份的具体情况。according to Hong Kong stock exchange records是一个介词短语作状语，表示阿里巴巴减持GoGoX股份的信息来源。这个句子的意思是说，阿里巴巴在过去两个月里四次减持GoGoX股份，截至去年年底，其持股比例从2023年中期的12.23%降至8.89%，根据香港证券交易所的记录显示。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态一直持续到现在。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, slashing its equity holding to 8.89 per cent as of late December from 12.23 per cent in mid-2023, according to Hong Kong stock exchange records.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个时态用have/has + 过去分词的形式表示，表示过去发生的动作或状态一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的延续性和持续性。在这个例句中，has cut表示阿里巴巴过去四次减持GoGoX股份，一直持续到现在，slashing its equity holding to 8.89 per cent as of late December from 12.23 per cent in mid-2023表示阿里巴巴自2023年中期以来将持股比例从12.23%减持至8.89%，持续至今。</p>    </li>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态在另一个过去发生的动作或状态之前已经发生或完成。    <p>原文例句：Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个时态用had + 过去分词的形式表示，表示过去发生的动作或状态在另一个过去发生的动作或状态之前已经发生或完成，强调动作或状态的先后顺序。在这个例句中，had hit表示Steven Lam Hoi-yuen在2022年6月24日香港证券交易所的上市仪式上敲响了锣，即他的这一动作发生在该上市仪式之前。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Alibaba has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, leaving it with an 8.89 per cent equity holding as of December</li>
<li>GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/2c781207-f507-4907-bf84-a2425ae1e9fa_2a843a15.jpg" /><figcaption>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022. Image: GoGoX</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> has further reduced its stake in Hong Kong-listed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/transport-and-logistics" target="_self" title="">logistics</a> service provider <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/gogovan" target="_self" title="">GoGoX Holdings</a>, which is facing cutthroat competition and regulatory pressure in the mainland’s intracity delivery courier market.</p><p>Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, has cut its GoGoX stake four times over the past two months, slashing its equity holding to 8.89 per cent as of late December from 12.23 per cent in mid-2023, according to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong-stock-market" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong stock exchange</a> records.</p><p>Following those moves, the biggest shareholder of GoGoX remains billionaire Yao Jinbo – the founder, chairman and chief executive of mainland Chinese online classifieds giant 58.com – with a 38.69 per cent share. GoGoX co-founder Chen Xiaohua, with a 5.95 per cent stake, retains his position as the company’s third-biggest shareholder.</p><p>Founded as GoGoVan in Hong Kong in 2013, GoGoX <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/china-tech/article/2108658/gogovan-become-hong-kongs-first-us1-billion-start-after-merger-58" target="_self" title="">became the city’s first unicorn in 2017</a> after its merger with short-distance freight service platform operator 58 Suyun. Still, GoGoX has recorded losses since 2018 owing to stiff competition on the mainland and its continued international expansion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/ab59b907-e9a0-49bd-b7d8-bd576851c04c_8a6158cb.jpg" title="GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX" width="2000" /><figcaption>GoGoX, one of Asia’s first mobile app-based logistics services platform operators, has expanded its operations over the years from Hong Kong to mainland China, Singapore, South Korea, India and Vietnam. Image: GoGoX</figcaption></figure></div><p>GoGoX, which operates as Kuaigou Dache on the mainland, has seen its market value shrink by more than 90 per cent since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3182875/gogox-shares-rise-hkex-trading-debut-listing-hong-kongs" target="_self" title="">its Hong Kong trading debut in June 2022</a>. Its share price closed up 6.8 per cent to HK$0.63 on Thursday.</p><p>The company – which expects to remain in the red this year, according to its 2022 prospectus – narrowed its losses to 642.9 million yuan (US$90.37 million) in the first half of 2023, from 1.05 billion yuan in the same period in 2022.</p><p>GoGoX also went through a major management reshuffle in December, as founder Chen resigned from his chairman role. The company tapped Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, another co-founder and the co-chief executive of GoGoX, as its new chairman.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hangzhou" target="_self" title="">Hangzhou</a>-based Alibaba’s partial divestment initiative at GoGoX comes amid its preparations for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3235860/alibabas-cainiao-files-us1-billion-ipo-helping-hong-kong-land-worlds-second-biggest-listing-2023" target="_self" title="">initial public offering (IPO) of Cainiao Smart Logistics Network</a>, which submitted its A1 filing to the Hong Kong stock exchange last September.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to sources cited in a Post report that month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee" class="image-inline caption" height="1298" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/daae0416-e269-4485-a0b4-cb91724c76ec_051879a6.jpg" title="Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee" width="2000" /><figcaption>Steven Lam Hoi-yuen, co-founder and co-chief executive of GoGoX, hits the gong during the company’s listing ceremony at the Hong Kong stock exchange on June 24, 2022. Photo: Dickson Lee</figcaption></figure></div><p>Alibaba is trying to stop the bleeding with its stake cut, as its initial goal with the GoGoX investment was to gain financial returns through the listing and create synergy with its own services, according to Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangdong-based consultancy iiMedia.</p><p>“This is still a market with huge demand and many opportunities even with the price wars, similar to those in the bike-sharing and ride-hailing sectors,” Zhang said. “So the bigger problem is more likely to lie within the operation of GoGoX, which will need revolutionary measures to reverse its losses.”</p><p>At present, GoGoX is competing in a crowded on-demand cargo delivery services market on the mainland, where its hometown rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246071/chinese-tech-ipos-watch-2024-global-fast-fashion-online-retailer-shein-leads-pack" target="_self" title="">Lalatech Holdings</a> operates Huolala. Competition has become more intense in recent years after traditional logistics firms and ride-hailing companies also set up similar app-based courier delivery operations.</p><p>Chinese ride-hailing giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/didi-chuxing" target="_self" title="">Didi Chuxing</a>, for example, started its own intracity freight service in 2020 and launched its autonomous trucking business Kargobot in April last year. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3137463/full-truck-chinas-uber-trucks-raise-us157-billion-us" target="_self" title="">Full Truck Alliance</a>, known as China’s “Uber for trucks” and focused on long-haul logistics services, in April launched its Sheng Sheng brand dedicated to same-city delivery.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3240676/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-will-enhance-its-overseas-presence-proposed-buyout-local-rival-best" title="">Alibaba logistics spin-off Cainiao to boost overseas position with Best buyout</a></h3><p>Huolala currently leads the mainland’s intracity courier delivery services market with a 61 per cent share, according to Frost &amp; Sullivan data cited in the prospectus of Lalatech, which is eyeing a Hong Kong IPO.</p><p>Similar to on-demand services like ride hailing, the early stage of competition in intracity freight services has relied heavily on subsidies for users.</p><p>That “cash-burning” business model, however, has faced increased scrutiny from regulators, who recently summoned Lalatech for talks regarding drivers’ rights and unfair price cuts.</p><p>GoGoX and other courier delivery services providers have also received “reminders” from regulators about their operations in the past year.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Amid US tech war, Premier Li Qiang urges China to focus on application of core technologies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Premier Li Qiang visited central China's Hubei province and called for enhancing cooperation between academia and industry amid the ongoing tech war with the US. He stressed the significance of developing core technologies, stabilizing the economy, and resolving the bottleneck problem with domestic technologies. The premier visited semiconductor and laser manufacturers, highlighting the importance of transforming scientific research into market production.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Premier Li's visit to Hubei province focuses on promoting technological self-reliance, fostering industry-academia collaboration, and addressing economic challenges.</li>    <li>Theme: The need for China to enhance technology innovation and industry-academia collaboration to achieve self-reliance and counter the US's containment efforts.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: China's commitment to developing core technologies, prioritizing economic stability, and tackling challenges in industry-academia collaboration.</li>    <li>Main information: Li's visit to universities and manufacturers in Hubei; emphasis on improving cooperation between academia and industry; push for transforming scientific research into market production; challenges in industry-academia collaboration in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  李克强总理访问了中国中部地区湖北省，并在持续的中美科技战中呼吁加强产学研合作。他强调了发展核心技术、稳定经济、以国产技术解决瓶颈问题的重要性。总理走访了半导体和激光制造商，强调了将科研成果转化为市场生产的重要性。  <ul>    <li>摘要：李克强总理访问湖北省，重点放在促进技术自主、加强产学研合作和应对经济挑战。</li>    <li>主题：中国需要增强技术创新和产学研合作，以实现自主自强，应对美国的围堵。</li>    <li>观点：中国致力于发展核心技术，优先考虑经济稳定，解决产学研合作中的挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：李克强访问湖北省的大学和制造商；强调加强产学研合作；推动将科研成果转化为市场生产；产学研合作在中国面临的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tackle (v.) - /ˈtækl/ 抓住；解决。    <p>原文例句：Given the escalating containment efforts by the United States, Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：tackle这个单词来源于古英语，由tacel（抓住）演变而来，经常与事物或问题等搭配使用，表示抓住、解决、处理的意思。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>sanction (n.) - 制裁；（尤指政府对个人或国家采取的）惩罚性行动。    <p>原文例句：Unlike China’s leading memory chip maker, YMTC, HGLaser has not been sanctioned by the US. </p>    <p>例句讲解：sanction这个单词来源于拉丁语词根sanctio，原意是“使神圣”，引申为“批准、认可”，在现代英语中，则常被用来表示制裁、惩罚等含义。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>milestone (n.) - 里程碑；具有里程碑意义的事件。    <p>原文例句：‘Important milestone’: China’s GPS-like BeiDou navigation system hits new height</p>    <p>例句讲解：milestone这个单词由mile（英里）和stone（石头）组成，最早是指1英里处作为距离标志的石头，后来引申为“里程碑”或“具有里程碑意义的事件”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>core technologies - 核心技术；关键技术。    <p>原文例句：Premier Li Qiang pushed for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive during a two-day tour of Hubei province this week</p>    <p>例句讲解：“核心技术”是指对一个国家或行业具有战略意义的关键技术，掌握核心技术对于一个国家或行业的发展至关重要。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>circular economy - 循环经济；循环经济模式。    <p>原文例句：The circular economy model seeks to minimise wasting resources and environmental impact by extending the life cycle of products.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“循环经济”是指通过对产品或材料进行再利用、再制造或再循环，以减少资源消耗和环境污染的一种经济模式。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li> GPS-like BeiDou - 类GPS的北斗系统；北斗导航系统。    <p>原文例句：The home-grown BeiDou system, which is China’s equivalent to the US’ Global Positioning System (GPS), can be applied to agriculture, forestry and meteorology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“类GPS的北斗系统”是指中国自主研发的北斗卫星导航系统，该系统与美国的GPS系统类似，可用于农业、林业和气象等领域。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Given the escalating containment efforts by the United States, Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology. - 鉴于美国不断升级的围堵，北京正持续寻求以国产技术解决瓶颈问题。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology，其中主语是Beijing，谓语是is continually seeking to tackle，宾语是choke points with home-grown technology。Given the escalating containment efforts by the United States是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示在中国升级的围堵下，北京正持续寻求以国产技术解决瓶颈问题。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语承受或经历的。    <p>原文例句：YMTC was added to the US trade blacklist in December 2022.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，主语是YMTC，谓语是被动语态的was added，宾语是to the US trade blacklist。这个句子表示YMTC在2022年12月被添加到美国的贸易黑名单中。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示虚拟、假设或不真实的情况。    <p>原文例句：As of the end of 2022, only 3.9 per cent of inventions at Chinese universities were industrialised, according to the latest data available by the China National Intellectual Property Administration, compared to around 50 per cent in the US.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气句子，从句是only 3.9 per cent of inventions at Chinese universities were industrialised，其中主语是only 3.9 per cent of inventions at Chinese universities，谓语是were industrialised。这个句子根据中国国家知识产权局的最新数据指出，截至2022年底，中国大学的专利转化率仅为3.9%，而美国约为50%。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central province of Hubei this week</li>
<li>He called for improved collaboration between academia and business amid the ongoing tech war with the United States</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/3a8be64d-f864-409e-859c-0eef4d4f4ae3_9e966ee7.jpg" /><figcaption>Premier Li Qiang visited a university, as well as semiconductor, laser and chemical manufacturers, during a two-day visit to the central Hubei province this week.</figcaption></figure><p>Premier Li Qiang pushed for “more and better” market applications of core technologies amid China’s self-reliance drive during a two-day tour of Hubei province this week, with the world’s second-largest economy in urgent need of stabilisation to quell investor concerns and lift market confidence.</p><p>“We must expedite the development of productivity driven by emerging technology, and kick-start a robust economic start of the year,” he said in a statement following the tour of the central province on Tuesday and Wednesday, according to the official Xinhua News Agency.</p><p>Hubei is a key part of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3237870/xi-jinping-tells-chinas-biggest-economic-zone-balance-growth-and-security-and-no-more-mega-projects" target="_self" title="">Yangtze River Economic Belt,</a> which is one of President Xi Jinping’s key regional development strategies. It includes 11 provinces and municipalities, and accounts for over 40 per cent of China’s population and economic size.</p><p>“We need to improve collaboration between academia and business, by introducing more precise and supportive measures, thus fluidly turning scientific research into market production,” the premier said after visiting HGLaser Engineering and semiconductor manufacturer Yangtze Memory Technologies Corporation (YMTC) in the provincial capital of Wuhan.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245242/amid-us-tech-war-china-stuck-middle-technology-trap-it-time-open-its-doors-wider" title="">Time to open its doors wider, or will China fall into a middle-technology trap?</a></h3><p>Given the escalating <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245242/amid-us-tech-war-china-stuck-middle-technology-trap-it-time-open-its-doors-wider" target="_self" title="">containment efforts by the United States,</a> Beijing is continually seeking to tackle choke points with home-grown technology.</p><p>Development was also mentioned as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3244856/chinas-development-biggest-political-priority-key-econ-meeting-leaders-vow-counter-risks-lift" target="_self" title="">China’s biggest priority</a> for 2024 at the tone-setting central economic work conference in mid-December.</p><p>HGLaser introduced China’s first fully domestically produced chip-cutting machine in July, according to the WeChat account of Donghu New Technology Development Zone in Wuhan.</p><p>But unlike China’s leading memory chip maker, YMTC, HGLaser has not been sanctioned by the US. YMTC was added to the US trade blacklist <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3203494/us-adds-36-chinese-companies-export-blacklist-including-countrys-top-flash-memory-chip-maker?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">in December 2022.</a></p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>During his two-day tour, Li also inspected Wuhan University’s laboratory on high-resolution Earth observation and the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3241788/chinas-gps-beidou-navigation-system-recognised-global-standard-commercial-aviation-important" target="_self" title="">BeiDou navigation system.</a></p><p>The home-grown BeiDou system, which is China’s equivalent to the US’ Global Positioning System (GPS), can be applied to agriculture, forestry and meteorology.</p><p>China, though, has long suffered from loose cooperation between academia, including universities and research institutes, and enterprises focused on market applications.</p><p>The cooperation issues include poor communication and insufficient resource sharing, which creates obstacles affecting the transformation of inventions in China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3241788/chinas-gps-beidou-navigation-system-recognised-global-standard-commercial-aviation-important" title="">‘Important milestone’: China’s GPS-like BeiDou navigation system hits new height</a></h3><p>As of the end of 2022, only 3.9 per cent of inventions at Chinese universities were industrialised, according to the latest data available by the China National Intellectual Property Administration, compared to around 50 per cent in the US.</p><p>Li also visited water conservancy projects and a chemical company focusing on green development in Yichang, as well as a battery industrial estate set up by Guangdong Brunp Recycling Technology, a subsidiary under China’s leading lithium battery maker, Contemporary Amperex Technology (CATL).</p><p>CATL is a supplier to several carmakers, including Tesla, BMW and Volkswagen.</p><p>The premier also encouraged companies to promote China’s sustainability by focusing on the circular economy to drive companies up the value chain.</p><p>The circular economy model seeks to minimise wasting resources and environmental impact by extending the life cycle of products.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>PDD halts development of local services offering to avoid head-on competition with Meituan and Ele.me, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247286/pdd-halts-development-local-services-offering-avoid-head-competition-meituan-and-eleme-report-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  PDD's plan to launch its local services offering in February 2024 has been halted to avoid direct competition with Meituan, Alibaba, and ByteDance in the local services market. PDD's community group-buying unit, Duoduo Maicai, was tasked with developing the service but has faced challenges in achieving profitability due to low gross margins. Meanwhile, the local services market in China is expected to reach 35 trillion yuan by 2025, making it an attractive sector for major tech companies. Meituan currently leads the market, while Alibaba and ByteDance are seeking to catch up with their respective services.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: PDD halts local services offering plans amid fierce competition.</li>    <li>Theme: China's local services market is highly competitive, with tech giants vying for supremacy.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: PDD's decision reflects the challenges of entering a crowded market dominated by established players.</li>    <li>Main information: PDD's planned launch of local services via Duoduo Maicai; profitability issues faced by the unit; dominance of Meituan and Alibaba in the market; ByteDance's growing presence in local services.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  据报道，拼多多原计划于 2024 年 2 月在其社区团购部门多多买菜的支持下推出本地生活服务产品，但现在暂停该计划，以避免与美团、阿里巴巴集团控股有限公司和字节跳动正面竞争。美团、阿里巴巴和字节跳动都在本地生活服务市场中争夺冠军宝座，预计到 2025 年该市场价值将达到 35 万亿元。据中国媒体《晚点 LatePost》报道，拼多多已经“全面叫停本地生活服务业务”。拼多多暂未回应置评请求。据《晚点 LatePost》报道，市值已于 11 月份超过阿里巴巴的拼多多计划在 2024 年 2 月份推出这项新服务，该服务通过多多买菜进行，可以预订酒店和电影票等到店服务。阿里巴巴是《南华早报》的母公司。据报道，拼多多利用多多买菜约 3,000 人的业务发展团队签约实体店，包括餐厅和旅游景点。亚马逊加倍押注中国电子商务战略，因为希音和小红书正在获得增长。但是，拼多多管理层对多多买菜的表现并不完全满意，多多买菜成立于 2020 年新冠疫情肆虐之时。它能让社区居民以较低的价格批量购买食品杂货和其他日用品。据《晚点 LatePost》援引一位拼多多高管的话称，尽管多多买菜已成为行业领军者，但由于毛利率低，它并不盈利。据中国新闻门户网站新浪网报道，尽管停止了本地生活服务，拼多多旗下多多买菜预计仍将继续运营。据市场情报公司艾瑞咨询估计，到 2025 年，中国本地生活服务市场的价值预计将达到 35 万亿元（合 4.9 万亿美元），美团、阿里巴巴和字节跳动等中国科技巨头在这一市场中争夺霸主地位。美团已经与餐厅评论网站大众点评和共享单车初创公司摩拜合并，目前在本地生活服务领域处于领先地位，提供一系列送餐、叫车和酒店预订服务。阿里巴巴一直寻求赶上美团，该公司的口碑餐厅评级服务与导航应用高德合并。阿里巴巴的本地生活服务部门还运营着送餐部门饿了么、生鲜配送服务淘鲜达和在线旅游平台飞猪。字节跳动的抖音是 TikTok 的中国版本，它利用其超过 6 亿的日活跃用户在大力发展按需电子商务领域。该公司于 2020 年成立了一个专门致力于本地生活服务的中心。放弃本地生活服务市场，在这个拼多多使用其 Temu 应用积极拓展海外业务的时刻发生，现在 Temu 已经进入美国、日本和其他几个市场。这一预算购物平台帮助拼多多第三季度收入几乎翻了一番，达到 688 亿元。  <ul>    <li>摘要：拼多多暂停本地生活服务业务以避免激烈竞争。</li>    <li>主题：中国本地生活服务市场竞争激烈，科技巨头争夺霸权。</li>    <li>观点：拼多多的决定反映了进入由老牌企业主导的拥挤市场的挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：拼多多计划通过多多买菜推出本地生活服务；该部门面临盈利能力问题；美团和阿里巴巴在市场上的主导地位；字节跳动在本地生活服务领域的影响力不断增加。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>leveraged (v.) - 利用，杠杆。    <p>原文例句：PDD had leveraged Duoduo Maicai’s business development team of around 3,000 people to sign up bricks-and-mortar outlets, such as restaurants and tourist attractions, the report said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语lier（提升）和-age（动作）,表示“撬起，提升，利用，杠杆”。在这个例句中，它指的是拼多多利用多多买菜的业务发展团队来签约实体店，包括餐厅和旅游景点。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>aggressive (adj.) - 积极的，激进的。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance’s Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has leveraged its more than 600 million daily active users to make aggressive moves in segments of on-demand e-commerce. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由aggredi（攻击）和-ive（具有……性质或倾向）组成，表示“积极的，激进的”。在这个例句中，它指的是字节跳动的抖音利用其超过 6 亿的日活跃用户在大力发展按需电子商务领域。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Meituan, which merged with restaurant review site Dianping and bike-sharing start-up Mobike, currently leads the sector with a range of food delivery, taxi-ride and hotel reservation services. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示美团目前在本地生活服务领域处于领先地位，提供一系列送餐、叫车和酒店预订服务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>PDD did not immediately respond to a request for comment. - 拼多多暂未回应置评请求。<p>句子分析：这是一个否定句，主语是PDD，谓语是did not respond，宾语是a request for comment。not是否定副词，immediately是副词，表示“立刻，马上”。这个句子的意思是说，拼多多暂未回应置评请求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Amazon has been seeking to catch up with the merger of its Koubei restaurant rating service and navigation app Amap. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示亚马逊一直在寻求赶上美团，该公司的口碑餐厅评级服务与导航应用高德合并。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>PDD had planned to launch local services offering in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, report says</li>
<li>Chinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in local services market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/416b82eb-4e16-46af-8cd9-c30d0a415c2f_5ba32be4.jpg" /><figcaption>Chinese Big Tech firms have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan by 2025. Photo: AFP </figcaption></figure><p>E-commerce giant PDD Holdings has halted work on its local life services offering, avoiding head-to-head rivalry with Meituan, Alibaba Group Holding and ByteDance, whose Douyin short video app has also dipped a toe into the sector.</p><p>PDD has “completely halted [development of] the local services business”, according to Chinese media outlet LatePost. PDD did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p>PDD, whose market cap overtook Alibaba in November after the firm beat revenue estimates, had planned to launch the service – which facilitates in-store orders including hotel reservations and movie tickets – in February 2024 under its community group-buying unit Duoduo Maicai, LatePost reported. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>PDD had leveraged Duoduo Maicai’s business development team of around 3,000 people to sign up bricks-and-mortar outlets, such as restaurants and tourist attractions, the report said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244976/amazon-doubles-down-china-e-commerce-strategy-rivals-shein-temu-gain-traction" title="">Amazon doubles down on China e-commerce strategy as Shein, Temu gain traction</a></h3><p>However, PDD’s management has not been completely satisfied with the performance of Duoduo Maicai, which was established in 2020 in the midst of the Covid-19 pandemic. It enables residents in a community to purchase groceries and other daily essentials in bulk, bringing prices down.</p><p>Although the unit has become an industry leader, it is not profitable due to low gross margins, according to the LatePost report, which cited a PDD executive. Duoduo Maicai is nevertheless expected to remain operational despite the halting of local life services, according to Chinese news portal Sina.</p><p>Chinese Big Tech firms including Meituan, Alibaba and TikTok owner ByteDance have jostled for supremacy in a local services market expected to be worth 35 trillion yuan (US$4.9 trillion) by 2025, according to estimates by market intelligence firm iResearch.</p><p>Meituan, which merged with restaurant review site Dianping and bike-sharing start-up Mobike, currently leads the sector with a range of food delivery, taxi-ride and hotel reservation services.</p><p>Alibaba has been seeking to catch up with the merger of its Koubei restaurant rating service and navigation app Amap. Alibaba’s local services segment also runs food delivery unit <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3048045/chinas-eleme-deliver-food-100-restaurants-frontline-medical-staff?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Ele.me</a>, grocery delivery service Taoxianda, and online travel platform Fliggy.</p><p>ByteDance’s Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has leveraged its more than 600 million daily active users to make <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3207434/bytedance-primes-short-video-app-douyin-challenge-meituan-demand-local-services-amid-chinas-push?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">aggressive moves in segments of on-demand e-commerce</a>. The company set up a centre dedicated to developing local services in 2020.</p><p>Abandoning the local services market comes as PDD continues to expand aggressively overseas with its Temu app, now available in the United States, Japan and several other markets. The budget shopping platform helped drive an almost doubling of PDD’s third-quarter revenue to 68.8 billion yuan.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Microsoft to show off Copilot AI key for Windows keyboards at CES, in first change to layout since 1994</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247280/microsoft-show-copilot-ai-key-windows-keyboards-ces-first-change-layout-1994</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Microsoft is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to quickly access its AI assistant. It's the first change to the keyboard layout since the addition of the Start key in 1994, emphasizing Microsoft's commitment to AI. The Copilot key will enable users to create images, write emails, and summarize text with AI assistance. Microsoft sees 2024 as "the year of the AI PC," mirroring the smartphone trend of promoting devices as "AI phones." The company has invested heavily in AI technologies, including GPT-4 from OpenAI, to enhance its products like Windows, Office, and Bing search. While AI services are being rolled out to existing and new devices, device makers have yet to see a boost in sales.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Microsoft introduces a Copilot key on Windows keyboards for easy access to AI features.</li>    <li>Theme: Microsoft's commitment to artificial intelligence and integration into its products and hardware.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Microsoft's strategy to make Windows and other products AI-powered and user-friendly.</li>    <li>Main information: The Copilot key's functions include image creation, email composition, and text summarization; Microsoft's investment in AI tech like GPT-4; the concept of "the year of the AI PC."; and the potential impact on device makers' sales.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  微软正在 Windows 键盘上添加一个 Copilot 键，以便用户可以快速访问其 AI 助手。这是自 1994 年添加开始键以来键盘布局的首次更改，突出了微软对人工智能的承诺。Copilot 键将使用户能够借助人工智能帮助创建图像、撰写电子邮件并总结文本。微软认为 2024 年是“人工智能个人电脑之年”，这与智能手机制造商将他们的最新型号宣传为“人工智能手机”的趋势相呼应。该公司已经大力投资人工智能技术，包括来自 OpenAI 的 GPT-4，以增强其产品，如 Windows、Office 和必应搜索。虽然人工智能服务正在推广到现有和新设备，但设备制造商尚未看到销售额的增长。  <ul>    <li>摘要：微软在 Windows 键盘上引入了一个 Copilot 键，以便轻松访问人工智能功能。</li>    <li>主题：微软对人工智能的承诺，并将其集成到产品和硬件中。</li>    <li>观点：微软的策略是使 Windows 和其他产品具有人工智能功能且对用户友好。</li>    <li>主要信息：Copilot 键的功能包括创建图像、撰写电子邮件和总结文本；微软对人工智能技术（如 GPT-4）的投资；“人工智能个人电脑之年”的概念；以及对设备制造商销售额的潜在影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>retool (v.) - /ˈriːtuːl/ 重新装备，重新设计。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由re-（再）和tool（工具）组成的，意思是“重新装备，重新设计”。在这个例句中，它表示微软在过去的一年中一直在重新设计其最大的产品，使其围绕着能够生成新内容的人工智能技术。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>prompt (n.) - /prɑːmpt/ 提示，触发。    <p>原文例句： “AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语prompt（及时），意思是“提示，触发”。在这个例句中，微软的首席营销官优素福·梅迪在宣布这一变化的博客中说，“人工智能将无缝地融入到Windows系统、芯片和硬件中”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in development - 正在开发中。    <P>原文例句：For device makers, Microsoft’s push into AI services has not yet translated into a boost for sales, as the novel Copilot features are being rolled out to new and existing devices alike. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由介词in，过去分词development和介词into组成，表示“处于开发中”。在这个例句中，它表示微软的人工智能服务还没有为设备制造商带来销售额的增长，因为新的Copilot功能正在面向新设备和现有设备推出。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves, but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets. - 这些标签本身并不具有太多分量，但微软在过去的一年中一直在围绕能够从海量数据集中生成新内容的人工智能技术重新设计其最大的产品。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets，其中主语是Microsoft，谓语是has spent，宾语是the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets。Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves是一个让步状语从句，表示虽然这些标签本身并不具有太多分量，但是微软在过去的一年中一直在围绕能够从海量数据集中生成新内容的人工智能技术重新设计其最大的产品。这个句子的意思是说，虽然这些标签本身并不具有太多分量，但是微软在过去的一年中一直在围绕能够从海量数据集中生成新内容的人工智能技术重新设计其最大的产品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去的某个时间或动作之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Mehdi’s promise of weaving AI into hardware and silicon may signal more pressure on consumers to upgrade as Microsoft evolves and improves its AI proposition. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + been + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示在过去的某个时间或动作之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，它表示梅迪承诺将人工智能融入硬件和芯片，可能会给消费者带来更大的升级压力，因为微软正在不断发展和改进其人工智能产品。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>原因状语从句 - 表示原因。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft sees 2024 as “the year of the AI PC”, according to Mehdi, mirroring the budding trend among smartphone makers to tout their latest models as “AI phones”. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个从句，结构是：because + 主句。其中because可以换成其他表示原因的连词或短语，如as，since，for等。这种从句表示原因或理由。在这个例句中，它表示微软将 2024 年视为“人工智能个人电脑之年”，原因是智能手机制造商正在兴起的趋势是将他们的最新型号吹捧为“人工智能手机”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Start key</li>
<li>The tech giant sees 2024 as ‘the year of the AI PC’ and has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/e31b152f-c194-4f64-8148-b14c9b1dd6e5_1adc5e70.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft said it is introducing a Copilot key to Windows keyboards to allow users to immediately call up its artificial intelligence assistant. Photo: YouTube / Windows</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft</a> is adding a button to the Windows keyboard to activate its AI Copilot service, with the first devices to sport the new key available this month.</p><p>The Copilot key, which will sit to the right of the space bar, is the first change to the Windows keyboard layout since Microsoft added the Windows/Start key in 1994, underscoring the company’s commitment to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a>. Microsoft’s hardware partners will show off Windows 11 computers with the Copilot button over the coming days at the CES technology conference and, over time, it will become a required feature.</p><p>The short cut will help users create images, write emails and summarise text with the help of AI.</p><p>“AI will be seamlessly woven into Windows from the system, to the silicon, to the hardware,” Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, Yusuf Mehdi, said in a blog announcing the change.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234530/microsoft-sees-booming-enterprise-ai-demand-hong-kong-amid-us-china-tech-war-threatens-cloud" title="">Microsoft touts booming enterprise AI demand in Hong Kong amid cloud push</a></h3><p>The Redmond, Washington-based company sees 2024 as “the year of the AI PC”, according to Mehdi, mirroring the budding trend among smartphone makers to tout their latest models as “AI phones”. Those labels don’t carry much weight by themselves, but Microsoft has spent the past year retooling its biggest products around AI tech that can generate new content from massive data sets. That list now includes Windows, Office, Bing search, security software and customer and finance products. The work heavily leverages the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">GPT-4 technology</a> from OpenAI, in which Microsoft has invested US$13 billion.</p><p>For device makers, Microsoft’s push into AI services has not yet translated into a boost for sales, as the novel Copilot features are being rolled out to new and existing devices alike. Mehdi’s promise of weaving AI into hardware and silicon may signal more pressure on consumers to upgrade as Microsoft evolves and improves its AI proposition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese search engine giant Baidu to donate quantum computing facility to state-backed lab in similar move to Alibaba</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247255/chinese-search-engine-giant-baidu-donate-quantum-computing-facility-state-backed-lab-similar-move</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese tech giants Baidu and Alibaba are donating their quantum computing research facilities to universities to focus on fundamental research and innovation in the field. The move is seen as part of the country's AI race with the US.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese tech firms Baidu and Alibaba donate quantum computing facilities to promote research and collaboration.</li>    <li>Theme: China's competitive AI landscape steers tech giants نحو the donation of quantum computing resources for academic advancement.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The strategic importance of quantum computing in driving AI innovation; the role of collaboration in advancing the field.</li>    <li>Main information: Baidu's donation to the Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences; Alibaba's donation to Zhejiang University; partnership with universities to facilitate IP cross-licensing.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国科技巨头百度和阿里巴巴将其量子计算研究设施捐赠给大学，以专注于该领域的根本研究和创新。此举被视为中国与美国人工智能竞赛的一部分。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国科技公司百度和阿里巴巴捐赠量子计算设施，以促进研究和协同创新。</li>    <li>主题：中国激烈的AI竞争格局引导科技巨头们捐赠量子计算资源以推动学术进步。</li>    <li>观点：量子计算在推动AI创新中的战略重要性；在该领域取得进步的合作作用。</li>    <li>主要信息：百度向北京量子信息科学研究院的捐赠；阿里巴巴向浙江大学的捐赠；与大学的合作以促进IP交叉授权。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>quantum computing - 量子计算。    <p>原文例句：Baidu said on Thursday it would donate its Baidu Institute for Quantum Computing and associated experiment apparatus to BAQIS. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由quantum（量子）和computing（计算）构成，表示“量子计算”。它是一种利用量子力学原理进行计算的新型计算方式，具有远超传统计算机的计算速度和能力。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>artificial intelligence - 人工智能。    <p>原文例句：Baidu, which was an early Chinese investor in AI applications including autonomous driving. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由artificial（人造的）和intelligence（智能）构成，表示“人工智能”。它是计算机科学的一个分支，致力于研究如何让计算机模拟人类的智能，包括认知、学习、推理和决策等。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>across-licensing - 交叉授权。    <p>原文例句：In March last year, Baidu and BAQIS jointly launched the country’s first quantum computing intellectual property (IP) alliance, with the goal of facilitating easier IP cross-licensing.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由across（交叉）和licensing（授权）构成，表示“交叉授权”。它是一种知识产权许可的方式，允许多个专利权人相互使用彼此的专利技术。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese search engine giant Baidu is donating its quantum computing research facility to the Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences (BAQIS), in a move similar to one made last year by e-commerce giant Alibaba Group Holding, as both firms lock horns in the country’s artificial intelligence (AI) race.    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，由两个并列分句组成，主句是Baidu is donating its quantum computing research facility to the Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences (BAQIS)，其中主语是Baidu，谓语是is donating，宾语是its quantum computing research facility to the Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences (BAQIS)。in a move similar to one made last year by e-commerce giant Alibaba Group Holding是一个状语从句，修饰主句，表示百度此举与去年阿里巴巴集团控股有限公司的举动类似。as both firms lock horns in the country’s artificial intelligence (AI) race是一个原因状语从句，修饰主句，表示百度和阿里巴巴两家公司在中国的人工智能竞赛中竞争激烈。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Baidu said on Thursday it would donate its Baidu Institute for Quantum Computing and associated experiment apparatus to BAQIS. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：be + 动词的-ing形式。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化。这种时态表示动作或状态正在进行，强调动作或状态的持续性。在这个例句中，it would donate表示百度将捐赠其量子计算研究所和相关的实验设备给BAQIS，表示这一动作正在进行。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示两个或多个事物或情况在某一方面的差异。    <p>原文例句：Quantum computers are not designed to replace traditional computers, they are able to solve very complex statistical problems via simultaneous multiple calculations, making them much faster.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个语法结构，结构是：比较级+than+被比较的事物或情况。其中比较级是形容词或副词的比较级形式。这种结构表示两个或多个事物或情况在某一方面的差异。在这个例句中，much faster表示量子计算机比传统计算机快得多，强调了量子计算机的计算速度优势。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Last March, Baidu and BAQIS jointly launched the country’s first quantum computing intellectual property alliance, with the goal of facilitating easier IP cross-licensing</li>
<li>In 2023, Alibaba’s in-house research institution Damo Academy announced it was donating its own quantum lab to Zhejiang University</li>
</ul><p>Chinese search engine giant Baidu is donating its quantum computing research facility to the Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences (BAQIS), in a move similar to one made last year by e-commerce giant Alibaba Group Holding, as both firms lock horns in the country’s artificial intelligence (AI) race.</p><p>Baidu said on Thursday it would donate its Baidu Institute for Quantum Computing and associated experiment apparatus to BAQIS, a government-backed laboratory. The two parties are currently discussing details of the donation, according to a company statement.</p><p>Beijing-based Baidu, which was an early Chinese investor in AI applications including autonomous driving, established its quantum computing facility in early 2018.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3230671/tech-war-new-us-investment-curbs-have-limited-impact-chinas-targeted-semiconductors-quantum" title="">New US investment curbs to have limited impact on China’s targeted tech sectors</a></h3><p>It was launched with a mission to “become a top-tier global quantum computing research institution in five years”, with a focus on several areas including quantum AI, quantum algorithms and quantum architecture, according to local media the Paper.</p><p>In March last year, Baidu and BAQIS jointly launched the country’s first quantum computing intellectual property (IP) alliance, with the goal of facilitating easier IP cross-licensing and innovation in the industry.</p><p>Quantum computing is an emerging field of science that harnesses the principles of fundamental physics to solve problems too complex for traditional computers.</p><p>While quantum computers are not designed to replace traditional computers, they are able to solve very complex statistical problems via simultaneous multiple calculations, making them much faster.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3224737/chinese-scientists-use-quantum-computing-simulate-black-hole" title="">Chinese scientists use quantum computing to simulate black hole</a></h3><p>China and the US have been competing for supremacy in this field in recent years, although the technology is still in its early stage of development. Beijing did not define the area as a national priority until late 2020.</p><p>Last November, Alibaba’s in-house research institution Damo Academy announced it was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242956/alibaba-donates-its-quantum-lab-local-university-shifts-focus-ai-agriculture-healthcare" target="_self" title="">donating its own quantum lab to Zhejiang University.</a> Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Damo Academy said at the time that it would become more focused on fundamental research in AI and its application in areas such as agriculture and healthcare.</p><p>While quantum computing is still a long way from achieving large-scale commercialisation, the new trend of generative AI has been spreading rapidly around the world.</p><p>OpenAI, which unleashed a new era of AI with its conversational bot ChatGPT, was reported to be generating annual revenues of US$1.6 billion, according to US digital media outlet The Information. The San-Francisco-based start-up’s rival Anthropic was forecast to rake in over US$850 billion in annualised revenue by the end of 2024.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TikTok eyes US$17.5 billion shopping business on Amazon’s turf</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247219/tiktok-eyes-us175-billion-shopping-business-amazons-turf</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  TikTok has set an ambitious e-commerce target to grow its US business tenfold to $17.5 billion this year, posing a challenge to Amazon and fellow Chinese-owned budget retailers Temu and Shein. Aiming to combine the ease of shopping on Amazon with the product discovery of social media, TikTok's strategy involves offering free shipping, subsidies for influencers, and easy shopping integration within its popular short-video app. TikTok Shop experienced rapid US growth during Black Friday and Cyber Monday, attracting over 5 million new customers. The company will increase fees for merchants to generate revenue, while ensuring they remain lower than Amazon's seller fees.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: TikTok's ambitious e-commerce expansion plans in the US.</li>    <li>Theme: TikTok's competitive strategy and the growing popularity of Chinese e-commerce apps in the US market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: TikTok's potential to disrupt the e-commerce landscape and the advantages it offers to users and merchants.</li>    <li>Main information: TikTok Shop's growth target, its unique shopping format, expansion plans, promotional strategies, and revenue-generating measures.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  TikTok设定雄心勃勃的电商目标，计划将美国业务增长十倍至175亿美元，对亚马逊和同属中国所有者的平价零售商Temu和Shein构成挑战。TikTok的策略旨在结合亚马逊购物的便捷性和社交媒体的产品发现功能，包括提供免运费、补贴网红并与其备受欢迎的短视频应用程序轻松整合购物功能。TikTok Shop在黑色星期五和网络星期一期间在美国迅速增长，吸引了500多万新客户。公司将提高商家费用以产生收入，同时确保费用低于亚马逊的卖家费用。  <ul>    <li>摘要：TikTok在美国雄心勃勃的电商扩张计划。</li>    <li>主题：TikTok的竞争策略以及中国电商应用程序在美国市场日益增长的受欢迎程度。</li>    <li>观点：TikTok扰乱电商格局的潜力，以及它为用户和商家提供的优势。</li>    <li>主要信息：TikTok Shop的增长目标、独特的购物形式、扩张计划、促销策略和创收措施。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ambitious (adj.) - /æmˈbɪʃəs/ 雄心勃勃的，有抱负的。    <p>原文例句：TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon, but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein. - TikTok的雄心勃勃的目标不仅与Amazon竞争，还与同样由中国所有者经营的Temu和Shein等服装竞争。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由amb-（周围）和ire（走）构成，表示“四周走动，四处奔走”，引申为“雄心勃勃的”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok的目标非常高，不仅要与亚马逊竞争，还要与同样由中国所有者经营的Temu和Shein等服装竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rival (n.) - /ˈraɪvəl/ 竞争对手。    <p>原文例句：TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales through its platform, Bloomberg News reported. The company is now seeking to expand sales across the US and Latin America, where it is planning to launch the e-commerce operation in coming months, two people familiar with the matter said. - 彭博新闻社报道，TikTok去年在全球商品总值中占据了约200亿美元，其中大部分销售额来自东南亚。该公司目前正寻求在美国和拉丁美洲扩大销售，据两位知情人士透露，它计划在未来几个月内在那里启动电商业务。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古代法语，由river（竞争）演变而来，表示“竞争者，对手”。在这个例句中，它指的是在市场上相互竞争的企业或个人。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>e-commerce (n.) - /ˌiː ˈkɑːmɜːrs/ 电子商务，网上购物。    <p>原文例句：TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams within its main social media app, hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee. - TikTok Shop允许用户在浏览其主要社交媒体应用中不断刷新的短视频和直播流时购买商品，希望消费者将其作为亚马逊或Shopee等平台的替代品。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由electronic（电子的）和commerce（商业）构成，表示“电子商务，网上购物”。在这个例句中，它指的是一种通过互联网进行商品或服务的买卖行为。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>set up (v.) - 设立，建立；准备，安排。    <p>原文例句：TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon, but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein. - TikTok的雄心勃勃的目标不仅与Amazon竞争，还与同样由中国所有者经营的Temu和Shein等服装竞争。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由set（设置）和up（向上）构成，表示“设立，建立；准备，安排”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok的目标非常高，不仅要与亚马逊竞争，还要与同样由中国所有者经营的Temu和Shein等服装竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>on track - 在轨道上，在正确的道路上。    <p>原文例句：The company is now seeking to expand sales across the US and Latin America, where it is planning to launch the e-commerce operation in coming months, two people familiar with the matter said. - 据两位知情人士透露，该公司目前正寻求在美国和拉丁美洲扩大销售，它计划在未来几个月内在那里启动电商业务。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由on（在）和track（轨道）构成，表示“在轨道上，在正确的道路上”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok的电商业务正在顺利进行中，并且计划在未来几个月内在美国和拉丁美洲推出。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>take control of - 控制，掌握。    <p>原文例句：In Indonesia, TikTok has taken control of GoTo Group’s e-commerce unit Tokopedia in a US$1.5 billion deal, which allowed the company to restart its online retail service after months of scrutiny by the local government. - 在印度尼西亚，TikTok以15亿美元的价格收购了GoTo集团的电商部门Tokopedia，使该公司能够在经过当地政府数月的审查后重新启动其在线零售服务。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由take（拿，取）和control（控制，掌握）构成，表示“控制，掌握”。在这个例句中，它指的是TikTok收购了GoTo集团的电商部门Tokopedia，从而控制了Tokopedia的业务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams within its main social media app, hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee. - TikTok Shop允许用户在浏览其主要社交媒体应用中不断刷新的短视频和直播流时购买商品，希望消费者将其作为亚马逊或Shopee等平台的替代品。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是TikTok Shop lets users buy items，其中主语是TikTok Shop，谓语是lets，宾语是users buy items。while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams within its main social media app是一个时间状语，表示用户在浏览TikTok Shop中不断刷新的短视频和直播流时。hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee是一个目的状语，表示TikTok Shop希望消费者将其作为亚马逊或Sea’s Shopee的替代品。这个句子的意思是说，TikTok Shop允许用户在浏览其主要社交媒体应用中不断刷新的短视频和直播流时购买商品，希望消费者将其作为亚马逊或Sea’s Shopee的替代品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>动词不定式做目的状语 - 表示目的或原因。    <p>原文例句：The company is now seeking to expand sales across the US and Latin America, where it is planning to launch the e-commerce operation in coming months, two people familiar with the matter said. - 据两位知  <ul><li>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon, but also fellow Chinese-owned outfits Temu and Shein</li>
<li>TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales</li>
</ul><p>TikTok, the global hit short-video platform owned by ByteDance, aims to grow the size of its US e-commerce business tenfold to as much as US$17.5 billion this year, according to people familiar with the matter, posing a bigger threat to Amazon.com.</p><p>The 2024 merchandise volume goal for the US version of TikTok Shop – which melds online entertainment with impulse buying – was discussed in internal meetings in recent weeks and may still change depending on how the business goes, said the people, who asked not to be named discussing private information.</p><p>TikTok’s ambitious target sets up a clash not just with Amazon but also fellow Chinese-owned budget retail outfits Temu and Shein, which have been making big strides among younger American shoppers.</p><p>Unlike its two rival discounters, TikTok is counting on its social media reach and the appeal of viral videos to hook buyers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>TikTok was last year on track to amass around US$20 billion in global gross merchandise value, with Southeast Asia contributing the bulk of sales through its platform, Bloomberg News reported. The company is now seeking to expand sales across the US and Latin America, where it is planning to launch the e-commerce operation in coming months, two people familiar with the matter said.</p><p>“The speculated US merchandise sales figures represented by Bloomberg are inaccurate,” TikTok said in a statement.</p><p>ByteDance, founded more than a decade ago by Zhang Yiming and Liang Rubo, grew into an internet leader worth more than US$200 billion thanks to the virality of short-video platforms TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin. TikTok Shop is one of the fastest-growing features for the Beijing-based, closely held company, which is seeking a new growth driver beyond social-media advertising. ByteDance’s revenue surged roughly 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing the projected growth of far more established social media rivals Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings.</p><p>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams within its main social media app, hoping consumers use it as an alternative to Amazon or Sea’s Shopee. That format – an effort to combine the ease of shopping on Amazon with the product discovery afforded by apps like Meta’s Instagram – has already helped Douyin snatch a significant portion of Chinese consumer spending from Alibaba Group Holding and JD.com, particularly after lockdown rules during the pandemic drove people to spend more time online. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/04/80b40a96-5660-44d3-a756-f6c48d3cb312_1126e908.jpg" title="TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>TikTok Shop lets users buy items while scrolling through a perpetual feed of short videos and live streams. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>ByteDance is intent on exporting its e-commerce model globally. In the US, TikTok is offering free shipping and subsidies to influencers who peddle gadgets, clothes and make-up in videos and live streams. In November, boosted by Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals, more than 5 million new US customers bought something on TikTok, the company said. It has roughly 150 million users in the country.</p><p>TikTok on Wednesday announced it will increase fees imposed on merchants to 6 per cent of each sale beginning in April and to 8 per cent in July in most product categories, marking an end to promotions used to entice sellers. Those commissions are still significantly lower than Amazon seller fees, which are typically about 15 per cent, but the boost signals TikTok is quickly moving to generate revenue from its e-commerce platform.</p><p>Americans are increasingly comfortable shopping on Chinese e-commerce apps, including the popular fashion site Shein and PDD Holdings' Temu, which has exploded in popularity since airing a Super Bowl ad in February.</p><p>It is unclear what sales targets TikTok Shop has set globally or for other markets. In Indonesia, TikTok has taken control of GoTo Group’s e-commerce unit Tokopedia in a US$1.5 billion deal, which allowed the company to restart its online retail service after months of scrutiny by the local government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247211/apple-leads-us383-billion-tech-rout-reversal-groups-2023-rally</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary:</h2>  After a year of fast growth, the "Magnificent Seven" tech giants, including Apple, Amazon, Alphabet, Microsoft, Meta Platforms, Tesla and Nvidia, faced a stock market correction at the start of 2024. This decline reflects investor concerns about the sustainability of their growth, especially with the Federal Reserve's pursuit of a soft landing for the economy. The tech giants now need to focus on delivering profitable technology to recoup the losses and maintain their market dominance.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tech stock loses momentum after a year of exponential growth.</li>    <li>Theme: The slowdown of the "Magnificent Seven" tech giants in 2024 amid economic uncertainties and rising investor doubts.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of delivering profitable technology to sustain growth in the tech industry.</li>    <li>Main information: The performance of the "Magnificent Seven" stocks in early 2024; factors contributing to their decline, such as investor doubts and economic factors; the challenges they face in maintaining growth.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  经过一年的快速增长，“七雄”科技巨头，包括苹果、亚马逊、Alphabet、微软、Meta Platforms、特斯拉和Nvidia，在2024年初面临股市回调。这种下滑反映了投资者对其增长的可持续性担忧，尤其是美联储为经济软着陆而采取的行动。这些科技巨头现在需要专注于提供有利可图的技术，以弥补损失并维持其市场主导地位。  <ul>    <li>摘要：科技股在经历一年的指数级增长后失去动力。</li>    <li>主题：“七雄”科技巨头在2024年经济不确定性和投资者怀疑情绪高涨的情况下增长放缓。</li>    <li>观点：提供有利可图的技术以维持科技行业增长的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：“七雄”股票在2024年初的表现；导致其下跌的因素，如投资者怀疑和经济因素；它们在保持增长方面面临的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>frenzy (n.) - /ˈfrɛnzi/ 疯狂，狂热，激情。    <p>原文例句：Though the Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语frenesie，意为“疯狂，狂热”，可用于描述强烈的情绪或行为。在这个例句中，它指的是对人工智能的狂热，推动了“七雄”科技巨头在去年大幅上涨。</p></li>    <li>rally (v.) - /ˈræli/ 集结，反弹，上涨，复苏。    <p>原文例句：A few members of the group have also seen specific stock pressure early this year. Apple shares have been weighed down after gaining a new bear; Barclays analysts early this week downgraded shares of the tech giant to underweight, saying they expect soft demand for iPhones going forward.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语ralier，意为“集结，反弹，上涨，复苏”，可用于描述股票或经济的反弹或复苏。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果股票在年初面临的抛压，导致其股价下跌。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>recoup (v.) - /rɪˈkup/ 补偿，挽回，追回，重新获得。    <p>原文例句：Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier, and some of the group – Amazon, Alphabet, Meta and Tesla – are still below their all-time highs, signalling they could have room to run.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语recoverer，意为“补偿，挽回，追回，重新获得”，可用于描述挽回损失或重新获得失去的东西。在这个例句中，它指的是“七雄”科技巨头在2023年的大部分涨幅抵消了前一年的亏损，表明它们仍有上涨空间。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：To be sure, it is likely too early to say the tech-focused rally is over. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示确定地说科技股的涨势已经结束还为时过早。</p></li>    <li>going forward - 以后，今后，未来。    <P>原文例句：The companies need to continue to deliver not only solid technology, but profitable technology going forward, according to Sosnick. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由going（进行）和forward（前进）组成，表示“以后，今后，未来”。在这个例句中，它表示Sosnick认为，这些公司需要继续提供不仅是可靠的技术，而且是未来有利可图的技术。</p></li>    </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The largest technology stocks that lifted the broader market last year are having a less-rosy start to 2024. - 去年提振了大盘走势的科技巨头们今年开局不佳。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The largest technology stocks are having a less-rosy start to 2024，其中主语是The largest technology stocks，谓语是are having，宾语是a less-rosy start to 2024。that lifted the broader market last year是一个定语从句，修饰The largest technology stocks，表示这些科技巨头在去年提振了大盘走势。这个句子的意思是说，去年提振了大盘走势的科技巨头们今年开局不佳。</p></li>    <li>Apple shares have been weighed down after gaining a new bear; Barclays analysts early this week downgraded shares of the tech giant to underweight, saying they expect soft demand for iPhones going forward. - 苹果股价在获得一位新看空者之后承压；巴克莱分析师本周早些时候将这家科技巨头的股票评级下调至“减持”，称他们预计iPhone未来的需求疲软。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Apple shares have been weighed down，其中主语是Apple shares，谓语是have been weighed down。after gaining a new bear; Barclays analysts early this week downgraded shares of the tech giant to underweight, saying they expect soft demand for iPhones going forward是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示苹果股票在获得一位新看空者之后承压。这个句子的意思是说，苹果股价在获得一位新看空者之后承压；巴克莱分析师本周早些时候将这家科技巨头的股票评级下调至“减持”，称他们预计iPhone未来的需求疲软。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示一个动作或状态从过去某个时间开始，一直持续到说话或写字的时间。    <p>原文例句：The largest technology stocks that lifted the broader market last year are having a less-rosy start to 2024. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则过去分词形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始，一直持续到说话或写字的时间，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示去年提振了大盘走势的科技巨头们今年开局不佳，强调这种开局不佳的状态从今年年初持续到现在。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 把句子中某个成分提前到句子开头，强调这个成分。    <p>原文例句：To be sure, it is likely too early to say the tech-focused rally is over. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个修辞手法，通常用于强调句子的某个成分。结构是：To be sure + 主语 + 谓语 + 其他。其中To be sure表示“可以肯定，事实上”。在这个例句中，它表示可以肯定地说科技股的涨势已经结束还  <ul><li>The Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023</li>
<li>Though Tesla said it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as top seller of EVs to China’s BYD</li>
</ul><p>The largest technology stocks that lifted the broader market last year are having a less-rosy start to 2024.</p><p>The so-called Magnificent Seven, which includes Apple, Amazon.com, Alphabet, Microsoft, Meta Platforms, Tesla and Nvidia, slipped for the last four trading days, the longest losing streak in a month, according to the Bloomberg Magnificent 7 Price Return Index.</p><p>Shares of Apple, down 4.6 per cent in the time period, lead the slump that has erased US$383 billion in market value. The Nasdaq 100 Index has also fallen in the last four trading days.</p><p>“We don’t know if last year’s rally has fully ended, but it is completely normal to expect markets will pull back after a rally like we saw,” said Steve Sosnick, chief strategist at Interactive Brokers Group. “Without the year-end factors that turbocharged the rally, I think we’re seeing the party winding down.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" title="">Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets</a></h3><p>It is a signal that investor doubts over the sticking power of the 2023 rally were well-placed.</p><p>Though the Magnificent Seven surged more than 100 per cent last year, driven by a frenzy in artificial intelligence, gains cooled in the second half of 2023 as investors mulled the Federal Reserve’s ability to execute a soft landing for the US economy, which would likely mean fewer interest rate cuts than expected.</p><p>“You’re not going to get high-single-digit or double-digit earnings growth if we get something worse than a soft landing,” Sosnick said. “But we’re not going to get six cuts with a soft landing.”</p><p>A few members of the group have also seen specific stock pressure early this year. Apple shares have been weighed down after gaining a new bear; Barclays analysts early this week downgraded shares of the tech giant to underweight, saying they expect soft demand for iPhones going forward.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" title="">Apple hits 7-week low after Barclays downgrade on demand concerns</a></h3><p>Tesla has shed 8.8 per cent in the last four days, its longest streak of losses in more than four weeks. Though Tesla reported on Tuesday that it delivered more electric vehicles in the fourth quarter than analysts expected, the company lost its place as the top seller of electric cars to China’s BYD.</p><p>To be sure, it is likely too early to say the tech-focused rally is over. Most of 2023’s gains recouped losses from a year earlier, and some of the group – Amazon, Alphabet, Meta and Tesla – are still below their all-time highs, signalling they could have room to run.</p><p>But, the largest tech names also have their work cut out for them in 2024. The companies need to continue to deliver not only solid technology, but profitable technology going forward, according to Sosnick.</p><p>“In December everyone bought the sizzle,” he said. “Now we have to see if the steak is any good.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>New refund policies from Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com spark fears of customer abuse among merchants</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247168/new-refund-policies-alibabas-taobao-and-jdcom-spark-fears-customer-abuse-among-merchants</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  中国电商平台淘宝和京东推出了新的退款政策：消费者可以无条件退款，即使他们已经收到货。一些商家对此表示担忧，认为这会鼓励消费者滥用政策，损害平台运营。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: New Chinese e-commerce policies allow unrestricted refunds, sparking abuse concerns.</li>    <li>Theme: Taobao and JD.com introduce "refund only" policies that allow customers to keep and receive a refund for unsatisfactory purchases, causing merchant apprehension about potential exploitation.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The possible negative impact of flexible refund policies on merchants and the potential for consumer exploitation and abuse.</li>    <li>Main information: Initiation of the new refund policy by Taobao and JD.com; merchant concerns about abuse; Pinduoduo's earlier implementation of a similar policy and its perceived success.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  淘宝和京东等中国电商平台推出了新的退款政策：即使消费者已经收到货，也可以无条件退款。一些商家对此表示担忧，认为这会鼓励消费者滥用政策，损害平台运营。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国新的电子商务政策允许无条件退款，引发滥用担忧。</li>    <li>主题：淘宝和京东推出“仅退款”政策，允许消费者保留不满意的商品并获得退款，引发商家对潜在滥用的担忧。</li>    <li>观点：灵活的退款政策对商家可能产生的负面影响以及消费者可能存在的滥用和欺诈行为。</li>    <li>主要信息：淘宝和京东出台新的退款政策；商家对滥用行为的担忧；拼多多较早实施类似政策并取得的所谓成功。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>refund (n.) - /ˈriːfʌnd/ 退款，退还。    <p>原文例句：Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse under new refund policies. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源自古法语refunder，意为“退还，退款”。在这个例句中，它表示一些商家担心新的退款政策可能被滥用。</p></li>  </ul> <ul>    <li>exploit (v.) - /ɪkˈspləɪt/ 剥削，利用。    <p>原文例句：Some merchants have raised concerns that consumers may look to exploit the terms of these ‘refund only’ policies.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源自拉丁语explicare，意为“展开”。在这个例句中，它表示一些商家担心消费者可能利用这些“仅退款”政策的漏洞。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>abuse (v.) - /əˈbjuːz/ 滥用，利用。    <p>原文例句：The 33-year-old online shop owner, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of retribution from the platforms, said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products, because they will bear higher costs in the event of more claims.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源自拉丁语abusus，意为“滥用”。在这个例句中，它表示这位33岁的网店店主担心新的退款政策可能会导致消费者滥用权利，给那些销售高质量产品的卖家带来损失。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>refund request - 退款请求。    <p>原文例句：Both Taobao and JD.com have said that any decisions on refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示消费者要求退款。在这个例句中，它表示淘宝和京东均表示，平台上的任何退款请求决定都将基于多个指标，包括商家和买家的历史记录，以及大数据分析。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse of the terms under new refund policies. 一些商家对新的退款政策条款可能被滥用表示担忧。<p>句子分析：这是一个含有介词of的复合句。Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse是主句，其中主语是Some merchants，谓语是have raised，宾语是concerns about potential abuse。of the terms under new refund policies是一个介词短语，作宾语about abuse的定语，表示新退款政策条款。这个句子的意思是说，一些商家对新的退款政策条款可能被滥用表示担忧。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Taobao and JD.com in late December introduced new policies that – in certain circumstances – allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示淘宝和京东在12月底推出了新的政策，在某些情况下，消费者即使保留产品也可以获得退款。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Taobao and JD.com have introduced policies that allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it</li>
<li>Some merchants have raised concerns that consumers may look to exploit the terms of these ‘refund only’ policies, hitting their operations</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/85b29bec-f2e3-42ad-ba41-d20ec559a707_664d3160.jpg" /><figcaption>Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse under new refund policies. Photo: SCMP</figcaption></figure><p>New “refund only” policies introduced by Chinese e-commerce players including Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao and JD.com have sparked concern among some sellers about potential abuse of the terms, according to merchants and analysts.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com in late December introduced new policies that – in certain circumstances – allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it. This may occur when a consumer complains about the poor quality of a product, or about an inaccurate and misleading description on the platform. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Alibaba, whose company mission is “to make it easy to do business anywhere”, had a long internal debate over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo, which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it.</p><p>Even though some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse, Alibaba came down on the side of consumer rights in such a situation as merchants are ultimately dependent on buyer confidence, according to a person briefed on the discussions who asked not to be identified.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>However, since the policy went into effect last week there has been an increased number of claims under the “refund but keep the purchase” policy, according to one merchant who runs apparel shops on both Taobao and JD.com, adding that some consumers were looking to exploit the situation.</p><p>The 33-year-old online shop owner, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of retribution from the platforms, said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products, because they will bear higher costs in the event of more claims.</p><p>“This refund terms only works for merchants who sell dirt-cheap goods,” she said, adding that the policy clearly favoured consumers.</p><p>Meanwhile, some merchants took to social media platforms such as Douyin and Weibo to express anger at the potential for policy abuse.</p><p>One user with the handle “PengqiangweiVerna” posted on Weibo that the practice will “foster a group of online freeloaders”. Another Douyin user called “Xinzhouxiaohuolang” posted a dozen videos denouncing such refund requests.</p><p>Both Taobao and JD.com have said that any decisions on refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments.</p><p>A person familiar with the situation at Taobao, who asked not to be identified as they are not authorised to talk to the media, said that the platform has offered merchants an appeal option if they think they have been wronged.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Wednesday.</p><p>Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice was initially launched in 2021 and is seen as a key factor behind the Shanghai-based budget-shopping platform’s rise to prominence.</p><p>Tang Guangyao, a 38-year-old Beijing software developer, said he has shifted from other e-commerce platforms to Pinduoduo as a primary shopping channel owing to its robust consumer protection, even though it focuses on budget prices.</p><p>But some analysts say simply following Pinduoduo’s lead may not work for rival platforms.</p><p>“This [new refund policy] isn’t very practical for platforms such as Taobao, Tmall and JD.com,” said Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangzhou-based iiMedia, pointing out that Pinduoduo’s focus on rock-bottom prices means that the costs of the scheme are more bearable than for merchants on rival sites.</p><p>“By following this [Pinduoduo] refund policy … [rival platforms] will give their merchants a dilemma,” he added.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
