<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>This year, prepare for the magic wand of generative AI to transform our world</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3247183/year-prepare-magic-wand-generative-ai-transform-our-world</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Generative AI is emerging as a multi-modal technology with applications in language, images, videos, and other forms of media.</li>    <li>It is expected to transform communication, art, and content creation by enabling the effortless combination of different media types.</li>    <li>Auto agents and personalized generative AI systems are being developed to enhance user interaction and tailor content.</li>    <li>Generative AI has implications for 6G technology, aiding in resource management and optimizing network performance.</li>    <li>It is seen as a valuable assistant that can support individuals and businesses in solving complex tasks and providing real-time solutions.</li>    <li>Governments must address ethical, privacy, and copyright issues to ensure responsible and beneficial use of the technology.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>生成式人工智能正在成为一种多模态技术，应用于语言、图像、视频和其他形式的媒体。</li>    <li>预计它将通过轻松结合不同类型的媒体来改变交流、艺术和内容创作。</li>    <li>正在开发自动代理和个性化生成式人工智能系统，以增强用户交互和定制内容。</li>    <li>生成式人工智能对 6G 技术有影响，有助于资源管理和优化网络性能。</li>    <li>它被视为一种有价值的助手，可以支持个人和企业解决复杂任务并提供实时解决方案。</li>    <li>政府必须解决道德、隐私和版权问题，以确保负责任和有益地使用该技术。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>multimodal (adj.) - /ˈmʌltɪˌmoʊd(ə)l/ 多模态的，多种形式的。    <p>原文例句：With the emergence of models like GPT-4, generative AI is shifting towards multi-modal expression, enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data.    <p>例句讲解：这个词由multi（多种）和modal（方式）组成，表示“多种形式的，多模态的”。在这个例句中，它描述了生成式人工智能正转向多模态表达，能够同时处理多种形式的数据。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>auto agent (n.) - /ˈɔːtəʊ ˈeɪdʒənt/ 自动代理。    <p>原文例句：In response to this limitation, scientists are researching “auto agent” technology.    <p>例句讲解：这个词由auto（自动）和agent（代理）组成，表示“自动代理”。在这个例句中，它描述了科学家正在研究“自动代理”技术，以解决生成式人工智能仅具有被动响应的问题。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>federated learning (n.) - /ˈfɛdəreɪtɪd ˈlɜːnɪŋ/ 联邦学习。    <p>原文例句：Generative AI applications that operate locally on personal computers and smartphones are built upon the concept of “federated learning”.    <p>例句讲解：这个词由federated（联邦的）和learning（学习）组成，表示“联邦学习”。在这个例句中，它描述了生成式人工智能应用程序在个人电脑和智能手机上本地运行的原理，即“联邦学习”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>single media type - 单一媒体类型。    <p>原文例句：Last year, most generative AI tools, algorithms and large language models were primarily focused on a single media type: text, images, speech or video, with limited emphasis on the simultaneous processing of multiple media.    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“单一媒体类型”。在这个例句中，它描述了去年大多数生成式人工智能工具、算法和大语言模型主要集中在单一媒体类型，如文本、图像、语音或视频上，并且对同时处理多种媒体的关注有限。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>connective intelligence - 连接智能。    <p>原文例句：Connective intelligence is a key force driving the development of the 6G network, enabling real-time, reliable and ubiquitous interaction and communication between humans, the physical world and the digital world.    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“连接智能”。在这个例句中，它描述了连接智能是推动 6G 网络发展的主要力量，可以实现人类、物理世界和数字世界之间实时、可靠和无处不在的交互和通信。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Generative AI will play a crucial role in 6G mobile technology. This year, work to set and agree on 6G standards will continue with the anticipation that the first standards could be introduced between 2027 and 2028, and the technology could reach commercialisation by 2030. - 生成式人工智能将在 6G 移动技术中发挥关键作用。今年，制定和同意 6G 标准的工作将继续进行，预计首批标准可能会在 2027 年至 2028 年之间推出，该技术可能在 2030 年实现商业化。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Generative AI will play a crucial role in 6G mobile technology，其中主语是Generative AI，谓语是will play a crucial role，宾语是in 6G mobile technology。This year, work to set and agree on 6G standards will continue with the anticipation that the first standards could be introduced between 2027 and 2028, and the technology could reach commercialisation by 2030是一个时间状语从句，表示今年，制定和同意 6G 标准的工作将继续进行，预计首批标准可能会在 2027 年至 2028 年之间推出，该技术可能在 2030 年实现商业化。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Generative AI has become an irreversible trend, penetrating our daily lives in profound ways.    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示生成式人工智能已经成为一种不可逆转的趋势，深刻地渗透到我们的日常生活。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：Governments must pay attention to ethical, privacy and copyright issues to ensure the positive development of the technology.    <p>语法讲解：这是一个语态，结构是：be + 过去分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是由动词的过去式或过去分词构成的。这种语态表示动作或状态是由句子中的宾语承受的。在这个例句中，它表示政府必须关注道德、隐私和版权问题，以确保该技术的积极发展。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Generative AI is becoming active, multimodal and being embedded in PCs and smartphones, penetrating our daily lives in profound ways</li>
<li>Governments must pay attention to ethical, privacy and copyright issues to ensure the positive development of the technology</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/993c33b7-d303-46f3-9fa7-b02b2516d087_73af80ad.jpg" /><figcaption>Customs inspector Hui Ka-hei explains how XiaoHui, a virtual ambassador introduced at Hong Kong’s airport and three control points, works to to handle public enquiries, on December 29. Photo: Dickson Lee</figcaption></figure><p>Since the debut of ChatGPT at the end of 2022, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243449/chatgpt-one-year-how-openais-chatbot-brought-generative-artificial-intelligence-public-consciousness" target="_self" title="">generative artificial intelligence</a> (AI) has gained popularity globally. Various industries are eagerly adopting generative AI for diverse applications including the creation of text, images, videos, computer codes and more.</p><p>The output of generative AI in these domains has proliferated, presenting a diverse array of creative work. According to Gartner, an information technology (IT) research and consulting company in the United States, use of generative AI will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245217/chinese-generative-ai-account-third-industrys-economic-value-2035-beijing-think-tank-says" target="_self" title="">increase substantially</a> by 2026. It projects that more than 80 per cent of businesses will have integrated generative AI application programming interfaces (APIs), models and/or applications into their operations by then, from less than 5 per cent now.</p><p>IT experts believe that generative AI will play a transformative role this year, akin to a magic wand that changes the world. In light of these developments, what major trends in generative AI can we expect this year?</p><p>Last year, most generative AI tools, algorithms and large language models were primarily focused on a single media type: text, images, speech or video, with limited emphasis on the simultaneous processing of multiple media. But with the emergence of models like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238197/baidu-says-ai-chatbot-ernie-now-matches-openais-gpt-4-unveils-new-enterprise-tools" target="_self" title="">GPT-4</a>, generative AI is shifting towards multi-modal expression, enabling the simultaneous handling of diverse forms of data.</p><p>This suggests that human-machine communication will one day effortlessly incorporate mixed media, as ChatGPT is starting to do. Users can input non-textual cues, such as images, making the conversation more convenient and natural.</p><p>Furthermore, multi-modal generative AI is poised to enhance the creative capabilities of artists and improve the efficiency of professionals in fields such as writing, journalism and music. When appropriately used, multi-modal generative AI can spark artistic inspiration, generate work drafts or even fully automate content creation.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>In 2024, there is likely to be a proliferation of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224924/ai-challenging-us-rethink-distinction-between-real-and-fake" target="_self" title="">AI-generated art</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3227291/ai-generated-hits-hong-kong-stars-surprise-fans-bring-dead-singers-back-life-and-raise-questions" target="_self" title="">music</a>, videos and stories. Experts believe that through generative AI’s artistic contributions, content will become more diverse, innovative and distinctive, ushering in a new era for creative industries.</p><p>Last year, generative AI operated primarily through user-driven prompts. Taking <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> as an example, interactions were conducted in a “question and answer” format and were purely passive. In response to this limitation, scientists are researching “auto agent” technology.</p><p>Auto agents can both generate and respond to prompts, performing tasks more rapidly and efficiently. A recent example is the AutoGPT system, which recently raised US$12 million in a funding round. The goal is to develop AutoGPT into a large-scale open-source AI platform, serving various industries.</p><p>Also set to thrive is the development of personalised generative AI systems. Computer companies are researching and developing AI personal computers capable of running generative AI applications locally, while chip companies have developed AI-embedded mobile processors, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236845/google-unveils-pixel-8-smartphones-pixel-watch-2-new-ai-features-mobile-processor" target="_self" title="">enabling smartphones</a> to execute generative AI models.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>A plethora of intelligent devices with diverse generative AI functionalities is emerging.</p><p>Generative AI applications that operate locally on personal computers and smartphones are built upon the concept of “federated learning”. This approach can afford consumers higher levels of privacy protection and security since these platforms do not need to send user data to the cloud for tasks such as searches or information organisation.</p><p>Meanwhile, by analysing user-specific data such as preferences, behaviours and conversations, this type of generative AI can optimise its performance based on individual characteristics and requirements, providing tailored content and task execution. This not only addresses concerns regarding privacy and security but also saves consumers time and effort.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3213160/how-ai-could-free-us-return-pursuit-wisdom" title="">Could AI free us to return to the pursuit of wisdom?</a></h3><p>Generative AI is also expected to play a significant role in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/6g" target="_self" title="">6G mobile technology</a>. This year, work to set and agree on 6G standards will continue with the anticipation that the first standards could be introduced between 2027 and 2028, and the technology could reach commercialisation by 2030. Generative AI can be applied to various aspects of 6G, such as network resource management, spectrum allocation and network topology optimisation.</p><p>It is also capable of meeting the demands of “connective intelligence” for new technologies. Connective intelligence is a key force driving the development of the 6G network, enabling real-time, reliable and ubiquitous interaction and communication between humans, the physical world and the digital world. This results in the creation of a decentralised and continually evolving intelligence, making it easier for users to share their discoveries and experiences with each other.</p><p>In summary, by the end of 2024, generative AI will become an invaluable assistant, providing support and help across different industries. Its powerful analysis and predictive capabilities will enable people to handle complex tasks and problems more efficiently, offering real-time solutions and recommendations.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3242417/fears-over-ai-dangers-are-hindering-chance-create-better-future" title="">How cooperation on AI governance can curb risks and create a better future</a></h3><p>Whether in fielding queries about professional knowledge or optimising and automating business processes, generative AI will play a crucial role. It will also become the ideal companion in consumption, leisure and entertainment.</p><p>Through personalised recommendation systems and intelligent assistant features, generative AI will gain a deep understanding of user preferences and needs, providing customised product and service suggestions. Whether in shopping, travel, music, film and television entertainment or social interaction, generative AI will enhance our experiences.</p><p>Generative AI has become an irreversible trend, penetrating our daily lives in profound ways. Governments must pay attention to ethical, privacy and copyright issues to ensure the positive development of the technology. Otherwise, there is a risk of unintended consequences, allowing malicious individuals to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246612/chatgpt-aided-ransomware-china-results-four-arrests-ai-raises-cybersecurity-concerns" target="_self" title="">exploit</a> generative AI’s capabilities.</p><p><strong>Wong Kam-fai is a legislative councillor, associate dean (external affairs) of the Faculty of Engineering at Chinese University and vice-president of the Hong Kong Professionals And Senior Executives Association</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple supplier Foxconn sees revenue decline in first quarter of 2024 amid weak global consumer electronics demand, sluggish iPhone sales</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>富士康2023年第一季度营收表现黯淡，环比下降7%，反映出苹果等主要客户对其预期销售额的担忧。</li>    <li>全球消费电子行业正处于淡季，业绩疲软反映出市场需求减弱。</li>    <li>受中国大陆新冠疫情影响，富士康郑州工厂曾出现工人罢工，导致产量下降。</li>    <li>苹果iPhone 15销售不佳，导致股价下跌，并面临来自华为等竞争对手的压力。</li>    <li>富士康加大投资力度，包括在印度加码生产苹果产品，以分散依赖中国的风险。</li>    <li>富士康在大陆继续投资河南，计划在今年建厂，扩大产能。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Foxconn's revenue for the first quarter of 2023 declined by 7% year-on-year to $198.9 billion, expressing concerns raised by investors of significant client Apple regarding sluggish iPhone sales.</li>    <li>The global consumer electronics industry is experiencing an off-peak season, mirroring weaker demand.</li>    <li>Foxconn's Zhengzhou iPhone plant was disrupted by a mass exodus of employees and labor disputes, impacting production due to a Covid-19 outbreak.</li>    <li>Apple's iPhone 15 sales have been lackluster, leading to stock downgrades and intense competition from Huawei's resurgent 5G handsets in China.</li>    <li>Foxconn is diversifying its manufacturing supply chain by investing in a plant in India and expanding its presence in Henan, China.</li>    <li>New construction projects for smartphone and electronics factories in Henan are planned for 2024, signaling continued investment in the region.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>plummet (v.) - /ˈplʌmɪt/ 暴跌，直线下降。    <p>原文例句：Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由plum（李子）和-et（小，形成动词）构成的，表示“像李子一样往下掉，暴跌，直线下降”。在这个例句中，它指的是科技巨头的股票在纽约时报报道美国司法部即将对该公司提起反垄断诉讼后，暴跌了0.4%，收于每股约181美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>exodus (n.) - /ˈɛksədəs/ 大量外流，出走。    <p>原文例句：The company went through a bumpy period a year ago when its biggest iPhone plant in Zhengzhou, capital of central Henan province, was rocked by an exodus of tens of thousands of employees and violent workers’ protests amid a Covid-19 outbreak that began in late October. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由ex（出）和odus（道路）构成的，意为“出走，外流”。在这个例句中，它指的是富士康位于河南省郑州市的工厂在去年遭遇了大规模员工出走和工人抗议，导致生产中断。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>given that - 鉴于，考虑到。    <P>原文例句：Revenue for the company’s December quarter fell 5.4 per cent year on year to NT$1.85 trillion (US$60 billion), but was up by 20 per cent from the previous quarter. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由give（给，给予）和that（那，那个）构成的，表示“考虑到，鉴于”。在这个例句中，它表示考虑到公司12月季度的收入同比下降5.4%，达到1.85万亿新台币（600亿美元），但比上一季度增长了20%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>put under investigation - 启动调查。    <P>原文例句：The Taiwanese firm, which was put under investigation in October by mainland regulators, this year plans to start building new factories for smartphones and other electronics products in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of 520 major construction projects for 2024 released this week by the province’s Development and Reform Commission. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由put（放置，放）和under investigation（在调查中）构成的，表示“启动调查”。在这个例句中，它表示这富士康在10月份受到大陆监管部门的调查，计划今年在河南的周口、开封和济源等城市建设新的智能手机和其他电子产品工厂，根据本周该省发展和改革委员会公布的2024年520个重点建设项目清单。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company went through a bumpy period a year ago when its biggest iPhone plant in Zhengzhou, capital of central Henan province, was rocked by an exodus of tens of thousands of employees and violent workers’ protests amid a Covid-19 outbreak that began in late October. - 该公司在去年经历了一段艰难时期，当时其位于河南省省会郑州市的最大的 iPhone 工厂受到数万名员工离职和暴力工人抗议的影响，而这是一次始于 10 月底的新冠肺炎疫情爆发造成的。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The company went through a bumpy period，其中主语是The company，谓语是went，宾语是a bumpy period。a year ago when its biggest iPhone plant in Zhengzhou, capital of central Henan province, was rocked by an exodus of tens of thousands of employees and violent workers’ protests amid a Covid-19 outbreak that began in late October是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示该事件发生在去年，当时其位于河南省省会郑州市的最大的 iPhone 工厂受到数万名员工离职和暴力工人抗议的影响，而这是一次始于 10 月底的新冠肺炎疫情爆发造成的。这个句子的意思是说，该公司在去年经历了一段艰难时期，当时其位于河南省省会郑州市的最大的 iPhone 工厂受到数万名员工离职和暴力工人抗议的影响，而这是一次始于 10 月底的新冠肺炎疫情爆发造成的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 表示强调。    <p>原文例句：The world’s largest electronics contract manufacturer also indicated that the year’s first quarter is typically an off-peak season for the industry. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种句型，结构是：It is/was/will be + 被强调部分 + that/who + 其他。这种句型表示强调被强调部分，强调它的重要性或特殊性。在这个例句中，it is + the year’s first quarter + that + is typically an off-peak season for the industry，强调了第一季度通常是电子行业淡季。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>倒装句型 - 表示强调或特殊含义。    <p>原文例句：On the mainland, Foxconn continues to invest in central Henan province, where it employs 200,000 workers in the firm’s Zhengzhou manufacturing complex. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种句型，结构是：状语 + 主语 + 谓语 + 其他。这种句型表示强调状语，或表示特殊含义。在这个例句中，状语On the mainland表示地点，主语Foxconn表示公司，谓语continues to invest表示持续投资，其他部分in central Henan province, where it employs 200,000 workers in the firm’s Zhengzhou manufacturing complex表示该公司在河南省中部郑州制造中心有20万名员工。这个句子的意思是说，在大陆，富士康继续在河南省中部投资，在那里它在郑州制造中心雇用了 200,000 名工人。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Foxconn did not provide an estimate of the quarterly drop, but said the year’s first three months represent an off-peak season for the industry</li>
<li>The world’s largest electronics contract manufacturer reported total 2023 revenue was down 7 per cent year on year to US$198.9 billion</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/e222829d-56dc-48eb-b8cb-9a2ea658a625_cee121ea.jpg" /><figcaption>Foxconn Technology Group’s dim first-quarter outlook reflects concerns raised by investors of major client Apple about sluggish iPhone sales. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foxconn?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Foxconn Technology Group</a>, the world’s biggest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> assembler, expects revenue to decline in the first quarter of 2024 amid weak global consumer electronics demand, extending a decrease in sales in the past three months.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>-based Foxconn, formally known as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hon-hai-precision-industry?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Hon Hai Precision Industry</a>, did not provide an estimate on the quarterly revenue drop, but said the first three months will be compared to a high base in the same period last year, when its factories in mainland China resumed normal operations after disruptive pandemic controls were relaxed by the government, according to the company’s statement on Friday.</p><p>The world’s largest electronics contract manufacturer also indicated that the year’s first quarter is typically an off-peak season for the industry.</p><p>Revenue for the company’s December quarter fell 5.4 per cent year on year to NT$1.85 trillion (US$60 billion), but was up by 20 per cent from the previous quarter. Total 2023 revenue was US$198.9 billion, down 7 per cent from 2022.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen" class="image-inline caption" height="1243" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/09a87505-ea2a-40a2-91f3-d3980a90b343_8f795096.jpg" title="People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen" width="2000" /><figcaption>People check out the iPhone 15 models on display at the Apple Store inside the IFC Mall in Central on September 22, 2023. Photo: Xiaomei Chen</figcaption></figure></div><p>Foxconn on Friday blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, even though the company went through a bumpy period a year ago when its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3225783/worlds-largest-iphone-factory-zhengzhou-ramps-hiring-foxconn-chairman-reassures-china-supply-chain" target="_self" title="">biggest iPhone plant in Zhengzhou</a>, capital of central Henan province, was rocked by an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3197909/coronavirus-iphone-factory-exodus-shows-how-chinas-covid-narrative-still-strikes-fear-public?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">exodus of tens of thousands of employees</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3200747/violence-erupts-foxconn-zhengzhou-plant-workers-protest-over-benefits-and-covid-19-controls-worlds?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">violent workers’ protests</a> amid a Covid-19 outbreak that began in late October.</p><p>The company’s dim first-quarter outlook reflects concerns raised by investors of major client Apple about sluggish iPhone sales, which prompted the US tech giant to be <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">hit by two ratings downgrades</a> this week.</p><p>“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">said in a client note</a>, which pointed to weakness in China and subdued demand in developed markets.</p><p>Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247501/apples-reign-worlds-most-valuable-stock-market-value-jeopardy-bumpy-2024-start" title="">Apple’s lofty status as world’s most valuable stock at risk from bumpy 2024 start</a></h3><p>Apple, which has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022, has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.</p><p>The company’s iPhones also face intense competition on the mainland against a resurgent <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, which is seeing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" target="_self" title="">strong demand for its new 5G handsets</a> in the world’s largest smartphone market.</p><p>While Apple <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" target="_self" title="">continues to lead the global premium smartphone market</a>, where handsets are priced from US$600, Huawei has gained ground in this segment on the back of its new Mate 60 series.</p><p>Foxconn is also <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234562/foxconn-offers-higher-hourly-rates-workers-shenzhen-its-huawei-production-unit-its-iphone-operation" target="_self" title="">offering higher rates for workers that make Huawei’s handsets</a> in southern tech hub <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shenzhen" target="_self" title="">Shenzhen</a> than those that make iPhones, according to a South China Morning Post report last September.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions" title="">Foxconn ramps up investment in giant Apple plant in India</a></h3><p>Still, Foxconn has stepped up efforts to diversify its manufacturing supply chain for Apple and other clients amid the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246222/chinas-middle-class-does-not-dare-spend-until-post-covid-economy-shows-clear-signs-recovery" target="_self" title="">weak post-pandemic economic recovery</a> in mainland China and rising geopolitical tensions between Beijing and Washington.</p><p>Foxconn won approval to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions" target="_self" title="">invest at least US$1 billion more in a plant</a> it is building in India that will make Apple products, on top of the US$1.6 billion it earlier pledged, according to a report by Bloomberg last month.</p><p>On the mainland, Foxconn continues to invest in central Henan province, where it employs 200,000 workers in the firm’s Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p><p>The Taiwanese firm, which was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239113/china-says-investigation-apple-supplier-foxconns-operations-mainland-normal-law-enforcement" target="_self" title="">put under investigation in October by mainland regulators</a>, this year plans to start building new factories for smartphones and other electronics products in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of 520 major construction projects for 2024 released this week by the province’s Development and Reform Commission.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s reign as world’s most valuable stock by market value in jeopardy from bumpy 2024 start</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247501/apples-reign-worlds-most-valuable-stock-market-value-jeopardy-bumpy-2024-start</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple shares fell 0.4 percent on Friday following a report that the US Justice Department is preparing to file an antitrust lawsuit against the company.</li>    <li>This development adds to the challenges faced by Apple, including declining iPhone sales and Apple Watch patent issues.</li>    <li>The potential lawsuit could target Apple's business model of integrating devices and services.</li>    <li>Apple's stock has suffered significant losses in market value this year, erasing about US$177 billion.</li>    <li>The company's market valuation has dropped to around US$2.8 trillion, narrowing its lead over Microsoft.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>苹果股票周五下跌 0.4%，此前有报道称美国司法部即将对该公司提起反垄断诉讼。</li>    <li>这一进展加剧了苹果面临的挑战，包括 iPhone 销量下降和 Apple Watch 专利问题。</li>    <li>潜在的诉讼可能针对苹果将设备和服务紧密集成的商业模式。</li>    <li>苹果的股票今年遭受了重大损失，市值抹去约 1770 亿美元。</li>    <li>该公司的市值已跌至约 2.8 万亿美元，与微软的差距缩小。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>erased (v.) - /ɪˈreɪst/ 擦除，消除。    <p>原文例句：The tech giant has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由e-（表示“除去，消除”）和rase（擦除，刮除）构成的，表示“擦除，消除”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司今年已经损失了约 1770 亿美元的市值。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>analyst (n.) - /ˈænəlɪst/ 分析师。    <p>原文例句：Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Anurag Rana wrote in a note. "The suit could attack Apple’s business model of tightly integrating its devices and services.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于希腊语，表示“解开，分析”。在这个例句中，它指的是彭博情报分析师阿努拉格·拉纳。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rout (n.) - /raʊt/ 溃败，大败。    <p>原文例句：Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语，表示“大败，溃败”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司在 2023 年反弹后遭遇的 3830 亿美元科技股溃败。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tightly integrating - 紧密集成。    <p>原文例句：The suit could attack Apple’s business model of tightly integrating its devices and services.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由tightly（紧紧地）和integrating（集成）组成，表示“紧密集成”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司将设备和服务紧密集成的商业模式。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rotate their portfolios - 调整投资组合。    <p>原文例句：“Everybody’s selling their winners and buying losers,” said Brian Mulberry, client portfolio manager at Zacks Investment Management. “There’s a big rebalance going on.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由rotate（调整）和portfolios（投资组合）组成，表示“调整投资组合”。在这个例句中，它指的是随着新年开始，投资者开始调整投资组合。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The potential antitrust case against Apple “would add to the plethora of problems it faces, from slowing iPhone sales to Apple Watch patent issues”, Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Anurag Rana wrote in a note. - 彭博情报分析师阿努拉格·拉纳在一份报告中写道，针对苹果的潜在反垄断案件“将加剧苹果面临的诸多问题，从 iPhone 销量放缓到 Apple Watch 专利问题”。<p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是The potential antitrust case against Apple would add to the plethora of problems it faces，其中主语是The potential antitrust case against Apple，谓语是would add，宾语是the plethora of problems it faces。from slowing iPhone sales to Apple Watch patent issues是一个介词短语作定语，修饰the plethora of problems，表示从 iPhone 销量放缓到 Apple Watch 专利问题。Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Anurag Rana wrote in a note是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示这句话是彭博情报分析师阿努拉格·拉纳在一份报告中写道的。这个句子的意思是说，针对苹果的潜在反垄断案件将加剧苹果面临的诸多问题，从 iPhone 销量放缓到 Apple Watch 专利问题。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人对某事的猜测、假设或愿望。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report.</p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气常用于表示说话人对某事的猜测、假设或愿望。在这个例句中，虚拟语气是由was hit表示的，它表示苹果的股票在公司 12 月季度收益报告前遭到了两次评级下调。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Shares of Apple fell 0.4 per cent on Friday after a report that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company</li>
<li>The tech giant has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/0bab1060-0f68-4b59-b625-ee8f62b7b778_cec54c59.jpg" /><figcaption>People walk past an Apple Store in the Glendale Galleria shopping mall in California on December 26, 2023. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> just had its worst start to the year by one measure, as investors react to mounting pressures on the company, putting its long-standing status as the world’s most valuable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/stocks" target="_self" title="">stock</a> by market value in jeopardy.</p><p>Shares of the technology giant fell 0.4 per cent on Friday to close at about US$181 after The New York Times reported that the US Justice Department is closer to filing an antitrust case against the company.</p><p>The decline notched the fifth consecutive negative day for Apple, its longest losing streak since October.</p><p>The potential antitrust case against Apple “would add to the plethora of problems it faces, from slowing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> sales to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246452/apple-resumes-sale-watches-after-appeals-court-lifts-us-ban" target="_self" title="">Apple Watch patent issues</a>”, Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Anurag Rana wrote in a note. “The suit could attack Apple’s business model of tightly integrating its devices and services.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/bdba7b4d-2eef-4fae-a196-1d3cd943fe89_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shoppers inside an Apple Store in Walnut Creek, California, on December 20, 2023. Apple’s stock was hit by two ratings downgrades ahead of the company’s December-quarter earnings report. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Cupertino, California-based company has been the world’s most valuable publicly-listed company since July 2022, but has seen about US$177 billion in market value erased so far this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.</p><p>While the stock has suffered bigger percentage declines in the first week of January, the losses are the biggest market value destruction at the start of any year on record.</p><p>The downturn began earlier in the week after the technology giant was hit by two <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns" target="_self" title="">ratings downgrades</a>, with analysts flagging a weak macro environment in China pressuring demand for iPhones.</p><p>That has shrunk its lead over fellow technology juggernaut <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft Corp</a> – whose shares have seen a less pronounced decline to begin the year – to less than US$100 billion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247211/apple-leads-us383-billion-tech-rout-reversal-groups-2023-rally" title="">Apple leads US$383 billion tech rout in reversal from group’s 2023 rally</a></h3><p>“Investors realise how rare it is to have two people go negative,” said Gene Munster, managing partner of Deepwater Asset Management. “I’ve been covering this company for a long time and I’ve never seen two downgrades before an earnings report.”</p><p>Apple is also likely under pressure as investors rotate their portfolios at the start of the year.</p><p>“Everybody’s selling their winners and buying losers,” said Brian Mulberry, client portfolio manager at Zacks Investment Management. “There’s a big rebalance going on.”</p><p>The losses have pushed Apple’s market value down to about US$2.8 trillion, nearing Microsoft’s US$2.7 trillion. Shares of Microsoft fell less than 0.1 per cent Friday to close at about US$368.</p><p>The Windows software maker has benefited from the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> trade that has mesmerised Wall Street over the past year. The company is <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247356/openai-talks-dozens-publishers-license-content" target="_self" title="">OpenAI</a>’s largest shareholder and has invested about US$13 billion into the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> parent.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech trade group representing TikTok, Snapchat and Meta sues Ohio over state’s new law limiting children’s use of social media apps</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247497/tech-trade-group-representing-tiktok-snapchat-and-meta-sues-ohio-over-states-new-law-limiting</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Ohio州通过一项法律，要求社交媒体公司在16岁以下的儿童注册社交媒体和视频游戏应用程序之前获得父母的许可。该法律被认为违宪，侵犯言论自由，并且过于宽泛和模糊。  <ul>    <li>Theme: Ohio's new law requires social media companies to obtain parental consent for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The law is unconstitutional and violates free speech rights.</li>    <li>Main information: The law is part of a state budget bill; it requires social media companies to provide privacy guidelines to parents; NetChoice, a trade group representing tech companies, has filed a lawsuit to block the law.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  俄亥俄州通过一项法律，要求社交媒体公司在16岁以下儿童注册社交媒体和电子游戏应用程序前必须获得父母的许可。该法律被认为违反宪法，侵犯言论自由，并且过于宽泛和模糊。  <ul>    <li>主题：俄亥俄州的新法律要求社交媒体公司在16岁以下的儿童注册社交媒体和视频游戏应用程序之前获得父母的许可。</li>    <li>观点：法律违宪侵犯言论自由权利。</li>    <li>主要信息：该法律是州预算法案的一部分；要求社交媒体公司向父母提供隐私指南；代表科技公司的行业团体NetChoice已提起诉讼以阻止该法律。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li> unconstitutionally (adv.) 违宪地    <p>原文例句：The NetChoice trade group argues that Ohio’s law unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“unconstitutionally”是由“un-”（否定前缀）和“constitutional”（合乎宪法的）构成的，意思是“违反宪法的”。在这个句子中，它表示NetChoice行业团体认为俄亥俄州的法律违反宪法，侵犯言论自由，并且过于宽泛和模糊。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>litigation (n.) 诉讼，争讼。    <p>原文例句：The litigation argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps – unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“litigation”源自拉丁语“litigatio”，意思是“诉讼，争讼”。在这个句子中，它指的是NetChoice行业团体对俄亥俄州法律提起的诉讼。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>implication (n.) 含意，暗示。    <p>原文例句：Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok useThe group has won lawsuits against similar restrictions in California and Arkansas.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“implication”源自拉丁语“implicare”，意思是“纠缠，牵连”。在这个句子中，它指的是蒙大拿州对阻止该州禁止使用TikTok的裁决提出上诉。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>free speech - 言论自由    <p>原文例句：The NetChoice trade group argues that Ohio’s law unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“free speech”是由“free”（自由的）和“speech”（言语，发言）构成的，意思是“言论自由”。在这个句子中，它指的是NetChoice行业团体认为俄亥俄州的法律违反宪法，侵犯言论自由，并且过于宽泛和模糊。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Ohio’s new law requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps. - 俄亥俄州的新法律要求社交媒体公司在16岁以下的儿童注册社交媒体和视频游戏应用程序之前获得父母的许可。    <p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是“Ohio’s new law”，谓语是“requires”，宾语是“social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps”。其中，“requires”是一个及物动词，表示“要求”；“social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps”是一个不定式短语作宾语，表示“社交媒体公司在16岁以下的儿童注册社交媒体和视频游戏应用程序之前获得父母的许可”。这个句子的意思是说，俄亥俄州的新法律要求社交媒体公司在16岁以下的儿童注册社交媒体和视频游戏应用程序之前获得父母的许可。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The group has won lawsuits against similar restrictions in California and Arkansas.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是由have/has和过去分词构成的，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个句子中，“has won”是由“have”和“won”构成的，表示NetChoice行业团体已经赢得了针对加利福尼亚州和阿肯色州类似限制的诉讼。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The law forms part of a state budget bill that Ohio Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July and is set to take effect on January 15</li>
<li>The NetChoice trade group argues that Ohio’s law unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/0827334f-9aca-4109-b4e2-813fa20ac5b8_06ce695b.jpg" /><figcaption>Ohio’s new law requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and video gaming apps. Photo: TNS</figcaption></figure><p>A trade group representing major tech companies including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/snapchat" target="_self" title="">Snapchat</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/facebook" target="_self" title="">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/instagram" target="_self" title="">Instagram</a> operator <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226704/meta-takes-aim-twitter-launch-rival-app-threads" target="_self" title="">Meta Platforms</a> sued Ohio on Friday over the state’s pending law that requires children to get parental consent to use <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">apps</a>.</p><p>The law was part of an US$86.1 billion state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law last July. It is set to take effect on January 15.</p><p>The administration pushed the measure as a way to protect children’s mental health, with Republican Lieutenant Governor Jon Husted saying at the time that social media was “intentionally addictive” and harmful to kids.</p><p>The NetChoice trade group filed its lawsuit against Republican Attorney General Dave Yost in US District Court for the Southern district of Ohio. It seeks to block the law from taking effect.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP" class="image-inline caption" height="1410" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/06/8d380f8f-5e87-4f75-add2-ca49bea0915b_3ad8b242.jpg" title="A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP" width="2000" /><figcaption>A pending law in Ohio that requires children to get parental consent to use social media apps forms part of a state budget bill that Republican Governor Mike DeWine signed into law in July 2023 and is set to take effect on January 15. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The litigation argues that Ohio’s law – which requires social media companies to obtain a parent’s permission for children under 16 to sign up for social media and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> apps – unconstitutionally impedes free speech, and is overbroad and vague.</p><p>The law also requires social media companies to provide parents with their privacy guidelines, so that families can know what content will be censored or moderated on their child’s profile.</p><p>“We at NetChoice believe families equipped with educational resources are capable of determining the best approach to online services and privacy protections for themselves,” Chris Marchese, director of the organisation’s litigation centre, said in a statement.</p><p>“With NetChoice v Yost, we will fight to ensure all Ohioans can embrace digital tools without their privacy, security and rights being thwarted.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247089/montana-appealing-ruling-blocked-state-barring-tiktok-use" title="">Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok use</a></h3><p>The group has won lawsuits against similar restrictions in California and Arkansas.</p><p>Husted, who leads Ohio’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> initiatives and championed the law, called Friday’s lawsuit “cowardly but not unexpected”.</p><p>“In filing this lawsuit, these companies are determined to go around parents to expose children to harmful content and addict them to their platforms,” Husted said in a statement.</p><p>He also alleged the tech companies know their algorithms are harming children “with catastrophic health and mental health outcomes”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China needs ‘groundbreaking’ policy changes to embrace disruptive technologies</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247450/china-needs-groundbreaking-policy-changes-embrace-disruptive-technologies</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China needs to adjust its industrial policymaking due to the impact of disruptive technologies such as AI and quantum computing.</li>    <li>A shift from selective industrial policy to a functional policy paradigm is crucial to adapt to disruptive technologies.</li>    <li>Promoting innovation, entrepreneurship, and market liberalization is necessary to foster small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) for technological diversification.</li>    <li>Addressing regional disparities and ensuring a balanced distribution of resources among companies is essential for inclusive economic development.</li>    <li>China needs to enhance basic research funding, particularly in enterprises, to drive innovation and technological advancement.</li>    <li>The government should establish effective communication channels with industry experts and stakeholders to inform policy decisions.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国需要调整其产业政策以应对人工智能和量子计算等颠覆性技术的影响。</li>    <li>从选择性产业政策向功能性政策范式的转变对于适应颠覆性技术至关重要。</li>    <li>促进创新、创业和市场自由化对于培育中小企业 (SME) 以实现技术多元化是必要的。</li>    <li>解决区域差异并确保资源在企业之间的平衡分配对于包容性经济发展至关重要。</li>    <li>中国需要加强基础研究资助，特别是在企业中，以推动创新和技术进步。</li>    <li>政府应建立有效沟通渠道与行业专家和利益相关者，以通知政策决定。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>paradigm (n.) - /ˈpærədaɪm/ 典范，模式。    <p>原文例句：Huang said in the report published by the English-language Asian Review of Political Economy in October 2022 that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：范式一词源于希腊语，由para（相近，接近）和deiknumi（显示）构成，表示“模式，榜样”。在这个例子中，它指的是选择性产业政策，即政府通过一系列政策措施引导和扶持某些产业的发展。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>disruptive (adj.) - /dɪsˈrʌptɪv/ 破坏性的，颠覆性的。    <p>原文例句：China needs to adjust its industrial policymaking to brace for possible revolutionary changes to its economy by disruptive technologies, analysts said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：颠覆性一词源自拉丁语，由dis（否定）和rumpere（打破）组成，表示“打破，中断，颠覆”。在这个例子中，它描述了人工智能和量子计算等颠覆性技术对中国经济可能产生的革命性变化。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>selective industrial policy - 选择性产业政策。    <p>原文例句：Huang said in the report published by the English-language Asian Review of Political Economy in October 2022 that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：选择性产业政策是指国家通过制定相应的政策措施措施，引导和扶持某些优先发展或需要重点发展的产业部门或行业，限制和阻止其他产业的增长，以达到有效配置资源、实现产业结构调整和优化、刺激国民经济发展等目标。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>functional policy paradigm - 功能性政策范式。    <p>原文例句：“How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgent,” he wrote in the report, which had earlier been published in Mandarin by the Journal of Comparative Studies in February 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：功能性政策范式是与选择性产业政策对应的，是一种产业政策制定理念。这种理念认为，产业政策应该是动态的，能够适应不断变化的经济环境，并能够促进经济的持续增长。功能性产业政策的主要目标是促进经济增长、创造就业机会、提高生产率和促进技术创新。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>This model has been adopted by other economies in East Asia during their development in the second half of 20th century. - 这种模式在20世纪下半叶的东亚其他经济体的发展中也被采用。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是This model，谓语是has been adopted，宾语是by other economies in East Asia。during their development in the second half of 20th century是一个介词短语作状语，表示在20世纪下半叶的经济发展过程中。这个句子的意思是说，这种模式在20世纪下半叶的东亚其他经济体的经济发展过程中也被采用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 把句子中某些成分的位置颠倒过来，以强调句子的某些成分或表达特殊的情感。    <p>原文例句：“Therefore, in the early development stage of disruptive technologies, economies of scale are not important and even dangerous.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，把主语economies of scale放在了句子开头，表示强调。这个句子的意思是说，因此，在颠覆性技术早期发展阶段，规模经济并不重要，甚至是有害的。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物承受的。    <p>原文例句：China needs to adjust its industrial policymaking to brace for possible revolutionary changes to its economy by disruptive technologies, analysts said.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，表示动作或状态是由句子主语以外的人或事物承受的。在这个句子中，动作或状态是由disruptive technologies承受的。这个句子的意思是说，分析人士表示，中国需要调整其产业政策，以应对颠覆性技术对其经济可能产生的革命性变化。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Disruptive technologies, including artificial intelligence and quantum computing, will significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate</li>
<li>China should make ‘groundbreaking changes’ to its industrial policymaking amid its push to become a global technological and economic leader, analysts said</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/05/df3b6f4b-498c-4140-80f2-8b42e0ebe9ed_9f02ea50.jpg" /><figcaption>China’s HL-2M reactor in Sichuan could provide a long-term solution to the world’s energy needs by generating power without producing nuclear waste. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>China needs to adjust its industrial policymaking to brace for possible revolutionary changes to its economy by disruptive technologies, analysts said.</p><p>From artificial intelligence (AI) to quantum computing, and from room-temperature superconductivity to controllable nuclear fusion, disruptive technologies are set to significantly alter the way that consumers, industries and businesses operate.</p><p>China’s economic miracle over the past four decades has been based on carefully crafted industrial policies and imported technologies to realise economies of scale and reduce production costs.</p><p>This model has been adopted by other economies in East Asia during their development in the second half of 20th century.</p><blockquote>How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgentHuang Shaoqing</blockquote><p>“As frontier technologies, no one knows what technology truly has promising prospects, which could ultimately be screened out by the market through competition,” Huang Shaoqing, a professor of economics at the Antai College of Economics and Management at Shanghai Jiao Tong University, said in a report.</p><p>“Therefore, in the early development stage of disruptive technologies, economies of scale are not important and even dangerous.”</p><p>Huang said in the report published by the English-language Asian Review of Political Economy in October 2022 that the selective industrial policy regime, which led to China’s economic success in the past, “may even lead to failure and become a trap in the future”.</p><p>“How to achieve a shift from the selective industrial policy paradigm to the functional policy paradigm has become critical and urgent,” he wrote in the report, which had earlier been published in Mandarin by the Journal of Comparative Studies in February 2022.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>The urgency has become more prominent for Beijing, which views innovation and technological advancement as key to countering the heightened containment efforts by the United States, and also crucial for its ambition to become an economic and tech superpower by the middle of the century.</p><p>Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, said China needs to plan areas where matured technologies can be applied, including sectors influenced by US export bans, and that involve more markets.</p><p>“China needs to make groundbreaking changes to its industrial policymaking, otherwise, it will never be a global technological and economic leader,” Peng said.</p><p>“Decision makers need to listen more to private companies, give them enough funding for industrial research, and place them at the front role of disruptive industrial exploration.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3247299/amid-us-tech-war-premier-li-qiang-urges-china-focus-application-core-technologies" title="">‘More, better’: premier urges China to focus on application of core technologies</a></h3><p>But as it is impossible to determine in advance which technology would prevail, a country can gain an advantage only if it develops enough small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) to offer sufficient diversified technological routes, Huang added.</p><p>“Only by promoting innovation and entrepreneurship, relaxing market access, improving the business environment, and allowing as many as SMEs as possible to grow rapidly can these SMEs play an important role in economic development driven by innovation,” he said.</p><p>In 2016 when mapping out a national scientific and technology plan, Beijing vowed to improve tracking revolutionary industrial development to be capable of prejudging “the turning point” of possible replacements for traditional industries.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>At the time it added that it would make a timely plan for research into disruptive technologies, such as AI, quantum information, genome editing, unmanned driving, hydrogen power and nanotechnology.</p><p>Li Yangwei, a technical consultant in the computing sector in Shenzhen, said disruptive technologies may lead to bigger tech and economic gaps among regions within China, but when there are more participants, the cost of any potential failures can be lowered.</p><p>He also said small market players can offer advice to the central government about industrial policies, but amid hefty external pressure and geopolitical complications, Beijing may still allocate resources to big companies or state-owned enterprises.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3243101/chinas-ai-aspirations-will-fuel-economy-drive-investment-trillions-dollars-mckinsey" title="">China’s AI gains will fuel economy as windfall swells into trillions: McKinsey</a></h3><p>“It also requires technocrats to be socially, economically and politically insightful, as well as having strong communication skills and being given central decision-making power,” Li said.</p><p>China’s basic research accounted for more than 6 per cent of its total research and development (R&amp;D) expenditure in the last four years, lower than the 16 to 18 per cent in the US and 22 per cent in France over the last 10 years.</p><p>Basic research from enterprises only accounted for 0.78 per cent of China’s overall R&amp;D expenditure, behind over 6 per cent in developed countries, according to a report in February by the Science and Technology Daily, a newspaper backed by the Ministry of Science and Technology.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
