<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Shanghai delivery worker’s ‘yuan millionaire’ claim sparks heated debate amid China’s bleak jobs outlook</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249238/shanghai-delivery-workers-yuan-millionaire-claim-sparks-heated-debate-amid-chinas-bleak-jobs-outlook</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>A food delivery worker in Shanghai, Chen Si, claimed to have earned over 1 million yuan in three years, sparking debate on social media.</li>    <li>Chen's story has captured the attention of Chinese state media and has been widely reported.</li>    <li>Many netizens questioned the authenticity of Chen's claims, considering the high average daily order rate and long working hours he would have to maintain.</li>    <li>Other delivery riders shared their experiences and earnings, with one stating that it would be almost impossible to maintain Chen's pace for over 1,000 days.</li>    <li>Online job listings in Shanghai show average salaries for food delivery riders ranging from 9,000 to 15,000 yuan, with an average daily order rate of 40 to 70.</li>    <li>Chen attributed his success to his fitness, luck, and dedication, working long hours and barely taking any days off.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>上海一名外卖小哥陈思自称三年赚百万，在社交媒体引发热议。</li>    <li>陈思的遭遇引起中国官媒注意，并被广泛报道。</li>    <li>许多网友对陈思的说法提出质疑，认为他声称的高平均日单量和长时间工作时间难以实现。</li>    <li>其他外卖骑手分享了自己的经历和收入，其中一位表示不可能连续 1,000 天保持陈思的节奏。</li>    <li>上海的在线招聘信息显示，外卖骑手的平均工资在 9,000 元至 15,000 元之间，平均日单量在 40 至 70 单之间。</li>    <li>陈思将自己的成功归功于他的体能、运气和奉献精神，他长时间工作，几乎没有休息日。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>gig (n.) - /ɡɪɡ/ 零工。    <p>原文例句：After the youth unemployment rate hit a record high of 21.3 per cent last June, authorities stopped releasing the data, citing a need to reassess the calculation methodology. - 在去年 6 月青年失业率创下 21.3% 的历史新高后，当局停止发布数据，理由是需要重新评估计算方法。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由gig（旋转，舞蹈）演变而来，意思是“零工，小工”等。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>uneven economic recovery - 不平衡的经济复苏。    <p>原文例句：The inspirational story of a self-made millionaire comes as China is being challenged by an uneven economic recovery that has seen lay-offs across a wide range of industries, with new graduates facing a bleak job market. - 在中国正受到不平衡的经济复苏挑战的情况下，一个白手起家的百万富翁的故事令人振奋，这种复苏导致了多个行业大面积裁员，导致新毕业生面临严峻的就业市场。</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由uneven（不平坦的，不均匀的）和economic recovery（经济复苏）组成，描述了中国经济复苏的不平衡性。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>His best performance was delivering 108 orders in one day, according to a screenshot of the Meituan ranking he shared with the Post, Yang said it would be almost impossible for anyone to maintain that pace for more than 1,000 days in a row. - 阳说，根据他与《邮报》分享的美团排行榜的截图，他最好的表现是一天送出 108 个订单，对于任何人来说，连续 1,000 多天保持这种速度几乎是不可能的。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是it would be almost impossible for anyone to maintain that pace for more than 1,000 days in a row。主语是IT，谓语是would be，宾语是for anyone to maintain that pace for more than 1,000 days in a row。根据他与《邮报》分享的美团排行榜的截图，阳说这几乎是不可能的。这是一个复杂句，主句是Yang said it would be almost impossible for anyone to maintain that pace for more than 1,000 days in a row。从句是His best performance was delivering 108 orders in one day，其中主语是His best performance，谓语是was delivering，宾语是108 orders in one day。这个句子的意思是，根据他与《邮报》分享的美团排行榜的截图，阳说，对于任何人来说，连续1000多天保持这种速度几乎是不可能的，最好的表现是一天送出108单。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由分词和其宾语、状语等构成的短语。    <p>原文例句：Based on Chen’s claims, he would need to earn an average of 28,000 yuan each month, delivering an average of 107 orders everyday consistently over a span of 1,000 days. - 根据陈的说法，为了持续 1,000 天，平均每天送出 107 个订单，他每个月需要挣到平均 28,000 元。</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语包括现在分词短语和过去分词短语。现在分词短语由现在分词和其宾语、状语等构成的短语，作定语或状语。过去分词短语由过去分词和其宾语、状语等构成的短语，作定语或补语。在这个例句中，delivering an average of 107 orders everyday consistently over a span of 1,000 days是一个现在分词短语，作状语，表示持续1000天，平均每天送出107个订单。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In a video on Douyin, Chen, wearing his Meituan uniform, said his failed restaurant business in his home province left him with a debt of 800,000 yuan (US$112,274)</li>
<li>Based on Chen’s claims, he would need to earn an average of 28,000 yuan a month, delivering 107 orders per day consistently over a span of 1,000 days</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/21/3a4413d3-b37b-4219-9ee0-63d0b1302528_b039a533.jpg" /><figcaption>A group of Meituan couriers waits for order in Beijing on November 16, 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Claims by a food delivery worker in Shanghai that he made more than 1 million yuan (US$140,343) in three years, a story widely reported by state media and debated on social media, has offered hope to the unemployed amid China’s sputtering economic recovery and bleak job market outlook.</p><p>Chen Si, a 26-year-old from the central province of Jiangxi, suggested in a series of videos posted on Douyin, the Chinese sibling of ByteDance’s TikTok, that he made a total of 1.02 million yuan from three years of delivering meals in the Chinese financial hub.</p><p>In one video, Chen, wearing his Meituan courier uniform, said his failed restaurant business in his home province left him with a debt of 800,000 yuan. This prompted him to come to Shanghai where he landed a food courier gig to help pay off his debts.</p><p>“I work 18 hours every day … worked over 1,000 days in three years, barely taking leave,” Chen said, adding that he has paid off all his debt.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247829/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-offers-shoppers-us-grouped-delivery-service-cutting-shipping-times" title="">Cainiao offers shoppers in US grouped delivery service, cutting shipping times</a></h3><p>Chen’s videos were highlighted by Chinese state media, sparking heated online debate across the country, where the average monthly wage of people employed by private firms in cities was only 5,436 yuan in 2022, according to data compiled by the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).</p><p>While some have endorsed Chen’s diligence, many questioned whether he was telling the truth. Based on Chen’s claims, he would need to earn an average of 28,000 yuan each month, delivering an average of 107 orders everyday consistently over a span of 1,000 days.</p><p>One food delivery rider surnamed Yang, who worked for Meituan in Beijing for five years, told the South China Morning Post that he averaged between 40 and 50 orders a day, earning more than 10,000 yuan a month, by putting in a minimum of 12 hours per day.</p><p>While his best performance was delivering 108 orders in one day, according to a screenshot of the Meituan ranking he shared with the Post, Yang said it would be almost impossible for anyone to maintain that pace for more than 1,000 days in a row.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A food delivery courier for Meituan in Beijing, on September 1, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" class="image-inline caption" height="1445" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/21/0ec90034-33b8-40bb-a342-1af3cfb45f3d_7c1d99ea.jpg" title="A food delivery courier for Meituan in Beijing, on September 1, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" width="2000" /><figcaption>A food delivery courier for Meituan in Beijing, on September 1, 2023. Photo: Simon Song</figcaption></figure></div><p>Online job listings published by a Shanghai-based recruitment agency show salaries of between 9,000 yuan and 15,000 yuan for food delivery riders in the city, with the average daily order rate being between 40 and 70.</p><p>Meituan did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Sunday.</p><p>In interviews with state media, Chen said that his fitness “based on practising martial arts when he was young”, coupled with a dose of good luck, helped him achieve the result.</p><p>He told the Hunan-based newspaper Xiaoxiang Chenbao that he wakes at 5:50am daily and works until midnight, and that he hardly took any time off, even during the Lunar New Year festival when most workers stop work to celebrate with their families.</p><p>The inspirational story of a self-made millionaire comes as China is being challenged by an uneven economic recovery that has seen lay-offs across a wide range of industries, with new graduates facing a bleak job market.</p><p>After the youth unemployment rate hit a record high of 21.3 per cent last June, authorities stopped releasing the data, citing a need to reassess the calculation methodology.</p><p>When the reporting recently resumed, the NBS figures pegged the unemployment rate for the 16 to 24 year old age bracket at 14.9 per cent for last December, but the number excluded students still in school. Overall, China’s urban unemployment rate was 5.1 per cent in December.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3238995/dont-worry-ill-deliver-it-caring-china-police-officer-helps-food-courier-finish-round-after-bike" title="">‘Don’t worry, I’ll deliver it’: cop completes food dispatch for rider after crash</a></h3><p>Food delivery couriers like Chen, as well as ride-share drivers and parcel couriers, make up China’s army of flexible employment workers, which numbered more than 200 million at the end of 2021.</p><p>Starting early 2023, internet platforms like Meituan and ride-sharing service Didi Chuxing began to emerge from years of strict oversight by Beijing, but now face the prospect of a challenging economic environment. In a reversal of policy, Beijing is now openly praising the role of such platforms in bolstering growth and creating jobs.</p><p>However, compared with full-time employment, gig workers face job insecurity and a lack of benefits.</p><p>“I don’t want people to follow my work style, as it is not suitable for everyone. I also don’t want people to think delivering meals is a good job just because of how much I’ve made,” Chen said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Goldman Sachs doubles loan facility to Hong Kong fintech start-up FundPark to US$500 million</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3249220/goldman-sachs-doubles-loan-facility-hong-kong-fintech-start-fundpark-us500-million</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  高盛决定扩大其资产支持证券化工具，证明了FundPark的能力和业绩，首席执行官Anson Suen说。 <ul>    <li>Abstract: Goldman Sachs increases funding facility for FundPark, a Hong Kong-based fintech company providing trade finance to SMEs.</li>    <li>Theme: FundPark's track record and capability attract additional investment for SME lending.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Importance of fintech in addressing the trade finance gap for SMEs; FundPark's technology-driven loan assessment model and value-added services.</li>    <li>Main information: Goldamn Sachs' facility increase to US$500 million; FundPark's disbursement of US$2 billion to 16,500 SMEs; plans for continued investment in technology and expansion.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>摘要：</h2>  高盛决定将其资产支持证券化工具扩大至5亿美元，证明了FundPark的能力和往绩，首席执行官Anson Suen说。  <ul>    <li>摘要：高盛增加对FundPark的融资工具，这是一家总部位于香港的金融科技公司，为中小型企业提供贸易融资。</li>    <li>主题：FundPark的往绩和能力吸引了更多对中小型企业贷款的投资。</li>    <li>观点：金融科技在解决中小型企业贸易融资缺口方面的重要性；FundPark的技术驱动贷款评估模型和增值服务。</li>    <li>主要信息：高盛提供的工具增加到5亿美元；FundPark向16,500家中小型企业发放了20亿美元贷款；计划继续投资于技术和扩张。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>underlying (adj.) - /ˈʌndərˌlaɪɪŋ/ 基础的，潜在的，潜在的。    <p>原文例句：FundPark provides loans to SMEs secured by their underlying cashflows, inventory or receivables. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由under（在……下面）和lie（躺，位于）构成，表示“在……下面，潜在的，潜在的”。在这个例句中，它指的是FundPark向中小型企业提供的贷款是由他们的基础现金流、库存或应收账款作为担保的。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>deploy (v.) - /dɪˈplɔɪ/ 部署，利用。    <p>原文例句：“Goldman Sachs’ decision to upsize up to US$500 million is a combination of how it looks at FundPark’s track record in the past 18 months and how FundPark has the capability to deploy the capital rapidly,” he said.    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语deploye，表示“展开，部署”。在这个例句中，它描述了FundPark能够快速部署资本，这是高盛决定将融资工具增加到5亿美元的因素之一。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>trade finance - 贸易融资。    <P>原文例句：FundPark, a Hong Kong-based fintech start-up that provides trade finance for small and medium enterprises (SMEs), has secured US$500 million from Goldman Sachs, the second funding facility from the US investment bank in two years. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由trade（贸易）和finance（金融）构成，表示“贸易融资”。在这个例句中，它指的是FundPark向中小型企业提供的贸易融资，这是一种帮助企业开展国际贸易的金融服务。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>small and medium enterprises (SMEs) - 中小企业。    <P>原文例句：FundPark, a Hong Kong-based fintech start-up that provides trade finance for small and medium enterprises (SMEs), has secured US$500 million from Goldman Sachs, the second funding facility from the US investment bank in two years. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由small（小）, medium（中等）, enterprise（企业）构成，表示“中小型企业”。在这个例句中，它指的是FundPark提供贸易融资的对象，即中小型企业。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Goldman Sachs’ decision to upsize up to US$500 million is a combination of how it looks at FundPark’s track record in the past 18 months and how FundPark has the capability to deploy the capital rapidly, he said. - 高盛决定将其扩大至 5 亿美元，这是基于其对过去 18 个月 FundPark 的往绩的审视，以及 FundPark 能够快速部署资本的能力，他表示。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Goldman Sachs’ decision is a combination，其中主语是Goldman Sachs’ decision，谓语是is，宾语是a combination。how it looks at FundPark’s track record in the past 18 months和how FundPark has the capability to deploy the capital rapidly是两个并列的非限制性定语从句，修饰a combination，表示高盛考虑的因素包括FundPark过去18个月的往绩以及FundPark快速部署资本的能力。这个句子的意思是说，高盛决定将其扩大至5亿美元，这是基于其对过去18个月FundPark的往绩的审视，以及FundPark能够快速部署资本的能力，他表示。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间之前发生或完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：FundPark has disbursed US$2 billion to 16,500 SMEs, mainly in the cross-border e-commerce sector since its inception in 2016.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则变化形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间之前发生或完成，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示FundPark自2016年成立以来，已经向16,500家中小企业发放了20亿美元贷款，这一动作发生在现在之前并且已经完成。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>倒装 - 为了强调或突出某些成分而改变其正常语序。    <p>原文例句：Virtual lender Livi eyes further SME business growth after strong 2023</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个语法现象，是指将句子中某些成分的正常语序颠倒过来。倒装可以用于强调或突出某些成分，使句子更具修辞效果。在这个例句中，将本应放在主语之后的动词eyes放在了主语之前，强调了虚拟贷方Livi对进一步的中小企业业务增长的关注。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Goldman Sachs’ decision to upsize its asset-backed securitisation facility is a testament to FundPark’s capability and track record, CEO Anson Suen says</li>
<li>The start-up has disbursed US$2 billion to 16,500 SMEs, mainly in the cross-border e-commerce sector since its inception in 2016</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/21/7b7f197a-0696-471d-956e-863040047853_f4106d42.jpg" /><figcaption>FundPark CEO and co-founder Anson Suen said the company will continue to upgrade its technological capabilities. Photo: Xiaomei Chen</figcaption></figure><p>FundPark, a Hong Kong-based fintech start-up that provides trade finance for small and medium enterprises (SMEs), has secured US$500 million from Goldman Sachs, the second funding facility from the US investment bank in two years.</p><p>Goldman recently doubled the asset-backed securitisation facility to up to US$500 million, from what it provided FundPark in 2022, CEO and co-founder Anson Suen Wai-loi said, adding that it was one of the largest of its kind received by a fintech firm in Asia.</p><p>“Goldman Sachs’ decision to upsize up to US$500 million is a combination of how it looks at FundPark’s track record in the past 18 months and how FundPark has the capability to deploy the capital rapidly,” he said.</p><p>The company plans to use the investment to provide loans to SMEs, which often have their requests for trade finance rejected by banks, creating a trade financing gap of US$2.5 trillion globally for small business, according to the Asian Development Bank.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="FundPark provides loans to SMEs secured by their underlying cashflows, inventory or receivables. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/21/f732afd8-15c7-4f7c-be7a-f842c1d4f48d_1638767f.jpg" title="FundPark provides loans to SMEs secured by their underlying cashflows, inventory or receivables. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>FundPark provides loans to SMEs secured by their underlying cashflows, inventory or receivables. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Since its inception in 2016, the company has disbursed US$2 billion to 16,500 SMEs, mainly in the cross-border e-commerce sector with US dollar working capital needs. Around half of the loan disbursements happened last year.</p><p>Suen said the performance of its underlying portfolio is “sustainable and healthy” and “beat the market benchmark for banks and non-banks”, but did not provide a number.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3244450/bochk-backed-virtual-lender-livi-eyes-further-sme-business-growth-after-strong-2023" title="">Virtual lender Livi eyes further SME business growth after strong 2023</a></h3><p>FundPark provides loans without typical collateral, such as property, but those are secured by SMEs’ underlying cashflows, inventory or receivables. It employs a proprietary AI-driven credit model to assess borrowers and provide financing solutions based on their needs and credit grading.</p><p>The AI credit model can predict clients’ business performance, such as future cashflows and repayment capability.</p><p>“Empowered by our in-house built credit model, it is able to continue to evolve itself and better understand a client’s creditworthiness,” Suen said. “That means our solution does not require what a traditional bank requires – traditional collateral or security such as property, etc.”</p><p>With the new funding, FundPark will continue to extend loans to the underserved and unserved digital SMEs, aiming for growth similar to last year, he said. It will also continue to invest in its technology and data analytics capabilities and look to provide data insights to clients as a value-added service other than lending.</p><p>In addition, the company is eyeing expansion beyond the 15 markets, such as Greater China, Southeast Asia, Europe and the US, where it serves clients. Exporters and importers in China’s e-commerce space will be a focus.</p><p>Apart from its Hong Kong headquarters in Kwun Tong, FundPark has offices in Shenzhen and Chengdu.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3211408/hong-kong-fintech-employs-ai-technology-promise-collateral-free-loans-citys-small-businesses" title="">Hong Kong fintech start-up offers collateral-free SME loans using AI power</a></h3><p>FundPark said it will maintain partnerships with e-commerce platforms such as Amazon and Walmart Marketplace and logistics service providers such as Cainiao to gain more access to SME merchants.</p><p>Suen expects the market for trade finance to keep growing as business activities increasingly go online.</p><p>“Digital footprint, together with AI technology and data analytics, will allow us to get the data online and respond quickly, and help our digital SME clients scale and capture their future potential.”</p><p>“This kind of scalability is exactly something we are eyeing to bridge the huge funding gap.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nokia set to exit telecommunications joint venture with Huawei amid US-China tensions</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249181/nokia-set-exit-telecommunications-joint-venture-huawei-amid-us-china-tensions</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Finnish telecom giant Nokia has found new buyers for its majority stake in a Beijing-based joint venture with Huawei Technologies.</li>    <li>The joint venture, TD Tech, will be jointly controlled by Huawei and a group of entities that include state-owned enterprises.</li>    <li> Regulators said they had no antitrust concerns on the deal and would solicit public feedback until January 28.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>芬兰电信巨头诺基亚已为其在北京与华为技术有限公司的合资企业中的多数股权找到了新的买家。</li>    <li>该合资企业——TD Tech，将由华为和包括国有企业在内的一组实体共同控制。</li>    <li>监管机构表示，他们对这笔交易没有反垄断担忧，并将征求公众意见至 1 月 28 日。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>venture capital (n.) - /ˈvɛntʃər ˈkæpɪtəl/ 风险投资，创业投资。</li>    <p>原文例句：The document did not reveal how much equity each of the new participants will hold. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Venture capital是指为处于早期阶段的企业提供资金的一种投资形式。风险投资机构通常会投资于那些具有高增长潜力的企业，以期获得高额回报。在这个例句中，它指的是新的参与者将持有多少股权。</p></li>    <li>stake (n.) - /steɪk/ 赌注，股份。</li>    <p>原文例句：Nokia owned 51 per cent of TD Tech, while Huawei held 49 per cent.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Stake是指在某项投资或事业中所拥有的份额或利益。在这个例句中，它指的是诺基亚和华为各自持有的TD Tech的股份比例。</li></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>solicit public feedback - 征求公众意见</li>    <p>原文例句：Regulators said they had no antitrust concerns on the deal and would solicit public feedback until January 28.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Solicit public feedback是指通过公开征求意见的方式来收集公众对某一问题的看法或建议。在这个例句中，它指的是监管机构将征求公众对这笔交易的意见。</p></li>    <li>joint venture - 合资企业</li>    <p>原文例句：Finnish telecoms equipment giant Nokia has found new buyers for its majority stake in a Beijing-based joint venture with Huawei Technologies.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Joint venture是指两个或两个以上的公司或组织共同出资成立的新公司。在这个例句中，它指的是诺基亚和华为在北京成立的合资企业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nokia had been the majority owner of the joint venture, while Huawei has been the de facto controller, according to industry observers. - 诺基亚一直是合资企业的大股东，而华为一直是事实上的控制者，据行业观察家称。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Nokia had been the majority owner of the joint venture，其中主语是Nokia，谓语是had been，宾语是the majority owner of the joint venture。while Huawei has been the de facto controller是一个现在完成时态的句子，表示华为一直是事实上的控制者。这两个句子用while连接，表示诺基亚一直是合资企业的大股东，而华为一直是事实上的控制者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由主语以外的人或物承受的。    <p>原文例句：The joint venture, TD Tech, will be jointly controlled by Huawei and a group of entities that include state-owned enterprises.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，表示TD Tech将由华为和包括国有企业在内的一组实体共同控制。在这个例句中，be动词is被省略了，谓语动词controlled用过去分词形式jointly controlled来表示被动语态。这个句子的意思是说，TD Tech将由华为和包括国有企业在内的一组实体共同控制。</p></li></li>    <li>现在完成时态 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Nokia had been the majority owner of the joint venture, while Huawei has been the de facto controller, according to industry observers.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态的句子，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个例句中，谓语动词had been和has been都用过去分词形式，表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。这个句子的意思是说，诺基亚一直是合资企业的大股东，而华为一直是事实上的控制者。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Finnish company will sell its majority stake in TD Tech to a group that includes state-owned entities, pending final government approval</li>
<li>Huawei has long been considered the de facto controller of TD Tech, which has been selling rebranded phones from the Chinese giant since 2021</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/96782c3a-8a2e-4d29-8e59-79d66ccfe5a6_def6fa44.jpg" /><figcaption>The Nokia headquarters in Espoo, Finland. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Finnish telecoms equipment giant Nokia has found new buyers for its majority stake in a Beijing-based joint venture with Huawei Technologies, after a proposed deal fell through last year following strong protest by the Chinese partner.</p><p>Under the latest agreement, wireless technology firm TD Tech will be jointly controlled by Huawei and a group of entities that include the government-owned Chengdu High-Tech Investment Group and Chengdu Gaoxin Jicui Technology Co, as well as venture capital firm Huagai, according to a disclosure published on Friday by the State Administration for Market Regulation (SAMR).</p><p>The document did not reveal how much equity each of the new participants will hold. Before the sale, Nokia owned 51 per cent of TD Tech, while Huawei held 49 per cent.</p><p>Regulators said they had no antitrust concerns on the deal and would solicit public feedback until January 28. Huawei and TD Tech together control no more than 10 per cent of China’s smartphone market, according to the SAMR, which did not specify the time frame for that data.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1334" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/20/36a09b3c-7803-48e6-a443-6a2cec7d849d_34f54c2a.jpg" title="An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>An advertisement for Huawei phones in Shanghai, China. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Huawei had a 14 per cent share in the Chinese smartphone market in the third quarter last year, putting it in fifth place behind its spin-off Honor and rivals Oppo, Vivo and Apple, data from market intelligence firm Counterpoint Research showed.</p><p>TD Tech, founded in 2005, had been a joint venture between Huawei and German tech conglomerate Siemens until 2007, when Siemens sold half of its stake to Nokia. In 2013, Siemens divested all its shares, making Nokia the major shareholder.</p><p>Known for its wireless communications equipment, including 4G and 5G networking gear, TD Tech has a presence in more than 100 countries serving 8 million industry customers, according to its website.</p><p>While Nokia had been the majority owner of the joint venture, Huawei has been the de facto controller, according to industry observers.</p><p>“The management are former Huawei employees, with product solutions based on Huawei products but fine-tuned for the industry market,” Yang Guang, an analyst covering the telecoms sector at research firm Omdia, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3216677/huawei-opposition-nokia-sale-joint-venture-threatens-finnish-firms-exit-us-china-tensions-weigh-deal" target="_self" title="">said last year</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3216677/huawei-opposition-nokia-sale-joint-venture-threatens-finnish-firms-exit-us-china-tensions-weigh-deal" title="">Huawei opposition to Nokia sale of joint venture threatens Finnish firm’s exit</a></h3><p>When Nokia last year tried to sell its majority stake to Shanghai-listed ink maker New East New Materials, Huawei threatened to stop licensing technology to TD Tech. That deal ultimately collapsed.</p><p>Huawei likely did not want to lose control of TD Tech, which could help the Chinese tech giant circumvent some US sanctions and help it address certain market segments more efficiently, Yang said at the time.</p><p>TD Tech in 2021 started selling what amounted to rebranded Huawei phones under its own brand. They included the M40 5G, which used a 7-nanometre chip from Taiwan-based MediaTek instead of Huawei’s own Kirin processors.</p><p>Sanctions imposed by Washington currently bar companies from selling to Huawei advanced chips made with US-origin technology, which includes MediaTek processors made by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-semiconductor-manufacturing-company-tsmc?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co</a>, the world’s largest contract chip maker.</p><p>Despite the US restrictions, Huawei last year launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233636/huaweis-mate-60-pro-will-help-it-take-lost-ground-china-can-it-help-smartphone-giant-regain-global" target="_self" title="">its Mate 60 Pro</a>, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G processor.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
