<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Alibaba co-founder Jack Ma praises rural teachers for their educational passion and ‘belief in the future’ in annual address</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249115/alibaba-co-founder-jack-ma-praises-rural-teachers-their-educational-passion-and-belief-future-annual</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese billionaire and Alibaba co-founder Jack Ma recently met with rural teachers in China, praising their work in bringing out the creativity, curiosity, and confidence of students despite challenging conditions. Ma, who stepped down as Alibaba's chairman in 2019 and has since maintained a low profile, expressed his admiration for the teachers' passion for education and faith in the future. This marks Ma's ninth consecutive year of meeting with rural teachers in the lead-up to the Chinese Lunar New Year.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Jack Ma praises rural teachers for their dedication and impact on fostering creativity, curiosity, and confidence in students.</li>    <li>Theme: Recognizing and supporting the valuable contributions of rural teachers in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Ma emphasizes the importance of education and commends teachers for their commitment to improving the lives of rural students.</li>    <li>Main information: Ma's meeting with rural teachers and his initiatives to promote education, including financial support and training programs.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国亿万富翁、阿里巴巴联合创始人马云近日与中国乡村教师会面，赞扬他们不畏艰难，激发学生创造力、好奇心和自信心的工作。马云在2019年辞去阿里巴巴董事长一职后一直保持低调，他表示钦佩这些教师对教育的热情和对未来的信念。这是马云连续九年在春节前夕与乡村教师会面。  <ul>    <li>摘要：马云赞扬乡村教师在培养学生创造力、好奇心和自信心方面做出的贡献，以及对教育事业的奉献。</li>    <li>主题：认可和支持乡村教师在提高农村学生生活质量方面的宝贵贡献。</li>    <li>观点：马云强调教育的重要性，赞扬教师致力于改善农村学生生活。</li>    <li>主要信息：马云与乡村教师的会面，以及他为促进教育而推出的倡议，包括财政支持和培训项目。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>foster (v.) - /ˈfɑːstər/ 培养，促进。    <p>原文例句：The projects have fostered 120 rural principals, enlisted 800 pre-service teachers, and revamped 63 boarding schools in rural areas.     </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，指“喂养，扶养，抚养”，在这个例句中，它表示“培养，促进”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>revamp (v.) - /rɪˈvæmp/ 改进，翻新。    <p>原文例句：The projects have fostered 120 rural principals, enlisted 800 pre-service teachers, and revamped 63 boarding schools in rural areas.     </p>    <p>例句讲解：“revamp”一词来源于“re-”（重新）和“vamp”（鞋帮），意为“重新制作”。在这个句子中，它表示“改进，翻新”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the lead-up to - 在...之前，在...的准备阶段。    <p>原文例句：Ma, 59, praises their “sincere passion for education” and their “belief in the future”, according to excerpts of his comments issued by the Foundation.Ma, who has maintained a low profile since stepping down as chairman of e-commerce giant Alibaba in 2019, has met with Chinese rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row.Jack Ma-backed firm 1.8 Meters starts online sales via Alibaba’s Freshippo and Tmall</p>    <p>例句讲解：“in the lead-up to”这个词组表示“在...之前，在...的准备阶段”。在这个句子中，它表示“在春节前夕”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Jack Ma Rural Teachers Initiative and Jack Ma Rural Teachers Award were officially launched on September 16, 2015. Every year, 100 outstanding rural teachers are shortlisted and granted 100,000 yuan (US$14,260) each to support rural education, according to the Foundation’s website. - 2015年9月16日，马云乡村教师计划和马云乡村教师奖正式启动。根据该基金会网站，每年评选出100名优秀乡村教师，每人发放10万元（合14260美元）资助乡村教育。<p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，主句是The Jack Ma Rural Teachers Initiative and Jack Ma Rural Teachers Award were officially launched on September 16, 2015. Every year, 100 outstanding rural teachers are shortlisted and granted 100,000 yuan (US$14,260) each to support rural education, according to the Foundation’s website.。其中主语是The Jack Ma Rural Teachers Initiative and Jack Ma Rural Teachers Award，谓语是were officially launched，宾语是Every year, 100 outstanding rural teachers are shortlisted and granted 100,000 yuan (US$14,260) each to support rural education, according to the Foundation’s website。这个句子的意思是说，2015年9月16日，马云乡村教师计划和马云乡村教师奖正式启动。根据该基金会网站，每年评选出100名优秀乡村教师，每人发放10万元（合14260美元）资助乡村教育。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 表示动词或谓语动词的状态、原因、方式、时间、条件、让步等。    <p>原文例句：Ma, who has maintained a low profile since stepping down as chairman of e-commerce giant Alibaba in 2019, has met with Chinese rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在分词短语作状语，是指在句中用作状语的现在分词及其修饰语构成的短语。现在分词短语可以表示动词或谓语动词的状态、原因、方式、时间、条件、让步等。在这个例句中，现在分词短语Ma, who has maintained a low profile since stepping down as chairman of e-commerce giant Alibaba in 2019作状语，表示马云自2019年辞去电商巨头阿里巴巴董事长一职后一直保持低调的状态。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Ma expressses his admiration for their efforts to bring out the creativity, curiosity and confidence of students in the countryside</li>
<li>Alibaba co-founder Ma has met with rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/c86b1bc7-27d2-4497-8b44-73ac9588866e_487c5401.jpg" /><figcaption>Alibaba founder Jack Ma praises rural teachers for their ‘belief in the future’. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Jack Ma, co-founder of Alibaba Group Holding, has praised the mentality of rural teachers in China and their “belief in the future”, in a message of public support from the increasingly reclusive Chinese billionaire.</p><p>In a videotaped speech issued by the Jack Ma Foundation on Thursday, Ma – a former teacher himself – is seen speaking to a group of rural Chinese teachers, expressing his admiration for their efforts to bring out the creativity, curiosity and confidence of students amid challenging conditions in the countryside.</p><p>Ma, 59, praises their “sincere passion for education” and their “belief in the future”, according to excerpts of his comments issued by the Foundation.</p><p>Ma, who has maintained a low profile since stepping down as chairman of e-commerce giant Alibaba in 2019, has met with Chinese rural teachers in the run up to the Chinese Lunar New Year for nine years in a row.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245634/jack-ma-backed-fishery-and-agriculture-company-18-meters-starts-sale-seafood-products-alibabas" title="">Jack Ma-backed firm 1.8 Meters starts online sales via Alibaba’s Freshippo and Tmall</a></h3><p>The Jack Ma Rural Teachers Initiative and Jack Ma Rural Teachers Award were officially launched on September 16, 2015. Every year, 100 outstanding rural teachers are shortlisted and granted 100,000 yuan (US$14,260) each to support rural education, according to the Foundation’s website. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>In recent years Ma has advocated for agricultural and educational development, as well as environmental protection. Ma, who signed off with a guitar and a rock star wig at a farewell event for thousands of employees in 2019, has pursued several educational causes, including the Rural Principal Initiative, launched in 2016, and the Pre-Service Teachers and Rural School Initiative, both launched in 2017.</p><p>The projects have fostered 120 rural principals, enlisted 800 pre-service teachers, and revamped 63 boarding schools in rural areas.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TikTok owner ByteDance allows employees to cash in stock options earlier under new payroll policy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3249073/tiktok-owner-bytedance-allows-employees-cash-stock-options-earlier-under-new-payroll-policy</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese short video platform ByteDance has adjusted its employee stock options policy. The new policy allows employees to sell their stock options faster, with a vesting schedule of 20% after the first year of service, 25% after the second and third years, and the remaining shares after the fourth year. Annual bonuses have also been standardized to three months' worth of salary, with additional sums based on merit.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: ByteDance adjusts employee stock options policy to allow faster selling.</li>    <li>Theme: ByteDance's revised stock options policy aims to encourage employee retention and provide more flexibility.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The new policy addresses the needs of employees seeking more liquidity and flexibility in their compensation.</li>    <li>Main information: Details of the new stock options vesting schedule, standardization of annual bonuses, mixed reactions among employees, and ByteDance's recent business developments.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国短视频平台字节跳动调整了员工股票期权政策。新的政策允许员工更快地出售他们的股票期权，其归属时间表为：第一年服务后 20%、第二年和第三年后 25%，其余股票在第四年后归属。年度奖金也已标准化为三个月的工资，并根据绩效和股票形式发放额外奖金。之前，员工可以选择是全部或部分以现金形式发放奖金。这项改变影响了数千名习惯于获得更高奖金的员工，例如产品设计和优化人员的奖金已达到六个月工资的水平。为了抵消影响，公司承诺提高产品经理的薪酬。  <ul>    <li>摘要：字节跳动调整员工股票期权政策以允许更快地出售。</li>    <li>主题：字节跳动修订的股票期权政策旨在鼓励员工留任并提供更大的灵活性。</li>    <li>观点：新政策满足了员工对薪酬流动性和灵活性的需求。</li>    <li>主要信息：新的股票期权归属时间表、年度奖金标准化的细节、员工的混合反应以及字节跳动最近的业务发展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>vest (v.) - /vɛst/ 使享有，授予，归属。    <p>原文例句：Thereafter, stock grants will be vested on a quarterly basis rather than annually, as was previously the case. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，意思是“穿衣服，披上（服装）”，引申为“给予权利或所有权”。在这个例句中，它表示股票授予将在季度而不是年度的基础上进行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>incentive (n.) - /ɪnˈsɛntɪv/ 诱因，刺激，激励。    <p>原文例句：The four-year time-based vesting schedule is commonly adopted by businesses to encourage staff to stay longer. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，意思是“开始，冲动”，引申为“激励，诱因”。在这个例句中，它表示四年基于时间的归属时间表通常被企业采用以鼓励员工留任。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>cash in (phr. v.) - 套现，兑现。    <p>原文例句：As ByteDance remains a private firm, the only way for staff to cash in their stock options is to sell to their employer.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由cash（现金）和in（进入）构成的，表示“把股票等变现，套现”。在这个例句中，它表示由于字节跳动仍是一家私营企业，员工套现股票期权的唯一方法是将其出售给雇主。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>mixed reactions - 褒贬不一，毁誉参半。    <p>原文例句：The new policy has generated mixed reactions among employees at China’s most-valuable start-up.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由mixed（混合的）和reactions（反应）构成的，表示“褒贬不一，毁誉参半”。在这个例句中，它表示这项新政策在中国最有价值的初创企业中引起了不同的反应。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance, owner of global short video hit TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin, has adjusted its payroll policy to allow employees to sell their stock options faster, as plans for an initial public offering (IPO) remain in limbo. - 字节跳动，全球短视频巨头 TikTok 的所有者及其中国兄弟应用抖音，已调整其工资政策，允许员工更快地出售其股票期权，因为首次公开募股 (IPO) 的计划仍处于不确定状态。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复句，主句是ByteDance has adjusted its payroll policy，其中主语是ByteDance，谓语是has adjusted，宾语是its payroll policy。owner of global short video hit TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin是一个定语从句，修饰ByteDance，表示字节跳动是全球短视频巨头TikTok及其中国兄弟应用抖音的所有者。as plans for an initial public offering (IPO) remain in limbo是一个时间状语从句，表示在首次公开募股（IPO）的计划仍然不确定时。这个句子的意思是说，字节跳动，全球短视频巨头TikTok及其中国兄弟应用抖音的所有者，已调整其工资政策，允许员工更快地出售其股票期权，因为首次公开募股（IPO）的计划仍处于不确定状态。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>非限定性定语从句 - 用于提供有关先行词的附加信息，但对先行词的意义不是必需的。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance, owner of global short video hit TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin, has adjusted its payroll policy to allow employees to sell their stock options faster, as plans for an initial public offering (IPO) remain in limbo.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个非限定性定语从句，修饰先行词ByteDance，提供有关ByteDance的附加信息。这个从句可以通过逗号与先行词分开，也可以用破折号或括号括起来。在这个例句中，它表示字节跳动是全球短视频巨头 TikTok 和其中国兄弟应用抖音的所有者。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>时间状语从句 - 表示动作或事件发生的时间。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance, owner of global short video hit TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin, has adjusted its payroll policy to allow employees to sell their stock options faster, as plans for an initial public offering (IPO) remain in limbo.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时间状语从句，表示ByteDance调整工资政策的时间。这个从句可以用as、when、while、until等连接词来引导。在这个例句中，它表示在首次公开募股（IPO）的计划仍然不确定时，字节跳动调整了其工资政策。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Under the new rule, staff will receive 20 per cent of their total stock awards after their first year of service, up from 15 per cent previously</li>
<li>Annual bonuses have been standardised to three months worth of salary, all granted in cash, with additional sums to be given on merit</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/6e2d688a-a5f7-4f1f-9db6-7f74a061f980_9463801a.jpg" /><figcaption>ByteDance’s logo is seen at the company’s office in Shanghai. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>ByteDance, owner of global short video hit TikTok and its Chinese sibling Douyin, has adjusted its payroll policy to allow employees to sell their stock options faster, as plans for an initial public offering (IPO) remain in limbo.</p><p>Under the new rule, applicable to ByteDance’s 110,000 employees worldwide, workers will receive 20 per cent of their total stock awards after their first year of service, up from 15 per cent previously, according to two people briefed on the matter on Thursday.</p><p>Thereafter, stock grants will be vested on a quarterly basis rather than annually, as was previously the case. Workers will get 25 per cent of their equity grants after the second year, and again in the third year, with all remaining shares to be vested after the fourth year.</p><p>ByteDance did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246294/after-tiktok-owner-bytedance-cuts-fat-focus-fundamentals-social-commerce-challenges-and-us-election" title="">TikTok owner ByteDance spent 2023 cutting the fat, but fresh challenges loom</a></h3><p>The four-year time-based vesting schedule is commonly adopted by businesses to encourage staff to stay longer. As ByteDance remains a private firm, the only way for staff to cash in their stock options is to sell to their employer.</p><p>The Beijing-based company’s share buy-back programme has taken place twice a year since 2017. The most recent one, in November, priced the stock at US$160 per share.</p><p>In its latest reform, ByteDance also standardised its annual bonuses to three months worth of salary, all granted in cash, with additional sums to be given on merit and in equity form. Previously, employees had been allowed to decide if they wanted their bonuses to be given entirely or partially in cash.</p><p>The change affects thousands of employees who are used to receiving higher bonuses, such as product design and optimisation staff whose bonuses had reached the level of six months’ salary. To offset the impact, the company has promised product managers pay rises.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A lights display by Douyin at a shopping centre in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/3078775a-24a5-417f-9719-ee6ae9394d11_1126e908.jpg" title="A lights display by Douyin at a shopping centre in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo" width="2000" /><figcaption>A lights display by Douyin at a shopping centre in Beijing. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure></div><p>The new policy has generated mixed reactions among employees at China’s most-valuable start-up.</p><p>One person said some staff may be happy to find more flexibility if they are considering a job change in the middle of the year. Another person said now that employees could not receive all bonuses as stock options, they could be charged higher income taxes.</p><p>Prospects for a ByteDance IPO remain uncertain amid intense scrutiny in the US over TikTok’s ties to China, as well as challenges in other overseas markets.</p><p>At home, ByteDance has retreated from the video gaming sector. It confirmed earlier this month that it was in talks with multiple potential buyers, including Tencent Holdings, to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations" target="_self" title="">sell its video-game operations</a>.</p><p>In December, the unicorn offered to buy back up to US$5 billion worth of shares from existing investors, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244025/tiktok-owner-bytedance-offers-buy-back-us5-billion-worth-investor-shares-ipo-prospects-remain-slim" target="_self" title="">valuing it at US$268 billion</a>, or about 10 per cent lower than a year earlier when ByteDance organised a US$3 billion share buy-back for earlier investors, the Post reported.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>World Economic Forum: CATL’s Robin Zeng calls for setting aside geopolitical tensions to address EV battery materials shortage</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3249090/world-economic-forum-catls-robin-zeng-calls-setting-aside-geopolitical-tensions-address-ev-battery</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Amid geopolitical tensions, China's Contemporary Amperex Technology Ltd (CATL), the world's largest manufacturer of batteries for electric vehicles, urges for collaboration on battery recycling technologies to ensure a sustainable and secure supply chain for the growing industry. CATL founder Robin Zeng emphasizes the urgency of addressing critical material shortages and proposes sharing China's mature battery recycling technologies with the world. By 2042, China aims to eliminate the need for new mineral mining through efficient recycling.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: CATL advocates for global collaboration in battery recycling to overcome geopolitical challenges and address material shortages.</li>    <li>Theme: Emphasizing the significance of battery recycling technologies in mitigating material shortages and enabling the transition to electric vehicles.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: CATL's perspective on the need for international cooperation and technological innovation to ensure a sustainable and secure supply chain for electric vehicles.</li>    <li>Main information: Zeng's call for setting aside geopolitical issues in recycling technologies; China's advanced battery recycling capabilities; CATL's willingness to share technologies and assist overseas carmakers; projected elimination of new mineral mining in China by 2042.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文概要：</h2>  在面临地缘政治紧张局势的大背景下，中国当代安培科技有限公司（CATL），作为全球电动汽车电池的最大制造商，呼吁全球协作开发电池回收技术，以保证不断增长的行业获得一个可持续且安全的供应链。CATL 创始人曾毓群强调了解决关键材料短缺的紧迫性，并提议与世界分享中国成熟的电池回收技术。到 2042 年，中国计划通过有效的回收消除对新矿产开采的需求。  <ul>    <li>摘要：CATL 倡导全球在电池回收方面进行合作，以克服地缘政治挑战并解决材料短缺问题。</li>    <li>主题：强调电池回收技术在缓解材料短缺和实现电动汽车转型的过程中所具有的重要意义。</li>    <li>观点：CATL 就国际合作和技术创新对于确保电动汽车的供应链可持续性与安全性的必要性所表达的观点。</li>    <li>主要信息：曾毓群呼吁在回收技术中摒弃地缘政治问题；中国在电池回收方面具备强大的能力；CATL 愿意与海外汽车制造商分享技术并提供帮助；预计到 2042 年中国将不再需要开采新的矿产材料。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>collaborate (v.) - /kəˈlæbəreɪt/ 协作，合作。    <p>原文例句：Countries – from government leaders to businesses and non-governmental organisations – must collaborate to accelerate innovation in the EV battery industry. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由col-（共同）和laborare（工作）组成，意为“共同工作，合作”。在这个例句中，它表示各国，从政府领导人到企业和非政府组织，必须合作才能加快电动汽车电池行业的创新。</p></li>    <li>resilience (n.) - /rɪˈzɪliəns/ 复原力，弹性。    <p>原文例句：to ensure a resilient supply chain, reduce dependency on critical metals and decarbonise the transport sector. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由re-（又）和salire（跳跃）组成，意为“反弹，恢复”，引申为“复原力，弹性”。在这个例句中，它表示要确保一个具有复原力的供应链，减少对关键金属的依赖，并对运输行业进行脱碳。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>net-zero transition - 净零排放转型。    <p>原文例句：could put the net-zero transition under threat. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由net（净的）和zero（零）组成，表示“净零排放”。transition（转型）表示“从一种状态或情况转变到另一种状态或情况”。在这个例句中，它表示持续的锂、镍和钴短缺可能会危及净零排放转型。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>But CATL’s business has been affected by the fraught relations between Beijing and the West. - 但 CATL 的业务受到北京与西方紧张关系的影响。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是But CATL’s business has been affected，其中主语是CATL’s business，谓语是has been affected，宾语是by the fraught relations between Beijing and the West。But是一个转折连词，表示转折或对比。fraught relations between Beijing and the West是一个介词短语作状语，表示北京和西方之间紧张的关系。这个句子的意思是说，但 CATL 的业务受到北京和西方之间紧张关系的影响。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 为了强调句子中的某个成分而改变其在句子中的正常语序。    <p>原文例句：By 2042, China will no longer need to mine new mineral materials because of its mature battery recycling market: Zeng. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，正常语序应该是China will no longer need to mine new mineral materials by 2042 because of its mature battery recycling market。在这个句中，把By 2042提到句首进行强调，表示到 2042 年。because of its mature battery recycling market是一个介词短语作状语，表示由于其成熟的电池回收市场。这个句子的意思是说，到 2042 年，由于其成熟的电池回收市场，中国将不再需要开采新的矿产材料，这是曾说过的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>‘We are fighting climate change … so whatever the geopolitical issues are, we have to find a way,’ CATL founder tells Davos panel</li>
<li>By 2042, China will no longer need to mine new mineral materials because of its mature battery recycling market: Zeng</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/4d47a3f8-9ba6-43ca-a388-054f3db16628_c80f5359.jpg" /><figcaption>CATL showcases its ‘Superfast Charging Battery Shenxing’ at the 2023 International Motor Show in Munich, in this file photo from September last year. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure><p>Geopolitical tensions must be set aside as the world faces shortages of critical battery materials such as lithium, nickel and cobalt due to surging demand, said Robin Zeng Yuqun, founder of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248522/china-evs-catl-worlds-top-battery-maker-plans-first-plant-beijing-supply-li-auto-and-xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Contemporary Amperex Technology Ltd (CATL)</a>, the world’s largest manufacturer of batteries for electric vehicles (EVs).</p><p>Countries – from government leaders to businesses and non-governmental organisations – must collaborate to accelerate innovation in the EV battery industry to ensure a resilient supply chain, reduce dependency on critical metals and decarbonise the transport sector to tackle the climate crisis, Zeng told the World Economic Forum meeting in Davos.</p><p>“We should really avoid any geopolitical issues in [battery] recycling technologies,” he said during a panel on Wednesday. “If we can provide these recycling technologies to Europe, to the US and to the rest of the world, it’d be very easy to manage mining issues.</p><p>“The demand for critical materials might increase by five times in the next 10 years, considering the fast growth of the industry. But at the end of the day, when we achieve 100 per cent electric cars, there will be very tiny amounts of new critical materials to be mined.”</p><p>China leads the world in battery recycling technologies, an important solution for addressing battery material shortages.</p><p>For instance, Zeng told the forum that CATL currently has the capacity to recycle as much as 99.6 per cent of precious metals such as nickel, cobalt and manganese, and up to 91 per cent of lithium, higher than Europe’s capacity of 70 per cent to 80 per cent. Last year, CATL recycled 100,000 tonnes of waste batteries through its subsidiary Brump to create 13,000 tonnes of lithium carbonate, he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3244015/chinese-ev-battery-giant-catl-will-set-research-and-development-centre-hong-kong-win-government" title="">EV battery giant CATL to open research and development centre in Hong Kong</a></h3><p>But CATL’s business has been affected by the fraught relations between Beijing and the West. In December, for instance, CATL was accused of posing a national security threat in the US and was banned from a US military base. The allegation was based on a letter from US lawmakers led by Republican senator Marco Rubio that said CATL enjoyed a close relationship with the Chinese leadership in Beijing.</p><p>“We are fighting climate change … so whatever the geopolitical issues are, we have to find a way,” Zeng said during the panel.</p><p>As sales of EVs continue to break records around the world, governments and carmakers are increasingly concerned about the persistent shortages of lithium, nickel and cobalt, which could put the net-zero transition under threat.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3231316/catl-produce-worlds-fastest-ev-battery-offers-400km-driving-range-just-10-minutes-charging-keep" title="">CATL to make battery offering 400km driving range from 10-minute charge</a></h3><p>S&amp;P Global forecast that a more than 270 per cent increase in lithium production levels is needed to meet the estimated demand from the EV battery sector by 2030. Nickel and cobalt are also expected to be critical, but to a lesser degree as the deployment of iron-based chemistries will remedy their potential shortage, it said.</p><p>The Fujian-based company is willing to share its technologies and help overseas carmakers address their battery shortages, Zeng said. By 2042, China will no longer need to mine new mineral materials because of its mature battery recycling market, he added.</p><p>CATL is increasingly <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3215488/tesla-talks-catl-chinas-leading-ev-battery-maker-building-plant-us" target="_self" title="">expanding its capacity overseas</a> with plants in Germany and Hungary. It is also partnering with Amsterdam-based multinational carmaker Stellantis and Ford Motor to build battery factories in Europe and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3210118/chinas-catl-provide-know-how-fords-new-us35-billion-electric-car-battery-plant-us" target="_self" title="">Michigan in the US</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>As an essential part of decarbonising the automotive ecosystem, the EV transition requires technological innovation, a sustainable and responsible supply chain and the concerted efforts of all stakeholders, Zeng said during another panel on Thursday.</p><p>Advancing mining and refinery technology helps to increase the supply of lithium and to alleviate shortages, he said. Increasing energy density helps improve material efficiency and therefore reduces the demand for raw materials.</p><p>Finding an alternative at lower costs, such as sodium-ion batteries or cobalt-free cathode materials, is also a solution for reducing dependency on critical materials such as lithium, he said.</p><p>According to Zeng, CATL introduced its first generation of sodium-ion batteries in 2021 and is currently working on its second generation, which will give cars a driving range of 400 to 500 kilometres per charge.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>How China is making its dream of flying cars, drones and sky cities come true</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3248760/how-china-making-its-dream-flying-cars-drones-and-sky-cities-come-true</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In Las Vegas, consumer electronics show CES 2024 has caught worldwide attention. China, with over 1,000 companies participating, has showcased its impressive contributions to global technology, especially in the electric vehicle (EV) industry. The low-altitude economy, including flying vehicles and drones, is gaining prominence in China with government support. Xpeng's modular flying car, AeroHT eVTOL, has successfully completed a test flight and is set for pre-orders. The Chinese government's focus on innovation and deployment of flying cars includes establishing economic demonstration zones and test bases. Additionally, China's close public-private collaboration and infrastructural support foster a nurturing ecosystem for EV makers. The development of China's low-altitude economy serves as an inspirational model for the integration of advanced aerial technologies into everyday life and urban planning.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's low-altitude economy showcases advancements in flying vehicles and drones, supported by government policies and infrastructural developments.</li>    <li>Theme: China's commitment to integrating advanced aerial technologies into daily life and urban planning, driving innovation and industrial growth.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The positive impact of government support and public-private collaboration on the development of China's low-altitude economy.</li>    <li>Main information: Xpeng's AeroHT eVTOL, China's green aviation plan, economic demonstration zones, test bases, infrastructural support, drones in agriculture and delivery, the low-altitude flight service platform, and industry regulations.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在拉斯维加斯，消费电子展CES 2024吸引了全世界的关注。中国有1000多家公司参展，展示了其对全球技术的杰出贡献，尤其是在电动汽车（EV）行业。低空经济，包括飞行器和无人机，在中国受到政府的大力支持而备受瞩目。小鹏汽车的模块化飞行汽车AeroHT eVTOL已经成功完成试飞，并已准备好预订。中国政府对飞行汽车创新和部署的关注包括建立经济示范区和测试基地。此外，中国紧密的公私合作和基础设施支持为电动汽车制造商创造了一个培育生态系统。中国低空经济的发展为先进航空技术融入日常生活和城市规划树立了鼓舞人心的典范。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国低空经济展示了飞行器和无人机的进步，得到政府政策和基础设施发展的大力支持。</li>    <li>主题：中国致力于将先进的航空技术融入日常生活和城市规划，推动创新和产业增长。</li>    <li>观点：政府支持和公私合作对中国低空经济发展产生的积极影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：小鹏汽车的AeroHT eVTOL、中国的绿色航空发展计划、经济示范区、测试基地、基础设施支持、无人机在农业和配送中的应用、低空飞行服务平台以及行业法规制度等。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>modular (adj.) - /ˈmɑːdjʊlər/ 模块化的，组装式。    <p>原文例句：Xpeng launched its modular Land Aircraft Carrier, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Late Latin，由modulus（模型）和-aris（表示……的）组成，表示“由模块组成的，可以组装或拆卸”。在这个例句中，它指的是小鹏汽车推出的模块化陆地航空母舰，它配有一个可从汽车上发射的单独飞机。</p></li>    <li>conducive (adj.) - /kənˈdjuːsɪv/ 有利的，有利于。    <p>原文例句：Policy, financial and infrastructural support is creating a conducive ecosystem for China’s ‘low altitude economy’, integrating advanced aerial tech into everyday life and urban planning。 </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由conducere（引导）和-ivus（倾向……的）组成，表示“引导的，有利于”。在这个例句中，它指的是政策、财政和基础设施支持正在为中国的“低空经济”创造一个有利的生态系统，将先进的航空技术整合到日常生活和城市规划中。</p></li>    </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take off - 起飞。    <p>原文例句：Shenzhen is building a grid of over 600 landing/take-off stations for low-altitude aircraft from by 2025. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿）和off（关闭）构成的，表示“起飞”。在这个例句中，它指的是深圳正在建设一个包含600多个低空飞机起降站的网络，预计在2025年完成。</p></li>    <li>low-altitude flight - 低空飞行。    <p>原文例句：This year, Shenzhen announced China’s first regulations over the low-altitude economy.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由low（低）和altitude（高度）以及flight（飞行）组成的，表示“低空飞行”。在这个例句中，它指的是今年深圳颁布了中国第一个关于低空经济的规定。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Chinese government is keen for companies to continue making leaps in flying vehicle technology and last year announced a “green aviation” development plan, including for electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft, or eVTOL. - 中国政府热衷于让企业继续在飞行器技术方面取得飞跃，并于去年宣布了一项“绿色航空”发展计划，其中包括电动垂直起降飞机，即eVTOL。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The Chinese government is keen for companies to continue making leaps in flying vehicle technology，其中主语是The Chinese government，谓语是is keen，宾语是for companies to continue making leaps in flying vehicle technology。and last year announced a “green aviation” development plan, including for electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft, or eVTOL是一个并列句，与主句的关系是并列关系。在这个例句中，and表示“以及”，last year announced a “green aviation” development plan, including for electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft, or eVTOL是一个插入语，表示“去年宣布了一项‘绿色航空’发展计划，其中包括电动垂直起降飞机，即eVTOL”。这个句子的意思是说，中国政府热衷于让企业继续在飞行器技术方面取得飞跃，并于去年宣布了一项“绿色航空”发展计划，其中包括电动垂直起降飞机，即eVTOL。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示可能性、愿望、建议、命令等。    <p>原文例句：China’s DJI is the world’s largest drone manufacturer with 70 per cent of the global market share.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语气，表示可能性、愿望、建议、命令等。通常用在从句中，从句的谓语动词用虚拟语气。虚拟语气的形式主要有：过去时、现在完成时、过去完成时和should+动词原形。在这个例句中，China’s DJI is the world’s largest drone manufacturer with 70 per cent of the global market share是一个陈述句，所以谓语动词用的是现在时态。这个句子的意思是说，中国的大疆公司是全球最大的无人机制造商，占全球市场份额的70%。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Policy, financial and infrastructural support is creating a conducive ecosystem for China’s ‘low altitude economy’, integrating advanced aerial tech into everyday life and urban planning</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/95294f31-6a7b-449b-ae1b-5cb7ef61e7b8_e137b3d0.jpg" /><figcaption>An EHang autonomous aerial vehicle conducting a demonstration flight at the Baoan District Low-Altitude Economy Investment Promotion Conference in Shenzhen last year. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3247413/ai-will-be-spotlight-consumer-electronics-show-2024-glasses-blind-shoes-make-you-walk-faster-and" target="_self" title="">CES 2024</a> consumer electronics show in Las Vegas last week mesmerised tech observers from around the world with more than 4,000 exhibitors, from start-ups to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" target="_self" title="">tech giants</a>. Over 1,000 companies were <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248469/alibaba-tiktok-woo-us-ai-and-live-streaming-e-commerce-ces-trade-show-setting-tone-2024" target="_self" title="">from China</a>, demonstrating the country’s impressive contributions to global technology.</p><p>In particular spotlight was China’s electric vehicle (EV) industry, after China was recently crowned the world’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247833/china-solidify-its-position-worlds-top-car-exporter-2024-it-banks-manufacturing-heft-ubs" target="_self" title="">largest car exporter</a>, accounting for about half of global EV sales. At the tech showcase, Xpeng astonished with its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" target="_self" title="">“flying car”</a>, the AeroHT eVTOL.</p><p>Built sleekly in the shape of a sports car, with propellers that unfurl, the futuristic vehicle evoked visions of flying vehicles seen in films such as <em>Star Wars</em> and <em>The Fifth Element</em>. The model, thought to be years away from broad use, completed a successful test flight in October 2022.</p><p>At CES, Xpeng also showcased its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" target="_self" title="">Land Aircraft Carrier</a>, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car, for which the company will take pre-orders in the fourth quarter this year, with deliveries to start a year later.</p><p>The Chinese government is keen for companies to continue making leaps in flying vehicle technology and last year announced a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3237594/china-outlines-vision-green-aviation-nev-industry-c919-models" target="_self" title="">“green aviation” development plan</a>, including for electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft, or eVTOL. This is part of an official strategy to support a “<a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245769/chinas-low-altitude-economy-set-take-vast-potential-could-contribute-us700-billion-2025" target="_self" title="">low altitude economy</a>”.</p><p>The low-altitude economy refers to a comprehensive realm of industries centred around civil-manned and unmanned aerial vehicles, including manufacturing, low-altitude flight operations and integrated services.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Xpeng launched its modular Land Aircraft Carrier, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/17/bfdb3d00-6397-4d67-82cf-a01cf3c2ebc0_00d05c81.jpg" title="Xpeng launched its modular Land Aircraft Carrier, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Xpeng launched its modular Land Aircraft Carrier, which comes with a separate aircraft that launches from the car. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>China’s green aviation plan presented actionable items to boost the innovation and deployment of flying cars. Important measures include setting up economic demonstration zones and test bases for low-flying aircraft. The plan includes the construction of infrastructure to integrate flying vehicles into urban transport and the daily commute.</p><p>While US flying car companies such as Kittyhawk (backed by Google founder Larry Page) shut down in 2022 due to commercialising and scaling difficulties, China’s policy support is fostering a more conducive ecosystem for nascent technologies like this to advance and benefit society.</p><p>Xpeng’s AeroHT eVTOL, for instance, unlike other flying vehicles such as by German company Volocopter and Hyundai’s Supernal, which was showcased at CES 2024, can transform between terrestrial and aerial modes.</p><p>While the inventions by Volocopter and Supernal resemble personal helicopters, Xpeng’s AeroHT eVTOL has propellers that emerge in flying mode and fold into the car’s body after use. This allows it to navigate road traffic and fit into a standard car park space.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People view the XPeng AeroHT “modular flying car” at the CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada, on January 11. Photo: AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1202" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/c8aea417-015f-46e6-bfce-0a8c0a29a6fb_e4c01113.jpg" title="People view the XPeng AeroHT “modular flying car” at the CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada, on January 11. Photo: AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>People view the XPeng AeroHT “modular flying car” at the CES 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada, on January 11. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>Another factor that enhances the research and development of flying cars in China is close public-private collaboration. For instance, in 2021, the Guangdong government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3125538/china-electric-cars-xpeng-receives-us77-million-investment" target="_self" title="">invested 500 million yuan</a> (US$70 million) in Xpeng. Guangdong’s Zhaoqing city has also supported Xpeng’s expansion, last year signing an investment agreement for a project worth 2 billion yuan. This type of financial and infrastructural support creates a nurturing ecosystem that enables Chinese EV makers to quickly transform concept cars into mass products.</p><p>China has highlighted the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3245769/chinas-low-altitude-economy-set-take-vast-potential-could-contribute-us700-billion-2025" target="_self" title="">low-altitude economy</a> as a core industry, deserving of special attention, at its annual <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3244856/chinas-development-biggest-political-priority-key-econ-meeting-leaders-vow-counter-risks-lift" target="_self" title="">central economic work conference</a> last month, together with artificial intelligence, the digital economy, green energy, biomedicine and private space flight. The vision is for China to address its economic challenges by investing in technology and industry, unlocking the country’s growth potential.</p><p>In addition to flying cars, drones are another area of China’s low-altitude economy that promises to revolutionise its agriculture, delivery services, emergency responses and more. Already, Shenzhen, China’s hi-tech hub, has <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3246693/chinas-low-altitude-economy-takes-skies-unmanned-passenger-drone-completes-maiden-commercial-flight" target="_self" title="">declared plans</a> to build itself a “city in the sky”.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/2184687/how-dji-went-university-dorm-project-worlds-biggest-drone-company" target="_self" title="">China’s DJI</a> is the world’s largest drone manufacturer with 70 per cent of the global market share. Its drone technology has helped in the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/2183603/drone-maker-dji-eyes-enterprise-business-transformation-hardware-maker" target="_self" title="">automation of farming</a>, including planning, sowing, weeding, watering and monitoring crop growth. Food delivery platform Meituan, for example, has <a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3224049/how-chinese-tech-giant-meituan-cracked-food-delivery-drone-densely-built-shenzhen-and-implications" target="_self" title="">embraced drones</a>, speeding up its commercial transactions and slashing its labour cost. In 2022, the drone industry in Shenzhen alone generated a market value of 75 billion yuan.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Shenzhen is building a grid of over 600 landing/take-off stations for low-altitude aircraft from by 2025. This will facilitate their deployment and reduce operational costs for companies. Infrastructural support is essential in this industry, especially when the aim is to promote widespread public usage.</p><p>With more companies developing flying cars and other low-altitude aircraft in China, industry regulation is also maturing. This year, Shenzhen announced China’s first regulations over the low-altitude economy. Effective from February 1, these regulations aim to standardise the construction of low-altitude flight infrastructure, coordinate the management of low-altitude airspace and flight services, and set safety standards.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/travel-leisure/article/3227433/rise-shenzhen-chinas-silicon-valley-seaside-town-fast-moving-city-secret-pockets-tranquillity" title="">The rise of Shenzhen, from seaside town to China’s Silicon Valley</a></h3><p>They stipulate the construction of a low-altitude flight service platform, providing services like flight approval applications, intelligent flight monitoring and message alerts to units or individuals conducting low-altitude flight activities.</p><p>The fierce market competition in China’s EV industry has certainly contributed to the industry’s exponential growth. But China’s institutional support also plays a role in quickly making hi-tech advancements accessible to ordinary citizens, and not just a few privileged individuals.</p><p>Although there are still gaps between the big cities and the underdeveloped areas, China’s policy principle that new technologies should improve people’s lives and livelihoods makes for a promising future.</p><p>The development of China’s low-altitude economy could serve as an inspirational model for the world, showing the potential for the integration of advanced aerial technologies into everyday life and urban planning.</p><p><strong>Gerui Wang is a visiting scholar at Stanford University</strong></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ChatGPT boosted user numbers and time spent on Microsoft’s Bing, but fails to dent Google’s search dominance</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3249012/chatgpt-boosted-user-numbers-and-time-spent-microsofts-bing-fails-dent-googles-search-dominance</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Despite high hopes, Microsoft's Bing search engine has only gained a marginal 1% market share since incorporating ChatGPT. While generative AI has generated excitement, Google's dominance remains unshaken, capturing over 90% of the market. Microsoft continues to add features like image generation but faces an uphill battle against Google's established user base and data advantage. Experts believe that to truly challenge Google, Bing needs more than just flashy AI features; it requires a fundamental shift in user behavior and a flywheel effect where increased usage leads to better answers.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Microsoft's Bing search engine gains a small market share with the integration of ChatGPT, but Google maintains its dominance.</li>    <li>Theme: The competitive landscape of search engines and the impact of generative AI on user behavior and advertising.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Experts emphasize the importance of user behavior and data accumulation for search engine success, suggesting that Bing faces challenges in overcoming Google's advantages.</li>    <li>Main information: Bing's market share increase, Google's continued dominance, Microsoft's addition of new AI features, the potential impact on advertising spending, and expert opinions on the challenges and opportunities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  尽管寄予厚望，微软的必应搜索引擎自接入 ChatGPT 以来，市场份额仅略微增长 1%。虽然生成式人工智能引起了热议，但谷歌的统治地位仍然稳固，占据了超过 90% 的市场份额。微软继续增加图像生成等功能，但与谷歌既有的用户基础和数据优势相比，它面临着艰难的挑战。专家认为，必应要真正挑战谷歌，仅靠炫酷的人工智能功能还不够；它需要用户行为发生根本性转变以及使用量增加带来更好答案的飞轮效应。  <ul>    <li>摘要：微软的必应搜索引擎在集成 ChatGPT 后获得了小幅市场份额，但谷歌仍保持主导地位。</li>    <li>主题：搜索引擎的竞争格局以及生成式人工智能对用户行为和广告的影响。</li>    <li>观点：专家强调用户行为和数据积累对于搜索引擎成功的重要性，认为必应在克服谷歌优势方面面临挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：必应的市场份额增长、谷歌的持续主导、微软增加的新人工智能功能、对广告支出的潜在影响以及专家对于挑战和机遇的看法。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>dominance (n.) - /ˈdɑːmɪnəns/ 统治，主导地位。    <p>原文例句：Google’s dominance in the search engine market is well-established. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源于拉丁语，由dominari（统治）和-ance（状态）组成，表示“统治权，主导地位”。在这个例句中，它指的是谷歌在搜索引擎市场中的统治地位，即谷歌在搜索引擎市场中占有绝对优势。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>prompts (n.) - /prɒmpt/ 提示，提示语。    <p>原文例句：Visitors can use it to create realistic-looking images with simple text prompts. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源于拉丁语，由pro（在……之前）和-mpt（促成）组成，表示“促使”。在这个例句中，它指的是简单的文本提示，即用户可以使用这些提示来创建逼真的图像。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>crucial (adj.) - /ˈkruːʃəl/ 至关重要的，关键的。    <p>原文例句：It has more than 90 per cent of the market and is the default search engine on Apple hardware, including iPhones, giving Google crucial critical mass. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源于拉丁语，由crux（十字架）和-ial（形容词后缀）组成，表示“像十字架一样至关重要，关键的”。在这个例句中，它指的是至关重要的临界值，即谷歌占有超过 90% 的市场份额，并且是苹果硬件（包括 iPhone）的默认搜索引擎，这为谷歌提供了至关重要的临界值。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fundamentally (adv.) - /ˌfʌndəˈmɛntəli/ 从根本上，本质上。    <p>原文例句：The retooling of search by both technology giants reflects a shared conviction that generative AI will fundamentally change the way people seek and receive answers online.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源于拉丁语，由fundamentum（基础）和-ally（副词后缀）组成，表示“从基础上，从本质上”。在这个例句中，它指的是从根本上，即这两家科技巨头对搜索的改造反映了他们共同坚信生成式人工智能会从根本上改变人们在线搜索和获取答案的方式。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>market share - 市场份额。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft’s Bing app. Photo: ReutersWhen Microsoft announced it was baking ChatGPT into its Bing search engine last February, bullish analysts declared the move an “iPhone moment” that could upend the search market and chip away at Google’s dominance. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由market（市场）和share（份额）组成，表示“市场份额”，即公司或产品在特定市场中的销售额或销量所占的比例。在这个例句中，它指的是微软的必应搜索引擎在搜索市场中的份额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Bing has long struggled for relevance and attracted more mockery than recognition over the years as a serious alternative to Google. - 众所周知，必应长期以来一直在为相关性而苦苦挣扎，这些年来一直受到更多嘲笑而不是被认可为谷歌的可靠替代品。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Bing has struggled for relevance，其中主语是Bing，谓语是has struggled，宾语是for relevance。and attracted more mockery than recognition over the years as a serious alternative to Google是一个并列句，表示Bing这些年来作为谷歌的可靠替代品而受到更多嘲笑而不是被认可。这个句子的意思是说，众所周知，必应长期以来一直在为相关性而苦苦挣扎，这些年来一直受到更多嘲笑而不是被认可为谷歌的可靠替代品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：The retooling of search by both technology giants reflects a shared conviction that generative AI will fundamentally change the way people seek and receive answers online.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句型，强调了句子中的成分people。强调句型的结构是：It is/was + 被强调的成分 + that/who + 其他。在这个例句中，被强调的成分是people，强调句型的结构是：It is people that will fundamentally change the way people seek and receive answers online，强调了人们将从根本上改变他们在线搜索和获取答案的方式。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The market share of Microsoft’s search engine rose less than 1 percentage point since the ChatGPT announcement</li>
<li>Microsoft is betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/f958a4b4-35bc-43ff-923e-d785b6e45d9d_84591264.jpg" /><figcaption>The Microsoft Bing app. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>When Microsoft announced it was baking ChatGPT into its Bing search engine last February, bullish analysts declared the move an “iPhone moment” that could upend the search market and chip away at Google’s dominance.</p><p>“The entire search category is now going through a sea change,” chief executive officer Satya Nadella said at the time. “That opportunity comes very few times.”</p><p>Almost a year later, the sea has yet to change.</p><p>The new Bing – powered by OpenAI’s generative artificial intelligence (AI) technology – dazzled internet users with conversational replies to queries asked in a natural way.</p><p>But Microsoft’s search engine ended 2023 with just 3.4 per cent of the global search market, according to data analytics firm StatCounter, up less than 1 percentage point since the ChatGPT announcement.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" class="image-inline caption" height="1416" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/081a8c1b-b628-46e0-b984-6897c60d3a63_b10d85c3.jpg" title="Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP" width="2000" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, right, on stage with OpenAI CEO Sam Altman at the start-up’s DevDay event in November. Photo: Getty Images via AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>Bing has long struggled for relevance and attracted more mockery than recognition over the years as a serious alternative to Google. Multiple rebrandings and redesigns since its 2009 debut did little to boost Bing’s popularity.</p><p>A month before Microsoft infused the search engine with generative AI, people were spending 33 per cent less time using it than they had 12 months earlier, according to SensorTower.</p><p>The ChatGPT reboot at least helped reverse those declines. In the second quarter of 2023, US monthly active users more than doubled year over year to 3.1 million, according to a Bloomberg Intelligence analysis of SensorTower mobile app data.</p><p>Overall, users were spending 84 per cent more time on the search engine, the data show. By year-end, Bing’s monthly active users had increased steadily to 4.4 million, according to SensorTower.</p><p>To build on the momentum, Microsoft has been adding more AI tools to Bing. In October, the company integrated the latest version of OpenAI’s image-generating model, DALL-E 3. Visitors can use it to create realistic-looking images with simple text prompts.</p><p>The offering does nothing to enhance Bing’s search abilities. But its addition generated a spike in usage, according to Jordi Ribas, Microsoft’s corporate vice-president of search and AI.</p><p>“We noticed an increase in usage by 10 times and that took us by surprise because if you think about it, DALL-E 2 was already quite good,” he said in an interview. “It really made a difference in the engagement and the users that came to our product.”</p><p>Yusuf Mehdi, Microsoft’s consumer chief marketing officer, declined to specify how many active users Bing has.</p><p>“Look, it’s still early days and new behaviours are being built,” he said. “We’re still learning new things, but have millions and millions of people using the new tools.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" class="image-inline caption" height="1257" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/751251ee-f99c-42e4-bf34-d1aa45378b12_882215d8.jpg" title="Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" width="2000" /><figcaption>Google CEO Sundar Pichai speaks onstage during a company event in May. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even as the Bing team adds crowd-pleasers, Google has been racing to develop its own AI tools.</p><p>In May, it launched an experimental version of its search engine called the “search generative experience”, which delivers conversational responses atop the familiar list of links. Dubbed SGE for short, it is still not widely available. However, Google plans to embed its most powerful large language model, Gemini, into SGE sometime this year.</p><p>The Alphabet division also retains considerable advantages. It has more than 90 per cent of the market and is the default search engine on Apple hardware, including iPhones, giving Google crucial critical mass. The more people who use it, the more the search engine knows and the more Google can use that data to deliver and rank results in a way people find useful.</p><p>The retooling of search by both technology giants reflects a shared conviction that generative AI will fundamentally change the way people seek and receive answers online.</p><p>For Microsoft, the shift is an opportunity to propel Bing forward. But the incremental gains so far make clear that buzzy AI features alone probably will not transform it into a formidable search player.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>“We are at the gold rush moment when it comes to AI and search,” said Shane Greenstein, an economist and professor at Harvard Business School, who has studied the commercialisation of the internet.</p><p>“At the moment, I doubt AI will move the needle because, in search, you need a flywheel: the more searches you have, the better answers are. Google is the only firm who has this dynamic well-established.”</p><p>Still, Greenstein said Bing, being the underdog, has more latitude to experiment. “Google has to be careful not to hurt its brand and product when it comes to testing new AI tools,” he said. “Bing can afford to take the risk. It has nothing to lose.”</p><p>Microsoft is also betting that generative AI will change how advertisers allocate their search spending. The current ad model rests on costs-per-click, but AI-powered searches are getting consumers to answers faster and more directly without a litany of blue links, according to marketing chief Mehdi.</p><p>“We have advertisers telling us they’re getting better outcomes as a result of our AI efforts and are deeply interested in how this works,” he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Reddit aims to launch IPO in March, sources say, in first stock market debut of a social media firm since 2019</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248999/reddit-aims-launch-ipo-march-sources-say-first-stock-market-debut-social-media-firm-2019</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Social media platform Reddit plans to launch its initial public offering (IPO) in March, seeking to sell about 10% of its shares.</li>    <li>The company aims to file its public documents in late February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March.</li>    <li>Reddit, valued at around US$10 billion in its 2021 funding round, has yet to turn a profit despite generating revenue primarily through advertising and premium access.</li>    <li>Factors such as investing in the platform, lower user engagement with advertising, market volatility, and competition from rivals like TikTok and Facebook have contributed to the company's delayed IPO plans.</li>    <li>The company expects to generate over US$800 million in advertising revenue in 2023, signaling a 20% increase from the previous year.</li>    <li>Reddit also intends to charge companies for accessing its application programming interface (API), a move that has sparked discontent among users reliant on third-party apps.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>社交媒体平台 Reddit 计划于 3 月份进行首次公开募股 (IPO)，拟出售约 10% 的股份。</li>    <li>该公司计划在 2 月底提交公开文件，3 月初启动路演，并于 3 月底完成 IPO。</li>    <li>Reddit 在 2021 年融资时估值约为 100 亿美元，尽管主要通过广告和高级访问权产生收入，但尚未实现盈利。</li>    <li>投资平台、用户对广告参与度较低、市场波动以及来自 TikTok 和 Facebook 等竞争对手的竞争等因素导致该公司推迟了 IPO 计划。</li>    <li>该公司预计 2023 年广告收入将超过 8 亿美元，较前一年增长 20% 以上。</li>    <li>Reddit 还打算对访问其应用程序编程接口 (API) 的公司收费，此举引发了依赖第三方应用程序的用户的不满。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li><strong>roadshow (n.)</strong> - /ˈroʊdʃəʊ/ （公司招股时举行的一系列）巡回宣传介绍。    <p>原文例句：Reddit is planning to make its public filing in February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March, sources say.</p>    <p>例句讲解：roadshow 是一个由 road 和 show 组成的复合词，意为“巡回宣传介绍”。在这个语境中，它特指公司在首次公开募股 (IPO) 前进行的一系列巡回宣传介绍活动，目的是向潜在投资者推介公司并吸引他们购买公司的股票。</p></li>    <li><strong>niche (n.)</strong> - /niːʃ/ 利基市场，壁龛。    <p>原文例句：Founded in 2005 by web developer Steve Huffman and entrepreneur Alexis Ohanian, Reddit became best known for its niche discussion groups and its users voting “up” or “down” on the content posted by other members.</p>    <p>例句讲解：niche 源自法语，意为“壁龛”。在这个语境中，niche 引申为“利基市场”。利基市场是指那些针对特定受众群体的市场，这些受众群体的需求往往比较特殊或小众，但对产品的要求也更高。Reddit 以其利基讨论组而闻名，这些讨论组针对特定主题，并允许用户对其他用户发布的内容进行“点赞”或“点踩”。</p></li>    </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li><strong>pull the IPO trigger</strong> - 启动 IPO。    <p>原文例句：The company held back from pulling the IPO trigger until it came closer to profitability.</p>    <p>例句讲解：pull the IPO trigger 是一个形象的比喻，意为“启动 IPO”。IPO 即首次公开募股，是指一家公司首次向公众出售其股票，以便筹集资金。pull the trigger 意为“扣动扳机”，而 IPO trigger 则喻指 IPO 的启动。在这个语境中，pull the IPO trigger 表示该公司推迟了启动 IPO 的计划，直到它更接近盈利的目标。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li><strong>Meta Platforms, which operates Facebook, have more than trebled in value over the past 12 months, while Snap’s shares rose 60 per cent over the same period.</strong> - 在过去的一年中，运营 Facebook 的 Meta Platforms 的价值增长了三倍以上，而同期 Snap 的股价上涨了 60%。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，由两个简单句组成。第一个简单句是 Meta Platforms, which operates Facebook, have more than trebled in value over the past 12 months，其中主语是 Meta Platforms, which operates Facebook，谓语是 have more than trebled in value，宾语是 over the past 12 months。第二个简单句是 while Snap’s shares rose 60 per cent over the same period，其中主语是 Snap’s shares，谓语是 rose，宾语是 60 per cent，介词短语 over the same period 表示“在同一时期”。这两个简单句用 while 连接，表示“一边……一边……”的关系。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li><strong>现在完成时 (Present Perfect Tense)</strong> - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Reddit has yet to turn a profit.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态是由 have/has + 过去分词构成的。have/has 的使用要根据主语的人称和数来确定。过去分词是由动词的词干加上相应的词尾 -ed 或 -en 构成的。现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，Reddit has yet to turn a profit 表示 Reddit 到目前为止还没有实现盈利，强调了 Reddit 一直处于亏损的状态。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Reddit is planning to make its public filing in February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March, sources say</li>
<li>The company, which generates its revenue primarily through advertising, has yet to turn a profit, co-founder Steve Huffman said last June</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/ceae1676-ec0a-453c-90b8-caa1d3c7da8a_ae468ee4.jpg" /><figcaption>Reddit is hoping to launch its IPO as soon as March, according to people familiar with the matter. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Social media platform Reddit has drawn up detailed plans to launch its initial public offering (IPO) in March, moving forward with a listing it has been eyeing for more than three years, according to people familiar with the matter.</p><p>It would be the first IPO of a major social media company since Pinterest’s debut in 2019, and would come as Reddit and its peers face stiff competition for advertising dollars from the likes of TikTok and Facebook.</p><p>The offering would also test the willingness of some Reddit users to back the company’s stock market debut. Many investors posting on the platform have helped fuel dozens of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3119536/gamestop-frenzy-how-reddit-nerds-sparked-wall" target="_self" title="">“meme” stock rallies</a> in the last three years, from retailer GameStop to movie operator AMC Entertainment Holdings.</p><p>Reddit, which filed confidentially for its IPO in December 2021, is planning to make its public filing in late February, launch its roadshow in early March, and complete the IPO by the end of March, two of the sources said.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP" class="image-inline caption" height="2581" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/a63256c8-0f58-4d2a-92c3-f97df71b18ee_a6b611e2.jpg" title="Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP" width="2000" /><figcaption>Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian with his wife, tennis star Serena Williams, in 2022. Photo: Invision/AP</figcaption></figure></div><p>The San Francisco-based company, which was valued at about US$10 billion in a funding round in 2021, is seeking to sell about 10 per cent of its shares in the IPO, the sources added. It will decide on what IPO valuation it will pursue closer to the time of the listing, according to the sources.</p><p>The sources cautioned that Reddit’s IPO plans could be pushed back, as has happened in the past, and asked not to be identified discussing confidential deliberations.</p><p>A Reddit spokesperson declined to comment.</p><p>Founded in 2005 by web developer Steve Huffman and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/apps-social/article/3087871/reddit-co-founder-alexis-ohanian-resigns-urges-black-board" target="_self" title="">entrepreneur Alexis Ohanian</a>, Reddit became best known for its niche discussion groups and its users voting “up” or “down” on the content posted by other members.</p><p>The company, which generates its revenue primarily through advertising and also offers premium access for US$5.99 per month, has yet to turn a profit, Huffman said in a Reddit post last June.</p><p>In the past, the company has attributed its losses to investing in the platform and its users engaging less with advertising on its site than other social media.</p><p>The company held back from pulling the IPO trigger until it came closer to profitability. Bouts of market volatility that shut down the IPO market for much of the last two years also contributed to it delaying its plans.</p><p>Reddit expected to generate slightly over US$800 million in advertising revenue in 2023, up more than 20 per cent from a year earlier, The Information reported last month.</p><p>Reddit said last year it would charge companies for access to its application programming interface, which is used by technology companies to train <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">large-language models used in artificial intelligence</a>. The move upset some users who rely on third-party apps to access Reddit.</p><p>Large social media stocks have rebounded over the past year, driven mainly by a rally in technology stocks as interest rates peaked. Shares of Meta Platforms, which operates Facebook, have more than trebled in value over the past 12 months, while Snap’s shares rose 60 per cent over the same period.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China remains a tough market to stage a comeback for world’s former top smartphone vendor Samsung</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248969/china-remains-tough-market-stage-comeback-worlds-former-top-smartphone-vendor-samsung</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland China smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets.</li>    <li>The fall of Samsung in China's smartphone market was due to inappropriate operations and increased competition from Chinese vendors.</li>    <li>Samsung has been trying to stage a comeback in China, but the ongoing US-China tech war and its relocation of factories have posed challenges.</li>    <li>Samsung's recent focus on the premium segment has attracted new users, but the overall outlook in China is complicated by various factors.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>三星已将重心转向中国大陆智能手机市场的细分高端市场，尤其是其可折叠手机。</li>    <li>三星在中国智能手机市场的地位下降，原因在于其运营不当以及中国供应商竞争加剧。</li>    <li>三星一直在尝试在中国市场复出，但持续的中美科技战及其工厂的搬迁带来了挑战。</li>    <li>三星最近专注于高端市场吸引了新用户，但其在中国市场的整体前景因各种因素而变得复杂。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>segment (n.) - /ˈsɛɡmənt/ 部分，节段。      <p>原文例句：Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland’s smartphone market.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Segment在这里表示“部分，节段”，指代高端智能手机市场。</p>    </li>    <li>devastating (adj.) - /ˈdɛvəsteɪtɪŋ/ 毁灭性的，破坏性的。      <p>原文例句：The harm to Samsung’s image was devastating.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Devastating在这里表示“毁灭性的，破坏性的”，指代三星的形象遭受的破坏。</p>    </li>    <li>localisation (n.) - /ˈləʊkəlaɪzeɪʃən/ 本地化，在地化。      <p>原文例句：Samsung has been working with some Chinese Big Tech companies，including Baidu and Tencent Holdings，to help step up localisation of its smartphones’ content ecosystem.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Localisation在这里表示“本地化，在地化”，指代三星与中国科技巨头合作，帮助其智能手机内容生态系统更加本地化。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>be unseated by - 被取代，被赶下台。      <p>原文例句：Samsung, which was unseated by Apple in terms of annual smartphone shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Be unseated by在这里表示“被取代，被赶下台”，指代三星在2023年首次被苹果在全球年度智能手机出货量方面赶超。</p>    </li>    <li>cast a shadow over - 笼罩，对……产生负面影响。      <p>原文例句：The ongoing US-China tech war has cast a shadow over the Korean firm’s supply chain network on the mainland.</p>      <p>例句讲解：Cast a shadow over在这里表示“笼罩，对……产生负面影响”，指代持续的中美科技战对三星在中国大陆的供应链网络产生了负面影响。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy Z Fold5 and Z Flip5 3D foldable smartphone displays are seen at the company’s flagship store in Shanghai on October 23, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock - 三星电子Galaxy Z Fold5和Z Flip5 3D可折叠智能手机的展示于2023年10月23日在上海的公司旗舰店举行。照片：Shutterstock</li>      <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy Z Fold5 and Z Flip5 3D foldable smartphone displays，谓语是are seen，宾语是at the company’s flagship store in Shanghai on October 23, 2023。这个句子简单介绍了三星电子Galaxy Z Fold5和Z Flip5 3D可折叠智能手机的展示情况。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>不定式短语 - 表示目的或原因。      <p>原文例句：Samsung has been working with some Chinese Big Tech companies, including Baidu and Tencent Holdings, to help step up localisation of its smartphones’ content ecosystem.</p>      <p>语法讲解：不定式短语是由不定式（to + 动词原形）构成的，它在句中充当状语，表示目的或原因。在这个例句中，不定式短语to help step up localisation of its smartphones’ content ecosystem表示三星与中国科技巨头合作的目的是帮助其智能手机内容生态系统更加本地化。</p>    </li>    <li>分词短语 - 表示动作或状态。      <p>原文例句：The relocation of Samsung’s factories from the mainland showed how the company “strategically deprioritised the Chinese market, resulting in reduced investment in brand and channel building”.</p>      <p>语法讲解：分词短语是由分词（现在分词或过去分词）+ 宾语或补语构成的，它在句中充当定语或状语，表示动作或状态。在这个例句中，分词短语The relocation of Samsung’s factories from the mainland表示三星将工厂从中国大陆迁出的动作，它作主语修饰整个句子。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end segment of the mainland’s smartphone market, particularly with its foldable handsets</li>
<li>The company has closed various production bases in China, including its last smartphone plant in Huizhou and last personal computer factory in Suzhou</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/bf4f1a5f-c528-4f08-b9c2-588ca952e7dd_16946b13.jpg" /><figcaption>Samsung Electronics’ Galaxy Z Fold5 and Z Flip5 3D foldable smartphone displays are seen at the company’s flagship store in Shanghai on October 23, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>A resident of eastern Jiangsu province, 48-year-old Shen Ling used to own a number of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphones</a> in the 2010s, attracted by the devices’ well-designed appearance and popularity among consumers across mainland China.</p><p>“It was once an age of glory for Samsung in China, when so many of my friends were using the brand for its high-end market standing,” Shen said. “I also chose to buy a Samsung phone at that time for the same reason.”</p><p>But Samsung’s strong run in the world’s largest smartphone market took a disastrous turn in late 2016, when the company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/enterprises/article/2027114/samsung-permanently-shuts-note-7-production" target="_self" title="">permanently halted production of its Galaxy Note 7 handset</a> amid increased concerns about the device catching fire. That followed widespread criticism from Chinese consumers after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/2023711/samsung-insists-note-7-china-safe-after-6th-reported-battery-explosion" target="_self" title="">several incidents where the handset’s battery exploded</a>. In January 2017, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korean</a> electronics giant admitted that those incidents were <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/2064560/samsungs-galaxy-note-7-fires-caused-battery-design-manufacturing-issues" target="_self" title="">caused by battery manufacturing and design issues</a> after an internal investigation.</p><p>“The harm to Samsung’s image was devastating,” Shen said. “It made me unsure if I could trust the quality of its future handsets.” Shen finally decided to switch to a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> smartphone in 2020.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/08229e1a-0baf-487d-a0d0-871525d20f84_5b21820d.jpg" title="A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Hong Kong-based Galaxy Note 7 smartphone user claimed in this Facebook post on September 19, 2016, that the device’s battery exploded when it was being charged. Photo: Facebook</figcaption></figure></div><p>Samsung was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/social-gadgets/article/2134770/how-samsung-went-no-1-also-ran-chinas-smartphone-market-and-can" target="_self" title="">once the biggest smartphone vendor on the mainland</a>, with a market share of about 20 per cent in 2013. The Korean firm ranked dead last among the market’s major handset vendors by 2018, with just a 1 per cent share and has since remained around that level.</p><p>The company’s fall in mainland China’s smartphone market was partly due to “a combination of inappropriate operations leading to a damaged reputation”, said Ivan Lam, a senior analyst for Counterpoint Research. He also indicated that major Chinese vendors – including Huawei, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/vivo" target="_self" title="">Vivo</a> – rose to become strong domestic and international competitors.</p><p>But Samsung, which was unseated by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> in terms of annual smartphone shipments worldwide <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above?utm_source=rss_feed" target="_self" title="">for the first time in 2023</a>, still has ambitions to return to its former glory on the mainland.</p><p>While Huawei has largely retreated from the Korean market primarily because of local consumers’ loyalty to homegrown Android handsets, Samsung is slowly trying to stage a comeback in China. Still, Samsung’s mission has become more difficult amid the mainland’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3248694/china-gdp-beijings-long-do-list-boost-economy-2024" target="_self" title="">shaky post-pandemic economic recovery</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>“Samsung has shifted its focus to the high-end market in China, particularly with the introduction of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foldable-phones" target="_self" title="">foldable models</a>,” Counterpoint’s Lam said. “The current strategy for Samsung in China appears to be characterised by conservatism, stability and continuity.”</p><p>Over the past few years, Samsung continued to launch new smartphone models on the mainland. It has also been working with some Chinese Big Tech companies, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>, to help step up localisation of its smartphones’ content ecosystem.</p><p>The reason Samsung did not fully leave mainland China was obvious: the country remains the world’s largest computing, smartphone, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> market. Continued operation in the vast market has become more important for the Korean conglomerate, as its sales have been hit hard by sluggish global consumer electronics demand.</p><p>In its earnings guidance released last week, Samsung said it expected to post its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" target="_self" title="">sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit</a>. The company estimated that its operating earnings for 2023 plunged 84.9 per cent year on year to 6.54 trillion won (US$4.86 billion), while annual revenue was expected to drop 14.6 per cent to 258.16 trillion won.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists" title="">Samsung profit tumbles 35% as chip weakness persists</a></h3><p>Samsung’s sharpened focus on the premium segment of China’s smartphone market has managed to attract a growing number of new users. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a> university student Cynthia Xia, for example, started using Samsung’s foldable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3192963/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-4-vs-motorola-razr-foldable-smartphones" target="_self" title="">Galaxy Z Flip 4</a> smartphone in 2022.</p><p>“I was totally attracted by the design and its flexibility to adopt customised settings,” Xia said. “I think no other brands are doing as well as Samsung in foldable phones.”</p><p>Still, Samsung’s outlook in the world’s second-largest economy is complicated by the ongoing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/us-china-tech-war-rivalry/news" target="_self" title="">US-China tech war</a>, which has cast a shadow over the Korean firm’s supply chain network on the mainland.</p><p>Although Samsung, along with memory chip rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3218776/south-korean-chip-maker-sk-hynix-denies-reports-it-selling-firms-dalian-flash-memory-fab-assuring" target="_self" title="">SK Hynix</a>, last year secured indefinite waivers from Washington to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3237485/tech-war-us-waiver-china-export-restrictions-advanced-semiconductor-equipment-south-koreas-samsung" target="_self" title="">ship advanced semiconductor-manufacturing equipment</a> for their China plants, the tech conglomerate has been downsizing its production facilities and number of employees in the country.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3014564/samsungs-last-china-smartphone-factory-closing-raising" title="">Will closing last Samsung smartphone factory hurt China’s role in global value chain?</a></h3><p>Over the past several years, Samsung has shut down multiple production bases on the mainland, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3014564/samsungs-last-china-smartphone-factory-closing-raising" target="_self" title="">its last smartphone plant</a> in Huizhou, a city in southern Guangdong province, and last personal computer factory in Suzhou, a bustling metropolis in Jiangsu. The company had 17,891 employees on the mainland in 2022, which was in stark contrast to its peak of 63,316 in 2013, according to Samsung’s Sustainability Report.</p><p>The relocation of Samsung’s factories from the mainland showed how the company “strategically deprioritised the Chinese market, resulting in reduced investment in brand and channel building”, Counterpoint’s Lam said.</p><p>With Samsung’s recently launched <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248863/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-smartphones-come-google-gemini-ai-technology-fight-apple-iphones" target="_self" title="">Galaxy 24 series, which features artificial intelligence technology</a>, all eyes are on how the company can help revive and bring change to the global smartphone market.</p><p>Still, that new handset is not expected to make a big splash on the mainland.</p><p>“None of my friends are using Samsung’s phones nowadays, so why wouldn’t I stick with domestic brands when they offer similar functionalities at lower prices?” Shen from Jiangsu said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei releases preview version of updated HarmonyOS Next as it accelerates shift away from Android</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248956/huawei-releases-preview-version-updated-harmonyos-next-it-accelerates-shift-away-android</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Huawei's latest homegrown mobile operating system, HarmonyOS Next, is now available for developers. This advanced version will replace Android-based applications and aims to attract 5,000 partners by 2024. Huawei invests heavily in ecosystem development, including collaborating with companies and educational institutions. The adoption of HarmonyOS has seen steady growth, currently running on over 800 million devices. Despite US sanctions, HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple's iOS in China this year, positioning Huawei as a strong competitor in the market.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei unveils HarmonyOS Next, aiming to challenge Android and iOS.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's HarmonyOS Next targets a robust ecosystem and aims to become a major player in the Chinese mobile operating system market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Huawei's investment and collaboration strategy for HarmonyOS's growth and its potential to disrupt the mobile OS market.</li>    <li>Main information: HarmonyOS Next developer preview release; target to support native apps and attract partners; investment in ecosystem development; current adoption and growth.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  华为自主研发的最新移动操作系统HarmonyOS Next现已面向开发者开放。该版本将取代安卓基于的应用程序，并计划在2024年底前吸引5000个合作伙伴。华为在生态系统建设上大举投资，包括与公司和教育机构的合作。HarmonyOS的采用量不断增长，目前已在超过8亿台设备上运行。尽管受到美国制裁，HarmonyOS预计今年将在中国超越苹果iOS，成为第二大操作系统，使华为在市场上成为强劲的竞争对手。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为发布HarmonyOS Next，旨在挑战安卓和iOS。</li>    <li>主题：华为HarmonyOS Next目标建立一个强大的生态系统，并旨在成为中国移动操作系统市场的主要参与者。</li>    <li>观点：华为为HarmonyOS的增长而进行的投资和合作策略，以及其颠覆移动操作系统市场的潜力。</li>    <li>主要信息：HarmonyOS Next开发者预览版发布；支持原生应用程序并吸引合作伙伴的目标；对生态系统发展的投资；目前的采用量和增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>mobile operating system - 移动操作系统    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies has unveiled the latest version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS for developers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Mobile operating system”指的是一种专门为移动设备（如智能手机和平板电脑）设计的操作系统。它负责协调和管理移动设备中的各种硬件和软件，为用户提供图形界面、应用程序管理、文件管理、网络连接、安全等功能。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>native app - 原生应用    <p>原文例句：Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native apps for HarmonyOS.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Native app”指的是专门为某个平台（如iOS或Android）开发的应用程序。这种应用程序使用该平台的原生编程语言和应用程序接口（API）进行开发，因此可以充分利用该平台的特性和功能，提供更好的性能和用户体验。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take on - 挑战，竞争。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies has unveiled the latest version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS for developers, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant takes on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Take on”在这里表示“挑战，竞争”的意思。它通常用于描述一个公司或个人与另一个公司或个人进行竞争的情况。在这个例句中，华为正在挑战谷歌的Android和苹果的iOS这两个在全球移动操作系统市场上占主导地位的系统。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights - 据TechInsights报道，华为HarmonyOS有望在2024年超过苹果iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024，其中主语是Huawei’s HarmonyOS，谓语是tipped to beat，宾语是Apple’s iOS。据TechInsights报道是一个介词短语作状语，表示消息来源，修饰谓语tipped to beat。这个句子的意思是说，据TechInsights报道，华为HarmonyOS有望在2024年超过苹果iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作状语 - 表示时间、原因、方式等情况。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies has unveiled the latest version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS for developers, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant takes on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去分词短语作状语，由as引出，表示时间。它修饰主句Huawei Technologies has unveiled the latest version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS for developers，表示华为推出HarmonyOS的最新版本是为了挑战谷歌的Android和苹果的iOS。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作宾语补足语 - 表示主语的动作或状态对宾语的影响或结果。    <p>原文例句：The company aims to get 5,000 partners on board by the end of 2024, Zhu Yonggang, president of Huawei Consumer Business Cloud Services, said at the Thursday event.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在分词短语作宾语补足语，由on board引出，表示主语The company的动作对宾语partners的影响或结果。它修饰宾语partners，表示该公司希望在2024年底前让5000个合作伙伴加入。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday</li>
<li>Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native apps for HarmonyOS</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/f12f9442-2dd3-4de3-a881-63405dd3a097_26cc2667.jpg" /><figcaption>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has unveiled the latest version of its home-grown mobile operating system HarmonyOS for developers, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant takes on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p><p>The developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next was made available to coders on Thursday, and the operating system will be launched for commercial use in the fourth quarter of this year, Huawei said at its developer conference.</p><p>HarmonyOS Next, billed as a major upgrade to Huawei’s mobile platform, will no longer support Android-based applications.</p><p>Over 200 industry partners have initiated the development of native HarmonyOS apps, and the company aims to get 5,000 partners on board by the end of 2024, Zhu Yonggang, president of Huawei Consumer Business Cloud Services, said at the Thursday event.</p><p>Meituan, the delivery services giant, has already finished the first version of its HarmonyOS app in the first batch of development partners, while other internet firms, such as lifestyle social media platform Xiaohongshu and online mapping service Amap, have also made progress.</p><p>Amap is backed by Alibaba Group Holding, the Post’s owner.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" title="">Huawei’s HarmonyOS tipped to beat Apple’s iOS in China in 2024: TechInsights</a></h3><p>To encourage development of a more robust ecosystem for HarmonyOS, Huawei will also work with more than 280 companies and over 300 educational institutions to cultivate developers for the operating system, according to a company release.</p><p>Huawei will also invest 7 billion yuan (US$983 million) to support innovation in areas from HarmonyOS native apps to Software Development Kit (SDK), a toolset used to help developers build apps for a particular platform, according to posts published on HarmonyOS’s official Weibo account.</p><p>The adoption of HarmonyOS has been growing. Since its launch in August 2019, HarmonyOS currently runs on over 800 million devices, according to Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group, speaking at the Thursday event.</p><p>HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List. Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>Driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment with its P60 Pro model, HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year, according to a report by TechInsights earlier this month.</p><p><em>Additional reporting by Ben Jiang</em></p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sheryl Sandberg, who helped turn Facebook into digital advertising empire, to leave company board</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248977/sheryl-sandberg-who-helped-turn-facebook-digital-advertising-empire-leave-company-board</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Sherryl Sandberg, Meta's former COO and a key figure in the company's growth, announced her resignation from the company's board. Sandberg joined Meta, then known as Facebook, in 2008 and played a significant role in its transformation into a digital advertising giant. Despite her contributions, she also faced criticism for the company's missteps. She stepped down as COO in 2022 but remained on the board. Sandberg expressed confidence in Meta's future under CEO Mark Zuckerberg and his team and stated that she will continue to serve as an advisor to the company.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Sheryl Sandberg, a prominent executive at Meta, announces her resignation from the company's board.</li>    <li>Theme: Sandberg's departure from Meta marks the end of an era, as she was instrumental in the company's growth and success.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Sandberg's resignation highlights the changing dynamics at Meta and the challenges facing the tech giant.</li>    <li>Main information: Sandberg's tenure at Meta, her contributions to the company's success, criticism she faced, her decision to step down, and her plans for the future.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  谢丽尔·桑德伯格，Meta的前首席运营官，也是公司发展中的关键人物，宣布辞去公司董事职务。桑德伯格于2008年加入Meta，当时的公司名为Facebook，她在将公司转型为数字广告巨头方面发挥了重要作用。尽管她做出了贡献，但她还因公司的失误而受到批评。她在2022年辞去了首席运营官的职务，但仍留在董事会。桑德伯格对公司在首席执行官马克·扎克伯格及其团队的领导下充满信心，并表示她将继续担任公司的顾问。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Meta的著名高管谢丽尔·桑德伯格宣布辞去公司董事会职务。</li>    <li>主题：桑德伯格离开Meta标志着一个时代的结束，因为她在公司发展和成功中发挥了作用。</li>    <li>观点：桑德伯格的辞职凸显了Meta的动态变化以及科技巨头面临的挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：桑德伯格在Meta的任期、她对公司成功的贡献、她面临的批评、她决定辞职以及她未来的计划。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>curriculum (n.) — 教学大纲。    <p>原文例句：The programme includes a middle-school curriculum as well as resources for adults.</p>    <p>例句讲解：curriculum源自拉丁语中“跑步”的含义，后指“赛程”。在此句中表示中小学的教学大纲、课程。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>stepping down — 辞去职务。    <p>原文例句：Sheryl Sandberg on Thursday announced that she is stepping down from the board of Meta.</p>    <p>例句讲解：stepping down是一个动词短语，意为“辞去职务，下台”。由step（台阶）和down（向下）组成，动词step down有“下台，辞去职务”的意思。在此句中，stepping down指谢丽尔·桑德伯格辞去Meta董事会职务。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>tech start-up — 科技初创公司    <P>原文例句：Sheryl Sandberg, who helped to transform Facebook from a tech start-up into a digital advertising empire, will step down from the board of Meta, Facebook’s parent company.</P>    <p>例句讲解：tech start-up是一个词组，意为“科技初创公司”。由tech（技术）和start-up（初创）组成，tech start-up指利用新技术或新商业模式创立的初创公司。在此句中，tech start-up指Facebook在创立初期是一家科技初创公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Sandberg said she will continue to serve as an adviser to Meta. - 桑德伯格表示将继续担任Meta的顾问。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单的陈述句，主语是Sandberg，谓语是said，宾语是she will continue to serve as an adviser to Meta。其中，continue to serve是动词不定式的进行时态，表示持续不断的动作。an adviser to Meta是一个介词短语，作serve的宾语补足语，说明桑德伯格担任Meta的顾问这一职务。这个句子的意思是说，桑德伯格表示将继续担任Meta的顾问。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Sandberg had served as COO of Facebook, and then Meta, for 14-and-a-half years and as a board member for 12 years. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示桑德伯格在Facebook和Meta担任首席运营官已有14年半，担任董事会成员已有12年。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示说话人的态度或想象中的情况。    <p>原文例句：“Under Mark’s leadership, Javi Olivan, Justin Osofsky, Nicola Mendelsohn and their teams have proven beyond a doubt that the Meta business is strong and well-positioned for the future, so this feels like the right time to step away,” Sandberg wrote.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的语气，结构是：should/would/could/might + 动词原形。这种语气表示说话人的态度、愿望、建议、想象等，并不一定符合事实。在这个例句中，它表示桑德伯格认为在马克·扎克伯格的领导下，Meta的业务很强劲，并且为未来做好了准备，所以现在是辞去职务的合适时机。这个句子表达了桑德伯格对Meta未来的信心和对马克·扎克伯格的信任。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Sandberg left Google to join Facebook in 2008, 4 years before the company went public and was the number 2 executive at Meta under CEO Mark Zuckerberg</li>
<li>She stepped down as COO of Meta in 2022 but remained a member of the company board. Sandberg said she will continue to serve as an adviser to Meta</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/19/d30b61be-bbea-4726-8b0d-53c086bdcd8c_20c6fc3d.jpg" /><figcaption>Sheryl Sandberg on Thursday announced she is stepping down from the board of Meta. Photo: Reuters </figcaption></figure><p>Sheryl Sandberg, who helped to transform Facebook from a tech start-up into a digital advertising empire, will step down from the board of Meta, Facebook’s parent company.</p><p>“With a heart filled with gratitude and a mind filled with memories, I let the Meta board know that I will not stand for re-election this May,” Sandberg wrote in a Facebook post.</p><p>Sandberg left <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/google" target="_self" title="">Google</a> to join <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/facebook" target="_self" title="">Facebook</a> in 2008, four years before the company went public. As the number two executive at Meta under CEO <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mark-zuckerberg" target="_self" title="">Mark Zuckerberg</a>, Sandberg also took a lot of heat for some of its biggest missteps.</p><p>She stepped down as chief operating officer of Meta in 2022 but remained a member of the company board. She had served as COO of Facebook, and then Meta, for 14-and-a-half years and as a board member for 12 years.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3180106/key-facebook-force-sheryl-sandberg-stepping-down" title="">Key Facebook force Sheryl Sandberg stepping down</a></h3><p>“Under Mark’s leadership, Javi Olivan, Justin Osofsky, Nicola Mendelsohn and their teams have proven beyond a doubt that the Meta business is strong and well-positioned for the future, so this feels like the right time to step away,” Sandberg wrote.</p><p>Sandberg said she will continue to serve as an adviser to the company.</p><p>Last year Sandberg announced that she was launching a girls’ leadership programme through her foundation to respond to what she calls stubborn gender inequities. The programme includes a middle-school curriculum as well as resources for adults.</p><p>Lean In is a project of the Sandberg Goldberg Bernthal Family Foundation, the private foundation Sandberg started with her late husband, Dave Goldberg.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese state media calls for crackdown on deceptive pricing in live-streaming e-commerce</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248938/chinese-state-media-calls-crackdown-deceptive-pricing-live-streaming-e-commerce</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Economic Daily, a Chinese state-owned media outlet, called for stricter regulation of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming e-commerce, as tactics like fake price comparisons and fabricating original prices are seen as price fraud. The article emphasized that these practices harm consumer rights and hinder the sustainable development of the sector.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Economic Daily demands stricter regulation of deceptive pricing in live streaming e-commerce.</li>    <li>Theme: Growing concerns over deceptive pricing tactics in China's live streaming e-commerce sector.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The need for better regulations to safeguard consumer rights and promote healthy growth of the industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Tactics like fake price comparisons and marking up original prices; negative impact on consumer rights and reputation of the industry; call for improved regulations, increased penalties, and clarification of responsibilities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国官媒《经济日报》呼吁对直播电商领域价格欺诈问题加强监管力度，打击虚假价格比较、虚构原价等价格欺诈行为。文章指出，此类做法损害了消费者的合法权益，阻碍了行业的高质量发展。  <ul>    <li>摘要：针对直播电商价格欺诈问题，《经济日报》发声。</li>    <li>主题：治理中国直播电商领域价格欺诈现象。</li>    <li>观点：需要加强监管，维护消费者权益，促进行业健康发展。</li>    <li>主要信息：虚假价格对比、虚构原价等欺诈行为；损害消费者权益、影响平台信誉；呼吁加强监管、提高处罚力度、明确各主体责任。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>deceptive (adj.) - /dɪˈsɛptɪv/ 欺骗性的，误导性的。    <p>原文例句：Economic Daily, a Chinese state media outlet, called for stricter regulation of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming e-commerce. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由de-（从，离开）和capio（抓住，夺取）组成，意为“抓住，欺骗”。在这个例句中，它描述了经济日报呼吁对直播电商领域欺骗性的价格欺诈行为加强监管。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fraudulent (adj.) - /frɔːdʒʊlənt/ 欺骗性的，诈骗性的。    <p>原文例句：Last month People’s Daily, the chief mouthpiece of the Chinese Communist Party, called for tighter oversight of live-streaming e-commerce. The paper said misconduct in the live-streaming industry, from fraudulent advertising to misleading pricing, should be addressed and punished for the sake of the sector’s healthy and sustained growth.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于French，意思是“欺骗性的，诈骗性的”。在这个例句中，它描述了人民日报呼吁对直播电商领域的欺诈性行为进行更严格的监管。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>at the sake of - 以……为代价，为了……的利益牺牲。    <P>原文例句：Last month People’s Daily, the chief mouthpiece of the Chinese Communist Party, called for tighter oversight of live-streaming e-commerce. The paper said misconduct in the live-streaming industry, from fraudulent advertising to misleading pricing, should be addressed and punished for the sake of the sector’s healthy and sustained growth.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由at（位于），the sake of（利益，目的）组成，表示“以……为代价，为了……的利益牺牲”。在这个例句中，它表示直播电商行业的不端行为应该得到解决和惩罚，其目的是为了行业的健康和可持续增长。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission. - 虚构或抬高原价，提供虚假折扣的行为被视为价格欺诈，文章援引中国发改委的规定称。<p>句子分析：这是一个并列句，由Fabricating or marking up the original price和offering fake discounts组成，其中Fabricating or marking up the original price是主语，offering fake discounts是谓语。are seen as price fraud是一个现在完成时态的被动语态，表示价格欺诈行为被视为价格欺诈，as price fraud作状语，表示价格欺诈行为的性质或特征。the article said作状语，表示这篇文章中的内容或观点。citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰rules，表示文章引用了中国发改委的规定。这个句子的意思是说，虚构或抬高原价，提供虚假折扣的行为被视为价格欺诈，文章援引了中国发改委的规定。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>并列句 - 表示两个或多个句子并列排列，有连接词相连。    <p>原文例句：Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个并列句，由Fabricating or marking up the original price和offering fake discounts组成，其中Fabricating or marking up the original price是主语，offering fake discounts是谓语。are seen as price fraud是一个现在完成时态的被动语态，表示价格欺诈行为被视为价格欺诈，as price fraud作状语，表示价格欺诈行为的性质或特征。the article said作状语，表示这篇文章中的内容或观点。citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰rules，表示文章引用了中国发改委的规定。这个句子的意思是说，虚构或抬高原价，提供虚假折扣的行为被视为价格欺诈，文章援引了中国发改委的规定。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时态 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The Economic Daily urged the government to improve regulations for the sector and increase the penalties for price fraud. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示经济日报敦促政府改善法规，提高对价格欺诈的处罚，从过去到现在一直持续着。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission</li>
<li>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years, with sales jumping 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/da9d4337-120c-49ea-b242-d1f49b587f18_9b05dbbb.jpg" /><figcaption>TikTok Shop and an online influencer prepare for a live-streaming session of selling goods from the Consumer Electronics Show (CES), Las Vegas, January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese state media Economic Daily has called for tighter regulatory scrutiny of deceptive pricing tactics in live streaming, as the country’s e-commerce players increasingly turn to these campaigns to lure customers and drive sales amid fierce competition and macro-economic headwinds.</p><p>In an opinion piece on Thursday, the official media blasted some live streamers for misleading consumers with tactics such as fake price comparisons and exaggerations, adding that more than 5,000 broadcasters were penalised last year for price manipulation.</p><p>Fabricating or marking up the original price and offering fake discounts are seen as price fraud, the article said, citing rules by China’s Development and Reform Commission.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247160/bytedances-douyin-makes-instant-refunds-mandatory-following-pdd-taobao-and-jdcom-amid-fierce-e" title="">Chinese version of TikTok makes instant refunds mandatory amid e-commerce rivalry</a></h3><p>“Live-streaming e-commerce has become an important part of the digital economy, but price fraud and other chaotic practices have hindered the high-quality development of the economy,” the article said. These tactics not only hurt consumers’ rights but also damaged the reputation of the live-streaming industry, it added.</p><p>The Economic Daily urged the government to improve regulations for the sector and increase the penalties for price fraud. The responsibilities of e-commerce platforms, merchants and broadcasters should be clarified in these cases, the media outlet said.</p><p>E-commerce platforms need to take the initiative to crack down on dubious live-streaming practices, the article urged, and they should impose harsher penalties and even ban those that repeatedly commit violations.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above" title="">Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with broad iPhone discounts</a></h3><p>The call for stricter oversight comes as e-commerce platforms are increasingly relying on live streaming to attract consumers amid fierce domestic competition and weaker consumer spending.</p><p>Key players in the field include traditional e-commerce platforms such as Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao, as well as short video apps like ByteDance’s Douyin and Kuaishou Technology. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Live-streaming e-commerce has seen exponential growth in recent years. Sales in the sector jumped 58.9 per cent year on year in the first 10 months of 2023, reaching 2.2 trillion yuan (US$311 billion), accounting for 18.1 per cent of all online shopping in China, according to data from the Ministry of Commerce.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1309" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/754d97a1-4883-40b6-b755-d027eb815bcf_113d2948.jpg" title="A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>A screen grab of a live-streaming session on the Joyy platform. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>However, the rapid growth has invited increasing regulatory attention. In April 2021, the Cyberspace Administration of China and six other regulators jointly released rules aimed at curbing malpractice such as selling fake products, falsifying view numbers and promoting pyramid schemes.</p><p>Last month People’s Daily, the chief mouthpiece of the Chinese Communist Party, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3243239/peoples-daily-calls-tighter-control-live-streaming-e-commerce-china-controversies-mount" target="_self" title="">called for tighter oversight of live-streaming e-commerce</a>. The paper said misconduct in the live-streaming industry, from fraudulent advertising to misleading pricing, should be addressed and punished for the sake of the sector’s healthy and sustained growth.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>TikTok owner ByteDance looks to expand in US, Canada and Australia amid rising competition and political headwinds</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248932/tiktok-owner-bytedance-looks-expand-us-canada-and-australia-amid-rising-competition-and-political</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  ByteDance, owner of TikTok, aims to grow its business operations in the United States, Canada, and Australia. The company is seeking to hire tech talent and transfer existing employees to these locations. The expansion aims to meet increased competition and political challenges, with TikTok’s active users surpassing 1 billion. ByteDance is also focusing on e-commerce, setting a target to increase its US shopping division's revenue tenfold this year. In 2023, the company’s revenue increased by around 30%, exceeding projected growth for rivals Meta and Tencent.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: ByteDance expands operations globally, focusing on tech talent acquisition and e-commerce growth.</li>    <li>Theme: ByteDance's strategic expansion to strengthen its position in the face of rising competition.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The company's focus on global growth and diversification to mitigate political and competitive risks.</li>    <li>Main information: Hiring tech experts, reassigning employees, setting revenue targets, and outpacing competitors' growth.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  TikTok 所有者字节跳动寻求在美国、加拿大和澳大利亚扩展其业务运营。该公司正在寻求招聘科技人才并将现有员工调动到这些地方。此次扩张旨在应对日益激烈的竞争和政治挑战，TikTok 的活跃用户已超过 10 亿。字节跳动还专注于电子商务，设定了今年将美国购物部门收入增加十倍至 175 亿美元的目标。 2023 年，该公司收入增长约 30%，超过了对竞争对手 Meta 和腾讯预期的增长。  <ul>    <li>摘要：字节跳动在全球范围内扩展业务，专注于科技人才招募和电子商务增长。</li>    <li>主题：字节跳动在竞争日益激烈的局面下加强自身地位的战略扩张。</li>    <li>观点：该公司专注于全球增长和多元化，以降低政治和竞争风险。</li>    <li>主要信息：招聘科技专家、重新分配员工、设定营收目标并超过竞争对手的增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.əˌnuː/ 收入，营业额。<p>原文例句：The company’s overall revenue expanded around 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing projected growth at Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings, according to a December Bloomberg report.</p><p>例句讲解：revenue 是一个名词，意思是“收入，营业额”。在这个句子中，它指的是字节跳动在 2023 年的总收入增长了约 30%，超过了对 Meta Platforms 和腾讯控股的预期增长。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>outpace (v.) - /ˌaʊtˈpeɪs/ 超过，胜过。    <p>原文例句：The company’s overall revenue expanded around 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing projected growth at Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings, according to a December Bloomberg report.</p>    <p>例句讲解：outpace 是一个动词，意思是“超过，胜过”。在这个句子中，它指的是字节跳动的整体收入增长超过了对其他公司的预期增长。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>gross merchandise volume - 商品交易总额    <P>原文例句：It has set an ambitious target for its US shopping operation to increase tenfold to US$17.5 billion in gross merchandise volume this year, according to a Bloomberg report. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由gross（总计的，全部的），merchandise（商品），volume（数量，容量）构成的，表示“商品交易总额”。在这个例句中，它指的是字节跳动为其美国购物业务设定的目标，即今年的商品交易总额要增长十倍，达到 175 亿美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations. – 字节跳动还将现有员工从其他地区调动到一些新地点。<p>句子分析：这是一个主动语态、一般现在时的句子。主语是ByteDance，谓语是is transferring，宾语是existing employees。from other regions是一个介词短语，表示“从其他地区”，to some of the new locations是一个介词短语，表示“到一些新地点”。这个句子的意思是说，字节跳动还将现有员工从其他地区调动到一些新地点。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作的承受者。    <p>原文例句：Its flagship app TikTok said in 2021 that its monthly active users (MAU) surpassed 1 billion.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，表示动作的承受者是TikTok的月活跃用户。结构是：主语 + be + 过去分词 + by + 施动者。在这个句子中，主语是its monthly active users (MAU)，be是said，过去分词是surpassed，施动者是TikTok。这个句子的意思是说，TikTok的旗舰应用在2021年表示，其月活跃用户已超过10亿。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：TikTok owner ByteDance looks to expand in Silicon Valley in the United States, and also in Canada and Australia as the sector continues to boom and amid rising competition.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时的句子，表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在。结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。在这个句子中，主语是TikTok owner ByteDance，谓语是looks，现在分词是expand。这个句子的意思是说，TikTok所有者字节跳动正在寻求在美国硅谷、加拿大和澳大利亚扩张，因为该行业持续繁荣且竞争日益激烈。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In addition to US, ByteDance is looking for talent to join its expanded operations in Canada and Australia to work on apps including TikTok</li>
<li>ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/6f1c2685-a484-454c-8ac6-1cbb7274395c_40276094.jpg" /><figcaption>TikTok owner ByteDance looks to expand in US, Canada and Australia. Photo: AFP  </figcaption></figure><p>ByteDance, which owns global short video hit TikTok, is looking to expand in Silicon Valley in the United States, and also in Canada and Australia as the sector continues to boom and amid rising competition.</p><p>The company is in talks to sublease a large office building on Coleman Avenue in San Jose, California, according to a report by the Bay Area News Group last week.</p><p>Meanwhile, it is looking for talent – mainly computer engineers – to join its expanded operations in Canada and Australia to work on apps including TikTok, video editor CapCut and social media and lifestyle app Lemon8, according to a report on Thursday by Chinese media outlet Jiemian.</p><p>In addition to hiring new staff, ByteDance is also transferring existing employees from other regions to some of the new locations. For example, it has relocated 120 people working across product, operations, and research and development from China to Canada and Australia, according to the Jiemian report.</p><p>ByteDance did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>The expansion comes as ByteDance seeks to maintain its business momentum amid rising competition and political headwinds.</p><p>Its flagship app TikTok said in 2021 that its monthly active users (MAU) surpassed 1 billion. CapCut’s MAU has hit 200 million, according to a March report by Baijing, a blog that covers Chinese companies doing business overseas.</p><p>Although ByteDance has retreated in video gaming, it is doubling down on e-commerce by leveraging the popularity of TikTok. It has set an ambitious target for its US shopping operation to increase tenfold to US$17.5 billion in gross merchandise volume this year, according to a Bloomberg report.</p><p>The company’s overall revenue expanded around 30 per cent in 2023 to more than US$110 billion, outpacing projected growth at Meta Platforms and Tencent Holdings, according to a December Bloomberg report.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance’s Douyin steps up oversight of live-streaming hosts, closing 290,000 accounts last year for ‘harmful’ content</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248921/bytedances-douyin-steps-oversight-live-streaming-hosts-closing-290000-accounts-last-year-harmful</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Amidst the growth of China's live-streaming sector, worth US$98.2 billion in 2023, Douyin, a popular short video platform, has taken steps to address inappropriate practices among its live-streaming hosts. These issues include using vulgar language, engaging in improper challenge games, and enticing viewers to spend more money. The crackdown led to the removal of over 290,000 host accounts, including top influencers. Douyin has also collaborated with authorities to tackle harmful content, scams, gambling, and pornography, resulting in the arrest of over 300 criminal suspects.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Douyin's efforts to curb inappropriate and harmful content in its live-streaming sector.</li>    <li>Theme: The live-streaming industry's rapid growth and the need for regulation to maintain a healthy online environment.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Douyin's responsibility as a major live-streaming platform to address and eliminate inappropriate practices among its hosts.</li>    <li>Main Information: Specific actions taken by Douyin, including removing host accounts, introducing a host rating system, and collaborating with authorities to tackle illegal activities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  在中国蓬勃发展的直播行业中，2023年价值达982亿美元的抖音采取措施解决其直播主播的不当行为。这些问题包括使用粗俗的语言、参与不当的挑战游戏以及诱骗观众花费更多金钱。这次打击行动导致29万多个主播账号被删除，其中包括一些顶级影响者。抖音还与有关部门合作，打击有害内容、诈骗、赌博和色情内容，导致300多名犯罪嫌疑人被捕。  <ul>    <li>摘要：抖音努力遏制其直播行业的不当和有害内容。</li>    <li>主题：直播行业的快速增长以及为了维护健康的在线环境而进行监管的必要性。</li>    <li>观点：抖音作为主要直播平台，有责任解决和消除其主播的不当行为。</li>    <li>主要信息：抖音采取的具体行动，包括删除主播账号、引入主播评级系统以及与有关部门合作打击非法活动。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>crackdown (n.) - /ˈkrækˌdaʊn/ 镇压，严厉打击。    <p>原文例句：The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Crackdown的意思是镇压，严厉打击，通常用于政府或执法部门对某些违法行为或不良现象进行严厉打击和整治。在这个例句中，它指的是抖音平台对违规直播行为的严厉打击，导致超过29万个主播账号被关闭。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>improper (adj.) - /ɪmˈprɑːpər/ 不适当的，不合适的。    <p>原文例句：Some outdoor live-streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Improper的意思是不适当的，不合适的，通常用于描述行为、言论或事物不符合社会规范或礼仪。在这个例句中，它指的是一些户外直播和挑战游戏存在不当行为，例如主播在直播过程中使用粗俗语言或骚扰路人。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>intervene (v.) - /ɪntərˈviːn/ 干预，介入。    <p>原文例句：It also has safeguards that intervene when its system determines an elderly user is falling prey to online scams on its app. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Intervene的意思是干预，介入，通常用于描述一个人或组织采取行动阻止或改变某个事件或过程的进程。在这个例句中，它指的是抖音平台的安全保障措施在系统判定老年用户在应用中遭遇网络诈骗时会进行干预。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take into account - 考虑，顾及。    <p>原文例句：Last September, it introduced a revamped host rating system to take into account multiple factors such as the severity of the alleged malpractice, and the hosts’ level of influence and popularity. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Take into account的意思是考虑，顾及，通常用于表示在决策或判断时将某些因素纳入考虑范围。在这个例句中，它指的是抖音平台在去年9月推出了一项改进后的主播评级系统，该系统会考虑多个因素，例如被指控不当行为的严重性以及主播的影响力和受欢迎程度。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fall prey to - 成为……的牺牲品，被欺骗。    <p>原文例句：It also has safeguards that intervene when its system determines an elderly user is falling prey to online scams on its app. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Fall prey to的意思是成为……的牺牲品，被欺骗，通常用于描述某人因为缺乏警惕或判断力而成为诈骗或欺骗的受害者。在这个例句中，它指的是抖音平台的安全保障措施在系统判定老年用户在应用中遭遇网络诈骗时会进行干预。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Some outdoor live-streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions. - 一些户外直播和挑战游戏导致了一些问题，例如直播期间主播使用粗俗的语言和骚扰路人。<p>句子分析：这是一个复句，主句是Some outdoor live-streaming and challenge games led to problems，其中主语是Some outdoor live-streaming and challenge games，谓语是led to problems。such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions是一个同位语从句，解释problems的内容，即这些问题包括直播期间主播使用粗俗的语言和骚扰路人。这个句子的意思是说，一些户外直播和挑战游戏导致了一些问题，例如直播期间主播使用粗俗的语言和骚扰路人。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语作状语 - 用于修饰句子中的动词或形容词，表示动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：In a joint effort with local authorities in Changsha, the capital of central Hunan province, Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. </p>    <p>语法讲解：In a joint effort with local authorities in Changsha, the capital of central Hunan province是一个分词短语，作状语，修饰谓语removed，表示抖音平台与当地政府合作采取的行动。since August last year是一个分词短语，作状语，修饰谓语removed，表示从去年8月以来抖音平台采取的行动。这个句子的意思是说，抖音平台与湖南省中部省会长沙市的当地政府合作，自去年8月以来已删除了超过10,000个主播的账号。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>介词短语作定语 - 用于修饰句子中的名词或代词，表示事物之间的关系。    <p>原文例句：Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming. </p>    <p>语法讲解：as ByteDance exits gaming是一个介词短语，作定语，修饰名词Tencent，表示腾讯允许抖音在字节跳动退出游戏业务后播放王者荣耀视频。这个句子的意思是说，腾讯允许抖音在字节跳动退出游戏业务后播放王者荣耀视频。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Some outdoor live streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions</li>
<li>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was worth US$98.2 billion in 2023</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/9a28fd60-8832-4f14-b4c3-01657424e7b0_5660f465.jpg" /><figcaption>An advertisement for Douyin seen at a bus stop in China. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure><p>Douyin, the sibling app of ByteDance’s global short video hit TikTok, said it imposed additional oversight on live-streaming hosts and their activities during 2023 to rein in inappropriate practices.</p><p>The live-streaming crackdown conducted throughout 2023 shut down more than 290,000 host accounts, including some top influencers, as the platform sought to weed out practices it deemed harmful, such as outdoor live-streaming containing vulgar content, improper challenge games among hosts, as well as enticing viewers to spend more money, the company said in a post published to its official WeChat account on Tuesday.</p><p>Some outdoor live-streaming and challenge games led to problems such as vulgar language and harassment of passers-by by hosts during their live sessions, according to the post.</p><p>In a joint effort with local authorities in Changsha, the capital of central Hunan province, Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248513/internet-titans-bury-hatchet-tencent-allows-douyin-air-honour-kings-videos-amid-bytedance-retreat" title="">Tencent allows Douyin to air Honour of Kings videos as ByteDance exits gaming</a></h3><p>The banned hosts had engaged in “harmful” outdoor live-streaming activities in Changsha, a major tourist spot which attracted live-streamers who wanted to broadcast its bustling nightlife.</p><p>Chinese regulators have increasingly tightened their leash on the live-streaming sector, which was forecast to have made 700 billion yuan (US$98.2 billion) in 2023, according to Statista.</p><p>Improper challenge games and enticed spending were also issues raised by the Cyberspace Administration of China over the past two years, as part of the top Chinese internet watchdog’s campaigns to root out malicious online content.</p><p>Douyin’s live-streaming clampdown also targeted live streamers who were promoting scams, gambling and pornographic content on the platform. Nearly two-thirds, or 190,000, of the hosts banned last year were involved in such activities.</p><p>Through efforts with the Chinese police, more than 300 criminal suspects have been arrested, Douyin said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3247755/watched-strangers-china-mother-live-streams-son-9-doing-homework-says-he-works-3-times-faster" title="">Chinese mother live-streams son, 9, doing homework so he is not distracted</a></h3><p>However, the crackdown is taking a toll on some hosts, who said they were incidentally banned as part of the measures. One host, based in the central province of Anhui, who requested anonymity for fear of retribution by the platform, told the South China Morning Post on Thursday that while she agreed with Douyin’s efforts, it was easy for some veteran hosts to get caught up, adding that losing access to accounts that took years to build up is a high cost.</p><p>Douyin did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Thursday.</p><p>The platform has also been improving the way it manages live streamers. Last September, it introduced a revamped host rating system to take into account multiple factors such as the severity of the alleged malpractice, and the hosts’ level of influence and popularity.</p><p>Meanwhile, verified hosts generating “good” content would be rewarded with support from Douyin to create a “healthy and positive” environment for live-streaming activities.</p><p>The rising trend of using artificial intelligence (AI)-powered virtual hosts has also caught Douyin’s attention. The short video app has put in place rules to require more transparency, with additional identity checks required for the individuals behind such virtual hosts.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" class="image-inline caption" height="1332" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/0141f38e-3a8c-4a47-84ce-4ce5fdc448a3_3366798b.jpg" title="In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images" width="2000" /><figcaption>In a joint effort with local authorities in the city of Changsha (pictured), Douyin removed the accounts of more than 10,000 hosts since August last year. Photo: Shutterstock Images</figcaption></figure></div><p>More than 765 million Chinese internet users had tuned into live sessions across various online services as of last June, according to data from the China Internet Network Information Centre, representing around 70 per cent of the country’s total 1.079 billion netizens.</p><p>The widespread adoption of live-streaming services has included people of all ages, including minors and seniors, two groups which Douyin said it was paying special attention to.</p><p>Douyin has introduced restrictions that prevent minors from hosting live sessions or tipping other hosts. It also has safeguards that intervene when its system determines an elderly user is falling prey to online scams on its app.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Private-equity investors to return to China in search of M&amp;A deals in 2024, Bain &amp; Co says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248937/private-equity-investors-return-china-search-ma-deals-2024-bain-co-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese private equity investors are returning to the mergers and acquisitions (M&A) market after three consecutive years of decline, hoping to benefit from economic recovery and high valuations.</li>    <li>Private equity investors will focus on improving profitability and revenue growth rather than high valuations when making investment decisions.</li>    <li>It may take longer to close deals, but there is certainty that more transactions will be conducted in 2024.</li>    <li>Bain's report also highlights the shift in investor preference towards large-scale businesses over small, high-growth firms.</li>    <li>Higher valuations have contributed significantly to the returns of private equity funds in China in recent years.</li>    <li>Middle Eastern countries are pursuing opportunities for China inbound M&A deals, particularly in new energy and electric vehicles.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>在连续三年下滑之后，中国私募股权投资（PE）正在回归并购（M&A）市场，希望从经济复苏和高估值中获利。</li>    <li>私募股权投资者在做投资决策时，将重点放在改善盈利能力和收入增长，而不是高估值上。</li>    <li>虽然达成交易可能需要更长时间，但可以确定的是今年将会有更多交易进行。</li>    <li>贝恩的报告还强调投资者偏好从小型高增长企业转向规模化企业。</li>    <li>近年来，较高的估值对中国私募股权基金的回报做出了重大贡献。</li>    <li>中东国家正在寻求中国入境并购交易的机会，特别是在新能源和电动汽车行业。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>resurface (v.) - /ˌriːsərˈfeɪs/ 重新出现，再次出现。    <p>原文例句：New talks on deal making [have] resurfaced since the second half of 2023,” he said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由re-（重新）和surface（表面）构成的，表示“重新出现，再次出现”。在这个例句中，它指的是自2023年下半年以来，关于交易的谈判再次出现。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>spur (v.) - /spɜːr/ 刺激，促进。    <p>原文例句：The central government will also prepare new supportive policies to spur the mainland’s economy, he added. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，表示“刺激，促进”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国中央政府将准备新的支持性政策来刺激中国经济。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take effect - 生效，起作用。    <P>原文例句：Kang Yi, head of China’s National Bureau of Statistics, said during a press conference on Wednesday that some incentives Beijing rolled out last year – such as the plan to issue 1 trillion yuan (US$139 billion) worth of special treasury bonds – will take effect in 2024. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，带）和effect（效果，影响）构成的，表示“生效，起作用”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国国家统计局局长康义在星期三的新闻发布会上表示，北京去年推出的一些激励措施——例如发行价值1万亿元人民币（合1390亿美元）特别国债的计划——将在2024年生效。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Bain’s statement is significant because, despite a drop in deal volumes, mainland China still accounted for 41 per cent of deals in the Asia-Pacific region in the first half of 2023, according to S&P Global Market Intelligence. - 贝恩的声明很重要，因为尽管交易数量下降，但根据标普全球市场情报的数据，2023年上半年中国大陆仍占亚太地区交易的41%。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是China still accounted for 41 per cent of deals in the Asia-Pacific region in the first half of 2023，其中主语是China，谓语是accounted for，宾语是41 per cent of deals in the Asia-Pacific region。Bain’s statement is significant because是一个原因状语从句，表示贝恩的声明很重要，原因是尽管交易数量下降。despite a drop in deal volumes是一个介词短语作状语，表示尽管交易数量下降。这个句子的意思是说，贝恩的声明很重要，因为尽管交易数量下降，但根据标普全球市场情报的数据，2023年上半年中国大陆仍占亚太地区交易的41%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>情态动词+原形动词 - 表示建议，请求，警告，允许，承诺等。    <p>原文例句：Private-equity investors will focus on improving profitability and bolstering revenue from their portfolio firms, rather than potential frothy valuations, when they are making investment decisions, said Zhou Hao, head of the firm’s Greater China private equity and M&A practice</p>    <p>语法讲解：情态动词+原形动词的结构一般表示建议、请求、警告、允许、承诺等。在这个句子中，情态动词will表示一种可能性或必然性，原形动词focus表示一种意向或计划。这句话的意思是，周浩表示，在做出投资决策时，私募股权投资者将专注于提高其投资组合公司的盈利能力和收入，而不是潜在的高估值。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示一种假设或不真实的情况。    <p>原文例句：“New talks on deal making [have] resurfaced since the second half of 2023,” he said. “It may take longer to conclude the deals, but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted this year.”</p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种表示假设或不真实情况的语法形式。在这个句子中，may表示一种可能性或不确定性，take longer表示一种假设或不真实的情况。这句话的意思是，他说：“关于交易的新谈判自2023年下半年以来重新浮出水面。”“达成交易可能需要更长时间，但可以确定的是今年将会有更多交易进行。”</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>It may take longer to conclude deals, ‘but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted’ in 2024, Bain executive says</li>
<li>Mainland China M&amp;A deals dropped to a nine-year low last year amid a third straight year of declines, Refinitiv data shows</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/18/3af570e6-afc9-4398-8253-c7bffe73cf71_6190bf99.jpg" /><figcaption>The Liuiazui financial hub in Shanghai. Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for GDP, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, at the National People’s Congress. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Global and domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3246654/china-ma-activity-set-rebound-2024-amid-renewed-overseas-interest-it-wont-be-business-usual-heres" target="_self" title="">private-equity investors</a> are making a comeback to the Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mergers-acquisitions" target="_self" title="">mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;A)</a> market following three straight years of decline, as they look to profit from an economic recovery, global consultancy Bain &amp; Co said.</p><p>Private-equity investors will focus on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247667/chinese-stocks-darkest-days-may-be-over-earnings-rebound-property-recovery-seen-lifting-gloom-2024" target="_self" title="">improving profitability and bolstering revenue</a> from their portfolio firms, rather than potential frothy valuations, when they are making investment decisions, said Zhou Hao, head of the firm’s Greater China private equity and M&amp;A practice.</p><p>“New talks on deal making [have] resurfaced since the second half of 2023,” he said. “It may take longer to conclude the deals, but it is certain that more transactions will be conducted this year.”</p><p>Bain’s statement is significant because, despite a drop in deal volumes, mainland China still accounted for 41 per cent of deals in the Asia-Pacific region in the first half of 2023, according to S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence.</p><p>Mainland China reported 5,156 M&amp;A deals in 2023, with a combined value of US$301 billion, according to Refinitiv data. This was a nine-year low and a third straight year of declines, in terms of deal volumes.</p><p>US dollar-denominated private-equity funds that have at least half their capital invested in China raised US$1.4 billion in the first half of last year, down about 90 per cent from a year earlier, according to Preqin data.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3248558/asset-manager-blackstone-expand-private-equity-headcount-singapore-southeast-asia-push" title="">Asset manager Blackstone to expand private-equity headcount in Singapore</a></h3><p>However, earlier this month, UBS forecast that profit growth for Chinese listed companies will jump to 8 per cent in 2024 from 3 per cent last year, buoyed by a recovery in the world’s second-largest economy.</p><p>Beijing will unveil its annual growth targets for gross domestic product, consumer inflation and fiscal deficit for 2024 in March, when the annual session of the National People’s Congress is held.</p><p>Moreover, Kang Yi, head of China’s National Bureau of Statistics, said during a press conference on Wednesday that some incentives Beijing rolled out last year – such as the plan to issue 1 trillion yuan (US$139 billion) worth of special treasury bonds – will take effect in 2024. The central government will also prepare new supportive policies to spur the mainland’s economy, he added.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3246654/china-ma-activity-set-rebound-2024-amid-renewed-overseas-interest-it-wont-be-business-usual-heres" title="">China M&amp;A activity set for rebound but 2024 won’t be business as usual</a></h3><p>Most investors with massive amounts of dry powder prefer large-scale businesses to small, high-growth firms, as they chase stable and sustainable returns in a fast-changing market, Bain said.</p><p>Private-equity dry powder soared to an unprecedented US$2.59 trillion globally as of December 1 last year, an 8 per cent increase over December 2022’s total of US$2.39 trillion, data by S&amp;P Global and Preqin shows.</p><p>Bain said in a research report released on Thursday that buyout funds mainly benefited from higher valuations of portfolio firms in China amid increasing price-to-earnings multiples, because investors in new rounds of financing were convinced of their future growth potential.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3245604/global-ma-deal-makers-miss-us3-trillion-mark-first-time-10-years" title="">Global M&amp;A: deal makers to miss US$3 trillion mark for first time in 10 years</a></h3><p>Higher valuations contributed to 55 per cent of the total returns private-equity funds reaped in China from 2012 to 2022, Bain said. Revenue increases contributed to 37 per cent of total returns while only 8 per cent of the returns were derived from profit rises.</p><p>Middle Eastern countries that are eager to shift from fossil fuel-based economies are pursuing opportunities for China inbound M&amp;A deals, particularly in the new energy and electric-vehicles (EV) sectors.</p><p>In October, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3239304/chinese-self-driving-technology-start-ponyai-gets-us100-million-investment-saudi-arabias-smart-city" target="_self" title="">Saudi Arabian smart city developer Neom</a> invested US$100 million in Chinese autonomous driving technology start-up Pony.ai to help fund its research and development and finance its operations.</p><p>On December 18, Chinese EV maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3242863/chinese-ev-maker-nio-sees-ai-robots-replacing-30-cent-workforce-2027-improve-efficiency-cut-costs" target="_self" title="">Nio</a> announced it had raised US$2.2 billion from CYVN Holdings, a fund backed by the Abu Dhabi government.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
