<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>European Union not in ‘Champions League’ of economic security, ASML rep says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3248135/european-union-not-champions-league-economic-security-senior-asml-official-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Dutch semiconductor giant ASML's representative criticized the European Union's efforts to reduce economic risks in relations with China, saying the EU is not in the "Champions League of economic security" and is falling behind countries like the United States, China, and Japan. He stated that the American policy of restricting technology exports to China is motivated by a desire to curtail China's industrial progress. The EU needs to act collectively and adopt effective economic security strategies to compete with the US and China.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: ASML's representative criticizes the EU's efforts to reduce economic risks with China.</li>    <li>Theme: The challenges faced by the European Union in achieving economic security and competing with global powers, particularly in the context of US-China tensions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The EU needs to improve its economic security strategy and assert itself as a global economic power, balancing relations with the US and China.</li>    <li>Main information: ASML's representative's assessment of the EU's economic security efforts; the US policy of restricting technology exports to China; the EU's struggle to compete with the US and China in economic security and technology.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  荷兰半导体设备巨头ASML的代表对欧盟为降低对华关系中的经济风险而做出的努力予以批评，称欧盟不在“经济安全的冠军联赛”之列，落后于美国、中国和日本等国家。他指出，美国限制对华技术出口的政策是为了遏制中国的工业发展。欧盟需要团结行动，采取有效的经济安全策略，与美国和中国展开竞争。    <ul>    <li>摘要：ASML代表批评欧盟降低对华经济风险的努力。</li>    <li>主题：欧盟在实现经济安全和与全球大国竞争中面临的挑战，尤其是在中美紧张局势的背景下。</li>    <li>观点：欧盟需要加强其经济安全战略，确立自身作为全球经济强国的地位，在美中之间保持平衡。</li>    <li>主要信息：ASML代表对欧盟经济安全努力的评价；美国限制技术出口至中国的政策；欧盟在经济安全和技术领域难与美中匹敌。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>looming (adj.) - /ˈluːmɪŋ/ 迫近的，来势汹汹的。    <p>原文例句：The threat of protectionism is looming larger than ever. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个形容词来源于loom（织布机），表示“迫近的，来势汹汹的”。在这个例句中，它描述了保护主义的威胁比以往任何时候都迫在眉睫。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>intercede (v.) - /ˌɪntəˈsiːd/ 干涉，调解。    <p>原文例句：We must do all we can to intercede and stop these planned attacks.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个动词来源于inter（在中间）和cede（让步），表示“干涉，调解”。在这个例句中，它描述了我们必须尽一切努力干涉和阻止这些计划中的袭击。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>fall behind - 落后于，掉队。    <P>原文例句：This means we can't fall behind in the development of new technologies.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由fall（落下）和behind（后面）构成的，表示“落后于，掉队”。在这个例句中，它表示我们不能在新技术的发展上落后。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>句子分析：这个句子是一个现在完成进行时态的句子，表示从过去的几年开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。主语是The company，谓语是由have been making和iPhone and other products构成的，其中have been making是现在完成进行时态的助动词，making是动词make的现在分词，iPhone and other products是宾语。这个句子的意思是说，这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行最新款的iPhone 15手机的制造。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达虚拟、假设、愿望等含义的语气。    <p>原文例句：If you were to ask me, I would say that this is the best movie I have ever seen.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气的条件句，表示虚拟或假设的情况。结构是：if + were to + 动词原形，其中were to是虚拟语气的助动词，动词原形是动词的原始形式。在这个例句中，它表示如果你问我，我会说这是我看过的最好的电影。这个句子的意思是说，如果你问我，我会说这是我看过的最好的电影。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较级 - 用于比较两个或多个对象或情况的程度。    <p>原文例句：This new phone is faster than the old one.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个比较级的句子，表示两个或多个对象或情况的程度的比较。结构是：形容词或副词的比较级 + than + 被比较的对象或情况。在这个例句中，faster是形容词fast的比较级，表示更快的。这个句子的意思是说，这款新手机比旧手机更快。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Dutch semiconductor equipment giant among several business groups on continent critical of Brussels’ efforts to de-risk its relations with Beijing</li>
<li>American policy “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, ASML’s top EU lobbyist adds</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/3ee1f9f0-3899-41eb-8332-c26934257ad0_b5a707dc.jpg" /><figcaption>A view of ASML Holding NV headquarters in Veldhoven, Netherlands. The Dutch semiconductor equipment company, a world leader in chipmaking, is valued at US$285 billion. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/european-union" target="_self" title="">European Union</a> is not in the “Champions League of economic security”, and even “struggles to perform at Europa League level”.</p><p>That was the withering assessment of a senior representative of ASML, Europe’s most valuable <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> company, who used a football analogy to attack Brussels’ efforts to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3241838/eu-leader-ursula-von-der-leyen-urges-states-begin-economic-de-risking-china-or-face-trouble" target="_self" title="">de-risk its relations with China</a>.</p><p>“If you think about the Champions League of economic security and geoeconomic statecraft, we have to think of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>, we have to think of China, and we also have to think of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a>,” said Wouter Baljon, the Dutch company’s top EU lobbyist, referring to Europe’s premier football tournament.</p><p>“If you think of the Europa League, or tier two, we look at countries particularly in our industry, like [<a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South] Korea</a>, like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>, and at best Europe, the EU as a collective.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>“The EU clearly … aspires to be in the Champions League, but for high technology, they struggled to perform at Europa League-level,” said Baljon at an event in Brussels on Wednesday, referring to the continent’s inferior competition.</p><p>ASML, valued at US$285 billion, is the world leader in the chipmaking equipment essential for manufacturing advanced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductors</a> and considered the crown jewel in Europe’s tech sector.</p><p>Its executives should have a good idea of who’s who in the pantheon of geopolitical arm-twisting, having been caught in the cross hairs of a fierce <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/us-china-tech-war-rivalry/news" target="_self" title="">US-China tech war</a>.</p><p>ASML has been forced to stop selling some advanced precision lithography machines to Chinese buyers at the behest of the Biden administration.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247042/chip-industry-giant-asml-blocked-us-netherlands-shipping-equipment-china-ahead-export-deadline" title="">ASML blocked from shipping chip-making equipment to China ahead of deadline</a></h3><p>The American policy was “all about curtailing the ability of China to make industrial progress”, Baljon said, adding that the EU was living in “la-la land” if it thought otherwise.</p><p>“We haven’t acknowledged that export controls have become an industrial policy instrument. We still live in this la-la land that it’s about dual-use goods, it’s military-civil fusion.”</p><p>Baljon delivered his comments in Brussels during an event hosted by the European Policy Centre on the EU’s capacity to act as an economic security power as it looks to reduce its dependencies on Beijing.</p><p>Earlier in the day, EU industry chief Thierry Breton described Europe as a “third bloc” in a multipolar world.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ba9b8fc1-5a69-4091-bb98-4a2a845fa781_1126e908.jpg" title="Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>Thierry Breton, the European commissioner for the EU’s internal market, Thierry Breton, has described Europe as a ‘third bloc’ in a multipolar world. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>“We need to continue to promote Europe as a third bloc, a balancing force between the US and China,” the commissioner said at the event. “Of course, we will remain an open continent, but on our terms, more assertive than ever.”</p><p>However, ASML’s representative was less confident, saying the European Commission would struggle to define an economic security strategy without the buy-in of powerful member states, which have pushed back against the policy.</p><p>“A certain humbleness might certainly help the EU to act as a collective, particularly in high technology,” said Baljon. “We are not an incumbent unfortunately. As the EU 27, we are a challenger, and we need the instruments and the approaches to reflect this.”</p><p>“We might speak of the ‘geopolitical commission’, but at this point, I think it’s only as geopolitical as [the] Franco-German axis allows it to be, and you also don’t have the manpower to really be in this Champions League.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246046/chinas-imports-dutch-chip-making-equipment-surged-tenfold-november-after-washington-tightened" title="">China’s imports of Dutch chip-making equipment surged tenfold in November</a></h3><p>The EU will present an “initiative” on screening outbound investments and a proposal on export controls for four crucial technologies, including microchips, on January 24. These form part of a package of tools aimed at de-risking its trading ties with China.</p><p>Baljon’s remarks were among a series of broadsides voiced at the event as businesses lined up to criticise the EU’s plans.</p><p>Malte Lohan, director general of Orgalim, a trade association representing Europe’s tech industries, said firms in his sector were facing “a tsunami of regulation”.</p><p>“You can’t just regulate your way to economic security from a few office blocks in Brussels,” Lohan said, adding he was “very nervous” about an “unprecedented shift to public intervention in our supply chains”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3244922/eu-china-relations-amid-brussels-de-risk-plans-european-firms-are-reluctant-speak-china" title="">EU firms are reluctant to speak up on China as Brussels tries to de-risk</a></h3><p>“If you look at any one of the instruments in isolation, of course there’s always a very good reason for it … I think we need to accept that this is a completely new paradigm in terms of how supply chains are regulated through public-sector intervention.”</p><p>Luisa Santos, deputy director general at BusinessEurope, another lobby group, said the EU endangered its competitiveness by putting security concerns ahead of economic growth.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ukraine-war" target="_self" title="">war</a> in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ukraine" target="_self" title="">Ukraine</a> had “created a new consensus in the business community” on the security issues Europe faces, she said.</p><p>“But we should not overdo it also, because we have other problems that we need to deal with and we have not dealt with yet, including our competitiveness … what we have seen in these last years is that compared to other partners in terms of overall competitiveness … we [in Europe] are not in such good shape.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China smartphone brand Realme unveils new handset on sidelines of trade show as its biggest rivals stay home</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248116/ces-2024-china-smartphone-brand-realme-unveils-new-handset-sidelines-trade-show-its-biggest-rivals</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Realme, a Chinese smartphone maker, showcased its latest smartphone, the 12 Pro+, at an event parallel to CES 2024 in Las Vegas. The company emphasized its focus on young overseas users and the device's enhanced zoom capabilities at a budget-friendly price.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Realme targets young users with enhanced zoom capabilities in its budget-friendly 12 Pro+ smartphone.</li>    <li>Theme: Realme's rebranding effort to appeal to young users and its strategy to cater to specific market segments.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of understanding and addressing the needs of young users in the smartphone market.</li>    <li>Main information: Unveiling of the 12 Pro+ smartphone; focus on zoom capabilities and collaboration with Qualcomm for image processing; company's rebranding and target market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Realme，一家中国智能手机制造商，在 2024 年国际消费类电子产品展览会 (CES) 期间在拉斯维加斯举办的平行活动中展示了其最新智能手机 12 Pro+。该公司强调专注于年轻海外用户以及设备在预算范围内增强的变焦功能。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Realme 推出价格实惠的 12 Pro+ 智能手机，为年轻用户提供增强的变焦功能。</li>    <li>主题：Realme 为吸引年轻用户而进行的品牌重塑工作，以及迎合特定细分市场的策略。</li>    <li>观点：了解和满足智能手机市场年轻用户需求的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：12 Pro+ 智能手机的发布；专注于变焦功能以及与高通公司合作进行图像处理；公司的品牌重塑和目标市场。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>periscope lens (n.) - 潜望镜镜头。    <p>原文例句：Realme said its latest 12 Pro+ handset has the largest sensor in any periscope lens on a smartphone sold globally. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由periscope（潜望镜）和lens（镜头）组成的，表示“潜望镜镜头”，是一种长焦镜头，通过反射镜将光线改变方向，使其能够以更长的焦距拍摄远距离物体。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>chipset (n.) - 芯片组。    <p>原文例句：Realme said the chipset used in the 12 Pro+ will not be made public until closer to its formal launch. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由chip（芯片）和set（集合）组成的，表示“芯片组”，是一组集成电路，通常包括处理器、内存和存储器等。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>collaboration (n.) - 合作，协作。    <p>原文例句：Realme said it collaborated with the US chip design firm on a solution to improve image-processing speed. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由co（一起）和labor（劳动）组成的，表示“合作，协作”，指两个或多个组织或个人共同努力完成一项任务或目标。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>give confidence that - 使人对……有信心。    <P>原文例句：The firm also touted its sales numbers – more than 200 million handsets sold since its incubation at Oppo – as “giving us confidence that we’re on to something”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由give（给予），confidence（信心）和that（使）组成的，表示“使人对……有信心”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>So the firm has combined a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones. - 因此，该公司将半英寸传感器与 3 倍光学变焦潜望镜镜头相结合，并将其构建在其中端智能手机系列中。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The firm has combined a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones，其中主语是The firm，谓语是has combined，宾语是a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones。So是一个并列连词，连接两个并列的句子，表示“因此”。这个句子的意思是说，因此，该公司将半英寸传感器与 3 倍光学变焦潜望镜镜头相结合，并将其构建在其中端智能手机系列中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由分词（现在分词或过去分词）及其修饰语构成的短语，具有形容词或副词的作用。    <p>原文例句：Realme, owned by mainland consumer hardware giant BBK Electronics which also controls Oppo and Vivo, held a parallel event in Las Vegas on the sidelines of the CES trade show to unveil its new handset as part of a rebranding effort targeting young overseas users. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，owned by mainland consumer hardware giant BBK Electronics which also controls Oppo and Vivo是一个现在分词短语，作定语修饰Realme，表示Realme是由大陆消费类硬件巨头步步高电子所有，它还控制着Oppo和Vivo。这个分词短语可以改为一个定语从句：Realme is owned by mainland consumer hardware giant BBK Electronics which also controls Oppo and Vivo。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company said it was focused on a niche market segment, where it has found success overseas at a time when global smartphone sales are slumping and China’s post-pandemic economic recovery has sputtered. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，has found是现在完成时的动词，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，即该公司已经找到了一块利基市场，并在全球智能手机销量下滑和中国疫情后经济复苏乏力的时期取得了成功。现在完成时可以表示一个已经完成的动作或状态，也可以表示一个正在进行的动作或状态，但强调的是动作或状态持续的时间而不是完成的时间。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The new 12 Pro+ handset to launch at the end of January provides a better zoom lens at a budget price, as Realme caters to young overseas users</li>
<li>Realme sister brand OnePlus was also in Las Vegas, while Xiaomi, Oppo and Vivo sat out the world’s largest consumer electronics show</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/1486c8f9-79ff-40ce-9c1a-5163f3d4b7b2_2eaa662e.jpg" /><figcaption>Realme unveiled the 12 Pro+ smartphone at an event parallel to the CES trade show. The company is targeting young users with better zoom capabilities in a budget device. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" target="_self" title="">Realme</a>, owned by mainland consumer hardware giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/2184877/meet-godfather-chinas-smartphone-industry" target="_self" title="">BBK Electronics</a> which also controls <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/vivo" target="_self" title="">Vivo</a>, held a parallel event in Las Vegas on the sidelines of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ces" target="_self" title="">CES</a> trade show to unveil its new handset as part of a rebranding effort targeting young overseas users.</p><p>While not an official exhibitor at CES, Realme was one of only two major Chinese smartphone brands to show up in Las Vegas this week. On Wednesday, Realme introduced its 12-series smartphones at the same hotel where its sister brand, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oneplus" target="_self" title="">OnePlus</a>, had a series of suites booked for its own presentations outside CES.</p><p>Realme said its latest 12 Pro+ handset has the largest sensor in any periscope lens on a smartphone sold globally, but pointed out that the company’s GT 5 Pro handset sold in China technically has a bigger lens.</p><p>“What sets us apart from other brands is that we are fully committed to the young generation,” Sam Cheung, senior marketing communications manager for Realme, said in his presentation during the firm’s hour-long event on the sidelines of CES 2024. “At Realme, we believe that every user at every price segment deserves an outstanding product.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1506" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/714bf56a-c08f-4ee3-bc44-695f0ea16d52_68aef08b.jpg" title="Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Realme, which did not reveal pricing for its latest handsets, said the chipset used in the 12 Pro+ will not be made public until closer to its formal launch. While the new device uses a mid-tier <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/qualcomm" target="_self" title="">Qualcomm</a> processor, Realme said it collaborated with the US chip design firm on a solution to improve image-processing speed.</p><p>The 11 Pro+ smartphone launched by Realme last year costs 2,799 yuan, or about US$400.</p><p>At its event, Realme said the firm’s slogan, “Dare to leap”, has been changed to “Make it real” as part of a rebranding effort.</p><p>The company said it was focused on a niche market segment, where it has found success overseas at a time when global smartphone sales are slumping and China’s post-pandemic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chinas-economic-recovery" target="_self" title="">economic recovery</a> has sputtered.</p><p>Realme acknowledged challenges from the pandemic, component shortages and longer replacement cycles from consumers, but the firm also touted its sales numbers – more than <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments">200 million handsets sold</a> since its incubation at Oppo – as “giving us confidence that we’re on to something”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" title="">China’s Realme surges past 200 million smartphone shipments</a></h3><p>Moving forward, Realme aims to double down on what it believes young users want most in a smartphone. The answer it came up with is better photos when zooming in. So the firm has combined a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones.</p><p>It also collaborated with watch designer Ollivier Savéo, who previously worked at Rolex and Piaget, among others, on a design evocative of famed Swiss watches.</p><p>At a time of rising scrutiny of all things Chinese, Realme made its latest product announcement in a country leading the charge against tech from China and where the company does not even sell smartphones.</p><p>For all the other missing Chinese brands – and the smattering of journalists and influencers who showed up to cover the Realme event – it may as well have been part of the show. Vivo and Oppo, two of China’s biggest smartphone brands, were nowhere to be found in Las Vegas, even though Realme spun out of Oppo. OnePlus, the Oppo-owned brand, had suites booked for private showings, but also had no presence on the CES exhibition floor.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>Neither <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> nor <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-blacklisted</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> were at CES.</p><p>Realme said it did not exhibit at CES because the 12 Pro+ handset has not officially launched yet. It organised a pre-briefing in Las Vegas because many of its contacts across a variety of markets would be in town for the world’s largest consumer electronics show.</p><p>While the company set a goal last year of selling in more than 100 markets over the next five years, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> is one market where it may not expand owing to the complexities of getting domestic network carrier support.</p><p>The bulk of US handset sales still happen through mobile network operators, forcing smartphone brands to strike deals to find success. OnePlus has struggled with this situation, despite the glowing reviews received by many of its devices from US tech media.</p><p>Realme said it was still trying to cooperate with a US carrier to get into the market, where 87 per cent of teenagers own an iPhone, according to a survey by investment bank Piper Sandler.</p><p>Meanwhile, Realme has been selling in parts of Europe and Latin America, which it described as an important market for the company’s upcoming 12-series handsets.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia reveals progress in China’s self-driving chip market, setting up competition with domestic players</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248095/nvidia-reveals-progress-chinas-self-driving-chip-market-setting-competition-domestic-players</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Nvidia gains success in the Chinese EV market, signing up multiple Chinese automakers for its autonomous driving system Drive Thor, despite being banned by the US from selling its most advanced semiconductors to China. The autonomous-driving sector has become more competitive as China promotes the adoption of advanced self-driving technology. Chinese EV makers are also heavily using Nvidia's auto chips for their vehicles.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Nvidia's Drive Thor autonomous driving system gains traction in China.</li>    <li>Theme: Nvidia's collaboration with Chinese EV makers to enhance their vehicles' performance with self-driving technology.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: China's push for greater adoption of autonomous-driving technology and the resulting competitive landscape.</li>    <li>Main information: Nvidia's partnership with major Chinese EV makers; the inclusion of automated driving, infotainment, and parking in Nvidia's system; increasing competition with Chinese manufacturers and foreign companies in the autonomous-driving segment.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  英伟达在美国禁止向中国出售其最先进的半导体的情况下，在中国电动汽车市场取得进展，其自动驾驶系统Drive Thor已与多家中国汽车制造商签约。随着中国大力推动采用先进自动驾驶技术，这一领域竞争日趋激烈。中国电动汽车制造商也在大量使用英伟达的汽车芯片。  <ul>    <li>摘要：英伟达Drive Thor自动驾驶系统在中国获得认可。</li>    <li>主题：英伟达与中国电动汽车制造商合作，利用自动驾驶技术提升车辆性能。</li>    <li>观点：中国大力推动采用自动驾驶技术，由此导致竞争格局的变化。</li>    <li>主要信息：英伟达与中国主要电动汽车制造商的合作关系；英伟达系统集成了自动驾驶、车载信息娱乐和泊车功能；自动驾驶领域中国制造商和外国公司竞争加剧。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>automotive (adj.) - /ˌɔːtəˈməʊtɪv/ 汽车的，汽车工业的。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia added Drive Thor – which integrates automated and assisted driving, in-vehicle infotainment, and parking in one single system – to its family of automotive system-on-a-chip solutions in September 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词由auto（自行，自动）和motive（动力）构成，意思是“汽车的，汽车工业的”。在这个例句中，它表示英伟达在2022年9月将Drive Thor集成到其汽车系统级芯片解决方案系列中，该系统集成了自动驾驶、辅助驾驶、车载信息娱乐和停车功能。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>penetration (n.) - /ˌpɛnɪˈtreɪʃən/ 渗透，进入。    <p>原文例句：In 2022, China sold about 7 million units of smart passenger vehicles equipped with assisted autonomous driving systems, which translates into a market penetration rate of 35 per cent. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源自拉丁语penetratio，意思是“渗透，进入”。在这个例句中，它指的是自动驾驶系统渗透汽车市场的情况。原文中说，2022年中国销售了约700万辆配备辅助自动驾驶系统的智能乘用车，这意味着市场渗透率为35%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>set up - 建立，创办。    <p>原文例句：Huawei has emerged as a leading player due to its experience in auto chip design and hardware systems after it set up a smart car solution unit in 2019.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由set（设置，摆放）和up（向上，起来）组成，表示“建立，创办”。在这个例句中，它表示华为在2019年成立了智能汽车解决方案部门，由此成为自动驾驶领域的领先企业。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system. - 英伟达已与长城汽车、理想汽车、小米和吉利控股的极氪汽车签约，为其提供Drive Thor自动驾驶系统。    <P>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的句子，主语是Nvidia，谓语是has signed up，宾语是Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR。for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system是一个介词短语，表示“为其Drive Thor自动驾驶系统”。这个句子的意思是说，英伟达已与长城汽车、理想汽车、小米和吉利控股的极氪汽车签约，为其提供Drive Thor自动驾驶系统。</P></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态对现在仍有影响。    <p>原文例句：Chinese EV makers have been big buyers of Nvidia auto chips. For example, Nio’s flagship sedans ET5 and ES7, Li Auto’s L9 model and Xpeng’s G9 vehicle all come equipped with Nvidia’s Orin chips.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是由have/has和过去分词构成的。have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的第三形式。现在完成时表示过去发生的动作或状态对现在仍有影响或与现在相关。在这个例句中，it表示中国电动汽车制造商一直是大买家Nvidia汽车芯片，例如，蔚来的旗舰轿车ET5和ES7，理想汽车的L9车型，以及小鹏汽车的G9车型都配备了Nvidia的Orin芯片。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子的承受者承受的。    <p>原文例句：In 2022, China sold about 7 million units of smart passenger vehicles equipped with assisted autonomous driving systems, which translates into a market penetration rate of 35 per cent. </p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是通过在动词前加上be动词的过去式或现在完成时态，然后加上过去分词来形成的。被动语态表示动作或状态是由句子的承受者承受的。在这个例句中，sold是过去分词，表示中国在2022年售出了约700万辆配备辅助自动驾驶系统的智能乘用车。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Autonomous-driving systems have become a competitive sector as China pushes greater adoption of advanced self-driving technology</li>
<li>Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/46325582-beb7-45f2-ae5c-8a43d08517a8_f1163133.jpg" /><figcaption>Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system. Photo: EPA-EFE </figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia, the US chip maker banned by Washington from selling its most advanced semiconductors to China, has revealed solid progress in the mainland’s electric vehicle (EV) market with its self-driving technology.</p><p>Nvidia said at the CES consumer electronics show in Las Vegas that Chinese EV makers, including Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR, have snapped up its Drive Thor autonomous driving system to enhance performance of their vehicles. This sets up increased competition with local self-driving system providers such as Huawei Technologies.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246414/huawei-and-xiaomi-launch-new-ev-models-china-reigniting-worries-about-price-wars-worlds-largest-ev" target="_self" title="">Autonomous-driving systems</a>, seen as the brains behind future cars, have become a competitive sector as China pushes greater adoption of advanced self-driving technology. Nvidia added Drive Thor – which integrates automated and assisted driving, in-vehicle infotainment, and parking in one single system – to its family of automotive system-on-a-chip solutions in September 2022.</p><p>As of June last year, Nvidia – which is unable to ship its advanced AI chips to China due to US trade sanctions – had about a 52 per cent share of the global navigate-on-autopilot (NOA) market and cooperation agreements with 25 automotive original equipment makers globally, according to data from Gasgoo Institute, a Shanghai-based research company.</p><p>“Nvidia remains predominant in terms of smart-driving chips in China,” said Brady Wang, an associate director with research firm Counterpoint. “But competition between Chinese manufacturers and foreign companies is set to intensify as they compete for a slice of the autonomous driving segment in China’s EV market.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>Chinese EV makers have been big buyers of Nvidia auto chips. For example, Nio’s flagship sedans ET5 and ES7, Li Auto’s L9 model and Xpeng’s G9 vehicle all come equipped with Nvidia’s Orin chips. Automotive chips are seen as a less sensitive area of the semiconductor market by US authorities when it comes to setting trade sanctions.</p><p>In 2022, China sold about 7 million units of smart passenger vehicles equipped with assisted autonomous driving systems, which translates into a market penetration rate of 35 per cent. In the first half of 2023, the market penetration rate rose to almost 43 per cent, according to data from China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT).</p><p>The MIIT in November issued a new policy that encourages EV makers to bring vehicles equipped with high-levels of autonomous driving to Chinese roads, in a major effort to accomplish Chinese President Xi Jinping’s vision of building a strong and modern transport network.</p><p>Thanks to policy stimulus, Chinese autonomous driving system solution providers – including Horizon Robotics and Black Sesame Technologies – have stepped up their game and are set for greater competition with the likes of Nvidia, Qualcomm, and Intel-owned MobileEye in areas such as autonomous driving chips and full-stack smart car solutions.</p><p>Nvidia topped China’s NOA computing solutions market with a share of 53 per cent in the first half of 2023, followed by smart mobility start-up Horizon Robotics with 31 per cent, and Texas Instruments with 9 per cent, according to data from the Gaogong Industry Research Institute (GGII), which tracks nascent industries in China such as EVs and batteries. Huawei and MobileEye ranked in equal 4th place with a 4 per cent market share each.</p><p>Huawei has emerged as a leading player due to its experience in auto chip design and hardware systems after it set up a smart car solution unit in 2019, the year it was added to a US trade blacklist. Under these sanctions, Huawei could not buy most US-origin semiconductors and had to rely on its own smart-driving chips.</p><p>Priot to the 2023 Shanghai Auto Show in April, Huawei launched its own home-grown smart driving platform, called advanced driving system 2.0 (ADS) and powered by a Huawei-made chipset MDC 610, according to a report by research company Counterpoint and a note in July by Kaiyuan Securities.</p><p>In November, Huawei announced it was transferring core technologies from its smart car business into a new joint venture with state-backed Changan Automobile. The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243139/huawei-accelerates-smart-car-ambitions-invitation-four-carmakers-invest-changan-joint-venture" target="_self" title="">new venture</a>, in which Changan has a 40 per cent stake, is open to other car makers as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3235762/superior-teslas-model-s-huawei-and-chery-automobile-ev-venture-luxeed-launch-first-production-model?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">equity investors</a>.</p><p>Despite still being in the red, the firm’s car unit achieved sales of 2.1 billion yuan (US$305 million) in 2022 and 1 billion yuan in revenue in the first half of last year, according to company information.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple supplier BOE, one of the world’s top display makers, forges US$9 billion deal to build next-generation plant in southwestern China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248092/apple-supplier-boe-one-worlds-top-display-makers-forges-us9-billion-deal-build-next-generation-plant</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  BOE Technology group, one of the biggest screen manufacturers, will invest US$9 billion to build a cutting-edge production facility in Chengdu, China. This investment is expected to make Chengdu a hub for advanced display manufacturing and is a sign of China's focus on increasing collaboration between the government and the tech industry to boost the economy. The new plant is projected to produce 32,000 glass substrates per month and will specialize in producing high-end displays for laptops and tablets.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: BOE Technology Group's investment in a next-generation production facility in Chengdu, China, signals China's focus on enhancing display manufacturing capacity.</li>    <li>Theme: The strategic collaboration between Chinese local governments and Big Tech companies, aiming to restore business confidence and drive economic recovery.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of OLED displays and the growing demand in the market, with China expected to dominate global display manufacturing capacity.</li>    <li>Main information: Details about the BOE production facility, including its capacity, production timeline, and specialization in advanced flexible panels.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  京东方科技集团，全球最大的显示器制造商之一，将在中国成都投资 90 亿美元建设一座最先进的生产设施。预计此项投资将使成都成为先进显示器制造中心，也是中国重点加强政府与科技产业合作以提振经济的标志。新工厂预计每月生产 32,000 个玻璃基板，并将专门生产用于笔记本电脑和平板电脑的高端显示器。  <ul>    <li>摘要：京东方科技集团在成都投资建设下一代生产设施，标志着中国专注于提升显示器制造能力。</li>    <li>主题：中国地方政府与科技巨头公司之间的战略合作，旨在恢复商业信心并推动经济复苏。</li>    <li>观点：OLED 显示器的重要性及市场需求不断增长，预计中国将在全球显示器制造能力方面占据主导地位。</li>    <li>主要信息：京东方生产设施的细节，包括其产能、生产时间表以及在先进柔性面板方面的专长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>soaring (adj.) - 飞速的，飞涨的。    <p>原文例句：The deal represents the largest single industrial project in terms of investment in Chengdu, the capital of southwestern Sichuan province </p>    <p>例句讲解：“Soaring”表示“飞涨的、飙升的”，形容投资金额巨大，是成都历史上最大的单一工业项目。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>bolster (v.) - 加强，巩固。    <p>原文例句：The deal is expected to bolster mainland China’s lead in display manufacturing capacity over the next few years. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“Bolster”意为“加强、巩固”，强调该项目将增强中国大陆在显示器制造能力方面的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>accommodate (v.) - 容纳，适应。    <p>原文例句：Apart from accommodating larger substrates, BOE said its Gen-8.6 AMOLED production line will be able to enhance panel-cutting efficiency for mid-size displays, reduce production costs, lower power consumption and achieve an extended lifespan. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“Accommodate”在此处意为“容纳、容纳”，指新的生产线可以适应更大型的基板，并在不断变化的环境中保持稳定运行。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：The deal represents the largest single industrial project in terms of investment in Chengdu, the capital of southwestern Sichuan province. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“In terms of”表示“在……方面、根据”，强调投资金额是成都历史上最大单一工业项目的关键因素。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>drive economic recovery - 推动经济复苏。    <p>原文例句：The deal underscores efforts by Chinese local governments to increase collaboration with Big Tech companies in the private sector, which is in line with the mainland’s efforts to restore business confidence and drive economic recovery. </p>    <p>例句讲解：“Drive economic recovery”是指通过增加政府与私营部门科技巨头之间的合作来恢复商业信心，从而推动经济复苏，是政府努力的重要组成部分。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>BOE, which initially announced the project last December, will build its so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED – for active-matrix organic light-emitting diode – production facility to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets, according to the firm. </p>    <p>句子分析：“BOE, which initially announced the project last December”是一个非限制性定语从句，对主句“BOE will build its so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED”提供补充信息。其中，“which”引导非限制性定语从句，“initially announced the project last December”是对“BOE”的修饰。“for active-matrix organic light-emitting diode”是一个介词短语，用来说明“Gen-8.6 AMOLED”的用途。最后，整个句子用逗号分隔，表示这是一个复杂句。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 当一个动词加-ing或-ed时，它就变成了一个分词，分词短语由分词和它修饰的成分组成。    <p>原文例句：Shares of BOE in Shenzhen closed up 1.07 per cent to 3.76 yuan on Thursday. </p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语“closed up 1.07 per cent”由过去分词“closed”和补语“up 1.07 per cent”组成，用来说明股票的涨幅。这个短语是对主句“Shares of BOE”的修饰，提供额外的信息。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>复合句 - 复合句是由两个或多个简单句连接而成的。    <p>原文例句：The deal underscores efforts by Chinese local governments to increase collaboration with Big Tech companies in the private sector, which is in line with the mainland’s efforts to restore business confidence and drive economic recovery. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子由两个简单句“The deal underscores efforts by Chinese local governments to increase collaboration with Big Tech companies in the private sector”和“which is in line with the mainland’s efforts to restore business confidence and drive economic recovery”连接而成。这两个简单句用“which”连接，形成一个复合句。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>BOE’s so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex is expected to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets</li>
<li>The deal represents the largest single industrial project in terms of investment in Chengdu, the capital of southwestern Sichuan province</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/f510ed59-cdd2-46ae-9e74-0cdf88c294bd_6e2e158b.jpg" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group’s new production complex for advanced displays in Chengdu, capital of southwestern Sichuan province, is expected to start mass production by the fourth quarter of 2026. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> supplier <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/3024664/how-chinese-accountant-turned-dying-state-owned-factory-worlds-no-1?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">BOE Technology Group</a>, one of the world’s largest display makers, will set up a 63-billion yuan (US$9 billion) next-generation production complex in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chengdu" target="_self" title="">Chengdu</a>, capital of southwestern Sichuan province, that is expected to bolster mainland China’s lead in display manufacturing capacity over the next few years.</p><p>The Chengdu municipal government on Wednesday said in a statement that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/beijing" target="_self" title="">Beijing</a>-based BOE and the city’s Hi-Tech Industrial Development Zone have signed the contract to build the plant, representing the largest single industrial project in the capital in terms of investment.</p><p>BOE, which initially announced the project last December, will build its so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED – for active-matrix organic light-emitting diode – production facility to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets, according to the firm.</p><p>Shares of BOE in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shenzhen" target="_self" title="">Shenzhen</a> closed up 1.07 per cent to 3.76 yuan on Thursday.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/81c3e4de-5983-4500-9e40-24c9b7f0441d_edd804f5.jpg" title="BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>The deal underscores efforts by Chinese local governments to increase collaboration with Big Tech companies in the private sector, which is in line with the mainland’s efforts to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3210306/chinas-key-private-sector-needs-continuity-stability-support-economic-recovery-doubts-remain" target="_self" title="">restore business confidence and drive economic recovery</a>.</p><p>The new BOE production facility is expected to position Chengdu as the display industry’s largest manufacturing base for advanced flexible panels.</p><p>Construction of the new plant is estimated to take 34 months, according to BOE, and mass production is projected to start by the fourth quarter of 2026. The next-generation plant is designed to produce 32,000 glass substrates – each measuring 2,290 millimetres by 2,620mm – every month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/73fdd8a8-8b16-4d68-8c5f-e654e2a0eacf_1126e908.jpg" title="BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Apart from accommodating larger substrates, BOE said its Gen-8.6 AMOLED production line will be able to enhance panel-cutting efficiency for mid-size displays, reduce production costs, lower power consumption and achieve an extended lifespan.</p><p>OLED displays for mobile and other information technology devices are expected to enjoy rapid expansion between 2022 and 2027, with a compound annual growth rate of 7.3 per cent, according to a recent report by Display Supply Chain Consultants (DSCC).</p><p>China is forecast to dominate global display manufacturing capacity, with a 72 per cent market share from 2026 to 2027, the DSCC report said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/3024664/how-chinese-accountant-turned-dying-state-owned-factory-worlds-no-1" title="">How Chinese accountant turned dying factory into No 1 display maker</a></h3><p>By comparison, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>’s market shares are expected to reach 8 per cent and 17 per cent, respectively, in 2027.</p><p>The global OLED market is predicted to generate US$64 billion in revenue in 2026, driven by demand for panels used in laptops, computers monitors and tablets, according to DSCC.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei secures JD.com as HarmonyOS partner as home-grown software emerges as alternative for Apple iOS, Android in China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248044/huawei-secures-jdcom-harmonyos-partner-home-grown-software-emerges-alternative-apple-ios-android</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  China's e-commerce giant JD.com will collaborate with Huawei to develop an app for HarmonyOS Next, a new iteration of Huawei's mobile platform known for its intelligence innovations and seamless transitions across different scenarios. This partnership is a milestone for HarmonyOS, aiming to expand its reach in China and challenge Apple's iOS as the second-leading operating system.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: JD.com joins forces with Huawei to develop an app for HarmonyOS Next, aiming to enhance the platform's adoption and challenge iOS.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's ongoing efforts to promote HarmonyOS in China and compete with Android and iOS.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of JD.com's partnership in boosting HarmonyOS's user base and the potential implications for the Chinese smartphone market.</li>    <li>Main information: JD.com's commitment to building an app for HarmonyOS Next; Huawei's ambitious goal to surpass Apple's iOS in China; upcoming milestones for HarmonyOS, including the launch of HarmonyOS Next and the developer preview in 2024.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国电子商务巨头京东将与华为合作，为HarmonyOS Next开发一款应用，HarmonyOS Next是华为移动平台的最新迭代版本，以其智能创新和跨不同场景的无缝过渡而闻名。这种合作关系是HarmonyOS的一个里程碑，旨在扩大其在中国的覆盖范围，并挑战苹果的iOS，使其成为第二大操作系统。  <ul>    <li>摘要：京东与华为联手为HarmonyOS Next开发应用，旨在提升平台的采用率并挑战iOS。</li>    <li>主题：华为在中国的持续努力来推广HarmonyOS并与安卓和iOS竞争。</li>    <li>观点：京东合作对于提升HarmonyOS用户群的意义，以及对中国智能手机市场潜在的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：京东承诺为HarmonyOS Next构建应用；华为雄心勃勃的目标是超越苹果的iOS在中国的地位；HarmonyOS即将达成的里程碑，包括HarmonyOS Next的推出以及2024年的开发者预览。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>iteration (n.) - /ˌɪtəˈreɪʃn/ - 迭代。    <p>原文例句：HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语iterare（重复），表示“重复，迭代”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为移动平台的下一个迭代版本，即HarmonyOS Next，其基于人工智能创新。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>transition (n.) - /trænˈzɪʃn/ - 过渡。    <p>原文例句：and its ability to support transitions between multiple scenarios</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自拉丁语transire（越过），表示“过渡，转移”。在这个例句中，它指的是HarmonyOS支持在不同场景之间无缝过渡的能力，使其能够适应多种使用情况。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take ground - 获得市场份额。    <p>原文例句：Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组常用来描述公司或产品在市场上获得份额或优势。在这个例句中，它表示华为自研的HarmonyOS将在中国的市场份额上从美国巨头那里获得一定份额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”, Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo. - 余承东称京东为“重量级合作伙伴”，表示此次合作是HarmonyOS发展史上的一个新的里程碑。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS，其中主语是Yu，谓语是said。Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰said，表示余承东在社交媒体平台微博上称京东为“重量级合作伙伴”。这个句子的意思是说，余承东称京东为“重量级合作伙伴”，表示此次合作是HarmonyOS发展史上的一个新的里程碑。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，表示动作或状态是由句子的宾语HarmonyOS承受的，主语是a milestone（一个里程碑）。is projected to reach是一个过去式被动语态，表示HarmonyOS预计将在2024年达到一个里程碑。with the launch of HarmonyOS Next是一个介词短语作状语，修饰is projected to reach，表示随着HarmonyOS Next的推出。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform</li>
<li>Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of HarmonyOS, which is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS in China this year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/5435c70a-132e-4030-86c0-5a8e160d23ce_92ca8b90.jpg" /><figcaption>A billboard advertising Huawei’s Harmony OS at the Smart China Expo in Chongqing, Sept. 4, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has secured another partner to promote use of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3136017/will-huaweis-harmony-operating-system-end-global-duopoly-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS</a>, as the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">US-sanctioned</a> telecommunications equipment giant continues to take on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p><p>Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform and its ability to support transitions between multiple scenarios, Richard Yu Chengdong, chief executive of Huawei’s consumer business group, said on Wednesday.</p><p>Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”, Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo.</p><p>Joining with a growing number of Chinese internet companies, Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of its home-grown HarmonyOS, which is projected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" target="_self" title="">surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China</a> this year, according to Canadian research firm TechInsights.</p><p>While Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, driven by the firm’s smartphone comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to TechInsights.</p><p>The self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative in August 2019, three months after the US government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">added Huawei to its Entity List</a>. Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p><p>A developer preview of HarmonyOS Next is expected to be launched in the first quarter of 2024. Huawei is already working with major Chinese companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p><p>Ant Group, the fintech affiliate of South China Morning Post owner <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, said last month that it was building a new version of mobile payment app Alipay based on HarmonyOS, after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242703/alibaba-develops-native-dingtalk-app-harmonyos-huawei-aims-end-support-android-apps?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba started development on a new version of DingTalk</a>, its workplace collaboration app.</p><p>Other major Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> companies – including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>, video gaming giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netease?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">NetEase</a> and food delivery market leader <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> – in November started to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241371/chinese-big-tech-firms-jdcom-netease-and-meituan-rush-hire-harmonyos-based-app-developers-huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">recruit developers to build native apps for HarmonyOS</a>.</p><p>McDonald’s China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees – became <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244236/mcdonalds-china-pushes-development-native-apps-based-harmonyos-adoption-huaweis-mobile-operating?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239589/xiaomi-launches-home-grown-cross-device-system-hyperos-us-sanctioned-huawei-moves-further-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS Next</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Elon Musk’s X tells watchdog it has shed 1,000 ‘safety’ staff</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248024/elon-musks-x-tells-watchdog-it-has-shed-1000-safety-staff</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>The eSafety Commission warns that Elon Musk’s Twitter cuts have created a haven for abusive content.</li>    <li>Australia has led efforts to regulate social media companies' handling of harmful content.</li>    <li>X has faced criticism for its handling of hate speech and child sexual abuse content.</li>    <li>The eSafety Commission obtained a breakdown of X's safety staff following Musk's takeover.</li>    <li>X has ignored an order to pay a fine for failing to address child pornography.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>澳大利亚网络安全委员会警告称，埃隆·马斯克对推特的裁员为有害内容的传播创造了温床。</li>    <li>澳大利亚一直走在规范社交媒体公司处理有害内容方面的最前沿。</li>    <li>X 因其处理仇恨言论和儿童性虐待内容而受到批评。</li>    <li>网络安全委员会在马斯克接管后获得了 X 的安全人员详细资料。</li>    <li>对于因未能处理儿童色情内容而被要求支付罚款的命令，X 视而不见。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>reinstate (v.) - /ˌriːɪnˈsteɪt/ 恢复，复职。    <p>原文例句：In a photo illustration, the Twitter X logo is displayed on the screen of a smartphone. Photo: SOPA Images/Zuma Press/TNSElon Musk’s X has shed more than 1,000 staff globally from teams responsible for stopping abusive content online, according to new figures released Thursday by Australia’s online watchdog.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由re-（重新，再次）和state（状态，处境）组成，表示“恢复，重新设置”。在这个例句中，它指的是马斯克解雇了 1,000 多名负责阻止在线辱骂内容的员工。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>corroborate (v.) - /kəˈrɑːbəreɪt/ 证实，证实。    <p>原文例句：The regulator has in recent months zeroed in on X – formerly known as Twitter – previously saying Musk’s takeover coincided with a spike in “toxicity and hate” on the platform.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由com-（共同，一起）和roborare（加强，增强）组成，表示“使更加坚固，加强”。在这个例句中，它指的是监管机构最近将注意力集中在 X 公司，并指出马斯克接管后该平台上的“毒性和仇恨”有所增加。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>eradicate (v.) - /ɪˈrædɪkeɪt/ 消除，根除。    <p>原文例句：“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away, it would be like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers,” she told AFP.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由e-（剥夺，去除）和radicare（扎根，根除）组成，表示“从根源上消除或去除”。在这个例句中，它指的是去除 80% 的专门工程师，就像沃尔沃公司取消其所有设计师或工程师一样。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>launch legal action - 提起法律诉讼。    <p>原文例句：But X ignored the deadline to pay the fine, before launching ongoing legal action to have it overturned.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由launch（发起，开始）和legal action（法律诉讼）组成，表示“提起法律诉讼”。在这个例句中，它指的是 X 忽视了支付罚款的截止日期，并提起了正在进行的法律诉讼以推翻罚款。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>crack down on - 严厉打击。    <p>原文例句：In October last year, the eSafety Commission slapped X with an A$610,500 (US$388,000) fine, saying it had failed to show how it was cracking down on child pornography.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由crack（破裂，打击）和down（向下，用力）组成，表示“严厉打击”。在这个例句中，它指的是 eSafety 委员会对 X 处以 610,500 澳元（388,000 美元）的罚款，称其未能证明正在严厉打击儿童色情内容。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Australia’s eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content. - 澳大利亚网络安全委员会表示，这些“大幅削減”加上数以千计被禁止账户的恢复，为有害内容的传播创造了一个“完美风暴”。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content，其中主语是The eSafety Commission，谓语是said，宾语是these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content。restoration of thousands of banned accounts是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示恢复数千个被禁止的账户的恢复，deep cuts是一个名词短语作主语，表示大幅削減，created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content是一个过去分词短语作结果状语，表示为有害内容的传播创造了一个“完美风暴”。这个句子的意思是说，澳大利亚网络安全委员会表示，这些“大幅削減”加上数以千计被禁止账户的恢复，为有害内容的传播创造了一个“完美风暴”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 表示动作或状态发生在句子动作发生之前或之后。    <p>原文例句：Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing firms to outline how they are tackling hate speech and child sexual abuse.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示动作或状态发生在句子动作发生之前或之后。结构是：主语 + 现在分词 + 其他。其中主语是Australia，现在分词是spearheaded，其他是the global push to regulate social media, forcing firms to outline how they are tackling hate speech and child sexual abuse。这个词组表示澳大利亚一直走在规范社交媒体公司的最前沿，迫使这些公司概述它们如何解决仇恨言论和儿童性虐待问题。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作结果状语 - 表示句子动作的结果或后果。    <p>原文例句：These “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去分词短语作结果状语，表示句子动作的结果或后果。结构是：主语 + had/have been + 过去分词 + 其他。其中主语是These “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts，had been是have been的过去式，过去分词是created，其他是a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content。这个词组表示这些“大幅削減”加上数以千计被禁止账户的恢复，为有害内容的传播创造了一个“完美风暴”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The eSafety Commission said the ‘deep cuts’ and reinstatement of banned accounts created a ‘perfect storm’ for the spread of harmful content</li>
<li>Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing firms to outline how they are tackling hate speech and child sexual abuse</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/194a6a33-50f8-40c7-89c1-765fdcb76853_d3339bb6.jpg" /><figcaption>In a photo illustration, the Twitter X logo is displayed on the screen of a smartphone. Photo: SOPA Images/Zuma Press/TNS</figcaption></figure><p>Elon Musk’s X has shed more than 1,000 staff globally from teams responsible for stopping abusive content online, according to new figures released Thursday by Australia’s online watchdog.</p><p>Australia’s eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content.</p><p>The regulator has in recent months zeroed in on X – formerly known as Twitter – previously saying Musk’s takeover coincided with a spike in “toxicity and hate” on the platform.</p><p>Using Australia’s groundbreaking Online Safety Act, the eSafety Commission has obtained a detailed breakdown of software engineers, content moderators and other safety staff working at X.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247497/tech-trade-group-representing-tiktok-snapchat-and-meta-sues-ohio-over-states-new-law-limiting" title="">Tech group with TikTok and Meta sues Ohio over law curbing children’s social media use</a></h3><p>Commissioner Julie Inman Grant, a former Twitter employee, said it was the first time these figures had been made public.</p><p>They showed 1,213 specialist “trust and safety staff”, including contractors, had left X since it was acquired by Musk in October 2022.</p><p>This included 80 per cent of the software engineers focused on “trust and safety issues”, said Inman Grant.</p><p>“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away, it would be like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers,” she told AFP.</p><p>“You’ve got a perfect storm. You’re drastically decreasing your defences, and you’re introducing repeat offenders back onto the platform.”</p><p>Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing tech companies to outline how they are tackling issues such as hate speech and child sexual abuse.</p><p>But attempts to exercise these powers have occasionally been met with indifference. In October last year, the eSafety Commission slapped X with an A$610,500 (US$388,000) fine, saying it had failed to show how it was cracking down on child pornography.</p><p>But X ignored the deadline to pay the fine, before launching ongoing legal action to have it overturned.</p><p>X did not reply to AFP’s request for comment, instead sending an automated response that read “busy now, please check back later”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei ends US lobbying operations after years of fighting ban</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3248018/huawei-ends-us-lobbying-operations-after-years-fighting-ban</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Huawei has ended its lobbying operations in Washington, a move that signifies the culmination of its years-long efforts to maintain a presence in the North American market. The company's lobbying expenses, which reached a peak of $3.6 million in 2021, have dwindled due to the US ban on Huawei products and its inability to access advanced technology. Former Huawei lobbyists and law firms have departed as a result of the company's diminished US presence.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei closes its US lobbying operations.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's withdrawal from the US market and the decline of its influence in Washington.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The effectiveness of the US ban on Huawei and the challenges faced by Chinese companies in operating in the American market.</li>    <li>Main information: Huawei's lobbying expenditures, loss of lobbyists, termination of contracts with law firms, and closure of offices in the US.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  华为公司关闭了其设在华盛顿的游说业务，标志着该公司多年来维持北美市场影响力的努力宣告终结。由于美国禁止华为产品，并阻止其获取先进技术，华为公司的游说支出在 2021 年达到 360 万美元的高峰后，如今已大幅缩减。随着华为在美国的存在感减弱，该公司的前任游说者和律所纷纷离场。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为关闭美国游说业务。</li>    <li>主题：华为退出美国市场，影响力在华盛顿衰落。</li>    <li>观点：美国对华为禁令的有效性，以及中国企业在美国市场运营所面临的挑战。</li>    <li>主要信息：华为的游说支出、游说者的流失、与律所的合同终止以及在美国的办事处关闭。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>shut down (v.) - 关闭，停产。    <P>原文例句：Huawei has shuttered its in-house lobbying operations in Washington.</P>    <P>例句讲解：shut down是shut的过去分词形式，意思是关闭，停产。in-house意为内部的，指华为内部的游说业务。lobbying operations指游说业务。Washington是地名，指美国首都华盛顿。</P></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>decline (n.) - 下降，衰落。    <P>原文例句：The Huawei logo is seen during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai, July 6, 2023. Photo: AFP.</P>    <P>例句讲解：decline是decline的动词形式，意思是下降，衰落。influence指影响力。in Washington意为在华盛顿，指美国首都华盛顿。</P></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>reach a peak - 达到顶峰。    <P>原文例句：At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives. </P>    <p>例句讲解：reach a peak是一个动词短语，意思是达到顶峰。它的结构是：reach + a/the + peak。在这个例句中，it指的是Huawei，peak指的是顶峰。这句话的意思是，华为在鼎盛时期拥有九家游说公司和一支庞大的公关团队。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists there – Jeff Hogg and Donald Morrissey – left in recent months, Bloomberg News found. - 彭博新闻社发现，华为最近几个月失去了其最后两位注册的游说者：杰夫·霍格和唐纳德·莫里西。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists，谓语是left，宾语是recent months。there是地点状语，修饰left。Bloomberg News found是独立主格结构，作状语，修饰left。这句话的意思是，华为最近几个月失去了其最后两位注册的游说者：杰夫·霍格和唐纳德·莫里西，彭博新闻社发现。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has lost outside lobbying firms as well. </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。其结构为：has/have + 过去分词。在这个例句中，has lost是现在完成时态，表示华为公司从过去某个时间开始一直到现在失去了外部游说公司。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, after a years-long effort to maintain a presence in North America</li>
<li>At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/61065c57-e9bf-4bb0-a892-196dc21024cd_6e1ed843.jpg" /><figcaption>The Huawei logo is seen during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai, July 6, 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies, the Chinese wireless equipment maker that spent tens of millions of dollars trying to win over US policymakers only to eventually be blacklisted, has shuttered its in-house lobbying operations in Washington.</p><p>Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists there – Jeff Hogg and Donald Morrissey – left in recent months, Bloomberg News found. The Shenzhen, China-based firm did not respond to multiple requests for comment.</p><p>The lobbyists’ recent departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, and marks a quiet end to the company’s costly, years-long effort to maintain presence in the North American market. The firm reached its peak by supplying small mobile firms across the US even as major carriers shunned it. Rising tensions with Beijing eventually all but banned it.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" title="">Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets</a></h3><p>More than a decade ago, Washington officials began warning of Huawei’s ability to embed spying capabilities in its gear, which was present in thousands of cell towers and other network equipment in the US. The company pushed back on those claims, saying its products posed no threat, but American regulators by 2022 had barred the company from selling products in the US and moved to starve it of access to cutting-edge technology.</p><p>At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives. Executives were known to regularly arrange briefings with congressional offices and major newsrooms. The company spent more than US$13 million lobbying in the past 10 years, according to federal filings.</p><p>In a single quarter of 2019, Huawei’s federal lobbying spending totaled US$1.8 million, a six-fold increase from the previous year. It spent US$3.6 million on lobbying in the US in 2021, according to the filings. Some of that went to glitzy parties populated by high-profile hired guns including veteran Democratic lobbyist Tony Podesta, who made US$1 million from Huawei that year, according to disclosures with the US Senate. Podesta said in a filing that his work for Huawei ended on December 30, 2022.</p><p>With a ban firmly in place and its US business scant, Huawei has little reason to keep burning through lobbying cash in Washington. “The US market isn’t a likely place for a breakthrough for Huawei in the near future,” said Chris Pereira, a former Huawei public relations executive and founder of the consultancy iMpact.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/e55aff24-0f6a-4156-9c60-9d12d7c1fc31_ac707f82.jpg" title="A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Morrissey, who lobbied for both Huawei and Futurewei, confirmed in a LinkedIn message that he left the company in December. He said he is now the senior director of government affairs at the battery technology company Gotion. Hogg, who had served as Huawei’s head of government relations since 2020, left the company in November, according to his LinkedIn profile. He did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p>The company has lost outside lobbying firms as well. Imperium Global Advisors and LeMunyon Group terminated their contracts with Futurewei, Huawei’s US-based research arm, in November 2023, according to filings with the Senate. And Squire Patton Boggs, a global law firm, has not reported lobbying activity to Congress on Futurewei’s behalf since the beginning of 2023. Former US Representative Lee Terry, Republican of Nebraska, terminated his lobbying contract with Huawei at the end of 2022. according to filings with the Senate.</p><p>By October, the only firm registered as working on Huawei’s behalf was Sidley Austin, which did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p>Huawei itself has filed its own notice that it was terminating lobbying efforts at the Capitol. The company has also ceased operations at offices in Plano, Texas, Trey Smith, executive vice-president at CBRE, a real estate services firm that handles leases for the building, said in an email.</p><p>In response to Huawei’s ban, China’s government has accused the US of abusing state power to hobble Chinese companies. Huawei in recent months offered its own de facto response, producing a new phone using highly advanced technology the US has been trying to keep out of China’s hands. The company says revenue surged 9 per cent in 2023, in part thanks to the new phone.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s Taobao and Tmall Group pushes new AI tools to boost merchants’ service to consumers in first major move after leadership reshuffle</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247985/alibabas-taobao-and-tmall-group-pushes-new-ai-tools-boost-merchants-service-consumers-first-major</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Taobao and Tmall Group (TTG) are introducing new AI features to improve services and attract customers for merchants on their e-commerce platforms. This initiative aims to enhance customer interaction, provide more exposure to quality merchants, and face competition from rivals like JD.com and emerging platforms.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: TTG adopts AI tools to enhance merchant services and competitiveness.</li>    <li>Theme: AI-powered customer service and exposure strategies for merchants on TTG's e-commerce platforms.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: TTG's efforts to stay competitive in China's e-commerce market by leveraging AI technology and improving merchant support.</li>    <li>Main information: Introduction of the AI-upgraded Dianxiaomi chatbot for customer service; focus on quality merchants for increased exposure; competition from JD.com and younger platforms.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  淘宝和天猫集团（TTG）正在引入新的AI功能，以改善其电子商务平台上商家的服务并吸引客户。该倡议旨在增强客户互动，为优质商家提供更多曝光，并应对来自京东等竞争对手和新兴平台的竞争。  <ul>    <li>摘要：TTG采用AI工具来增强商家服务和竞争力。</li>    <li>主题：针对TTG电子商务平台上的商家的AI驱动的客户服务和曝光策略。</li>    <li>观点：TTG通过利用AI技术和改进商家支持来保持在中国电子商务市场竞争力的努力。</li>    <li>主要信息：推出AI升级的Dianxiaomi聊天机器人进行客户服务；着重为优质商家提供更多曝光；来自京东和年轻平台的竞争。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>exposure (n.) - /ɪkˈspəʊʒə/ 曝光，显眼的位置。    <p>原文例句：TTG also vowed to provide “quality merchants” more exposure to consumers, from the homepage to advertised search results, TTG announced at the event. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于expose，意为“暴露，使显眼”。在这个例句中，它表示TTG承诺为“优质商家”提供更多曝光，从主页到广告搜索结果。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>platform (n.) - /ˈplætfɔːrm/ 平台，舞台。    <p>原文例句：TTG also vowed to provide “quality merchants” more exposure to consumers, from the homepage to advertised search results, TTG announced at the event. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于old French，意为“平台，舞台”。在这个例句中，它表示TTG承诺为“优质商家”提供更多曝光，从主页到广告搜索结果。</p></li>  </ul> </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>drive off - 赶走，赶跑。    <p>原文例句：TTG’s adoption of AI tools shows the effort being made by the Alibaba unit to fend off increased competition from main domestic rival JD.com and the challenge from younger platforms, such as PDD Holdings’ Pinduoduo and ByteDance-owned Douyin.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由drive（开车）和off（离开）构成的，表示“赶走，赶跑”。在这个例句中，它表示TTG采用AI工具表明阿里巴巴部门为抵御来自主要国内竞争对手京东和来自年轻平台（如拼多多和字节跳动旗下的抖音）的挑战所做的努力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Before TTG’s latest initiative, Alibaba’s international business-to-business wholesale marketplace Alibaba.com in November announced a new AI tool to help the platform’s merchants automate their client-facing operations, including writing emails, to entice more customers overseas.<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Alibaba.com announced a new AI tool to help the platform’s merchants automate their client-facing operations, 其中主语是Alibaba.com，谓语是announced，宾语是a new AI tool to help the platform’s merchants automate their client-facing operations。Before TTG’s latest initiative是一个过去分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示在TTG的最新举措之前。including writing emails, to entice more customers overseas是一个不定式短语作目的状语，修饰help the platform’s merchants automate their client-facing operations，表示帮助平台上的商家自动化他们的客户服务操作，包括撰写电子邮件，以吸引更多海外客户。这个句子的意思是说，在TTG的最新举措之前，阿里巴巴的国际B2B批发市场阿里巴巴国际站于11月宣布了一款新的AI工具，以帮助平台上的商家自动化他们的客户服务操作，包括撰写电子邮件，以吸引更多海外客户。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示过去发生的动作或状态一直持续到现在。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul> <li>现在进行时 - 表示现在正在发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba Group Holding’s main e-commerce unit is now beta testing artificial intelligence (AI) tools and functions for merchants on its Chinese online shopping sites, marking the first major move at the enterprise since a leadership reshuffle in December.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态正在现在进行，强调动作或状态的动态性和进行性。在这个例句中，它表示阿里巴巴集团的主要电子商务部门目前正在对其中国在线购物网站上的商家进行人工智能（AI）工具和功能的测试，这标志着自12月份领导层改组以来该企业的第一项重大举措。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Taobao and Tmall Group’s AI initiative is geared towards helping merchants improve their services and attract new customers</li>
<li>An AI-upgraded customer service chatbot, Dianxiaomi, is expected to be available to all Taobao and Tmall sellers by June</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/a64d09cb-4f09-4901-b140-db8cdc3ed1d4_a2cf7620.jpg" /><figcaption>Taobao and Tmall Group’s adoption of artificial intelligence tools shows the Alibaba Group Holding unit’s effort to fend off increased competition in China’s e-commerce market. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>’s main <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> unit is now beta testing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) tools and functions for merchants on its Chinese online shopping sites, marking the first major move at the enterprise since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245680/alibaba-names-new-taobao-and-tmall-ceo-major-move-fend-competition" target="_self" title="">a leadership reshuffle in December</a>.</p><p>The Taobao and Tmall Group (TTG) unveiled the new AI features, which are designed to improve services and attract new customers, at its “sellers’ conference” held on Tuesday in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hangzhou" target="_self" title="">Hangzhou</a>, capital of eastern Zhejiang province and home base of South China Morning Post owner Alibaba.</p><p>TTG said AI models would be employed to transform Dianxiaomi, a customer service chatbot, to enhance seller-consumer interaction. That will include tasks such as pre- and post-sales service, data analysis and other online sales activities.</p><p>The updated Dianxiaomi, which is currently undergoing tests with a select group of sellers, will be made available to all merchants by June, according to TTG. It said the accuracy rate of Dianxiaomi’s response time has so far improved to 85 per cent.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/342c70b0-1832-40c4-bff8-11fa840de980_6cb4cf92.jpg" title="The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>TTG also vowed to provide “quality merchants” more exposure to consumers, from the homepage to advertised search results, TTG announced at the event.</p><p>TTG’s adoption of AI tools shows the effort being made by the Alibaba unit to fend off increased competition from main domestic rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> and the challenge from younger platforms, such as PDD Holdings’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="">Pinduoduo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>.</p><p>The move comes weeks after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245680/alibaba-names-new-taobao-and-tmall-ceo-major-move-fend-competition" target="_self" title="">Eddie Wu Yongming</a> was named the new chief executive at TTG, replacing Trudy Dai Shan. TTG subsequently <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals" target="_self" title="">promoted six millennial executives</a> to lead key departments.</p><p>Before TTG’s latest initiative, Alibaba’s international business-to-business wholesale marketplace <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" target="_self" title="">Alibaba.com in November announced a new AI tool</a> to help the platform’s merchants automate their client-facing operations, including writing emails, to entice more customers overseas.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" title="">Alibaba pushes new AI tool to help wholesale merchants manage overseas clients</a></h3><p>At the seller’s event in Hangzhou, TTG said internal statistics showed that five-star-rated sellers enjoy a significantly higher repurchase rate than certain 3-star stores on its platform. The repurchase rate at five-star pet supply stores, for example, is about 127 per cent higher than those of 3-star peers.</p><p>TTG on Tuesday also said it will launch a new rating system for online shops, focusing on indicators related to consumer services. These indicators include the “rejection rate of refund request” and “platform intervention rate”, which weigh on consumers’ purchasing decisions.</p><p>Late in December, both JD.com and Taobao said they will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" target="_self" title="">offer a “refund only” policy</a> so consumers can keep the goods they had bought but complained about – matching an option that budget online retailer Pinduoduo has had in place since 2021.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US regulator SEC authorises bitcoin-spot ETFs in cryptocurrency breakthrough</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) has approved exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that invest directly in bitcoin, marking a landmark event for the digital asset sector. </li>    <li>The approval came after years of opposition from the SEC, with concerns over fraud and manipulation in the bitcoin market. </li>    <li>The SEC's decision follows a ruling by a federal appeals court that called the denial of a different bitcoin ETF application "arbitrary and capricious." </li>    <li>The approval of bitcoin ETFs is expected to broaden access to the digital asset, potentially leading to increased institutional investment. </li>    <li>The SEC's move is seen as a sign of growing maturity in the bitcoin industry, following a series of scandals and bankruptcies in the sector. </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  <ul>    <li>美国证券交易委员会 (SEC) 批准了直接投资比特币的交易所交易基金 (ETF)，这标志着数字资产领域的里程碑事件。</li>    <li>在 SEC 多年反对后，由于担心比特币市场的欺诈和操纵，该批准得以实现。</li>    <li>SEC 的决定是在联邦上诉法院裁定另一只比特币 ETF 申请被拒绝“武断且反复无常”之后做出的。</li>    <li>比特币 ETF 的获批有望扩大对数字资产的访问，可能导致更多的机构投资。</li>    <li>继该行业发生一系列丑闻和破产事件后，SEC 的举措被视为比特币行业日益成熟的标志。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>mark (v.) - /mɑːrk/ 标记，标注。    <p>原文例句：The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs</p>    <p>例句讲解：“mark”在这里作及物动词，意思是“标记，标注”。它表示美国证券交易委员会 (SEC) 的 X 账户上的一篇虚假帖子声称该机构已批准 ETF，这一事件发生在 SEC 批准 ETF 的前一天。</p></li>    <li>surveillance (n.) - /sɜːrˈveɪləns/ 监视，监督。    <p>原文例句：Because the CME’s surveillance can assist in detecting those impacts on CME bitcoin futures prices, the exchanges’ comprehensive surveillance-sharing agreement with the CME – a US regulated market whose bitcoin futures market is consistently highly correlated to spot bitcoin, albeit not of ‘significant size’ related to spot bitcoin – can be reasonably expected to assist in surveilling for fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices in the specific context of the proposals,” the order said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“surveillance”在这里作名词，意思是“监视，监督”。它表示芝加哥商品交易所 (CME) 具有监视能力，有助于检测那些对 CME 比特币期货价格的影响，因此，交易所与 CME 签订的全面监视共享协议——CME 是美国受监管的市场，其比特币期货市场与现货比特币始终高度相关，尽管与现货比特币相关的“规模不大”——可以合理地预期有助于在提案的具体背景下监视欺诈和操纵行为和做法。</p></li>    <li>correlation (n.) - /ˌkɒrɪˈleɪʃən/ 相关性，关联性。    <p>原文例句：In reviewing the latest set of proposals, the SEC said it examined the correlation between spot and futures trading at a variety of time intervals and concluded prices moved in such a way that irregularities on exchanges such as Kraken and Coinbase were likely to show up in the futures.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“correlation”在这里作名词，意思是“相关性，关联性”。它表示美国证券交易委员会 (SEC) 在审查最新一批提案时，表示其检查了现货和期货交易在不同时间段的相关性，并得出结论，价格以这种方式波动，以致于在 Kraken 和 Coinbase 等交易所的异常情况很可能在期货中显现出来。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>false post - 虚假帖子。    <p>原文例句：The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs</p>    <p>例句讲解：“false post”在这里是一个名词词组，意思是“虚假帖子”。它表示美国证券交易委员会 (SEC) X 账户上的一篇虚假帖子声称该机构已批准 ETF，这一事件发生在 SEC 批准 ETF 的前一天。</p></li>    <li>exchange-traded funds (ETFs) - 交易所交易基金 (ETF)。    <p>原文例句：US regulators for the first time approved exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that invest directly in bitcoin, a move heralded as a landmark event for the roughly US$1.7 trillion digital-asset sector that will broaden access to the largest cryptocurrency on Wall Street and beyond.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“exchange-traded funds (ETFs)”在这里是一个名词词组，意思是“交易所交易基金 (ETF)”。它表示美国监管机构首次批准了直接投资比特币的交易所交易基金 (ETF)，此举被誉为数字资产领域约 1.7 万亿美元的里程碑事件，将拓宽在华尔街及其他地区获取最大加密货币的渠道。</p></li>    <li>the denial of a different application - 拒绝另一项申请。    <p>原文例句：BlackRock’s surprise application last June, followed by an appeals court ruling that called the denial of a different application “arbitrary and capricious,” triggered a blistering rally in the cryptocurrency as speculation that US regulators would finally give their blessing to the structure.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“the denial of a different application”在这里是一个名词词组，意思是“拒绝另一项申请”。它表示在去年 6 月黑岩提交了令人惊讶的申请后，上诉法院裁定拒绝另一项申请“武断且反复无常”，引发了一波加密货币的飙涨，原因是人们猜测美国监管机构最终会批准这种结构。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Securities and Exchange Commission, whose three-part mandate includes investor protection, authorised funds from industry heavyweights BlackRock, Invesco and Fidelity to smaller competitors including Valkyrie to begin trading Thursday. - 美国证券交易委员会的三部分任务包括保护投资者，该委员会授权行业巨头黑岩、英伟达和富达等向较小的竞争对手，包括 Valkyrie 提供资金，以便在周四开始交易。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是The Securities and Exchange Commission authorised funds to begin trading Thursday，其中主语是The Securities and Exchange Commission，谓语是authorised，宾语是funds。whose three-part mandate includes investor protection是一个定语从句，修饰The Securities and Exchange Commission，表示美国证券交易委员会的三部分任务包括保护投资者。from industry heavyweights BlackRock, Invesco and Fidelity to smaller competitors including Valkyrie是一个介词短语，表示从行业巨头黑岩、英伟达和富达等向较小的竞争对手，包括 Valkyrie 提供资金。这个句子表示，美国证券交易委员会的三部分任务包括保护投资者，该委员会授权行业巨头黑岩、英伟达和富达等向较小的竞争对手，包括 Valkyrie 提供资金，以便在周四开始交易。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>非谓语动词 - 动词的非谓语形式，包括不定式、动名词、现在分词和过去分词。    <p>原文例句：In reviewing the latest set of proposals, the SEC said it examined the correlation between spot and futures trading at a variety of time intervals and concluded prices moved in such a way that irregularities on exchanges such as Kraken and Coinbase were likely to show up in the futures.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，动词examined、concluded和show up都是非谓语动词。examined是过去分词，作定语，修饰proposals，表示美国证券交易委员会审查了最新一批提案。concluded是过去分词，作状语，表示美国证券交易委员会得出结论。show up是现在分词，作目的状语，表示异常情况很可能在期货中显现出来。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade</li>
<li>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/df6929be-b19f-4119-85e5-a531ae26273d_52ea2e34.jpg" /><figcaption>A bitcoin is seen in an illustration picture taken in Paris, France, June 23, 2017. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>US regulators for the first time approved exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that invest directly in bitcoin, a move heralded as a landmark event for the roughly US$1.7 trillion digital-asset sector that will broaden access to the largest cryptocurrency on Wall Street and beyond.</p><p>The Securities and Exchange Commission, whose three-part mandate includes investor protection, authorised funds from industry heavyweights BlackRock, Invesco and Fidelity to smaller competitors including Valkyrie to begin trading Thursday.</p><p>The approvals also mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade, ever since Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss first proposed a bitcoin ETF in 2013. BlackRock’s surprise application last June, followed by an appeals court ruling that called the denial of a different application “arbitrary and capricious,” triggered a blistering rally in the cryptocurrency as speculation that US regulators would finally give their blessing to the structure.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239953/hong-kongs-hashkey-launches-first-crypto-trading-app-retail-investors-gives-away-new-token" title="">Hong Kong gets first crypto trading app for retail investors</a></h3><p>“While we approved the listing and trading of certain spot bitcoin ETP shares today, we did not approve or endorse bitcoin,” SEC Chair Gary Gensler said in a statement. “Investors should remain cautious about the myriad risks associated with bitcoin and products whose value is tied to crypto.”</p><p>At the crux of the SEC’s previous rulings against a spot ETF was the argument that no regulated exchange was able to adequately monitor bitcoin trading in a way that would reliably detect fraud and manipulation. That contention was opposed by Cathie Wood’s Ark Investments, among others, which provided data showing a high correlation between cash trading and the futures contracts that trade on CME Group’s platform.</p><p>In reviewing the latest set of proposals, the SEC said it examined the correlation between spot and futures trading at a variety of time intervals and concluded prices moved in such a way that irregularities on exchanges such as Kraken and Coinbase were likely to show up in the futures.</p><p>“Because the CME’s surveillance can assist in detecting those impacts on CME bitcoin futures prices, the exchanges’ comprehensive surveillance-sharing agreement with the CME – a US regulated market whose bitcoin futures market is consistently highly correlated to spot bitcoin, albeit not of ‘significant size’ related to spot bitcoin – can be reasonably expected to assist in surveilling for fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices in the specific context of the proposals,” the order said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246909/crypto-services-firm-linked-huobi-sees-losses-expand-40-cent-ftx-funds-still-out-reach" title="">Losses mount at Huobi-linked crypto firm while FTX funds still out of reach</a></h3><p>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs. The regulator subsequently said that the account had been compromised, causing the price of bitcoin to fluctuate widely.</p><p>Gensler voted along side the agency’s two Republicans to back exchanges’ plans to list the products, the SEC’s website showed. The regulator’s two other Democrats voted against the proposals.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/9a0bebf2-048a-459e-9a2e-2dd720360177_a66cec46.jpg" title="The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Bitcoin rose about 3.4 per cent to US$47,500 following the approvals. The original cryptocurrency, which sank 64 per cent in 2022, more than doubled in 2023 in large part because of speculation that the SEC would eventually approve ETFs that will allow investors to get exposure to the token in their traditional brokerage accounts instead of one of the crypto-native start-ups that have come under increasing government scrutiny following a series of sector scandals and bankruptcies.</p><p>“The approval means that both retail and institutional investors now have the ability to diversify their portfolio with crypto exposure without worrying about the complicated issues of custody,” said Campbell Harvey, finance professor at Duke University. “The ETF makes it easy to add to your portfolio.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246538/china-calls-tougher-crackdown-use-crypto-illegal-forex-trading" title="">China calls for tougher crackdown on use of crypto for illegal forex trading</a></h3><p>Crypto proponents have for years argued that a so-called spot fund that invests directly in bitcoin would be beneficial to investors and would help bring the industry closer to the more highly regulated world of traditional finance. It also suggests a sort of milestone of maturity for the relatively nascent industry, where skirmishes with regulators came to a climax after the collapse of Sam Bankman-Fried’s FTX empire highlighted risks lurking in the industry.</p><p>The landmark decision comes after Grayscale Investments won a key victory over the SEC. A federal appeals court had overturned the rejection of Grayscale’s application to convert its bitcoin trust into an ETF. The court called the denial “arbitrary and capricious” because the commission failed to explain its different treatment of similar products. ETFs that hold bitcoin futures were approved in 2021.</p><p>The SEC’s loss to Grayscale was one of the reasons why the SEC approved the applications, Gensler said in Tuesday’s statement.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China rich list compiler Hurun clarifies Tsinghua graduate Zhang Zetian’s ranking to quell online controversy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247956/china-rich-list-compiler-hurun-clarifies-tsinghua-graduate-zhang-zetians-ranking-quell-online</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>According to Hurun's ranking, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates who became billionaires in China.</li>    <li>Zhang Zetian, wife of tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, was listed as the third-richest Tsinghua graduate, sparking controversy online.</li>    <li>Hurun clarified that Zhang's wealth is jointly owned with her husband, addressing questions about her personal wealth.</li>    <li>The ranking highlights the scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>根据胡润的排名，清华大学和浙江大学培养出最多的毕业生成为中国亿万富翁。</li>    <li>京东创始人刘强东的妻子张泽天被列为清华大学第三富有毕业生，引发网上争议。</li>    <li>胡润澄清，张的财富与丈夫共同拥有，回应了质疑她个人财富的质疑。</li>    <li>这项排名凸显了中国对个人财富和收入不平等的审查。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>massive (adj.) - /ˈmæsɪv/ 庞大的，巨大的。    <p>原文例句：However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle English，由masse（块，体积）演变而来，表示“庞大的，巨大的”。在这个例句中，它指的是张泽天所谓的巨大财富，即她是否真的拥有如此庞大的财富受到质疑。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>jointly (adv.) - /ˈdʒɔɪntli/ 共同地，联合地。    <p>原文例句：In the case of Tsinghua’s Zhang, her 60 billion yuan worth falls under her and [husband] Liu jointly.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由joint（结合，连接）和-ly（后缀，表示方式或状态）组成，表示“共同地，联合地”。在这个例句中，它指的是张泽天和刘强东共同拥有600亿人民币的财富，即她的财富是她和丈夫共同拥有的。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>短语：</h2>  <ul>    <li>under scrutiny - 受到审查，受到密切关注。    <p>原文例句：The controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语是由under（在……下面）和scrutiny（审查，密切关注）组成的，表示“受到审查，受到密切关注”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国对个人财富和收入不平等的审查加剧，即中国对个人财富和收入不平等的审查更加严格。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>According to a list published by Hurun last Friday, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China. - 根据胡润上周五发布的榜单，清华大学和浙江大学培养出最多的毕业生成为中国亿万富翁。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是According to a list published by Hurun last Friday，谓语是have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China，宾语是Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University。这个句子的意思是说，根据胡润上周五发布的榜单，清华大学和浙江大学培养出最多的毕业生成为中国亿万富翁。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are two of the most high-profile and richest graduates to have come from Peking University and Wuhan University, respectively. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是two of the most high-profile and richest graduates，表示北京大学和武汉大学分别培养出两位最知名和最富有的毕业生。这个句子的意思是说，北京大学和武汉大学分别培养出两位最知名和最富有的毕业生。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>According to Hurun, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China</li>
<li>Zhang ranked behind Meituan founder Wang Xing and Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/22f80ee8-51eb-4f11-94d0-38c9096e305d_32c40a21.jpg" /><figcaption>JD.com chairman Richard Liu Qiangdong and wife Zhang Zetian at Princess Eugenie’s wedding. Photo: YouTube </figcaption></figure><p>The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.</p><p>According to a list published by Hurun last Friday, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China. And 30-year-old Zhang was ranked as the third-richest graduate from Tsinghua, with a net worth of 60 billion yuan (US$8.4 billion).</p><p>Zhang ranked behind 44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan and 62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group. However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p><p>Hurun issued a statement on Monday to clarify its methodology for the ranking of rich Chinese alumni. “In the case of Tsinghua’s Zhang, her 60 billion yuan worth falls under her and [husband] Liu jointly.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239156/chinese-tech-founders-bounce-back-huruns-2023-rich-list-number-and-overall-wealth-billionaires-drop" title="">Chinese tech billionaires move up Hurun 2023 Rich List amid internet rebound</a></h3><p>The controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China. According to a separate rich list published by Forbes in November 2023, the net worth of Liu, founder and chairman of e-commerce giant JD.com, was US$4.7 billion, ranking No. 69 in China’s top 100 rich list.</p><p>Liu’s celebrity-style marriage to Zhang is also rare among Chinese tech billionaires, with many maintaining a low profile when it comes to family matters.</p><p>The Tsinghua alumni rich list was part of a Hurun Most Successful University Alumni 2023 ranking the research firm released. Hurun defined the “most successful alumni” to include former full-time undergraduates, postgraduates and those entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</p><p>A total of 58 universities, 45 Chinese and 13 overseas, have at least three alumni on the Hurun China Rich List 2023. Tsinghua and Zhejiang University topped the list, each with 32 alumni on the list.</p><p>Peking University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, and Wuhan University came in third, fourth and fifth with 22, 21, and 17 alumni respectively on the list.</p><p>Robin Li Yanhong, founder, chairman and CEO of Baidu, and Xiaomi chairman and CEO Lei Jun are two of the most high-profile and richest graduates to have come from Peking University and Wuhan University, respectively, according to the list.</p><p>Outside China, Stanford University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, University of California, Yale University and Harvard University from the US were the top five institutions with the most Hurun China Rich listers.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
