<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Apple gets deeper into China’s smartphone price wars with widening iPhone discounts, but rival Huawei stays above the fray</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248666/apple-gets-deeper-chinas-smartphone-price-wars-widening-iphone-discounts-rival-huawei-stays-above</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple topped the global smartphone market in 2023 with 20.1% market share, dethroning Samsung.</li>    <li>Apple's iPhone 15 sales in China are facing fierce competition, with discounts of up to US$112 compared to Apple's own price cut of 500 yuan.</li>    <li>Chinese smartphone vendors like Xiaomi and Honor are also lowering prices on their Android models, while Huawei is not pursuing a similar strategy.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>苹果公司2023年以20.1%的市场份额登顶全球智能手机市场，击败了长期市场领导者三星。</li>    <li>苹果iPhone 15在中国的销售面临激烈竞争，与苹果公司自身500元的降价相比，iPhone 15最高降价800元。</li>    <li>小米、荣耀等中国智能手机厂商也在对旗下安卓机型降价，而华为暂未采取类似策略。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unseat (v.) - /ʌnˈsit/ 击败，取代。    <p>原文例句：Apple topped global smartphone shipments in 2023 to unseat long-standing market leader Samsung, according to research firm IDC. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于un-（否定）和seat（座位），表示“使失去位置，击败”。在这个例句中，它描述了苹果在2023年击败了长期市场领导者三星，登上了全球智能手机市场榜首。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>discount (n.) - /ˈdɪskaʊnt/ 折扣，减价。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s atypical discount drive on the mainland shows the US tech giant’s focus to gain ground in the world’s second-biggest economy amid sluggish global iPhone sales. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于dis-（分开）和count（计算），表示“扣除，减价”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果在中国大陆进行的非典型的折扣活动，这表明了这家美国科技巨头希望在全球iPhone销售疲软的情况下，在中国这个全球第二大经济体中获得更多市场份额。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>fierce (adj.) - /fɪərs/ 激烈的，猛烈的。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s iPhone 15 sales in China are facing fierce competition, with discounts of up to US$112 compared to Apple’s own price cut of 500 yuan.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle English，由firce（残忍的）和-ce（后缀）组成，表示“残忍的，猛烈的”。在这个例句中，它描述了苹果iPhone 15在中国销售时面临的激烈竞争，其价格折扣高达112美元，而苹果自身的价格折扣仅为500元人民币。</p></li>     </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>price war - 价格战。    <p>原文例句：A price war in mainland China, the world’s largest smartphone market, has intensified amid widening discounts offered for iPhones by online marketplaces. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由price（价格）和war（战争）构成，表示“价格战”。在这个例句中，它指的是在中国大陆，作为全球最大的智能手机市场，由于在线市场对iPhone提供的折扣不断扩大，价格战已经加剧。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>smartphone vendor - 智能手机厂商。    <p>原文例句：Apple was also the sole smartphone vendor in the top-four rankings – including Samsung, Xiaomi and Oppo – to record unit shipment growth in 2023.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由smartphone（智能手机）和vendor（厂商）组成，表示“智能手机厂商”。在这个例句中，它指的是在2023年，苹果是排名前四的智能手机厂商中唯一一家记录到出货量增长的厂商，其他三家分别是三星、小米和OPPO。</p></li>    </ul>  <ul><li>Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com on Monday touted discounts of as much as US$112 off on the iPhone 15, higher than Apple’s own local price markdown</li>
<li>Apple topped global smartphone shipments in 2023 to unseat long-standing market leader Samsung, according to research firm IDC</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/66dac82e-619d-4ada-b6cc-c633141a8133_2a932251.jpg" /><figcaption>The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors knocked down prices on their various Android handsets in both online and offline retail campaigns. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>A price war in mainland China, the world’s largest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> market, has intensified amid widening discounts offered for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhones</a> by online marketplaces, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> unseated rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a> in annual industry shipments worldwide for the first time in 2023.</p><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> on Monday touted deeper discounts of as much as 800 yuan (US$112.24) off on the latest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3235981/apple-iphone-15-review-faster-cheaper-new-standard-models-are-big-jump-over-their-predecessors" target="_self" title="">iPhone 15</a> model in a post on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a>, which was on the same day <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248529/apples-china-price-cuts-iphones-macbooks-cancel-out-pressure-rivals-chasing-premium-segment-say" target="_self" title="">Apple offered to cut prices by up to 500 yuan</a> on a range of models, including the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3148864/apples-iphone-13-may-not-have-many-new-features-its-lower-price-tag" target="_self" title="">iPhone 13</a> and its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235532/apples-iphone-15-draws-long-lines-china-despite-competition-huawei" target="_self" title="">new handsets that debuted last September</a>.</p><p>The latest iPhone markdowns have come as major Chinese smartphone vendors, including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honor" target="_self" title="">Honor</a>, knocked down prices on their various Android models in both online and offline retail campaigns. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, which last year <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china" target="_self" title="">made a comeback in the 5G smartphone market</a>, did not pursue a similar strategy.</p><p>Apple’s atypical discount drive on the mainland shows the US tech giant’s focus to gain ground in the world’s second-biggest economy amid sluggish global iPhone sales, which has seen the company <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">hit by two ratings downgrades</a> in the first week of this year.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/49690f1b-f395-4601-bae1-959ea30c7d93_ca1ba25a.jpg" title="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro smartphones are seen on display at its store in Shanghai on September 8, 2023. The Shenzhen-based company has so far not pushed to mark down the prices of its latest 5G handsets. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Apple faced more challenges in China compared to the rest of the world,” said Will Wong, senior research manager for client devices at IDC Asia-Pacific. “It not only faced competition from Huawei, but also a change in consumers’ sentiment that is now more cautious in spending.”</p><p>In the first week of the year, iPhone sales on the mainland were already down 30 per cent year on year, according to a Jefferies research note published on January 7. The brokerage indicated that there was “a big rise in discounts” for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3209228/apple-cuts-iphone-14-prices-china-us125-making-rare-sales-push-following-quarterly-revenue-drop" target="_self" title="">iPhone 14</a> and 14 Plus models, while the newer iPhone 15 and 15 Plus models saw “a moderate rise” in discounts.</p><p>The iPhone’s total sales volume last year on the mainland was down 3 per cent from 2022, which translated to a 0.4 per cent decline in Apple’s market share, according to Jefferies.</p><p>Worries about smartphone demand have pushed Apple’s shares down this month, enabling <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="">Microsoft</a> to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248395/microsoft-overtakes-apple-worlds-most-valuable-company-us289-trillion-market-capitalisation" target="_self" title="">become the world’s most valuable company</a> after ending the January 12 trading session in the US higher than the iPhone maker.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3248395/microsoft-overtakes-apple-worlds-most-valuable-company-us289-trillion-market-capitalisation" title="">Microsoft overtakes Apple as world’s most valuable company at US$2.89 trillion</a></h3><p>Still, Apple received some good news on Monday when research firm IDC reported that the Cupertino, California-based company topped global smartphone shipments last year to dethrone long-standing market leader Samsung.</p><p>Apple’s global smartphone shipments last year reached 234.6 million units that gave the company a record market share of 20.1 per cent, up 3.7 per cent from 226.3 million in 2022, according to IDC. Apple was also the sole smartphone vendor in the top-four rankings – including Samsung, Xiaomi and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> – to record unit shipment growth in 2023.</p><p>On the intense global smartphone competition, the “overall Android space is diversifying within itself”, said Ryan Reith, group vice-president at IDC’s Worldwide Mobility and Consumer Device Trackers unit. “Huawei is back and making inroads quickly within China.”</p><p>Shenzhen-based Huawei’s return to the premium segment of the smartphone market was paved by its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china" target="_self" title="">launch last August of the Mate 60 Pro 5G handset</a>, powered by an advanced home-grown processor that defied US tech restrictions. The company’s new 5G smartphone and its advanced chip was hailed as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">symbolic of China’s victory in defying tough US sanctions</a>, fanning strong patriotic fervour that translated into robust domestic sales.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain" title="">Huawei’s Mate 60 Pro is a blow to US sanctions but battles remain, analysts say</a></h3><p>Huawei, however, faces a supply shortage for the Mate 60 Pro because of production constraints. The popular 5G model is still subject to a reservation purchase scheme without immediate availability on the company’s official website.</p><p>As Apple and its Chinese rivals turn to price promotions amid the weak macroeconomic environment on the mainland, Huawei will need to rely on the strength of its brand name to weather these headwinds, according to IDC’s Wong.</p><p>“The production constraints seem like a hurdle to Huawei, but it may also be a marketing tactic [to create greater demand],” Wong said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>HashKey claims ‘unicorn status’ after raising US$100 million for one of Hong Kong’s two licensed cryptocurrency exchanges</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248601/hashkey-claims-unicorn-status-after-raising-us100-million-one-hong-kongs-two-licensed-cryptocurrency</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>HashKey Group, a Hong Kong-based cryptocurrency exchange, has raised nearly US$100 million in funding, giving it a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion.</li>    <li>The funding round was led by OKX Ventures, the investment arm of one of the world's largest cryptocurrency exchanges, OKX.</li>    <li>HashKey plans to use the funding to "solidify" its web3 ecosystem, diversify its licensed product offerings in Hong Kong, and develop its business globally.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>总部位于香港的加密货币交易所 HashKey Group 已筹集近 1 亿美元资金，使其估值达到 12 亿美元。</li>    <li>此轮融资由全球最大加密货币交易所之一 OKX 的投资部门 OKX Ventures 领投。</li>    <li>HashKey 计划利用这笔资金来“巩固”其 web3 生态系统、使其在香港的持牌产品多元化，以及在全球范围内发展业务。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>valuation (n.) - /ˌvæljuˈeɪʃ(ə)n/ 估值。    <p>原文例句：Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, HashKey Group said</p>    <p>例句讲解：“valuation”意为“估值”，是指对某项资产或公司的价值进行评估。在这个例句中，“valuation”是指 HashKey Group 在新一轮融资前的估值。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>ecosystem (n.) - /ˈiːkəʊsɪstəm/ 生态系统。    <p>原文例句：HashKey plans to use the funding to "solidify" its web3 ecosystem, diversify its licensed product offerings in Hong Kong, and develop its business globally.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“ecosystem”意为“生态系统”，是指由生物及其赖以生存的环境共同组成的一个功能系统。在这个例句中，“ecosystem”是指 HashKey Group 的 web3 生态系统。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>diversify (v.) - /dɪˈvɜːsɪfaɪ/ 多样化，使多样化。    <p>原文例句：HashKey plans to use the funding to ... diversify its licensed product offerings in Hong Kong, and develop its business globally.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“diversify”意为“使多样化”，是指使某事物变得更加多样化。在这个例句中，“diversify”是指 HashKey Group 计划使其在香港的持牌产品多样化。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>pre-money valuation - 在获得融资前的估值。    <P>原文例句：Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, HashKey Group said</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由pre-（在……之前）和money（金钱）以及valuation（估值）构成的，表示“在获得融资前的估值”。在这个例句中，它表示HashKey Group在获得这轮融资前的估值为12亿美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>venture capital funding - 风险投资资金。    <P>原文例句：Venture capital funding in the cryptocurrency industry plunged last year following a series of collapses in 2022.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由venture capital（风险投资）和funding（资金）构成的，表示“风险投资资金”。在这个例句中，它表示加密货币行业的风险投资资金在2022年的一系列崩溃后暴跌。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>HashKey Group, a Hong Kong-based cryptocurrency exchange, has raised nearly US$100 million in funding, giving it a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion. - 香港加密货币交易所 HashKey Group 已筹集近 1 亿美元资金，使其估值达到 12 亿美元。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是 HashKey Group has raised nearly US$100 million in funding，其中主语是 HashKey Group，谓语是 has raised，宾语是 nearly US$100 million in funding。a Hong Kong-based cryptocurrency exchange 是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰 HashKey Group，表示这是一家总部位于香港的加密货币交易所。giving it a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion 是一个现在分词短语作结果状语，表示筹集资金的结果是使 HashKey Group 的估值达到 12 亿美元。这个句子的意思是说，总部位于香港的加密货币交易所 HashKey Group 已筹集近 1 亿美元资金，使其估值达到 12 亿美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：HashKey Group, established in Hong Kong in 2018, was approved by the Securities and Futures Commission last August to serve retail investors under the city’s new regime for centralised cryptocurrency exchanges.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。其结构为：have/has + been + 过去分词。在这个例句中，was approved 是现在完成时态，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的状态，即香港证券及期货事务监察委员会于去年 8 月批准 HashKey Group 在该市针对集中式加密货币交易所的新制度下为散户投资者提供服务。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, HashKey Group said</li>
<li>OKX Ventures is one of the lead investors in HashKey’s funding round, Bloomberg reported</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/3db425dc-5d1c-4046-8dd8-4e916a7cbc11_056fab3a.jpg" /><figcaption>A view of HashKey Group’s booth during the 2021 Hong Kong FinTech Week at the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre on 3 November 2021. Photo: Shutterstock.</figcaption></figure><p>HashKey Group, the company behind one of Hong Kong’s two cryptocurrency exchanges approved to serve retail investors, said it raised nearly US$100 million in a funding round that valued it at more than US$1 billion, making it a so-called unicorn company.</p><p>Existing and new investors took part in its new Series A round, giving HashKey a pre-money valuation of US$1.2 billion, the Hong Kong-based company <a href="https://group.hashkey.com/en/newsroom/HashKey-Group-Series-A-Financing-Round" target="_self" title="">said in a statement</a> on Tuesday, without disclosing any names.</p><p>OKX Ventures, the investment arm of OKX, one of the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchanges and an applicant for Hong Kong’s virtual asset exchange license, is one of the lead investors in HashKey’s funding round, Bloomberg reported. HashKey and OKX both declined to comment.</p><p>HashKey operates the licensed HashKey Exchange, the HashKey Capital venture capital and asset management arm and other blockchain technology services. It will use the funding to “solidify” its web3 ecosystem, diversify its licensed product offerings in Hong Kong and develop its business globally, it said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246047/chinas-crypto-craving-back-door-binance-traders-look-more-important-exchanges-future-wake-us" title="">China’s back-door cryptocurrency traders look more important than ever to Binance’s future</a></h3><p>HashKey Group, established in Hong Kong in 2018, was approved by the Securities and Futures Commission <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3229913/hashkey-and-osl-receive-hong-kongs-first-approvals-operate-crypto-exchanges-retail-investors" target="_self" title="">last August</a> to serve retail investors under the city’s new regime for centralised cryptocurrency exchanges.</p><p>The exchange attracted 15,500 registered users at the end of 2023, with daily trading volume exceeding US$630 million in December, HashKey said last month. Nearly 40 per cent of the value traded on its platform came from professional investors, it said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3201697/what-are-virtual-assets-hong-kong-and-what-do-citys-new-rules-mean-crypto-trading" title="">What does Hong Kong mean by virtual assets?</a></h3><p>HashKey Exchange handled US$15.3 million in trading volume over 24 hours through Tuesday, according to the market tracker CoinGecko. That is a trickle compared with the US$13.6 billion transacted over the same period on Binance, the world’s largest exchange for cryptocurrencies.</p><p>HashKey is one of a range of cryptocurrency firms banking on Hong Kong’s push to embrace the virtual asset industry, even as public perception of the sector has plunged following scandals involving companies including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ftx" target="_self" title="">FTX</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jpex-cryptocurrency-scandal" target="_self" title="">JPEX</a>.</p><p>Twelve companies have so far submitted their applications for Hong Kong’s licence for virtual asset trading platforms.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3237817/hong-kongs-crypto-hub-dream-mired-high-costs-other-barriers-one-year-jpex-one-stumbling-block" title="">High costs cloud Hong Kong’s crypto hub dream</a></h3><p>Venture capital funding in the cryptocurrency industry plunged last year following a series of collapses in 2022. In the three months ending September 2023, cryptocurrency firms around the world raised US$1.8 billion across 309 deals, representing a 69.6 per cent decline in deal value and 55.9 per cent drop in deal numbers from the same period a year ago, according to data by PitchBook.</p><p>The market recently bounced back on the back of enthusiasm brought by the US’ approval of the first spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs), which allow investors to gain exposure to virtual assets without directly buying any cryptocurrency tokens.</p><p>Hong Kong last month also said that it will move to open up retail access to cryptocurrency spot ETFs, after previously only allowing retail participation in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3203539/crypto-futures-etfs-debut-hong-kong-lukewarm-interest-after-market-turmoil-ftx-collapse?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">cryptocurrency futures ETFs</a>, which hold cryptocurrency futures contracts, instead of direct investments in cryptocurrency tokens at their spot prices.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech war: Chinese chip-tool giant Naura forecasts surge in 2023 sales on strong local demand amid US export controls</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3248610/tech-war-chinese-chip-tool-giant-naura-forecasts-surge-2023-sales-strong-local-demand-amid-us-export</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese semiconductor equipment giant Naura Technology Group expects a 42% to 57% increase in its revenue and a 57% to 80% increase in its net profits in 2023. The company's technological breakthroughs, particularly in etching, deposition, and cleaning equipment, have secured a larger market share for Naura domestically. Meanwhile, Naura's major clients, such as China's largest foundries including Yangtze Memory Technologies Corp, are seeking domestic alternatives to imported semiconductor tools due to tightening US export controls.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Naura Technology Group's strong financial performance in 2023 is attributed to technological advancements and increased domestic demand, prompted by geopolitical factors.</li>    <li>Theme: Naura Technology Group's progress and success in the Chinese semiconductor industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of technology breakthroughs on Naura's market share; the significance of domestic alternatives in response to geopolitical challenges.</li>    <li>Main information: Naura's projected revenue and net profit growth; technological advancements in etching, deposition, and cleaning equipment; client's pursuit of domestic alternatives to US-made tools.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国半导体设备巨头纳芯科技集团预计，2023年其收入将增长约一半，净利润将增长57%至80%。该公司的技术突破，特别是在蚀刻、沉积和清洗设备方面，为纳芯赢得了更大的国内市场份额。与此同时，纳芯的主要客户，包括中国最大的晶圆厂长江存储科技公司，正在寻求国内替代进口半导体工具，原因是美国出口管制的收紧。 <ul>    <li>摘要：纳芯科技集团在2023年的强劲财务表现归因于技术进步和国内需求的增加，而国内需求的增加是受地缘政治因素的推动。</li>    <li>主题：纳芯科技集团在中国半导体行业的进步和成功。</li>    <li>观点：技术突破对纳芯市场份额的影响；在地缘政治挑战下寻求国内替代品的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：纳芯预计的收入和净利润增长；在蚀刻、沉积和清洗设备方面取得的技术进步；客户寻求美国制造工具的国内替代品。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>self-sufficiency (n.) - /ˌsɛlf səˈfɪʃənsi/ 自给自足，自力更生。    <p>原文例句：Amid a government-supported semiconductor self-sufficiency drive, YMTC has been in talks with domestic tool suppliers, including what was said to be a major company based in the Chinese capital, to produce replacements for crucial parts widely found in its equipment made by US firm Lam Research, sources told the Post last year. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由self（自我）和sufficiency（足够，充足）组成，意思是“自给自足，自力更生”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国政府支持的半导体自给自足运动，以减少对国外半导体技术的依赖。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>alternative (n.) - /ɔːlˈtɜːnətɪv/ 替代品，选择。    <p>原文例句：With foreign players pulling their staff and operations out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由alter（另一个）和nativus（天然的）组成，意思是“替代品，选择”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国本地芯片制造商在国外公司撤出中国后，急于寻找国内替代品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>on the back of - 在……的支持下，借助……的力量。    <p>原文例句：Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment China, Naura’s main rival, has said it expects 2023 revenue to rise more than 30 per cent on the back of strong demand from mainland fabs. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由on（在……上面）和the back of（后面）构成的，意思是“在……的支持下，借助……的力量”。在这个例句中，它表示Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment China 预计其2023年的收入将在来自中国大陆晶圆厂的强劲需求的支持下增长30%以上。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>out of China - 从中国撤出。    <p>原文例句：With foreign players pulling their staff and operations out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由out of（从……外面）和China（中国）构成的，意思是“从中国撤出”。在这个例句中，它表示随着外国公司从中国撤出其员工和业务，本地芯片制造商争相寻找国内替代品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Beijing-based Naura counts China’s largest foundries as major clients, such as Yangtze Memory Technologies Corp (YMTC). - 总部位于北京的纳芯将中国最大的晶圆厂视为主要客户，例如长江存储技术公司 (YMTC)。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是Beijing-based Naura，谓语是counts，宾语是China’s largest foundries as major clients。such as Yangtze Memory Technologies Corp (YMTC)是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰China’s largest foundries，提供更多的信息。在这个句子中，主语北京纳芯将中国最大的晶圆厂视为主要客户，例如长江存储技术公司。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示过去某一个时间发生的动作或状态一直持续到现在。    <p>原文例句：Naura Technology Group expects its 2023 revenue to jump by around half from a year earlier, as leaps in its technology helped it gain a larger market share in the country. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示纳芯科技集团预计其2023年收入将比去年同期增长约一半，因为其技术飞跃帮助其在国内获得了更大的市场份额。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Naura Technology expects a jump in both its revenue and net profit in 2023, as technology breakthroughs drive local demand</li>
<li>With foreign semiconductor equipment manufacturers pulling out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/dc40cd20-632e-4e89-9957-bc5f891f0b1e_628de1bf.jpg" /><figcaption>Naura Technology Group expects last year’s sales to grow by roughly half. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>State-backed Chinese semiconductor equipment giant Naura Technology Group expects its 2023 revenue to jump by around half from a year earlier, as leaps in its technology helped it gain a larger market share in the country.</p><p>The company said in a regulatory filing on Monday evening that its revenue last year is projected to grow between 42 per cent and 57 per cent to 20.9 billion yuan and 23.1 billion yuan (US$2.93 billion and US$3.24 billion).</p><p>“[Naura] has made technology breakthroughs and achieved volume production of more than a dozen of semiconductor equipment including etching, deposition and cleaning, and furnace, which help the company to cover more semiconductor manufacturing processes, leading to higher market shares,” Naura said.</p><p>Net profits are expected to increase between 57 per cent and 80 per cent to between 3.3 billion yuan and 3.8 billion yuan.</p><p>The company said it received over 30 billion yuan worth of new equipment orders in 2023, over 70 per cent of them related to semiconductor-related tools. It did not disclose similar figures in its revenue forecasts for 2022 or 2021.</p><p>Beijing-based Naura counts China’s largest foundries as major clients, such as Yangtze Memory Technologies Corp (YMTC).</p><p>Amid a government-supported semiconductor self-sufficiency drive, YMTC has been in talks with domestic tool suppliers, including what was said to be a major company based in the Chinese capital, to produce replacements for crucial parts widely found in its equipment made by US firm Lam Research, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3235074/tech-war-chinas-top-memory-chip-maker-ymtc-forges-closer-ties-domestic-supplier-replace-us-parts" target="_self" title="">sources told the Post last year</a>.</p><p>Lam Research has suspended equipment supply and services to clients in mainland China after Washington tightened US export controls in October 2022.</p><p>With foreign players pulling their staff and operations out of China, local chip makers have rushed to find domestic alternatives. The surging demand has helped lift sales of Chinese equipment manufacturers, although most of their products – especially those in advanced nodes below 10 nanometres – are thought to lag in quality.</p><p>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment China, Naura’s main rival, has said it expects 2023 revenue to rise more than 30 per cent on the back of strong demand from mainland fabs.</p><p>Shares of Shenzhen-listed Naura rose around 3 per cent to nearly 239 yuan in the morning trading session on Tuesday.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Microsoft launches consumer version of Copilot for US$20 a month with access to ChatGPT technology through Office</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248564/microsoft-launches-consumer-version-copilot-us20-month-access-chatgpt-technology-through-office</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Microsoft has introduced a consumer version of its Copilot AI tool and expanded the corporate version to smaller companies. Consumers can access Copilot Pro, which offers features like answering questions and creating content. Corporations no longer require a minimum of 300 subscriptions for the enterprise service.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Microsoft's Copilot AI becomes available to consumers and smaller companies.</li>    <li>Theme: Expanding access to Copilot's AI assistance to cater to individual and smaller business needs.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Microsoft sees potential revenue growth through AI integration in Office products and meets increasing demand from users.</li>    <li>Main information: Copilot Pro features for consumers, removal of the 300-subscription minimum for enterprise service, positive user response, and plans for a builder tool.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  微软推出面向消费者的Copilot人工智能工具，并将企业版扩展到更小的公司。消费者可以访问Copilot Pro，提供回答问题和创建内容等功能。企业不再需要为企业服务订阅至少300个订阅。  <ul>    <li>摘要：微软的Copilot人工智能工具开始面向消费者和小公司提供。</li>    <li>主题：扩展Copilot的人工智能辅助功能，以满足个人和小型企业的需求。</li>    <li>观点：微软看到了通过在其Office产品中集成人工智能而获得的潜在收入增长，并满足了用户不断增长的需求。</li>    <li>主要信息：Copilot Pro 面向消费者的功能、取消企业服务300个订阅的最低限额、积极的用户反响，以及对构建器工具的规划。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>demand (n.) - /dɪˈmænd/ 需求。    <p>原文例句：Executives have said demand is unusually high, with Azure chief Scott Guthrie likening it to the queues outside shops to purchase Windows 95 software nearly three decades ago. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，意思是“要求，索取”。在这个例句中，它指的是对Copilot的需求量非同寻常地高。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>feature (n.) - /ˈfiːtʃər/ 特征，功能。    <p>原文例句：Microsoft’s consumer service, called Copilot Pro, offers similar features to OpenAI’s ChatGPT Plus at the same price, though the integration with Office differentiates their product, Spataro said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，意思是“外形，形状”。在这个例句中，它指的是Copilot Pro提供的功能。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：Unlike data from corporate customers, Microsoft said it will retain a portion of prompts and responses from the consumer model to retrain models and improve the product. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示与企业客户的数据不同，微软表示它将保留一部分来自消费者模型的提示和回复，以重新训练模型和改进产品。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Microsoft has debuted a consumer version of its Copilot artificial intelligence tool. Photo: AP Photo - 微软推出其协同驾驶人工智能工具的消费者版本。照片：美联社照片<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是Microsoft has debuted，其中主语是Microsoft，谓语是has debuted。a consumer version of its Copilot artificial intelligence tool是一个名词短语作宾语，表示微软推出的协同驾驶人工智能工具的消费者版本。Photo: AP Photo是一个介词短语作状语，表示微软推出的协同驾驶人工智能工具的消费者版本的图片由美联社提供，这个句子的意思是说，微软推出其协同驾驶人工智能工具的消费者版本。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 表示存在。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的句型，表示某地或某时存在某物或某人。结构是：There + be + 主语 + 其他。其中be要根据主语的数和时态进行变化，主语一般是名词或代词。在这个例句中，be用的是are，表示现在时态，主语是plenty of reasons，>表示很多理由。这个句子的意思是说，有很多理由使用Firefox作为你的主要浏览器。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Consumers of Office will be able to use Copilot Pro to help answer questions and create content in Word, Outlook, Excel and PowerPoint</li>
<li>Companies previously had to buy at least 300 subscriptions to use Copilot, a requirement Microsoft is getting rid of</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/16/60d99f9f-7754-4b8a-9cd6-70a210df5cd6_c9e26244.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft has debuted a consumer version of its Copilot artificial intelligence tool. Photo: AP Photo</figcaption></figure><p>Microsoft is opening up its artificial intelligence assistant to consumers and making the corporate version available to smaller companies as it tries to increase the number of paying customers for the new services.</p><p>Microsoft is selling a US$20-a-month consumer version of Copilot, with access to OpenAI’s latest ChatGPT technology and image-creation features, the Redmond, Washington-based software giant said in a statement.</p><p>Consumers with a cloud subscription to Office will be able to use Copilot to help answer questions, summarise data and create content in Word, Outlook, Excel and PowerPoint.</p><p>The company, which has been selling a similar product to large businesses for a monthly fee of US$30 per user, will get rid of the 300-subscription minimum for its enterprise service.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>As Microsoft has revamped nearly all of its products around artificial intelligence tools based on technology from OpenAI, its Office products remain one of the best ways to get customers to pay extra for AI assistance.</p><p>Executives have said demand is unusually high, with Azure chief Scott Guthrie likening it to the queues outside shops to purchase Windows 95 software nearly three decades ago.</p><p>Microsoft has been testing the Office-based copilot, now called Copilot for Microsoft 365, since March. The company began selling it widely in November, as long as companies purchased at least 300 subscriptions. That left out small businesses and those that wanted to begin with a smaller trial, said Jared Spataro, a Microsoft vice-president, in an interview.</p><p>“We have just never seen demand in the commercial space for a product like we are seeing for Copilot from Microsoft 365,’’ he said. “We have had pressure I have never seen from small and medium businesses saying ‘why will you not let us buy this? Let us try it’.”</p><p>Microsoft announced the new services ahead of the World Economic Forum in Davos, which will be attended by chief executive officer Satya Nadella.</p><p>Microsoft’s consumer service, called Copilot Pro, offers similar features to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3235800/openai-updates-chatgpt-ability-hear-and-speak-see-images-it-still-cannot-sing" target="_self" title="">OpenAI’s ChatGPT Plus</a> at the same price, though the integration with Office differentiates their product, Spataro said.</p><p>The company plans to roll out a builder tool, similar to what OpenAI unveiled last year, that will let individuals create their own Copilots for a specific topic, a service that is already available to enterprises.</p><p>Microsoft’s privacy rules for the consumer version also differ from the business one. Unlike data from corporate customers, Microsoft said it will retain a portion of prompts and responses from the consumer model to retrain models and improve the product.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>AirPods maker Goertek to open Vietnam factory as part of Apple’s supply chain diversification</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248542/airpods-maker-goertek-open-vietnam-factory-part-apples-supply-chain-diversification</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Goertek, an Apple supplier, announced plans to invest up to $280 million in a Vietnamese subsidiary to expand its operations and meet client demand. The Vietnamese entity, located in Bac Ninh province, will manufacture consumer electronics and cater to Goertek's future development and client needs. This move aligns with Apple's strategy of diversifying production outside China, following disruptions caused by COVID-19 restrictions.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Goertek invests in Vietnam to diversify production and meet client demand.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's efforts to diversify production and reduce reliance on China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The impact of COVID-19 restrictions on global supply chains and the importance of diversifying production locations.</li>    <li>Main information: Goertek's investment in Vietnam, the Vietnamese entity's manufacturing focus, Apple's influence on its suppliers' diversification strategy, and the involvement of other Apple suppliers like Foxconn.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果供应商歌尔股份宣布计划在越南子公司投资高达 2.8 亿美元，以扩大其业务并满足客户需求。位于北宁省的越南实体将生产消费电子产品，并满足歌尔股份未来的发展和客户需求。此举符合苹果将生产多元化至中国以外的战略，此前受新冠肺炎限制措施影响，导致其制造供应链中断。  <ul>    <li>摘要：歌尔股份投资越南以实现生产多元化并满足客户需求。</li>    <li>主题：苹果努力实现生产多元化并减少对中国的依赖。</li>    <li>观点：新冠肺炎限制措施对全球供应链的影响以及实现生产地多元化的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：歌尔股份在越南的投资、越南实体的制造重点、苹果对其供应商多元化战略的影响以及其他苹果供应商（如富士康）的参与。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>subsidiary (n.) - /səbˈsɪdɪerɪ/ 子公司，分公司。    <p>原文例句：Apple supplier Goertek said on Monday it would invest up to US$280 million to establish a wholly-owned subsidiary in Vietnam to meet demands for “business expansion and long-term operation” in the Southeast Asian nation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：subsidiary 是一个形容词，源于拉丁语“subsidium”（帮助），意为“帮助，辅助，辅助性，附属性”。在这个例句中，subsidiary 是一个名词，指的是歌尔股份在越南建立的全资子公司。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>diversify (v.) - /dɪˈvɜːsɪfaɪ/ 多样化，使多样化。    <p>原文例句：Apple has encouraged its contract manufacturing partners to diversify into other countries, including Vietnam, to reduce its reliance on China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：diversify 是一个动词，源于拉丁语“diversus”（不同的）和“facere”（做），意为“使不同，使多样化”。在这个例句中，diversify 表示苹果鼓励其代工合作伙伴在其他国家/地区（包括越南）实现生产多元化，以减少对中国的依赖。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>consumer electronics (n.) - /ˈkɒnsjʊmər ɪlekˈtrɒnɪks/ 消费电子产品。    <p>原文例句：Goertek’s Vietnamese entity, which will manufacture consumer electronics products, from AirPods and smartwatches to virtual reality and augmented reality gear, is a project that will meet both the Chinese assembler’s future development plan and client demand.</p>    <p>例句讲解：consumer electronics 是一个名词短语，由“consumer”（消费者）和“electronics”（电子产品）组成，意为“消费电子产品”。在这个例句中，consumer electronics 是指歌尔股份的越南实体将生产的消费电子产品，包括 AirPods、智能手表、虚拟现实和增强现实设备等。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in order to - 为了，以便。    <p>原文例句：The Vietnamese subsidiary is expected to be located in the Bac Ninh province, which has attracted investment from a raft of South Korean firms.</p>    <p>例句讲解：in order to 是一个介词短语，由“in order”和“to”组成，意为“为了，以便”。在这个例句中，in order to 表示越南子公司预计将位于北宁省，那里吸引了许多韩国企业的投资。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>South Korean firms have emerged as major investors in that province, setting up factories for electronics, smartphones, semiconductors and precision mechanical manufacturing equipment, according to the Vietnam Chamber of Commerce and Industry. - 据越南工商会称，韩国公司已成为该省的主要投资者，他们建立了电子产品、智能手机、半导体和精密机械制造设备的工厂。<p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是South Korean firms have emerged as major investors in that province，其中主语是South Korean firms，谓语是have emerged，宾语是major investors。一个分词短语setting up factories for electronics, smartphones, semiconductors and precision mechanical manufacturing equipment作状语，修饰谓语have emerged，表示韩国公司在该省建立了电子产品、智能手机、半导体和精密机械制造设备的工厂。这个句子的意思是说，韩国公司已成为该省的主要投资者，他们建立了电子产品、智能手机、半导体和精密机械制造设备的工厂。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple has encouraged its contract manufacturing partners to diversify into other countries, including Vietnam, to reduce its reliance on China.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，苹果自过去以来一直鼓励其代工合作伙伴在其他国家/地区实现生产多元化，包括越南，以减少对中国的依赖，重点在于对苹果代工合作伙伴多元化战略的持续性。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Goertek was tapped by Apple as one of the major mainland suppliers of its mixed-reality Vision Pro headset, which is set to launch in early February</li>
<li>The Vietnamese subsidiary is expected to be located in the Bac Ninh province, which has attracted investment from a raft of South Korean firms</li>
</ul><p>Apple supplier Goertek said on Monday it would invest up to US$280 million to establish a wholly-owned subsidiary in Vietnam to meet demands for “business expansion and long-term operation” in the Southeast Asian nation, according to a corporate filing.</p><p>Goertek’s Vietnamese entity, which will manufacture consumer electronics products, from AirPods and smartwatches to virtual reality and augmented reality gear, is a project that will meet both the Chinese assembler’s future development plan and client demand, it said in the filing to the Shenzhen Stock Exchange.</p><p>“[The project] is advantageous to make better use of local resources in Vietnam to enhance the company’s overall competitiveness,” Goertek said.</p><p>The company has been tapped by Apple to become one of the major mainland suppliers of its mixed-reality Vision Pro headset, which is set to launch in early February.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248092/apple-supplier-boe-one-worlds-top-display-makers-forges-us9-billion-deal-build-next-generation-plant" title="">Apple supplier BOE signs US$9 billion deal to build display plant in China</a></h3><p>The Vietnamese subsidiary, which will be set up through its Hong Kong entity Goertek (Hong Kong) Co, is expected to be located in northern Bac Ninh province, which has attracted investment from a raft of South Korean firms including consumer electronics and semiconductor giant Samsung Electronics.</p><p>South Korean firms have emerged as major investors in that province, setting up factories for electronics, smartphones, semiconductors and precision mechanical manufacturing equipment, according to the Vietnam Chamber of Commerce and Industry.</p><p>Goertek’s latest move comes as Apple is starting to shift more of its production outside China, a move that came after Beijing’s stringent Covid-19 restrictions during the pandemic disrupted the US firm's manufacturing supply chain, impacting its global sales in the lead up to the Christmas shopping season in 2022.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248044/huawei-secures-jdcom-harmonyos-partner-home-grown-software-emerges-alternative-apple-ios-android" title="">JD.com supports Huawei’s HarmonyOS as alternative for Apple iOS, Android in China</a></h3><p>Since then, Apple has encouraged its contract manufacturing partners to diversify into other countries, including Vietnam, to reduce its reliance on China.</p><p>Apple suppliers, including Taiwanese electronics contract manufacturer Foxconn Technology Group, have invested up to US$16 billion to reduce their dependence on China, by relocating facilities to India, Vietnam, Mexico as well as the US, according to a report by AppleInsider, citing research by investment bank TD Cowen.</p><p>Foxconn, formally known as Hon Hai Precision Industry and the world's biggest maker of iPhones, late last year announced a plan to invest US$1.6 billion in India to expand its presence in the South Asian nation.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
