<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>Alibaba, TikTok woo US with AI and live-streaming e-commerce at CES trade show, setting the tone for 2024</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248469/alibaba-tiktok-woo-us-ai-and-live-streaming-e-commerce-ces-trade-show-setting-tone-2024</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  At the CES trade show in 2024, Alibaba.com launched its new Smart Assistant, a chatbot powered by artificial intelligence, while TikTok Shop focused on live-streaming e-commerce. Alibaba's tool uses advanced language models to help buyers source products, while TikTok Shop seeks to attract sellers and influencers for its platform. Chinese suppliers remain crucial for platforms like Alibaba.com, Shein, and Temu due to their cost advantages. Start-ups like Spaceship use AI to help businesses manage their supply chains and reduce reliance on large platforms.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese tech giants Alibaba and TikTok showcased their AI and live-streaming prowess at CES 2024.</li>    <li>Theme: Alibaba.com's AI-powered Smart Assistant and TikTok Shop's live-streaming e-commerce strategy aim to revolutionize overseas markets.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The role of artificial intelligence and live streaming in transforming e-commerce and the importance of Chinese suppliers in the global supply chain.</li>    <li>Main information: Alibaba.com's Smart Assistant utilizes large language models to aid buyers; TikTok Shop targets influencers for live-streaming sales; Chinese suppliers provide cost advantages to platforms.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  在2024年CES贸易展上，阿里巴巴国际站推出了其新款智能助手，一个由人工智能驱动的聊天机器人，而TikTok Shop则专注于直播电子商务。阿里巴巴的工具使用先进的语言模型来帮助买家采购产品，而TikTok Shop则寻求吸引卖家和影响者在其平台上进行销售。中国供应商仍然是阿里巴巴国际站、Shein和Temu等平台的关键因素，因为它们具有成本优势。像Spaceship这样的初创公司使用人工智能来帮助企业管理其供应链并减少对大型平台的依赖。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国科技巨头阿里巴巴和TikTok在2024年CES上展示了其人工智能和直播实力。</li>    <li>主题：阿里巴巴国际站的人工智能驱动的智能助手和TikTok Shop的直播电子商务策略旨在革新海外市场。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能和直播在电子商务转型中的作用以及中国供应商在全球供应链中的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：阿里巴巴国际站的智能助手利用大型语言模型来帮助买家；TikTok Shop针对有影响力的人进行直播销售；中国供应商为平台提供成本优势。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>generative AI (n.) - 生成式人工智能。    <p>原文例句：By putting generative AI at the center of its exhibition, Alibaba.com made it clear where it thought the platform’s advantage lies.</p>    <p>例句讲解：指一类能够产生新数据或创造新内容的人工智能模型，如生成式文本、图像、音乐和视频。</p></li>    <li>gold supplier (n.) - 金牌供应商。    <p>原文例句：A number of CES attendees at the Alibaba.com presentation were made up of select “gold suppliers”, or those that pay for a premium membership on the platform.</p>    <p>例句讲解：指在电子商务平台上支付额外费用以获得更多曝光和特权的卖家。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>put down (v.) - 放下。    <p>原文例句：TikTok, already famous for its more traditional recommendation algorithms that have made its short video service so difficult to put down, went in a different direction at CES.</p>    <p>例句讲解：此处作“放弃”解，指停止使用或观看某物。</p></li>    <li>take on (v.) - 承担，挑战。    <p>原文例句：TikTok Shop is also seeking to take on Shein and Temu.</p>    <p>例句讲解：指与竞争对手竞争或对抗。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant showed how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year. - 阿里巴巴国际站推出智能助手表明了今年CES上人工智能创新无处不在。    <p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant showed how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year，从句是how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year。主句的主语是Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant，谓语是showed，宾语是how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year。从句的主语是AI innovation，谓语是was，宾语是ubiquitous。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Chinese suppliers are also Alibaba.com’s bread and butter. - 中国供应商也是阿里巴巴国际站的命脉。    <p>语法讲解：这个时态由have/has been + 现在分词构成，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个例句中，supplier are has been + 现在分词been + 现在分词navigating，表示中国供应商一直是阿里巴巴国际站的命脉。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In its international launch at CES, Alibaba.com’s new AI chatbot showed how it can help buyers with sourcing for merchandise</li>
<li>TikTok Shop set up a booth for influencers to sell their wares via live streaming from CES, showing where the platform figures its strengths lie</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/4b4e3c96-5e9f-4a0e-a12a-4b8ebd59c282_e1e0e1d3.jpg" /><figcaption>At the recent CES trade show in Las Vegas, Alibaba.com and TikTok Shop focused on their respective strengths in artificial intelligence and live-streaming e-commerce. Photos: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a> each put their technological prowess on display last week at <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ces" target="_self" title="">CES 2024</a> in Las Vegas, where their respective <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/live-streaming" target="_self" title="">live-streaming</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> products set the tone for how they plan to embed themselves further into daily life in overseas markets.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" target="_self" title="">Alibaba.com</a>, the international business-to-business wholesale marketplace of South China Morning Post owner Alibaba, launched its Smart Assistant feature at the world’s largest consumer electronics show, with computers set up around the centre of its booth to show how the embedded chatbot can help buyers navigate the sourcing website.</p><p>Smart Assistant is powered by multiple large language models (LLMs) – the technology used to train <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> and similar services – including home-grown <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3234385/alibaba-opens-ai-model-tongyi-qianwen-public-competition-baidu-tencent-and-other-chinese-big-tech" target="_self" title="">Tongyi Qianwen</a>, depending on use case, an Alibaba.com representative said.</p><p>“With advances in AI, we are ushering in the next generation of sourcing and empowering small businesses to succeed with our Smart Assistant at their side,” Chris Lu, general manager at Alibaba.com North America, said in a statement last week.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Alibaba.com booth features the e-commerce platform’s artificial intelligence-powered Smart Assistant, designed to help users navigate the sourcing website, at the CES trade show in Las Vegas on January 12, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1356" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/7ea9cc8d-352b-43d1-8802-d0195ff7dfbc_4677c949.jpg" title="The Alibaba.com booth features the e-commerce platform’s artificial intelligence-powered Smart Assistant, designed to help users navigate the sourcing website, at the CES trade show in Las Vegas on January 12, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Alibaba.com booth features the e-commerce platform’s artificial intelligence-powered Smart Assistant, designed to help users navigate the sourcing website, at the CES trade show in Las Vegas on January 12, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Alibaba.com’s debut of Smart Assistant showed how ubiquitous AI innovation was at CES this year. No tech giant’s exhibition was complete without showing off its effort in that space.</p><p>By putting generative AI at the centre of its exhibition, Alibaba.com made it clear where it thought the platform’s advantage lies, despite some grumblings from a marketing manager that the product was not quite yet ready for prime time, according to a brand ambassador at the booth.</p><p>A number of CES attendees at the Alibaba.com presentation were made up of select “gold suppliers”, or those that pay for a premium membership on the platform, according to some exhibitors.</p><p>A test of Smart Assistant by the Post showed the all-too-common limitations of new LLM-powered chatbots. When asked about the best options for sourcing a 10,000-milliampere-hour power bank, it offered a link to search results for the product on Alibaba.com. A follow-up query on the best way to determine differences in quality among suppliers resulted in a generic response about checking certifications and standards.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="An online influencer is seen at the TikTok Shop booth preparing for a live-streaming session to sell goods directly from CES inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas on January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1256" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/b4f2b04e-92e3-4588-8f81-51fac86ad8ed_ab01d493.jpg" title="An online influencer is seen at the TikTok Shop booth preparing for a live-streaming session to sell goods directly from CES inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas on January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>An online influencer is seen at the TikTok Shop booth preparing for a live-streaming session to sell goods directly from CES inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas on January 10, 2024. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned TikTok, already famous for its more traditional recommendation algorithms that have made its short video service so difficult to put down, went in a different direction at CES. Its TikTok Shop booth inside the Aria Resort &amp; Casino in Las Vegas, was set up with a live-streaming area where some influencers were invited to sell their wares directly from the trade show.</p><p>While TikTok remains best known outside China as a platform to consume bite-sized videos, live-streaming e-commerce is already big business for the app’s Chinese version, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>. E-commerce is seen by Beijing-based parent ByteDance as an important area for future growth.</p><p>TikTok Shop representatives were roaming the CES floor looking for companies they can convince to sell on the platform. That task may have been harder for the US team. A US-based TikTok Shop employee told Shenzhen-based mechanical keyboard maker Keychron that he was not allowed to sign up Chinese companies. Only their team in mainland China can on-board those suppliers.</p><p>Connections with mainland Chinese suppliers are seen as the secret weapon for new e-commerce entrants like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3240612/china-founded-e-commerce-start-shein-said-aim-us90-billion-valuation-us-ipo" target="_self" title="">Shein</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3243140/discount-e-commerce-giant-pdd-nearly-doubles-quarterly-revenue-closing-alibaba-meituan-also-chalks" target="_self" title="">PDD Holdings</a>’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>. These platforms are taking on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon.com</a> on its home turf with dirt-cheap products, which are sold as they roll off the factory floor from their mainland suppliers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>“Temu or Shein can get those very low-cost items and low-cost shipping because they have the volume,” said Stanley Wong, co-founder and chief product officer of Hong Kong-based Spaceship, which exhibited at CES under its Taiwanese entity. “They have very professional teams to do that kind of supply chain management.”</p><p>TikTok Shop is also seeking to take on Shein and Temu. TikTok sees international e-commerce expansion so important to its future that it <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244634/tiktok-restarts-e-commerce-indonesia-us15-billion-investment-goto-gojek-tokopedia-unit" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244634/tiktok-restarts-e-commerce-indonesia-us15-billion-investment-goto-gojek-tokopedia-unit">bought a 75 per cent stake</a> in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/indonesia" target="_self" title="">Indonesia</a>’s largest online shopping platform, enabling the firm restart its local operations which had earlier been suspended by regulators in Southeast Asia’s largest economy.</p><p>Chinese suppliers are also Alibaba.com’s bread and butter. While it is ostensibly a global sourcing platform, the vast majority of companies on Alibaba.com are Chinese, which typically offer big cost advantages owing to the mainland’s vast manufacturing supply chain.</p><p>Even <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups">start-ups</a> are trying to use AI to help companies navigate the changing landscape of e-commerce in the West. Spaceship, for example, uses AI to help brands manage their own shops with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3146298/tiktok-partners-shopify-latest-step-expand-its-e-commerce-efforts" target="_self" title="">Canadian e-commerce firm Shopify</a> to determine the best logistics options for goods manufactured in China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" title="">Alibaba pushes new AI tool to help wholesale merchants manage overseas clients</a></h3><p>“Our focus is to enable individual sellers to” achieve cost-effective supply chain management like Shein and Temu, Spaceship’s Wong said.</p><p>As more merchants try to control their own brands and reduce the money they lose to platforms like Shein, Temu and TikTok Shop by operating their own sites, services like Spaceship make sense when making price comparisons on logistics solutions.</p><p>Still, Spaceship does not have its own generative AI product yet to take on the likes of Alibaba. The company said it is considering one for customer service.</p><p>Many of the underpinnings of AI LLMs are open-source code, making the technology easily accessible to start-ups even if they do not have the data advantage of tech giants. But it could be some time before the kinks are worked out and these start-ups can handle more sophisticated requirements of business users.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: Hong Kong start-ups attract interest from Microsoft, Best Buy amid overseas push</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248382/ces-2024-hong-kong-start-ups-attract-interest-microsoft-best-buy-amid-overseas-push</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Hong Kong start-ups are making a splash at the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in Las Vegas, attracting interest from tech giants like Microsoft and Best Buy.</li>    <li>AI Guided, a Hong Kong start-up, showcases its AI-powered belt for guiding the blind, catching the attention of Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella.</li>    <li>Other Hong Kong start-ups, such as Invisible & Innovation Technology and XOXO Beverages, are also generating interest with their innovative products, including furniture with embedded speakers and an automated cocktail-making machine.</li>    <li>CES provides a platform for these start-ups to connect with potential partners and expand beyond their home market.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>香港初创企业在拉斯维加斯举行的消费者电子展 (CES) 上大放异彩，吸引了微软和百思买等科技巨头的兴趣。</li>    <li>香港初创企业 AI Guided 展示了其人工智能驱动的盲人引导腰带，引起了微软首席执行官萨蒂亚·纳德拉的注意。</li>    <li>其他香港初创公司，如 Invisible & Innovation Technology 和 XOXO Beverages，也凭借其创新产品引起了人们的兴趣，包括带有嵌入式扬声器的家具和自动鸡尾酒机。</li>    <li>CES 为这些初创企业提供了一个平台，让他们可以与潜在合作伙伴建立联系并拓展海外市场。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>accessibility (n.) - /ˌæksɛsəˈbɪləti/ 无障碍性，可及性。    <p>原文例句： “Microsoft really supports accessibility technology,” said Steve Kong, co-founder and chief technology officer of AI Guided. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Accessibility 意为“可及性、无障碍性”，是指使人们（尤其是残疾人）能够使用和访问产品、服务或环境的能力。在这个例句中，它指的是微软非常支持无障碍技术。</p></li>    <li>navigate (v.) - /ˈnævɪgeɪt/ 导航，驾驶。    <p>原文例句： “The dream of our company is that in three to five years … visually impaired people can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：Navigate 意为“导航、驾驶”，是指通过使用地图、指南针或其他设备来确定位置和方向，并找到从一个地方到另一个地方的路径。在这个例句中，它指的是 AI Guided 公司的梦想是让视障人士在三到五年内能够不借助双手就能在世界上导航。</p></li>    <li>Eureka (n.) - /jʊˈrɪkə/ 尤里卡，灵感，顿悟。    <p>原文例句：Even leading up to the show, Hong Kong Science and Technology Park (HKSTP) said 40 companies applied to exhibit in the Eureka Park start-up area, </p>    <p>例句讲解：Eureka 意为“尤里卡、灵感、顿悟”，是指突然发现或意识到一个问题的解决方案或答案。在这个例句中，它指的是在 CES 展会开始之前，香港科技园表示有 40 家公司申请在 Eureka Park 初创企业区参展。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：We had to make some selection of companies that have more of a mature level of readiness in terms of being ready to sell,” </P>    <p>例句讲解：In terms of 意为“就……而言、从……方面来说”，常用来表示从某种角度或标准来看。在这个例句中，它表示香港科技园必须选择一些在准备就绪方面更成熟的公司才能参展。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Realme unveils 12 Pro series smartphone in parallel event to CES - Realme 在 CES 期间的平行活动中发布了 12 Pro 系列智能手机。    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是 Realme，谓语是 unveils，宾语是 12 Pro series smartphone。in parallel event to CES 是一个介词短语，作时间状语，表示在 CES 期间。这个句子的意思是 Realme 在 CES 期间的平行活动中发布了 12 Pro 系列智能手机。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The Hong Kong pavilion at this year’s CES, which concluded on Friday, featured a variety of start-ups that make products ranging from the quirky to the practical.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态的句子。现在完成时态由“have/has + 过去分词”构成，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。在这个例句中，it featured a variety of start-ups 是谓语动词，其中featured是have的过去分词，表示香港展馆在今年的 CES 上展出了各种各样的初创企业。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella stopped by the booth of a start-up at the Hong Kong pavilion that makes an AI-powered belt to guide blind people</li>
<li>Other start-ups say they have received interest at the show from retailers and other potential partners as Hong Kong firms look overseas</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/c4aa2f7b-bda4-4f1d-8d18-95ebfe7901e8_6e29421c.jpg" /><figcaption>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella meets with Steve Kong, co-founder and chief technology officer of AI Guided, at CES to learn more about the Hong Kong start-up’s belt for guiding the blind. Photo: Handout </figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/microsoft">Microsoft</a> and Best Buy expressed interest in Hong Kong <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/start-ups">start-ups</a> at CES 2024, after the city’s pavilion at the world’s largest consumer electronics show saw the most interest there in years.</p><p>Last Tuesday, the first day of the trade show in Las Vegas, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella swung by the Tech Hong Kong pavilion to chat with AI Guided, a company that makes a belt with haptic feedback for obstacle detection, helping to guide the blind.</p><p>“Microsoft really supports accessibility technology,” said Steve Kong, co-founder and chief technology officer of AI Guided. “The dream of our company is that in three to five years … visually impaired people can have some hands-free experience to navigate the world.”</p><p>AI Guided is one of 20 Hong Kong-based companies exhibiting with the city’s start-up pavilion this year, a big improvement over the eight that exhibited last year because of the last-minute lifting of Covid-19 restrictions.</p><p>Even leading up to the show, Hong Kong Science and Technology Park (HKSTP) said 40 companies applied to exhibit in the Eureka Park start-up area, a marked improvement over previous years, according to H L Yiu, corporate development officer for HKSTP, which runs the pavilion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248116/ces-2024-china-smartphone-brand-realme-unveils-new-handset-sidelines-trade-show-its-biggest-rivals" title="">Realme unveils 12 Pro series smartphone in parallel event to CES</a></h3><p>“We had to make some selection of companies that have more of a mature level of readiness in terms of being ready to sell,” Yiu said in an interview. “We really mean to help them get new business.”</p><p>With limited space, HKSTP focused on picking companies that were closer to having products ready to go, or even already in the market, with the goal of picking up business deals at CES.</p><p>For some, that could pan out in a big way.</p><p>Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology, aka Invisible Tech, which builds speakers into furniture, said it has received interest from Best Buy. A representative from the largest electronics retail chain in the US told Invisible Tech that it had not seen other products like its cabinet with an embedded speaker in the base, according to the start-up’s co-founder Patrick Lee.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1507" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/8c535fe2-a0b7-472a-a511-c0de39fad1c7_cffec5fe.jpg" title="Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Invisible &amp; Innovation Technology makes cabinets with embedded speakers, which are partially made of recycled materials. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>“Best Buy always wants to source something new,” said Lee. “Furniture is a very traditional thing that [has not had] much disruptive design or link with technology.”</p><p>Invisible Tech also uses recycled materials in some parts of its products. Henry Cheung, the company’s other co-founder, said the company wants to “help Hong Kong fulfil its carbon neutral mission”. The city aims to be carbon neutral by 2050.</p><p>The Hong Kong pavilion at this year’s CES, which concluded on Friday, featured a variety of start-ups that make products ranging from the quirky to the practical.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" title="">Chinese EV maker shows off flying car but admits urban use is far off</a></h3><p>XOXO Beverages already has its cocktail-making machine in about 10 bars and restaurants in Hong Kong, but it has not expanded to home use yet. Co-founder Peter Yau said CES was the best show the company has been to.</p><p>“People from all around the world come by and are very interested in the product,” Yau said. “[We got] a lot of contacts, and we’re looking to see what we can do after [the show] with those guys.”</p><p>Two of the participating companies, Sitan Semiconductor International and Raysolve Technology, make micro-LED displays, something that has become more important amid rising interest in augmented reality glasses.</p><p>Sitan was started at the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, and the company said its tech has already found its way into products from big brands like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tcl" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tcl">TCL</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo">Oppo</a> and Meizu – although not all of these products have been released.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1613" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/15/2b040077-b3ac-4878-bb0e-daa1b2414354_75a0b9ef.jpg" title="XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>XOXO Beverages has made a machine that will automatically mix cocktails to specifications inputted through an app. SCMP / Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>For most of the start-ups, though, CES was about getting leads and looking for ways to expand beyond their home market. Getting the attention of a tech giant like Microsoft is one way to achieve that.</p><p>Asked about the prospects of Microsoft investing, AI Guided’s Kong said, “I hope so … I will still have another discussion with them, so we’ll see.”</p><p>This kind of attention also may help the Hong Kong government justify its efforts to turn the city into a tech hub, which has had mixed results in a city better known as a regional financial hub.</p><p>“From a tech area standpoint, I think the opportunity to come to Hong Kong is surging,” said HKSTP’s Yiu. “The number of start-ups that we nurture every year is an increasing trend.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Elon Musk’s Tesla loses US$94 billion in market valuation as winter sets in for global electric vehicle market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248400/elon-musks-tesla-loses-us94-billion-market-valuation-winter-sets-global-electric-vehicle-market</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Tesla's dream start of 2023 has turned into a nightmare in 2024. The electric vehicle maker has lost more than $94 billion in market value in the first two weeks of January, with shares down 12% since the start of the year. This is the worst start to any year for Tesla, and the biggest hit to its market capitalization since it went public in 2010.  The company is facing a barrage of negative news, including price cuts, rising labor costs, and signs of slowing demand for electric vehicles. Tesla's aggressive price cuts in China have also raised concerns about a race to the bottom in the EV industry.  Tesla has also been forced to divert shipments to its Berlin plant due to security concerns in the Red Sea, and is suspending production at the plant for two weeks. The company's fourth-quarter delivery numbers were better than expected, but Tesla still lags behind China's BYD Co in global electric car sales.  Tesla's problems have taken a toll on CEO Elon Musk's personal wealth, with his net worth shrinking by $23 billion so far this year. Tesla's market capitalization is still much larger than any other car company in the world, but the company's shares are highly vulnerable to negative news. Some analysts argue that Tesla should not be compared to regular car companies, as its ultimate value lies in the future development of self-driving vehicles. However, this technology is still years away, and Tesla has been unable to deliver on its promises in this area.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tesla's market value has plummeted in 2024 due to a barrage of negative news.</li>    <li>Theme: Tesla faces a difficult start to 2024 amid slowing demand, rising costs, and production disruptions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Tesla's aggressive price cuts in China raise concerns about a race to the bottom in the EV industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Tesla's market capitalization loss; price cuts, rising labor costs, and slowing demand; production disruption at Berlin plant; fourth-quarter delivery numbers; impact on Elon Musk's personal wealth; comparison to regular car companies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  特斯拉在2023年的梦幻开局在2024年变成了噩梦。这家电动汽车制造商在一月的前两周中市值损失超过940亿美元，股票自年初以来下跌了12%。这是特斯拉有史以来最糟糕的开局，也是自2010年上市以来市值遭受的最大打击。该公司正面临一系列负面消息，包括降价、劳动力成本上升以及电动汽车需求放缓的迹象。特斯拉在中国的激进降价也引发了对电动汽车行业陷入价格战的担忧。由于红海的安全问题，特斯拉还被迫将运往柏林工厂的货物改道，并暂停该工厂两周的生产。该公司的第四季度交付量好于预期，但特斯拉在全球电动汽车销量上仍落后于中国的比亚迪。特斯拉的问题对首席执行官埃隆·马斯克的个人财富造成了影响，他的净资产今年到目前为止已缩水230亿美元。特斯拉的市值仍然远高于世界上任何其他汽车公司，但该公司的股票极易受到负面消息的影响。一些分析师认为，特斯拉不应与普通汽车公司相提并论，因为其最终价值在于未来自动驾驶汽车的发展。然而，这项技术仍需数年时间，而且特斯拉一直未能兑现在此领域的承诺。  <ul>    <li>摘要：由于一系列负面消息，特斯拉的市值在2024年大幅缩水。</li>    <li>主题：在需求放缓、成本上升和生产中断的情况下，特斯拉面临着艰难的2024年开局。</li>    <li>观点：特斯拉在中国激进的降价引发了对电动汽车行业陷入价格战的担忧。</li>    <li>主要信息：特斯拉的市值损失；降价、劳动力成本上升和需求放缓；柏林工厂生产中断；第四季度交付量；对埃隆·马斯克个人财富的影响；与普通汽车公司的比较。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>barrage (n.) - /ˈbærɪdʒ/ 排山倒海的攻击，猛轰。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由bar（块状物）和rage（愤怒）构成的，表示“猛击，炮击，猛轰”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉自去年初以来一直积极降价以提振需求。</p></li>    <li>stagnate (v.) - /ˈstæɡneɪt/ 停滞，不再增长。    <p>原文例句：Tesla is stagnating growth – Cowen analyst Jeffrey Osborne</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词源自拉丁语stagnum（池塘），表示“变得死气沉沉或停滞”。在这个例句中，它指特斯拉的增长停滞不前。</p></li>    <li>worsen (v.) - /ˈwɜːrsən/ 恶化，变得更糟。    <p>原文例句：To make matters worse, the odds of an imminent turnaround for the EV maker do not look good.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词是由worse（较差的）构成的，表示“变得更坏，恶化”。在这个例句中，它指电动汽车制造商近期好转的几率不大，事情变得更糟了。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>      price cuts - 降价。      <p>原文例句：Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</p>      <p>例句讲解：这个词组由两个名词price（价格）和cut（减少）组成，表示“降低价格”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉在中国降价以保持高端电动汽车市场的份额。</p>    </li>    <li>      production disruption - 生产中断。      <p>原文例句：Tesla has also been forced to divert shipments to its Berlin plant due to security concerns in the Red Sea, and is suspending production at the plant for two weeks.</p>      <p>例句讲解：这个词组由两个名词production（生产）和disruption（中断）组成，表示“生产中断”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉由于红海的安全问题而被迫将运往柏林工厂的货物改道，并暂停该工厂两周的生产。</p>    </li>    <li>      deliver on - 兑现，实现。      <p>原文例句：Tesla has not been able to deliver on fully autonomous driving and AI promises.</p>      <p>例句讲解：这个词组由动词deliver（交付）和介词on（在……上）组成，表示“兑现，实现”。在这个例句中，它指的是特斯拉一直未能兑现完全自动驾驶和人工智能的承诺。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>With all that being said, Tesla remains a key player in the global transition from petrol-powered vehicles to largely electric ones. - 话虽如此，特斯拉仍然是全球汽油动力汽车向电动汽车转型过程中的关键参与者。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Tesla remains a key player in the global transition from petrol-powered vehicles to largely electric ones，其中主语是Tesla，谓语是remains，宾语是a key player in the global transition from petrol-powered vehicles to largely electric ones。With all that being said是一个连接副词，表示“话虽如此”，将两个句子连接在一起。这个句子的意思是说，话虽如此，特斯拉仍然是全球汽油动力汽车向电动汽车转型过程中的关键参与者。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。      <p>原文例句：Tesla had a blockbuster 2023, as its shares more than doubled in 12 months. </p>      <p>语法讲解：过去完成时态由had + 过去分词构成，表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，had a blockbuster 2023表示特斯拉在2023年取得了巨大的成功，more than doubled in 12 months表示其股票在12个月内上涨了一倍多，这两个动作都发生在过去某个时间点之前。这个句子的意思是说，特斯拉在2023年取得了巨大的成功，其股票在12个月内上涨了一倍多。</p>      <ul><li>Tesla’s losses in the first two weeks of this year have come from a barrage of negative news, including another price cut for its made-in-China cars</li>
<li>The US carmaker has been cutting prices on its vehicles aggressively since early last year in an effort to boost demand</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/83cb01fa-622e-4130-b271-fd9276597c55_850fb60a.jpg" /><figcaption>Tesla chief executive Elon Musk applauds the roll-out of new electric vehicles at the opening of the firm’s Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant  in Germany on March 22, 2022. Photo:  AP</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> had a blockbuster 2023, as its shares more than doubled in 12 months. But 2024 is starting on a different note, with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/elon-musk" target="_self" title="">Elon Musk</a>’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle</a> (EV) maker off to its worst start to any year – ever.</p><p>The company has lost more than US$94 billion in market valuation in just the first two weeks of this year. It is not hard to figure out why, as the Austin, Texas-based EV maker has been pounded by a barrage of negative news: an about-face on EVs from the car rental giant Hertz Global Holdings, yet another price cut for its cars <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-manufacturing" target="_self" title="">made in China</a>, and signs of rising labour costs.</p><p>All of this comes in the face of slowing growth in demand for EVs, especially in the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a>.</p><p>“Investors’ main concern on Tesla is stagnating growth,” Cowen analyst Jeffrey Osborne said in an interview. The price cuts in China only fan those concerns, because it is starting to look like “a race to the bottom for the EV industry given intense competition in that market”.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/b52c250b-b6c8-47e5-91ec-7f2278c772c1_a66cec46.jpg" title="A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Tesla driver charges his car at one of the company’s charging stations in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The hit to Tesla’s market capitalisation to start the year is the biggest the company has seen over a similar period since it went public in 2010. In percentage terms, Tesla’s 12 per cent drop since the start of January is the worst since 2016, when the stock fell 14 per cent over the first nine trading days of the year.</p><p>To make matters worse, the odds of an imminent turnaround for the EV maker do not look good.</p><p>Tesla has been cutting prices on its cars aggressively since early 2023 in an effort to boost demand. But the result has been a steady erosion of its once-hefty profit margin. Tesla’s automotive gross margin ex-regulatory credits for the third quarter fell to 16.3 per cent from 27.9 per cent a year ago. And the pressure is only mounting, now that production workers at Tesla’s US plants are getting pay rises.</p><p>“We are going through a cyclical downturn for EVs, but competitive dynamics are exacerbating the cyclical pressures,” Ivana Delevska, chief investment officer at Spear Invest, said in an interview. “Price cuts and plummeting margins are all a function of these unfavourable competitive dynamics.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing" title="">Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</a></h3><p>Adding to the woes, Tesla has had to divert shipments destined for its Berlin plant after Western military actions and security concerns in the Red Sea, and is suspending most production at its plant near the German capital from January 29 to February 11, according to a person familiar with the matter.</p><p>Tesla first warned about the deceleration in EV demand during its October third-quarter earnings report. Almost immediately after, carmakers and suppliers across the globe chimed in with their own downbeat forecasts. Many carmakers dialled back their plans for expansion.</p><p>Then, earlier this month, Tesla reported its fourth-quarter delivery numbers. While they were better than what analysts expected, they put the company behind China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD Co</a> in global electric-car sales.</p><p>The result has been a rude awakening for Tesla investors. Last year, the stock was the eighth best performer in the S&amp;P 500. So far this year, it is the eighth worst.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa" class="image-inline caption" height="1201" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/47b22035-65d8-46f4-a5cf-8ceaf3d20b48_c243b8f2.jpg" title="Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa" width="2000" /><figcaption>Tesla has largely suspended production at its Gigafactory Berlin-Brandenburg plant in Germany amid security concerns in the Red Sea. Photo: dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Naturally, Musk is taking a big hit personally. The world’s richest person, who gained more wealth last year than anyone else on the planet, has seen his net worth shrink by US$23 billion so far this year, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index.</p><p>Musk regained the top spot on Bloomberg’s wealth index last year, overtaking LVMH Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton founder and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226276/lvmh-boss-bernard-arnaults-visit-highlights-growing-importance-huge-mainland-chinese-market-luxury" target="_self" title="">Bernard Arnault</a>, but now <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon.com</a> founder and executive chairman <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jeff-bezos" target="_self" title="">Jeff Bezos</a> is rapidly closing in, with US$179 billion to Musk’s US$206 billion as of Friday’s close.</p><p>The bulk of Musk’s net worth comes from his 13 per cent stake in Tesla and about 304 million exercisable stock options. He also owns about 42 per cent of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/spacex" target="_self" title="">Space Exploration Technologies</a>, which is valued at about US$53 billion, according to Bloomberg’s wealth index.</p><p>With all that being said, Tesla remains a key player in the global transition from petrol-powered vehicles to largely electric ones. The reason: the company is so far ahead of its potential rivals. China’s BYD may have surpassed Tesla in the number of units sold, but it still lags in revenue and profits. And BYD does not sell cars in the US, where Tesla remains the market leader.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" title="">China’s BYD overtakes Tesla as largest maker of pure-electric vehicles</a></h3><p>In many ways, Tesla’s biggest problem may be its past success and the hope it generated. As investors piled into the stock, Tesla’s market capitalisation ballooned, making it way larger than any other car company in the world. However, with the shares priced for perfection, that also made them highly vulnerable to big reactions to any negative news.</p><p>That is why so many Tesla proponents argue that it should not be compared to regular car companies. To them, the ultimate true value of the company rests in the future and it is hope to develop the first truly <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/self-driving-cars-autonomous-vehicles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">self-driving vehicles</a>. The only problem is Tesla has been promising this for years, and most experts say the technology is still years, maybe even decades, away.</p><p>“Tesla has not been able to deliver on fully autonomous driving and AI promises, which are already embedded in the valuation,” Spear’s Delevska said. “Being simply another automotive manufacturer is not going to cut it for a US$750 billion valuation.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese etching tools giant AMEC sees 2023 sales rise more than 30% on strong demand from mainland semiconductor fabs</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248391/chinese-etching-tools-giant-amec-sees-2023-sales-rise-more-30-strong-demand-mainland-semiconductor</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment (AMEC)，一家上海的刻蚀设备制造商，预计其2023年的收入将达到8.79亿美元，较前一年增长32.1%，这主要得益于强劲的国内订单。该公司表示，其核心蚀刻工具的销售额将占去年总收入的75%。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: AMEC预计2023年收入将增长32.1%，核心蚀刻工具销售额将占总收入的75%。</li>    <li>Theme: AMEC受益于强劲的国内订单，预计2023年收入将实现大幅增长。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: AMEC的核心技术突破使其能够向国内半导体制造厂部署更多芯片制造设备。</li>    <li>Main information: AMEC预计2023年收入将达到62.6亿元人民币（8.79亿美元），同比增长32.1%；公司新订单录得83.6亿元人民币，同比增长32.3%；预计去年净利润为17亿至18.5亿元人民币，同比增长45%至58%。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  上海的先进微制造设备（AMEC）预计去年的收入将比2022年增长30%以上，因为核心技术突破使该公司能够向国内半导体制造厂部署更多芯片制造设备。AMEC在周日的一份监管文件中表示，预计2023年收入将达到62.6亿元人民币（8.79亿美元），同比增长32.1%，主要是由于强劲的国内需求。该公司表示，新订单录得83.6亿元人民币，同比增长32.3%。去年净利润预计为17亿至18.5亿元人民币，同比增长45%至58%。AMEC的积极收益指引反映了其成功扩展中国大陆销售的策略，几个月前，创始人、董事长兼首席执行官尹志尧表示，该公司已制定了一份详细的路线图，以在收紧美国半导体制裁的情况下，用国产零部件替换外国生产的零部件。总部位于上海的先进微制造设备是中国领先的半导体和发光二极管制造商的工艺技术、工具和专业知识提供商。尹志尧表示，AMEC使用的80%的受美国限制的组件将在去年年底前被国产零部件所取代。他预计公司将在2024年实现100%的替代率。上周五，AMEC在上海的股价收跌2.07%，至134.66元。在中国政府支持下，为了实现中国半导体供应链的本地化，自2022年10月华盛顿首次实施出口管制以切断中国从美国、日本和荷兰获得先进芯片制造设备以来，中国大陆半导体代工厂加快了采用国产设备的步伐。AMEC预计，其核心蚀刻工具的销售额，包括电容耦合等离子体（CCP）和电感耦合等离子体（ICP），将占去年公司总收入的75%，将增长近50%至47亿元人民币。先进微制造设备的Prismo UniMax系统用于大规模生产氮化镓基微型发光二极管，这些二极管应用于电视机、笔记本电脑、显示器、汽车和户外显示器等产品。AMEC表示，由于公司去年在核心技术方面取得突破，其CCP和ICP设备被国内代工厂客户越来越多地采用。蚀刻工具是半导体代工厂使用的一些最重要的加工设备。这是中国拥有AMEC和国家支持的纳诺科技集团等强势参与者的一个领域。AMEC的国内CCP设备市场份额预计在不久的将来将达到60%，高于2022年10月的24%。根据公司首席执行官尹志尧的说法，该公司在大陆ICP设备销售中的份额预计将从几乎为零上升到75%，因为曾经占主导地位的美国芯片设备制造商Lam Research的大陆销售额大幅下降。###</div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.njuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：Shanghai-based AMEC expects its 2023 revenue to reach US$879 million, up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic orders</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，意思是“归还，返还”。在这个例句中，它表示AMEC 2023 年的收入预计将达到 8.79 亿美元，比上一年增长 32.1%，这主要是由于强劲的国内订单。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>etching (v.) - /ˈetʃɪŋ/ 蚀刻，腐蚀。    <p>原文例句：AMEC’s positive earnings guidance reflects its successful strategy to expand sales on the mainland, months after founder, chairman and chief executive Gerald Yin Zhiyao said the firm had devised a detailed road map to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts amid tightened US semiconductor sanctions.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语，意思是“划伤，刻画”。在这个例句中，它表示 AMEC 的积极收益指引反映了其成功扩展中国大陆销售的策略，几个月前，创始人、董事长兼首席执行官尹志尧表示，该公司已制定了一份详细的路线图，以在收紧美国半导体制裁的情况下，用国产零部件替换外国生产的零部件。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>核心技术 - core technology    <p>原文例句：The company said sales of its core etching tools will account for 75 per cent of its total revenue last year</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由核心（core）和技术（technology）组成，表示“构成某一学科或领域中最重要的基础部分的技术”。在这个例句中，它表示该公司销售的核心蚀刻工具将占其去年总收入的 75%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>With state-backed efforts to localise great swathes of China’s semiconductor supply chain, mainland semiconductor foundries have accelerated adoption of locally made equipment since October 2022, when Washington first tightened export controls to cut off the country’s access to advanced chip-making gear from the US, Japan and the Netherlands. - 在国家支持下，为了实现中国半导体供应链的本地化，自2022年10月华盛顿首次实施出口管制以切断中国从美国、日本和荷兰获得先进芯片制造设备以来，中国大陆半导体代工厂加快了采用国产设备的步伐。</li><p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是mainland semiconductor foundries have accelerated adoption of locally made equipment，其中主语是mainland semiconductor foundries，谓语是have accelerated adoption of locally made equipment，宾语是locally made equipment。With state-backed efforts to localise great swathes of China’s semiconductor supply chain是一个介词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示在国家支持下，为了实现中国半导体供应链的本地化。since October 2022, when Washington first tightened export controls to cut off the country’s access to advanced chip-making gear from the US, Japan and the Netherlands是一个时间状语从句，修饰主句，表示自2022年10月华盛顿首次实施出口管制以切断中国从美国、日本和荷兰获得先进芯片制造设备以来。这个句子的意思是说，在国家支持下，为了实现中国半导体供应链的本地化，自2022年10月华盛顿首次实施出口管制以切断中国从美国、日本和荷兰获得先进芯片制造设备以来，中国大陆半导体代工厂加快了采用国产设备的步伐。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时（Present Perfect Tense） - 表示从过去某一时间开始一直延续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Yin had said 80 per cent of US-restricted components that AMEC used would be replaced with domestic parts by the end of last year.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是一种时态，表示从过去某一时间开始一直延续到现在或与现在有关的动作或状态。其结构是：主语 + have/has + 过去分词。在这个例句中，had said表示尹志尧之前曾说过，would be replaced表示将被替换，by the end of last year表示到去年年底。这个句子的意思是说，尹志尧  <ul><li>Shanghai-based AMEC expects its 2023 revenue to reach US$879 million, up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic orders</li>
<li>The company said sales of its core etching tools will account for 75 per cent of its total revenue last year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/977166e1-00b7-4d05-941a-ada3e90b90d0_07dcf1ac.jpg" /><figcaption>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment workers at the company’s main production site in Shanghai. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese etching tools giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3232334/tech-war-china-chip-tool-firm-amecs-profit-boosted-strong-local-demand-it-reshuffles-tech-board-wake" target="_self" title="">Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment</a> (AMEC) expects revenue last year to grow more than 30 per cent from 2022, as core <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-technology" target="_self" title="">technology</a> breakthroughs enabled the firm to deploy more chip-making gear to domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductor</a> fabrication plants.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a>-based AMEC said in a regulatory filing on Sunday that its 2023 revenue is expected to reach 6.26 billion yuan (US$879 million), up 32.1 per cent from the previous year, on the back of strong domestic demand. The company said it recorded 8.36 billion yuan worth of new orders, a 32.3 per cent year-on-year increase.</p><p>Net profit last year is projected to be from 1.7 billion yuan to 1.85 billion yuan, representing year-on-year growth of between 45 per cent and 58 per cent.</p><p>AMEC’s positive earnings guidance reflects its successful strategy to expand sales on the mainland, months after founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230803/us-wants-chinas-chip-industry-5-generations-behind-cutting-edge-head-equipment-maker-amec-says-wuxi" target="_self" title="">Gerald Yin Zhiyao</a> said the firm had devised a detailed road map to replace foreign-produced components with domestic parts amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3238693/new-us-curbs-chip-exports-china-set-escalate-battle-tech-supremacy" target="_self" title="">tightened US semiconductor sanctions</a>.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1124" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/8dc83513-a48d-478e-9d86-f625246bf8fe_ada0205e.jpg" title="Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Shanghai-headquartered Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment is China’s leading provider of process technologies, tools and expertise for manufacturers of semiconductors and light-emitting diodes. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Yin had said 80 per cent of US-restricted components that AMEC used would be replaced with domestic parts by the end of last year. He expected the company to achieve a 100-per cent replacement rate in 2024.</p><p>AMEC shares in Shanghai closed down 2.07 per cent to 134.66 yuan last Friday.</p><p>With state-backed efforts to localise great swathes of China’s semiconductor supply chain, mainland semiconductor foundries have accelerated adoption of locally made equipment since October 2022, when Washington <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3195461/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-self-sufficiency-drive-under-siege-new" target="_self" title="">first tightened export controls</a> to cut off the country’s access to advanced chip-making gear from the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">US</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netherlands" target="_self" title="">the Netherlands</a>.</p><p>AMEC expects sales of its core etching tools, including so-called capacitively coupled plasma (CCP) and inductive coupled plasma (ICP), to account for 75 per cent of the firm’s total revenue last year, which would be up nearly 50 per cent to 4.7 billion yuan.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1414" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/646d3f0c-dcc0-4e3c-87fa-0e91b99b21a2_bfef4330.jpg" title="Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment’s Prismo UniMax system is used to mass-produce gallium nitride-based mini-light-emitting diodes found in products that include televisions, laptop computers, monitors, and automotive and outdoor displays. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>AMEC said that its CCP and ICP equipment saw increased adoption by domestic foundry clients on the strength of the firm’s breakthroughs in core technologies last year.</p><p>Etching tools are some of the most important processing equipment used by semiconductor foundries. It is an area where China has strong players such as AMEC and state-backed Naura Technology Group.</p><p>AMEC’s domestic CCP equipment market share is projected to hit 60 per cent in the near future, up from 24 per cent in October 2022. The firm’s share in ICP gear sales on the mainland is predicted to reach 75 per cent from almost zero, according to company chief executive Yin, after once-dominant US chip equipment maker Lam Research saw its mainland sales drop sharply.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China price wars help spark US$157 billion rout in mainland consumer stocks, as firms including Alibaba, Yum China and BYD drag the market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248377/china-price-wars-help-spark-us157-billion-rout-mainland-consumer-stocks-firms-including-alibaba-yum</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Consumer stocks in China have been underperforming in the MSCI China Index since September 2023 due to a lack of positive drivers.</li>    <li>Companies are offering big discounts to attract customers amid tepid consumer demand and a persistent property slump.</li>    <li>The EV industry has been particularly hard hit by intense competition, with Tesla cutting prices to boost sales.</li>    <li>E-commerce giants like Alibaba and JD.com have also been impacted by the price war, leading to a decline in their stock prices.</li>    <li>Many are hoping for interest-rate cuts and government spending to prevent a deflationary spiral in the economy.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>自2023年9月以来，中国消费类股票在明晟中国指数中表现不佳，原因是缺乏积极的驱动因素。</li>    <li>在消费者需求疲软和房地产持续低迷的情况下，公司正在提供大幅折扣以吸引客户。</li>    <li>电动汽车行业受到激烈竞争的特别严重打击，特斯拉降价以提振销售。</li>    <li>阿里巴巴和京东等电子商务巨头也受到价格战的影响，导致其股价下跌。</li>    <li>许多人希望通过降息和政府支出防止通货紧缩螺旋。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>slump (n.) - /slʌmp/ 经济衰退，不景气。    <p>原文例句：People fly dragon-shaped kites on the Bund in front of buildings in Pudong’s Lujiazui Financial District in Shanghai on January 9, 2024. China’s stock market suffers from a lack of positive drivers ahead of the Lunar New Year. Photo: Bloomberg</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由slump（向下滑落）构成，表示“经济衰退，不景气”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国股市在春节前缺乏积极的驱动因素，导致市场低迷。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>tepid (adj.) - /ˈtɛpɪd/ 不温不火的，不活跃的。    <p>原文例句：The seemingly relentless decline in prices of Chinese goods amid tepid consumer demand is denting expectations that corporate earnings can revive the flagging stock market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由tepid（不温不火的）构成，表示“不温不火的，不活跃的”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国消费者的需求不温不火，导致企业收益无法提振低迷的股市。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>drag on - 拖累。    <p>原文例句：The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include Alibaba, Yum China Holdings and BYD, which have all been offering big discounts</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由drag（拖累）和on（在……之上）构成，表示“拖累”。在这个例句中，它指的是阿里巴巴、百胜中国和比亚迪等公司给明晟中国指数造成拖累。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>That’s all symbolic of a very weak consumption environment that includes lack of consumer confidence and weak income growth. - 这是非常弱的消费环境的象征，包括缺乏消费者信心和收入增长乏力。<p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是That’s all symbolic of a very weak consumption environment，其中主语是That，谓语是symbolic of，宾语是a very weak consumption environment。从句是that includes lack of consumer confidence and weak income growth，其中主语是that，谓语是includes，宾语是lack of consumer confidence and weak income growth。这个句子的意思是说，这是非常弱的消费环境的象征，包括缺乏消费者信心和收入增长乏力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行或发生的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Consumer prices fell for a third-straight month in December, the longest streak since 2009, deepening concerns about companies’ profits and share prices.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态正在进行或发生，强调动作或状态的进行性。在这个例句中，它表示消费者价格连续第三个月下降，自2009年以来最长，加剧了人们对公司利润和股价的担忧。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023</li>
<li>The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include Alibaba, Yum China Holdings and BYD, which have all been offering big discounts</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/b3e8597a-be7a-4197-85aa-c1a7be1f6626_e063aefc.jpg" /><figcaption>People fly dragon-shaped kites on the Bund in front of buildings in Pudong’s Lujiazui Financial District in Shanghai on January 9, 2024. China’s stock market suffers from a lack of positive drivers ahead of the Lunar New Year. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>The seemingly relentless decline in prices of Chinese goods amid <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247712/chinas-retail-sales-weaken-year-falling-home-prices-jobs-outlook-feed-consumer-insecurity-ubs" target="_self" title="">tepid consumer demand</a> is denting expectations that corporate earnings can revive the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/china-stock-market" target="_self" title="">flagging stock market</a>.</p><p>From <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicles</a> (EVs) to fast food, companies are engaging in a battle of promotions aimed at luring customers who are spooked by dim job prospects and have seen a persistent property slump hurt wealth creation. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3244649/china-inflation-4-takeaways-novembers-data-deflationary-pressure-heightened" target="_self" title="">Consumer prices</a> fell for a third-straight month in December, the longest streak since 2009, deepening concerns about companies’ profits and share prices.</p><p>“That’s all symbolic of a very weak consumption environment that includes lack of consumer confidence and weak income growth,” said Ng Xin-yao, an investment director for Asian equities at abrdn. “We are cautious on fourth-quarter earnings across most sectors, and would assume that continues in the first quarter unless the government starts doing something massive to support the economy.”</p><p>Gauges of consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/msci" target="_self" title="">MSCI China Index</a> since the end of September, after the real estate measure. The aggregate market value of companies included in the two consumer indexes has fallen by about US$157 billion since.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="2000" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/14/c17c04b3-1a34-4b5f-9767-75f9273ed6e5_8a6158cb.jpg" title="Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Consumer stocks have been the worst performers on the MSCI China Index since the end of September 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>The biggest drags on the MSCI benchmark in this span include e-commerce giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, restaurant operator <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3209531/kfc-pizza-hut-operator-yum-china-open-1300-stores-worst-over-posts-earnings-decline-2022" target="_self" title="">Yum China Holdings</a> and EV maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD Co</a> – which have all been offering big discounts. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>The world’s second-largest stock market has started 2024 on a dismal note, with the MSCI China gauge already down more than 4 per cent so far this year. It capped a third straight annual decline in 2023.</p><p>“The bigger picture is that the weak demand is leading to a deflationary environment, which particularly bodes ill for businesses that cannot achieve higher volumes with lower prices,” said Daisy Li, a fund manager at EFG Asset Management HK.</p><p>The EV industry has been among the worst hit by intense competition as growth slows, with Chinese makers following the lead of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> in lowering prices to boost sales. BYD and local peers including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a> have shed billions of dollars in market value in the past few months.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing" title="">Tesla cuts prices in China to keep grip on premium EV market</a></h3><p>“Retail prices are falling fast,” Morgan Stanley analysts wrote in their 2024 outlook report for the Chinese EV sector. “While local brands, in general, have fared better than luxury and foreign brands in terms of widening discounts, we expect discounts to further widen into the first quarter this year on the back of seasonality effects.”</p><p>Even China’s vaunted <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> giants have been impacted, with Alibaba and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> seeing their stock prices tumble, as they wage a fierce battle for market share. The price war has made US-listed <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247286/pdd-halts-development-local-services-offering-avoid-head-competition-meituan-and-eleme-report-says" target="_self" title="">PDD Holdings</a>, operator of discount sites <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="">Pinduoduo</a> on the mainland and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>, one of the rare bright spots in China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> industry.</p><p>Many economy and market observers are hoping for interest-rate cuts and government spending to help prevent the nation from entering a deflationary spiral.</p><p>Fund managers have said the next catalyst they are watching is pricing and sales data around the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/lunar-new-year" target="_self" title="">Lunar New Year</a> in February, which will offer more clues on consumer confidence.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>The next few weeks may also be key for policy action, given Chinese leaders will soon gear up for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/national-peoples-congress" target="_self" title="">National People’s Congress</a>. That annual legislative session, held in March, is where the government is expected to announce its official growth target for 2024.</p><p>A Morgan Stanley survey conducted late last month suggests seasonally better consumer sentiment ahead of the holidays. However, “sustainability is in doubt amid slowing economic recovery”, analysts including Lillian Lou wrote in a note.</p><p>Salary cuts and job losses have remained among the top concerns of households, they wrote, adding that the number of consumers anticipating the economy to worsen ticked up by two percentage points from November to 13 per cent.</p><p>In all, there is little hope for a quick fix. Citigroup expects consensus estimates to fall for <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-ning-company-ltd" target="_self" title="">Li Ning</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3217413/anta-sports-seeks-us15-billion-equity-placement-market-discount-triggering-stocks-worst-sell-six" target="_self" title="">Anta Sports Products</a> around the upcoming results season, hurt by foreign competition and pushes into lower-tier cities with cheaper products.</p><p>Fast-food companies are still locked in a protracted fight for customers, with some offering full meals for around US$3. It is difficult to make money at such low prices.</p><p>“We expect industry margins to erode until the irrational price war ends,” Kevin Yin, an analyst at JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co., wrote in a note, while cutting estimates for Yum China. “No player is immune” to the headwinds created by the nation’s slowing demand growth, he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Stanford students win hearts in China with US$32,000 household robot that can cook shrimp and wash pans</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248330/stanford-students-win-hearts-china-us32000-household-robot-can-cook-shrimp-and-wash-pans</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In response to the growing need for domestic robots in the aging global population, Stanford University researchers have developed Mobile Aloha, a two-handed robot system capable of autonomously performing various tasks like cooking, cleaning, and lifting objects. The robot's success rate in these tasks is at least 80% after undergoing training with human demonstrations and data sets. With its ability to work autonomously or be remotely controlled, Mobile Aloha paves the way for domestic robots to play a significant role in smart home ecosystems.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Emergent two-handed robot Mobile Aloha impresses with its autonomous capabilities in household tasks.</li>    <li>Theme: Mobile Aloha's groundbreaking performance in completing complex home tasks through imitation learning.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of human-like dexterity and autonomy in advancing domestic robots' role in smart home ecosystems.</li>    <li>Main information: Mobile Aloha's development by Stanford researchers; its capability to autonomously perform cooking, cleaning, and lifting tasks with an 80% success rate; the robot's ability to work autonomously or under remote control; the potential role of domestic robots in aging societies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  针对全球人口老龄化对家用机器人的日益增长需求，斯坦福大学的研究人员开发了 Mobile Aloha，这是一种能够自主执行各种任务（如做饭、清洁和搬运物品）的双手机器人系统。在接受人类示范和数据集训练后，该机器人在这些任务中的成功率至少为 80%。凭借自主工作或远程控制的能力，Mobile Aloha 为家用机器人发挥其在智能家居生态系统中的重要作用铺平了道路。  <ul>    <li>摘要：新颖的双手机器人 Mobile Aloha 以其在家庭任务中自主执行能力令人印象深刻。</li>    <li>主题：Mobile Aloha 通过模仿学习在完成复杂家庭任务方面取得的突破性表现。</li>    <li>观点：类人般的灵巧性和自主性对于提升家用机器人智能家居生态系统作用的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：Mobile Aloha 由斯坦福大学的研究人员开发；能够自主执行烹饪、清洁和搬运任务，成功率达 80%；该机器人能够自主工作或远程控制；家用机器人在家用生态系统中的潜力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>autonomous (adj.) - /ˌɔːtˈɑːnəməs/ 自主的。    <p>原文例句：Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词由auto（本身）和nomos（法律）组成，意为“自动的，自主的”。形容机器人可以自主执行任务，而无需人工干预。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>co-train (v.) - /ˌkoʊˈtreɪn/ 共同训练。    <p>原文例句：After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词由co-（共同）和train（训练）组成，意为“共同训练”。这是一种训练机器学习模型的方法，使用来自多个数据源或任务的数据来增强模型的性能。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>data-driven AI approach - 数据驱动的 AI 方法。    <P>原文例句：The duo took a “data-driven AI approach using human demonstration data to teach the robot” instead of the traditional way of “tons of programming and manual tuning” that is not scalable, Fu said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由data（数据），driven（驱动的），AI（人工智能），approach（方法）组成，表示“数据驱动的 AI 方法”。这是一种人工智能方法，使用大量数据来训练模型，而不是依靠人工设计规则。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Fu said they had to tackle both hardware and software challenges. - Fu 说他们不得不应对硬件和软件两方面的挑战。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Fu said，其中主语是Fu，谓语是said。they had to tackle both hardware and software challenges是一个过去分词短语作宾语，表示Fu他们不得不应对硬件和软件两方面的挑战。这个句子的意思是说，Fu说他们不得不应对硬件和软件两方面的挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 强调句中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：It took three months to develop the robot, according to Zipeng Fu, who co-leads the project with Tony Zhao, advised by Stanford assistant professor Chelsea Finn. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，把It took three months to develop the robot提到了前面，强调了这个事实。根据句子的结构，这个倒装句可以改写成：According to Zipeng Fu, who co-leads the project with Tony Zhao, advised by Stanford assistant professor Chelsea Finn, it took three months to develop the robot.</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Fu and Zhao are also student researchers at Google DeepMind, an artificial intelligence (AI) research laboratory.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示Fu和Zhao现在仍然是Google DeepMind的实习研究员，强调他们一直在从事这项研究工作。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Mobile Aloha, a two-handed system, can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning</li>
<li>It is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, the inventors say</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/13/a5391667-ecfe-41e0-ba55-d4bcc8573340_5eb9826c.jpg" /><figcaption>Mobile Aloha is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning. Photo: Screenshot</figcaption></figure><p>A US$32,000 robot developed by a team at Stanford University has caught the attention of Chinese online users, after a video showing the two-handed robot cooking a three-course meal went viral.</p><p>Mobile Aloha, built by two computer-science PhD candidates from China, is a two-handed system that can be remotely controlled by a human user, or work autonomously through imitation learning.</p><p>After going through 50 human demonstrations and being co-trained on data sets, the machine is able to cook shrimp, rinse a pan, lift a glass of wine and wipe spilled liquid beneath – with a success rate of at least 80 per cent, according to the project’s website.</p><p>It took three months to develop the robot, according to Zipeng Fu, who co-leads the project with Tony Zhao, advised by Stanford assistant professor Chelsea Finn. Fu and Zhao are also student researchers at Google DeepMind, an artificial intelligence (AI) research laboratory.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Fu said they had to tackle both hardware and software challenges. To save cost, they assembled the machine on their own. The goal was to make a robot that could “complete complex home or office tasks that were not shown to be possible previously”.</p><p>The robot can walk at 1.42 metres per second, roughly equivalent to human speed, reach as high as 2 metres and extend one metre beyond its base, the team said.</p><p>When it comes to the software, the duo took a “data-driven AI approach using human demonstration data to teach the robot” instead of the traditional way of “tons of programming and manual tuning” that is not scalable, Fu said.</p><p>The robot cost US$32,000 to build, including on-board power and computing. Fu said he and Zhao, who have open-sourced the whole system, “don’t have any business plan at the moment”.</p><p>As the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ageing-society" target="_self" title="">global population gets older</a>, domestic robots are expected to play a critical role in the smart home ecosystem. The market is estimated to grow at an annual rate of nearly 20 per cent from US$8.6 billion this year to US$22.5 billion by 2029, according to market research firm Mordor Intelligence.</p><p>Global tech giants have been betting big on the sector. In 2021, American online retailer Amazon.com unveiled Astro, a nearly US$1,000 household robot designed for home monitoring. Japanese electronics giant Sony launched the latest generation of its Aibo robot dog in 2018, priced at around US$2,900.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
