<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China’s video gaming market ended 2023 battered and bruised, but can world-beating titles and innovation save the day?</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3248249/chinas-video-gaming-market-ended-2023-battered-and-bruised-can-world-beating-titles-and-innovation</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Throughout 2023, Chinese video game companies and players faced various challenges. Strict regulations, a decrease in consumer spending, and increasing competition both domestically and internationally impacted the industry. ByteDance and Blizzard Entertainment made significant exits from the market, while Tencent introduced new initiatives to support smaller projects. Despite the hurdles, Chinese games continued to gain international recognition with titles such as Baldur's Gate 3, Honkai: Star Rail, and Genshin Impact winning awards. Analysts expect the industry to focus on producing high-quality games and expanding overseas, while tackling issues such as minors' gaming addiction and excessive consumer spending. The approval of 105 new video game licenses in December signaled a potential easing of regulatory pressure, and the industry looks forward to a brighter 2024 with opportunities in the global market.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Despite challenges, Chinese video games made international strides in 2023, with titles winning awards and recognition abroad.</li>    <li>Theme: Chinese video game industry navigates regulatory changes, economic headwinds, and international expansion in 2023.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The need for balancing commercial success with social and cultural considerations in the Chinese gaming industry.</li>    <li>Main information: Layoffs and closures in the industry; initiatives to support smaller projects; international success of Chinese titles; focus on quality and overseas expansion; addressing concerns about minors' gaming addiction and excessive spending.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  2023 年，中国电子游戏公司和玩家面临着诸多挑战。严格的监管、消费者支出的下降以及国内和国际不断加剧的竞争都对该行业产生了影响。字节跳动和暴雪娱乐从市场显着退出，而腾讯推出了新举措以支持小型项目。尽管存在这些障碍，中国游戏凭借《博德之门 3》、《崩坏：星穹铁道》和《原神》等游戏在国际上赢得了认可。分析师预计该行业将专注于制作高质量游戏和海外扩张，同时解决未成年人沉迷游戏和消费者过度支出的问题。12 月批准 105 款新视频游戏许可证标志着监管压力可能有所缓解，业界期待 2024 年在全球市场迎来更光明的前景。  <ul>    <li>摘要：尽管面临挑战，中国电子游戏在 2023 年取得了国际进步，一些游戏在国外获得了奖项和认可。</li>    <li>主题：中国电子游戏行业在 2023 年经历监管变化、经济逆风和国际扩张。</li>    <li>观点：中国游戏行业在追求商业成功的同时还需平衡社会和文化方面的考量。</li>    <li>主要信息：行业内的裁员和倒闭事件；支持小型项目的新举措；中国游戏产品的国际成功；对质量和海外扩张的关注；解决对未成年人沉迷游戏和过度支出的忧虑。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue-generating (adj.) - 产生收入的。    <p>原文例句：The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings, released by Tencent Holdings in 2015.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词由revenue（收入）和generating（产生）组成，表示“产生收入的”。在这个例句中，它指出《王者荣耀》在 2023 年仍然是收入最高的手游，由腾讯控股于 2015 年发行。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>overseas (adj.) - 海外的，国外的。    <p>原文例句：Analysts expect Chinese studios to roll out more hits in 2024, although it remains to be seen whether the content will match up with Beijing’s desire for “excellent” video games that promote socialist values, highlight Chinese culture and demonstrate the country’s advanced technology.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词由over（在……之上）和seas（海洋）组成，表示“海外的，国外的”。在这个例句中，它表明分析人士预计中国工作室将在 2024 年推出更多热门游戏，但这些游戏的内容是否能满足北京对“优秀”电子游戏的期望，即弘扬社会主义价值观、突出中国文化并展示该国先进技术，仍有待观察。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <p>原文例句：In terms of innovation, local developers are likely to “leverage augmented and virtual reality equipment and software” as well as “artificial intelligence (AI) to make the same game playable across different platforms – mobile, desktop and consoles – for a more immersive gameplay experience”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示在创新方面，本地开发人员可能会“利用增强和虚拟现实设备和软件”以及“人工智能 (AI) 使同一款游戏可在不同平台（移动端、桌面端和游戏机）上玩，以获得更沉浸的游戏体验”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. Photo: Shutterstock<p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的简单句，主语是Beijing，谓语是has cracked down，宾语是on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors。has cracked down表示“严厉打击”，是一个现在完成时态的动词，表示这个动作已经完成，并且对现在有影响。to prevent addiction among minors是一个不定式短语，作目的状语，表示“为了防止未成年人沉迷”。minor是“未成年人”的意思。这个句子的大意是：为了防止未成年人沉迷游戏，北京对电子游戏行业进行了严厉打击。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：China’s video games industry is not an island and faces the same headwinds as the wider economy – namely weak domestic consumption amid an unsteady, post-pandemic recovery.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时态表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。其结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。在这个例句中，has been facing表示中国电子游戏行业一直在面临与整个经济相同的阻力，其中namely weak domestic consumption amid an unsteady, post-pandemic recovery是一个现在分词短语，作状语，表示“国内消费疲软，后疫情复苏不稳定”。这个句子的大意是：中国电子游戏行业并非孤岛，它也面临着与整个经济相同的阻力，即国内消费疲软，后疫情复苏不稳定。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Industry regulator ended the year with a draft rule change designed to curb excessive consumer spending on in-game items, sparking market rout</li>
<li>China-backed games continue to make headlines around the world, and many analysts see overseas opportunities for domestic video game firms</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/94beb22e-5bd3-49df-8e52-6405f925421a_939b4d96.jpg" /><figcaption>China-backed games continue to win awards and analysts see more overseas opportunities for domestic developers in 2024. Illustration: SCMP/Lau Ka-kuen</figcaption></figure><p>Although 2023 started with new hope, the year was not filled with fun for Chinese video gaming companies and players.</p><p>ByteDance, the deep-pocketed owner of TikTok that had aggressively acquired gaming operations, decided to throw in the towel and Blizzard Entertainment left the Chinese market after its 14-year-old partnership with NetEase ended.</p><p>Last but not least, the country’s video games regulator ended the year with a draft rule change designed to curb excessive consumer spending on items such as avatars and in-game weapons, wiping out around US$80 billion in market value from Chinese gaming stocks.</p><p>The total number of video game players in China has been peaking.</p><p>By the end of 2023 there were 668 million gamers in China, a tiny increase from the 666 million at the end of 2022. They jointly spent 303 billion yuan (US$42 billion) on games, or about US$63 per gamer last year – roughly a quarter of the amount spent by US gamers.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
<div>
</div>
</div><p>The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained <em>Honour of Kings</em>, released by Tencent Holdings in 2015.</p><p>Amid an increase in regulatory oversight in recent years, China’s video gaming market has, in some ways, become walled off like the country’s television market.</p><p>Censors scrutinise content and control licence approvals, and domestic gaming studios – including Tencent and NetEase – are increasingly expected to deliver Chinese “social values” with their titles. Meanwhile, the companies need to maintain an uneasy balance between maximising revenue for shareholders and protecting minors from gaming addiction.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/310b9ccf-967e-4db1-9a3a-f0047ea1bb08_cda5d6ab.jpg" title="Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Beijing has cracked down on the video gaming industry to prevent addiction among minors. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Video gaming, once seen as a gold mine in China’s internet sector, was also hard hit by lay-offs and closures in the past year, according to industry insiders and executives.</p><p>“Every studio that I know is cutting costs, even industry leader Tencent,” said Mark Wu, who works for a gaming studio in Guangzhou, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p><p>But does this herald another barren year for China’s video game market or is it just a much-needed bout of consolidation and recalibration for an industry that has been subject to wild swings of investment in recent years?</p><p>Earlier this month, the gaming unit of Tencent launched a “spring bamboo shoots” initiative to support low- and medium-budget projects, in a change from a previous focus on projects with heavy production costs, according to industry blog Youxiputao. Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246197/china-approves-105-video-games-christmas-miracle-does-not-revive-stocks-after-suggested-spending" title="">China’s Christmas gift to game developers: 105 approved titles, the most all year</a></h3><p>However, China-backed games continue to make headlines around the world.</p><p>In December The Game Awards (TGA) named <em>Baldur’s Gate 3, c</em>reated and published by Tencent-backed Belgian developer Larian Studios, as video game of the year. Another nominee for the award was <em>Alan Wake 2</em>, from Remedy Entertainment and published by Epic Games, both backed by Tencent.</p><p>Shanghai-based miHoYo – which cracked the global video games market with its hit title <em>Genshin Impact</em> in 2021 – saw its <em>Honkai: Star Rail</em> win TGA’s best mobile game and Apple’s iPhone game of the year in 2023.</p><p>Analysts expect Chinese studios to roll out more hits in 2024, although it remains to be seen whether the content will match up with Beijing’s desire for “excellent” video games that promote socialist values, highlight Chinese culture and demonstrate the country’s advanced technology.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Honkai: Star Rail has delivered another set of game awards for Shanghai-based studio miHoYo. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1125" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/37809897-88de-484d-a18e-024f1aadca30_a18f5966.jpg" title="Honkai: Star Rail has delivered another set of game awards for Shanghai-based studio miHoYo. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Honkai: Star Rail has delivered another set of game awards for Shanghai-based studio miHoYo. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>“In coming years, China’s gaming industry will be focused on producing premium titles and overseas expansion,” said Zhang Shule, an analyst with CBJ Think Tank. “Local developers are expected to step up R&amp;D efforts to make quality games, drawing on their experience and success in the domestic market.”</p><p>In another bright spot, it appears China is set to welcome the massively-popular <em>World of Warcraft</em> back, after developer Blizzard struck a new deal with old partner NetEase, according to a report by domestic media outlet 36Kr.</p><p>CBJ’s Zhang said that while there is still uncertainty about the “remarriage”, NetEase “does stand out in a crowd of options”. “Its experience from the last tie-up and operational edge will be a strong draw.”</p><p>Chinese mobile game user spending in 2023 remained at a level similar to that of 2022, as the market saw an influx of new titles with more games obtaining licences from authorities, according to Nan Lu, director of Asia-Pacific marketing at research firm Sensor Tower.</p><p>Similar spending levels have been recorded in overseas markets, such as the US, South Korea and Southeast Asia in the past year. Still, Sensor Tower has observed a gradual increase in global user spending since the Christmas and 2024 New Year holiday. “Overall, the overseas market continues to offer opportunities for Chinese developers in the coming years, especially those focused on hybrid casual genres,” added Lu.</p><p>According to data from the Game Publishing Committee of the China Audio-Video and Digital Publishing Association, the semi-official industry association, overseas revenue from China video game titles dropped 5.7 per cent in 2023 to US$16.3 billion.</p><p>Meanwhile, China’s video games industry is not an island and faces the same headwinds as the wider economy – namely weak domestic consumption amid an unsteady, post-pandemic recovery.</p><p>Matthew Chen, co-founder and chief operating officer of Chengdu-based Zencat Gaming in southwestern Sichuan province, said that players in China “are not spending that much money amid a slowing economy”.</p><p>UBS analyst Christine Peng said this week that heightened fears among consumers about salary cuts and job security have dragged down retail sales growth in the world’s second-largest economy. The Swiss bank expects China’s retail sales to climb 5.5 per cent in 2024, one percentage point lower than the estimated 6.5 per cent rise last year.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" title="">China to curb excess spending on video games in blow for world’s biggest market</a></h3><p>Wu, the Guangzhou-based video games worker, said that the end of strict pandemic controls in late 2022 led to some good signs in the first few months, but added “demand for gaming [subsequently] gave way to the need [to spend] on necessities”.</p><p>Meanwhile, the overall tone of policy towards the industry remains uncertain. As things stand, all online video games must go through rigorous screening to obtain licences before being released to the public and monetised, and all players are required to have real-name registration.</p><p>Earlier this week, Tencent announced its winter policy for players aged under 18 – they can only play its games online for a combined 16 hours between January 22 and February 24. The rule is designed to comply with Beijing’s 2021 move to impose a play time ceiling for minors.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings , released by Tencent Holdings in 2015. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1503" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/bc900708-65b5-4106-977a-84409ccb6f9e_f9f7aaf5.jpg" title="The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings , released by Tencent Holdings in 2015. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>The biggest revenue-generating mobile game in 2023 remained Honour of Kings , released by Tencent Holdings in 2015. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>But while Beijing has toned down its overall view of video games as “spiritual opium”, the industry was rocked at the end of last year when regulator the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) proposed in a draft rule that games must not offer rewards that entice people to spend excessively, such as for daily logins and funding top-ups.</p><p>The timing and severity of the proposed rule change dealt a fresh blow to already-fragile investor confidence in Chinese stocks. NetEase, the country’s No. 2 gaming operator, fell by nearly a quarter in a single trading day, with Tencent dropping over 12 per cent.</p><p>Zeng Xiaofeng, vice-president of industry research firm Niko Partners, expects the rule change – if passed in its present form – to hit titles that rely heavily on loot boxes for monetisation or incentives for user acquisition, and those that have a large number of high spenders.</p><p>Popular games like Tencent’s <em>Honour of Kings</em> and NetEase’s <em>Eggy Party</em> are less likely to be impacted, as both have relatively low average revenue per user, according to Niko Partners.</p><p>Around 26 per cent of China’s mobile game users are payers, while high spenders – which refers to players that spend 300 yuan (US$42) monthly – only account for 2.5 per cent of mobile gamers in China, according to Niko Partners.</p><p>However, in the wake of the market rout triggered by the NPPA’s action, Beijing attempted to limit the damage by stating its desire for “healthy” development of the industry.</p><p>Meanwhile, Feng Shixin, a key figure overseeing the industry, subsequently stepped down from his official role as the publication bureau chief at the Communist Party’s Central Propaganda Department, according to a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes" target="_self" title="">Post report</a> citing sources.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245240/bytedance-throws-towel-video-games-chinese-studio-mihoyo-claims-global-wins-honkai" title="">As ByteDance retreats in video games, miHoYo claims global wins with new title</a></h3><p>And Beijing approved 105 new video game licences in December, the most in 17 months. In 2023 the regulator issued 1,075 licences for domestic and foreign games, more than double the number in 2022. 98 imported titles also received the greenlight in 2023, up from 44 in 2022, and Niko Partners expects another increase this year.</p><p>CBJ’s Zhang says that in terms of innovation, local developers are likely to “leverage augmented and virtual reality equipment and software” as well as “artificial intelligence (AI) to make the same game playable across different platforms – mobile, desktop and consoles – for a more immersive gameplay experience”.</p><p>Meanwhile, many of the industry workers the Post interviewed have used generative AI, the technology popularised by OpenAI’s ChatGPT, to produce various gaming content, including text, images and video.</p><p>Zencat Gaming’s Chen said that the use of AI tools to modify pictures, generate video and dub animated characters can cut the costs of overall video game development by roughly 20 per cent.</p><p>This can be a double-edged sword though. As Wu, the Guangzhou-based industry worker pointed out, while the new technology can be a “great assistant” it may very well kill entry-level jobs.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tech war: China chip imports fall in 2023 but semiconductors remain country’s largest item ahead of crude oil</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248269/tech-war-china-chip-imports-fall-2023-semiconductors-remain-countrys-largest-item-ahead-crude-oil</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  In 2023, China's imports of integrated circuits (ICs) experienced a decline both in volume and value, mainly due to economic challenges and the country's efforts to promote local chip production. The United States' export control measures have further restricted China's access to advanced chips, prompting the country to focus on boosting domestic output.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China's IC imports declined in 2023 due to economic headwinds, localization efforts, and US export controls.</li>    <li>Theme: China's chip industry faces challenges due to a combination of factors, including global economic conditions, geopolitical tensions, and the country's drive for self-sufficiency in chip production.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The rising tensions between China and the United States, particularly in the technology sector, have a significant impact on China's ability to import advanced chips, forcing the country to focus on building its own domestic chip production capabilities.</li>    <li>Main information: China's total IC imports decreased by 10.8% in volume and 15.4% in value in 2023; efforts to promote local output of legacy chips have shown progress; US export controls have disrupted global semiconductor supply chains.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2023 年，中国进口集成电路（IC）的数量和价值均出现下降，主要原因是经济挑战和国家促进本地芯片生产的努力。美国的出口管制措施进一步限制了中国获得先进芯片的机会，促使该国专注于提高国内产量。  <ul>    <li>摘要：由于经济逆风、本地化努力和美国出口管制，中国 2023 年的 IC 进口下降了。</li>    <li>主题：中国芯片行业面临挑战，原因多种多样，包括全球经济状况、地缘政治紧张局势，以及国家芯片生产自给自足的努力。</li>    <li>观点：中美之间日益加剧的紧张局势，尤其是在科技领域，对中国进口先进芯片的能力产生了重大影响，迫使该国专注于建设自己的国内芯片生产能力。</li>    <li>主要信息：2023 年，中国进口的 IC 总量按数量计算下降了 10.8%，按价值计算下降了 15.4%；促进传统芯片本地产出的努力取得进展；美国的出口管制扰乱了全球半导体供应链。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>headwind (n.) - /ˈhɛdwɪnd/ 逆风。    <p>原文例句：The weaker imports of ICs and semiconductor devices reflect economic headwinds in the world’s second-largest economy last year, in particular China’s weak smartphone and laptop sales. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于head（头）和wind（风），表示“逆风”。在这个例句中，它指的是阻碍经济发展的因素，如经济衰退、失业率上升和消费者信心下降。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>rely on - /rɪˈlaɪ ɑːn/ 依靠，依赖。    <p>原文例句：The US intensified its export controls on China in October 2022, which caused widespread disruption for global fabless and semiconductor tools companies in their China-related businesses. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个短语是由rely（依靠，依赖）和on（在……上，依靠）构成的，表示“依靠，依赖”。在这个例句中，它指的是全球无晶圆厂公司和半导体工具公司在与中国相关的业务中依赖于中国。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>integrated circuit (IC) - 集成电路。    <P>原文例句：China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由integrated（集成）和circuit（电路）构成的，表示“集成电路”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国从国外进口的集成电路的数量和价值大幅下降。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>semiconductor device - 半导体器件。    <P>原文例句：China’s imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices, a proxy of garden-variety commodity chips, were also down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year.  </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由semiconductor（半导体）和device（器件）构成的，表示“半导体器件”。在这个例句中，它指的是去年中国进口的二极管和类似的通用商品芯片的数量也下降了 23.8% 。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023, although semiconductors remained the mainland’s largest import item ahead of crude oil, according to customs data released on Friday. - 根据周五公布的海关数据，2023年中国进口集成电路（IC）的数量和价值均大幅下降，尽管半导体仍然是大陆最大的进口项目，超过了原油。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023，其中主语是China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC)，谓语是plunged，宾语是by both volume and value in 2023。although semiconductors remained the mainland’s largest import item ahead of crude oil是一个让步状语从句，表示尽管半导体仍然是大陆最大的进口项目，超过了原油。这个句子的意思是说，根据周五公布的海关数据，2023年中国进口集成电路（IC）的数量和价值均大幅下降，尽管半导体仍然是大陆最大的进口项目，超过了原油。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>倒装句 - 为了强调或突出句子的某个成分，把句子的谓语动词或助动词提前到主语之前。    <p>原文例句：In 2023, China imported a total of 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个倒装句，把谓语动词imported提前到主语China之前，表示强调2023年中国进口集成电路的情况。这个句子的意思是说，2023年，中国总共进口了4795亿个集成电路，价值3494亿美元。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>强调句 - 在句中使用there be结构，把要强调的成分放在there之后，be动词之后。    <p>原文例句：Under rigid US export control measures, China is unable to directly purchase advanced chips such as Nvidia’s H100 and A100 GPUs. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个强调句，把要强调的成分China is unable to directly purchase advanced chips such as Nvidia’s H100 and A100 GPUs放在there之后，be动词is之后，表示强调中国无法直接购买英伟达的H100和A100等先进芯片。这个句子的意思是说，在严格的美国出口管制措施下，中国无法直接购买英伟达的H100和A100等先进芯片。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In 2023, China imported a total of 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion</li>
<li>Under rigid US export measures, China is unable to directly purchase advanced chips such as Nvidia’s H100 and A100 GPUs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/7a87b40d-bebc-417b-9aa1-baaa805bde8c_3c46d64f.jpg" /><figcaption>China chip imports fall in 2023 on economic headwinds and localisation efforts. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>China’s imports of integrated circuits (IC) plunged by both volume and value in 2023, although semiconductors remained the mainland’s largest import item ahead of crude oil, according to customs data released on Friday.</p><p>In 2023, China imported a total of 479.5 billion IC units worth US$349.4 billion, down 10.8 per cent by volume and 15.4 per cent in value from 2022, official data showed. By comparison, the country spent US$337.5 billion importing crude oil last year, a fall of 7.7 per cent.</p><p>The weaker imports of ICs and semiconductor devices reflect economic headwinds in the world’s second-largest economy last year, in particular China’s weak smartphone and laptop sales. Meanwhile, the data was also affected by China’s efforts to boost local output to cut reliance on imported chips.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248095/nvidia-reveals-progress-chinas-self-driving-chip-market-setting-competition-domestic-players" title="">Nvidia reveals progress in China’s self-driving chip market as competition revs up</a></h3><p>Under rigid US export control measures, China is unable to directly buy advanced chips, such as the H100 and A100 graphics processing units designed by US-based Nvidia. However, the country is making solid progress in boosting local output of legacy chips, including those being used in cars and home appliances, to satisfy domestic demand.</p><p>According to the customs data, China’s imports of diodes and similar semiconductor devices, a proxy of garden-variety commodity chips, were also down by 23.8 per cent in volume terms last year.</p><p>The US intensified its export controls on China in October 2022, which caused widespread disruption for global fabless and semiconductor tools companies in their China-related businesses. In October last year, the US further tightened the noose, cutting China’s access to workaround chips that Nvidia had tailor-made for mainland customers.</p><p>In a state-backed drive to build a more resilient domestic chip supply chain, China’s semiconductor players have upped their localisation efforts with closer cooperation between the biggest companies. These efforts may also have contributed to the decline of imported chips as China added mature capacity to enable production of the vast majority of chips locally.</p><p>China currently has 44 semiconductor wafer fabs in operation and a further 22 under construction, Taiwan-based IC research company TrendForce said in a recent note. By the end of 2024, the capacity for mature chip production – defined as 28-nanometre and older technologies – will be expanded at 32 Chinese fabs.</p><p>The massive expansion, which has caused alarm in the US and EU, will see China’s global share of mature process capacity reach 39 per cent by 2027, up from 31 per cent in 2023, with room for further growth if equipment procurement proceeds smoothly, the TrendForce note said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tencent’s e-commerce drive takes off in 2023 on the back of super app WeChat’s short video and live streaming function</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248254/tencents-e-commerce-drive-takes-2023-back-super-app-wechats-short-video-and-live-streaming-function</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  WeChat Channels, a short video and live streaming feature of WeChat, has witnessed remarkable growth in 2023. Gross merchandise volume (GMV) for online orders placed through this platform nearly tripled last year, with the number of orders rising by over 244 percent, according to data released at the annual Open Class Pro developer conference. WeChat Channels has also been a major driver of Tencent's advertising business, helping it achieve a 20% year-over-year growth in the third quarter.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: WeChat Channels' short video and live streaming feature has fueled its growth in China's e-commerce landscape.</li>    <li>Theme: WeChat Channels' tremendous growth and its impact on Tencent's advertising and e-commerce businesses.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: WeChat's strategic focus on short video content and live-streaming e-commerce as a means to expand its user base and revenue streams.</li>    <li>Main information: WeChat Channels' impressive GMV and order growth in 2023; its contribution to Tencent's advertising revenue; the platform's growing number of active users.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  微信频道的短视频和直播功能在2023年取得了显著增长。根据在一年一度的开放课程专业开发者大会上发布的数据，通过该平台下的订单总额（GMV）去年几乎增长了两倍，订单数量增长了244％以上。微信频道也是腾讯广告业务的主要驱动力，帮助其在第三季度实现同比增长20％。  <ul>    <li>摘要：微信频道的短视频和直播功能推动了其在中国电商领域的发展。</li>    <li>主题：微信频道的巨大增长及其对腾讯广告和电商业务的影响。</li>    <li>观点：微信战略性地关注短视频内容和直播电商，以此作为其扩大用户群和收入流的一种手段。</li>    <li>主要信息：微信频道在2023年令人印象深刻的GMV和订单增长；其对腾讯广告收入的贡献；该平台活跃用户数量的增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>gross merchandise volume (GMV) - /ˌgroʊs ˈmɜːrtʃəndaɪz ˈvɒljuːm/ 销售总额，商品交易总额。    <p>原文例句：WeChat’s short video and live streaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023. - 微信的短视频和直播功能促使平台在2023年将销售总额（GMV）提高了近两倍。</p>    <p>例句讲解：“gross merchandise volume”是由gross（总的）、merchandise（商品）和volume（量）组成的，意为“销售总额，商品交易总额”，表示某个电子商务平台或企业在一段特定时间内销售的所有商品或服务的总价值。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>town hall meeting - /ˈtaʊn hɔːl ˈmiːtɪŋ/ 市政厅会议，全体职工大会。    <p>原文例句：Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. - 腾讯控股创始人、董事会主席兼首席执行官马化腾在2022年12月的一次内部市政厅会议上表示，短视频是公司的“希望”。</p>    <p>例句讲解： “town hall meeting”是由town(城市、市政厅)、hall（厅）和meeting（会议）组成的，意为“市政厅会议，全体职工大会”，表示一种由组织或政府在特定场所召开的公开会议，目的是让员工或公民参与讨论组织或政府的政策和重大决策。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make inroads into - 取得进展，渗透。    <p>原文例句：The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s internet industry, as Tencent Holdings quietly made inroads into the live-streaming e-commerce market. - 微信频道的进展在中国互联网行业备受关注，因为腾讯控股悄悄地渗透了直播电商市场。</p>    <p>例句讲解：词组是由make（做，制作）, inroads（侵入，渗透）和into（进入）组成的，意为“取得进展，渗透”，表示某人或组织通过努力逐渐取得成功或进展。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>take on - 承担，接受。</li>    <p>原文例句：Tencent quietly made inroads into the live-streaming e-commerce market to take on ByteDance-owned Douyin and Kuaishou Technology – the country’s two largest short video platforms. - 腾讯悄悄地渗透了直播电商市场，以接纳字节跳动旗下的抖音和快手科技——两个国内最大的短视频平台。</p>    <p>例句讲解：词组是由take（拿，接受）和on（在……之上）组成的，意为“承担，接受”，表示某人或组织自愿或被迫承担或接受某项责任或挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>WeChat Channels raked in 3 billion yuan (US$421 million) in advertising revenue during the second quarter. - 在第二季度，微信频道获得了30亿元人民币（4.21亿美元）的广告收入。</li>    <p>句子解析：这个句子由两个分句组成，主句是WeChat Channels raked in 3 billion yuan in advertising revenue，其中主语是WeChat Channels，谓语是raked in，宾语是3 billion yuan in advertising revenue。during the second quarter是一个时间状语，表示在第二季度。句子的意思是微信频道在第二季度获得了30亿元人民币的广告收入。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Tencent Holdings, China’s video gaming and social media giant, saw its ubiquitous super app WeChat achieve significant growth in its live-streaming e-commerce business last year. - 中国视频游戏和社交媒体巨头腾讯控股去年其无处不在的超级应用微信在直播电商业务上取得了显著增长。</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是由have/has been + 现在分词构成的，表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。have/has根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。在这个例句中，saw表示看到，achieve表示取得，这两个动词都用现在完成时表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由句子的宾语承受的。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15. - 多年来，该公司一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，包括最新的iPhone 15。</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是由be + 过去分词构成的，表示动作或状态是由句子的宾语承受的。be根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词。在这个例句中，be用的是has been，过去分词是making，表示该公司一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Online orders made through WeChat’s short video and live streaming function, Channels, grew more than 244 per cent in 2023 over the previous year</li>
<li>WeChat Channels has also become a major driver of Tencent’s advertising business, which grew 20 per cent year on year in the third quarter</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/424841e5-a3ac-4b8a-ae91-51168cfa301a_99a90435.jpg" /><figcaption>The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s internet industry, as Tencent Holdings quietly made inroads into the live-streaming e-commerce market. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tencent" target="_self" title="">Tencent Holdings</a>, China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video gaming</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/social-media" target="_self" title="">social media</a> giant, saw its ubiquitous super <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">app</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> achieve significant growth in its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/live-streaming" target="_self" title="">live-streaming</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce business</a> last year, thanks to the popularity of its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="">TikTok</a>-style short video function.</p><p>WeChat’s short video and live streaming function enabled the platform to record nearly triple gross merchandise volume (GMV) in 2023, according to information released on Thursday during the app’s annual Open Class Pro developer conference held in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/guangzhou-0" target="_self" title="">Guangzhou</a>, capital of southern Guangdong province.</p><p>While the platform’s exact GMV figures were not released, conference attendees were told that the number of orders made through WeChat’s video function – marketed as Channels – grew more than 244 per cent in 2023 over the previous year, according to a report by Chinese online media outlet Thepaper.cn.</p><p>A number of attendees at the conference, which was held as a closed-door event exclusive to industry partners, on Friday confirmed the reported growth rate. Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="2408" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/382a2415-7317-4bb1-8359-257715bbe26b_8190c8e6.jpg" title="Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>Tencent Holdings founder, chairman and chief executive Pony Ma Huateng told an internal town hall meeting in December 2022 that short video was “the hope” of the company. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>WeChat’s high GMV performance last year showed how prescient Tencent founder, chairman and chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/abacus/who-what/who/article/3028219/pony-ma-tycoon-behind-chinas-social-media-and-gaming-giant" target="_self" title="">Pony Ma Huateng</a> was in December 2022, when he told an internal town hall meeting that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3204291/tencents-pony-ma-says-cost-cutting-will-continue-2023-and-pins-hope-short-video-major-growth-driver" target="_self" title="">short video was key to the company’s future</a>.</p><p>The progress of WeChat Channels has been closely watched in China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> industry, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244790/tencent-set-hit-e-commerce-sales-milestone-2023-closing-short-video-rivals-bytedance-kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Tencent quietly made inroads</a> into the live-streaming e-commerce market to take on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/kuaishou" target="_self" title="">Kuaishou Technology</a> – the country’s two largest short video platforms.</p><p>Tencent was expected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244790/tencent-set-hit-e-commerce-sales-milestone-2023-closing-short-video-rivals-bytedance-kuaishou" target="_self" title="">hit 100 billion yuan (US$13.9 billion) in e-commerce GMV</a>, a measure of the total value of goods sold online, through WeChat Channels last year, according to a report last month by Chinese media outlet LatePost.</p><p>While the e-commerce turnover on WeChat Channels is small compared with those of Kuaishou and TikTok’s Chinese sibling Douyin, Tencent has bet on swiftly building its online retail business on the back of the country’s vast number of WeChat users, estimated at 1.34 billion.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/648b1380-6ea8-4522-b681-e27f1eb67183_1126e908.jpg" title="WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>WeChat short video function Channels has become a force in Tencent Holdings’ advertising and live-streaming e-commerce operations. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Tencent also plans to expand its live-streaming e-commerce-related headcount and broaden its product categories, as the WeChat Pay team builds the vital transaction infrastructure to facilitate online payments, according to the LatePost report.</p><p>WeChat Channels has already become a major driver of Tencent’s advertising business, which increased 20 per cent year on year in the third quarter, the fastest growth achieved by all of the company’s business segments in that period. During the second quarter, WeChat Channels raked in 3 billion yuan (US$421 million) in advertising revenue.</p><p>Launched in 2020, Channels has been growing rapidly and had about 813 million active users as of June 2022. That number was ahead of Douyin’s 680 million users and the 390 million on Kuaishou, according to estimates by Chinese data analytics firm QuestMobile.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tesla cuts prices in China on Model 3 and Model Y EVs to keep commanding lead in premium segment of fast-growing market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3248171/tesla-cuts-prices-china-model-3-and-model-y-evs-keep-commanding-lead-premium-segment-fast-growing</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Tesla has lowered prices in China to maintain market share amidst rising competition from Chinese electric car makers. The company's Shanghai-made Model 3 and Model Y saw price cuts of up to 6%, with the standard Model 3 starting at 245,900 yuan ($36,814) and the base Model Y priced at 258,900 yuan. Tesla's price adjustments aim to maintain competitiveness in a growing market where domestic rivals are launching new intelligent electric vehicles.  <ul>    <li>Tesla cuts prices in China to stay competitive amid increasing rivals.</li>    <li>Price cuts of up to 6% on locally produced Model 3 and Model Y.</li>    <li>Tesla's market share at stake due to fierce competition from domestic EV manufacturers.</li>    <li>Chinese home-grown rivals introducing new intelligent electric cars.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文摘要：</h2>  特斯拉下调中国售价以应对中国电动汽车制造商日益激烈的竞争，以保持市场份额。该公司在上海生产的 Model 3 和 Model Y 的价格最高下调 6%，标准版 Model 3 起售价为 245,900 元（36,814 美元），基本版 Model Y 起售价为 258,900 元。特斯拉的价格调整旨在保持在一个增长市场中的竞争力，因为国内对手正在推出新的智能电动汽车。  <ul>    <li>特斯拉为保持竞争力而降低在中国的售价。</li>    <li>在本地生产的 Model 3 和 Model Y 的价格最高下调 6%。</li>    <li>由于国内电动汽车制造商的激烈竞争，特斯拉的市场份额面临风险。</li>    <li>中国本土竞争对手推出新的智能电动汽车。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>premium (n.) - /ˈpriːmɪəm/ 溢价，保险费。    <p>原文例句：Tesla apparently hopes to maintain its market share in the highly competitive market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Premium 在这里表示“溢价”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>raft (n.) - /ræft/ 木筏，大量，一系列。    <p>原文例句：“Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder,” analyst says.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Raft 在这里表示“一系列”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>nipping (v.) - /ˈnɪpɪŋ/ 咬，夹，减。    <p>原文例句：The company’s domestic rivals are not exactly nipping at its heels.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Nip 在这里表示“减，削弱”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>lure (v.) - /ljʊər/ 引诱，诱惑。    <p>原文例句：Some leading players spearheading price cuts to lure customers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Lure 在这里表示“引诱”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>maintain its market share - 维持其市场份额。    <p>原文例句：Tesla apparently hopes to maintain its market share in the highly competitive market.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Maintain its market share 在这里表示“维持其市场份额”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>launch a raft of new intelligent electric cars - 推出一系列新的智能电动汽车。    <p>原文例句：“Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder,” analyst says.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Launch a raft of new intelligent electric cars 在这里表示“推出一系列新的智能电动汽车”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>price cuts to lure customers - 降价以吸引顾客。    <p>原文例句：Some leading players spearheading price cuts to lure customers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Price cuts to lure customers 在这里表示“降价以吸引顾客”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market.     <p>句子解析：这个句子是典型的复合句，由主句 Tesla has cut 和从句 as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market 组成。主句谓语是 has cut，宾语是 the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles。从句谓语是 work，主语是 it，宾语是 to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market。这个句子主要讲述了特斯拉为了保持其在全球最大的电动汽车市场的领先地位，将上海制造的汽车价格下调了最高 6%。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Tesla has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest electric vehicle (EV) market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例子中，has cut 是现在完成时态，表示特斯拉已经并将继续削减其上海制造汽车的价格，以努力保持其在全球最大的电动汽车市场的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Carmaker cut prices by up to 6 per cent after reporting 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December</li>
<li>‘Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder,’ analyst says</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/7e2c041a-9f88-4d42-864b-ea64912c8bf0_9e3fcf96.jpg" /><figcaption>People look at a Tesla Model 3 at a showroom in Beijing on January 6, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p><a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/tesla" target="_self" title="">Tesla</a> has cut the prices of its Shanghai-made vehicles by up to 6 per cent as it works to maintain its leading position in the premium segment of the world’s largest <a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/electric-cars" target="_self" title="">electric vehicle (EV)</a> market.</p><p>The Texas-based company announced on Friday that the price of the entry-level edition of its Model 3 will be reduced from 261,400 yuan (US$36,814) to 245,900 yuan, while the starting price of the Model Y is now 258,900 yuan, down from 266,400 yuan.</p><p>The price cuts come after Tesla reported 15.7 per cent month-on-month sales growth to 75,805 units in mainland China in December, according to data released by the China Passenger Car Association.</p><p>“Tesla apparently hopes to maintain its market share in the highly competitive market,” said Phate Zhang, founder of Shanghai-based EV data provider CnEVPost. “Chinese home-grown rivals have launched a raft of new intelligent electric cars to mount a challenge to the US EV builder.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua" class="image-inline caption" height="1618" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/eb3603e2-9af8-4fa3-8ecc-aae102cfa6f6_a8c0939e.jpg" title="Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua" width="2000" /><figcaption>Workers check a new Xpeng EV at the end of an assembly line in Zhaoqing, in southeast China’s Guangdong province, on October 09, 2023. Photo: Xinhua</figcaption></figure></div><p>Tesla also lowered the price of the dual-motor version of the Model 3 by 3.9 per cent to 285,900 yuan and offered a 2.1 per cent discount on the dual-motor Model Y, which now sells for 299,900 yuan.</p><p>The front-runner in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3241811/chinas-premium-ev-segment-set-cutthroat-competition-huawei-baidu-and-xiaomi-join-fray" target="_self" title="">China’s premium electric vehicle (EV) segment</a> delivered 603,664 EVs made in its Shanghai Gigafactory to buyers in China last year, up 37.3 per cent from 2022. The growth was nearly unchanged from the 37 per cent sales rise recorded in 2022 when it delivered about 440,000 vehicles.</p><p>The company’s domestic rivals are not exactly nipping at its heels. Its closest competitor in the premium segment, <a href="http://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="">Li Auto</a>, delivered about 376,000 cars in 2023.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Tesla adjusts the prices of its locally built vehicles regularly based on production costs, Grace Tao, Tesla’s head of communications and government affairs in China, said on the microblogging site Weibo last January. Since January 2020, Tesla China cut prices on its Chinese-made models six times. This is the first reduction since August 2023; Tesla slightly raised prices between October and November when growth of deliveries in China slowed.</p><p>The Gigafactory, Tesla’s largest production hub worldwide, has an annual capacity of about 1 million units.</p><p>Aside from deliveries to mainland customers, the Shanghai factory also shipped 344,078 vehicles to markets like Japan and Germany in 2023, up 26.9 per cent year on year, according to data compiled by the CnEVPost.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247942/ces-2024-china-ev-maker-xpeng-accepts-pre-orders-flying-car-notes-urban-use-far" title="">Chinese EV maker shows off flying car but admits urban use is far off</a></h3><p>Sales of electric cars in China jumped 37 per cent last year, with deliveries of pure EVs and plug-in hybrids hitting 8.9 million units. At present, mainland China accounts for about 60 per cent of global EV sales.</p><p>But sales growth of battery-powered vehicles in mainland China is expected to slow to 20 per cent year on year in 2024, according to a Fitch Ratings’ report in November.</p><p>Intensifying competition is piling pressure on the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3237078/chinas-ev-war-only-strongest-will-survive-byd-xpengs-dominance-knock-out-15-pretenders-amid-supply" target="_self" title="">200-plus Chinese EV makers</a> this year, with some leading players spearheading price cuts to lure customers.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247906/vw-and-gm-lose-ground-chinese-ev-makers-petrol-heavy-line-ups-fall-out-favour-worlds-largest-car" title="">VW and GM lose ground to Chinese EV makers as petrol-heavy line-ups lose favour</a></h3><p>A new round of price cuts is in effect, with BYD, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247041/chinas-byd-poised-overtake-tesla-worlds-largest-maker-pure-electric-vehicles-fourth-quarter-ev-sales" target="_self" title="">the world’s largest EV maker</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xpeng" target="_self" title="">Xpeng</a> offering discounts to bolster sales.</p><p>Early last month, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/byd" target="_self" title="">BYD</a> cut the price of its Han luxury car by as much as 20,000 yuan to meet its annual sales target. Xpeng followed by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3245621/china-evs-xpeng-cuts-price-bestselling-g6-suv-maintain-high-sales-volume-amid-intensifying" target="_self" title="">cutting the price of its bestselling G6 SUV</a> by 10,000 yuan, or about 5 per cent.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US$3 billion top Asia fund bets on Tencent again despite China gaming rules, favours Samsung over TSMC in chip market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3248169/us3-billion-top-asia-fund-bets-tencent-again-despite-china-gaming-rules-favours-samsung-over-tsmc</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which outperformed its peers, recently re-added Tencent Holdings to its portfolio, despite China's new restrictions on online gaming. The fund manager, Jonathan Pines, believes the Chinese market is undervalued and offers attractive investment opportunities. He sold Tencent shares a year ago but sees it as undervalued now. The fund also prefers Samsung Electronics over TSMC in the semiconductor market.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Fund manager sees value in Chinese market despite gaming restrictions.</li>    <li>Theme: Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund's investment strategy in the Chinese market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Jonathan Pines's optimistic outlook on China's beaten-down market and his preference for Samsung Electronics over TSMC.</li>    <li>Main information: Fund's outperformance; Tencent's valuation; China's gaming restrictions; Samsung Electronics' position in the memory chip sector.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund，一支表现优于大多数同行的基金，最近将其投资组合中重新加入了腾讯控股，押注这家游戏公司的有吸引力的估值，尽管中国政府进一步限制了该行业。该基金的管理人乔纳森·派恩表示，中国市场估值过低，提供了有吸引力的投资机会。他一年前卖出了腾讯的股票，但现在认为其估值被低估。该基金还更青睐三星电子而不是台积电在半导体市场中的地位。  <ul>    <li>摘要：基金经理看好中国市场，尽管有游戏限制。</li>    <li>主题：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund 在中国市场的投资策略。</li>    <li>观点：乔纳森·派恩对中国低迷市场的乐观前景以及他对三星电子优于台积电的偏好。</li>    <li>主要信息：基金的优异表现；腾讯的估值；中国对游戏行业的限制；三星电子在存储芯片领域的市场地位。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>peers (n.) - 同行，同类。    <p>原文例句：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：Peers 的意思是同类、同行，在经济学中经常用这个词。 在这个例句中，它指的是Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund的同类基金。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>curb (v.) - 限制，抑制。    <p>原文例句：China released draft guidelines on December 22, 2023, aimed at curbing excessive spending on online gaming.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：Curb 的意思是限制、抑制，表示采取措施来减少或阻止某件事的发生。在这个例句中，它指的是中国政府发布的旨在限制过度支出用于网络游戏的指导方针。</p>    </li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>valuation (n.) - 估值。    <p>原文例句：The investment reflects the fund’s optimism over the nation’s beaten-down market, where valuations are “absolutely incredible”, said Jonathan Pines, who manages the US$3.1 billion fund.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：Valuation 的意思是估值，是指对某项资产或业务的价值进行评估的过程或结果。在这个例句中，它指的是Jonathan Pines对中国市场的估值。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>cyclical (adj.) - 周期的。    <p>原文例句：TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：Cyclical 的意思是周期的，形容词，指具有周期性，即在一定时间内重复发生的。在这个例句中，它指的是TSMC的周期性低迷。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>outperform sth. - 优于某物。    <p>原文例句：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：Outperform sth. 的意思是优于某物，表示在表现或结果方面超过某物。在这个例句中，它指的是Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund在过去三年中优于其83%的同行。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>make a purchase - 进行购买。    <p>原文例句：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：Make a purchase 的意思是进行购买，表示购买商品或服务。在这个例句中，它指的是Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund在新年进行了购买。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>be due for sth. - 即将遇到某事。    <p>原文例句：TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now.    </p>    <p>例句讲解：Be due for sth. 的意思是即将遇到某事，表示某件事即将发生。在这个例句中，它指的是TSMC即将遇到周期性低迷。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December. - Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund 在过去三年中表现优于其 83% 的同行，即使在中国发布游戏限制草案后，它仍在新年进行了购买。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund made the purchase，其中主语是Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund，谓语是made the purchase。which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund，表示Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund在过去三年中表现优于其83%的同行。even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December是一个时间状语，表示即使在中国发布游戏限制草案后。这个句子的意思是说，Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund 在过去三年中表现优于其 83% 的同行，即使在中国发布游戏限制草案后，它仍在新年进行了购买。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在分词做状语 - 表示动作或状态发生的时间或原因。    <p>原文例句：Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a draft rule on gaming restrictions in December.    </p>    <p>语法讲解：现在分词做状语是指用现在分词形式作状语，表示动作或状态发生的时间或原因。在这个例句中，which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years是一个现在分词做状语，表示Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund在过去三年中表现优于其83%的同行。</p>    </li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>过去分词做定语 - 表示对名词或代词的修饰和限定。    <p>原文例句：TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory  <ul><li>Investment reflects fund’s optimism over beaten-down market, where valuations are ‘absolutely incredible’, says fund manager</li>
<li>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund also prefers Samsung Electronics over TSMC in the semiconductor market</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/b3633bc7-a417-4b09-b1bb-2156486982fa_cf3478d7.jpg" /><figcaption>A man plays an online game from Tencent on a train. China released draft guidelines on December 22, 2023, aimed at curbing excessive spending on online gaming. Photo: AP</figcaption></figure><p>A fund that outperformed most of its peers has added Tencent Holdings back to its portfolio recently, betting on the gaming company’s attractive valuation despite further industry curbs by the Chinese government.</p><p>Federated Hermes Asia Ex-Japan Equity Fund, which beat 83 per cent of its peers for the past three years, made the purchase in the new year, even after China released a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246161/chinas-video-gaming-watchdog-speaks-out-after-draft-spending-rules-roil-market" target="_self" title="">draft rule on gaming restrictions in December</a>. The investment reflects the fund’s optimism over the nation’s beaten-down market, where valuations are “absolutely incredible”, said Jonathan Pines, who manages the US$3.1 billion fund.</p><p>“We are buying it now because of its very cheap value,” he said in an interview Wednesday, referring to Tencent’s shares. Pines’ fund sold most of its shares in Tencent as well as in Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) about a year ago.</p><p>Tencent yielded its position as Asia’s second-most valuable company after China’s new rules on online gaming erased US$53 billion off its market value in 2023, capping a third year of losses. The shares trade at less than 16 times forward earnings, or about half the 10-year average, making them attractive, Pines said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations" title="">ByteDance confirms talks with Tencent, other buyers for video game operations</a></h3><p>While China currently is not the preferred investment destination for many, a combination of ultra-cheap valuations and low allocations outweighs the risks of investing in the nation’s stocks, according to Pines.</p><p>“We think the risks of investing in China are worth taking because the stocks are so cheap,” he said.</p><p>The fund, which is also overweight on South Korea, prefers Samsung Electronics to TSMC in the Asia semiconductor space.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" title="">China to curb excess spending on video games in blow for world’s biggest market</a></h3><p>TSMC is due for a cyclical downturn, and its shares trade at nearly five times book value, while Samsung’s earnings are poised to recover, Pines said, adding that the Korean company’s position in the memory chip sector makes it a better place to be for now.</p><p>While Korea’s largest company this week reported a steeper-than-expected 35 per cent drop in operating income, reflecting weak demand for consumer electronics globally, Pines said the results would not prevent him from being positive on its earnings trajectory. “Things are going to improve from here,” he said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Google slashes over 1,000 jobs to focus on AI amid competition with Microsoft, OpenAI</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248158/google-slashes-over-1000-jobs-focus-ai-amid-competition-microsoft-openai</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  谷歌正在进行裁员以降低成本并专注于人工智能，增加了其核心互联网搜索业务的压力。裁员涉及语音助手、硬件和工程团队以及高级管理人员，例如副总裁和董事。目前已有超过1000名员工被解雇，其中包括Fitbit的联合创始人，而谷歌仍在继续裁员。公司员工士气低落，质疑管理层的决策。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Google lays off employees to cut costs and focus on AI, amid pressure on its core search business.</li>    <li>Theme: Google's ongoing restructuring, affecting various teams and levels of employees, in response to competition and cost concerns.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Balancing resource allocation between different projects and technologies while addressing workforce morale and stability.</li>    <li>Main information: Teams affected include voice assistant, hardware, and engineering; executive level employees being let go; total layoffs exceeding 1000; concerns among employees about job security and company priorities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  谷歌正在进行裁员以降低成本并专注于人工智能，增加了其核心互联网搜索业务的压力。裁员涉及语音助手、硬件和工程团队以及高级管理人员，例如副总裁和董事。目前已有超过1000名员工被解雇，其中包括Fitbit的联合创始人，而谷歌仍在继续裁员。公司员工士气低落，质疑管理层的决策。  <ul>    <li>摘要：谷歌裁员以降低成本并专注于人工智能，核心搜索业务面临压力。</li>    <li>主题：谷歌正在进行的重组，影响到各个团队和级别的员工，以应对竞争和成本问题。</li>    <li>观点：在不同项目和技术之间平衡资源配置，同时解决员工士气和稳定性问题。</li>    <li>主要信息：受影响的团队包括语音助手、硬件和工程；高管被解雇；总裁员数超过1000人；员工对工作保障和公司优先事项的担忧。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>scrutinise (v.) - /ˈskrutinʌɪz/ 仔细检查，审查。    <p>原文例句：On calls with investors in recent months, Google executives pledged to scrutinise their operations to identify places where they can make cuts, and free up resources to invest in their biggest priorities.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是来源于拉丁语“scruta”，意为“废物盒”。它表示“仔细检查，审查”。在这个例句中，它表示谷歌高管承诺仔细检查他们的业务，以找出可以削减成本的地方，并释放资源来投资他们最重要的优先事项。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>vice-president (n.) - /ˌvaɪs ˈprezɪdənt/ 副总裁。    <p>原文例句：The cuts struck both rank-and-file employees and executives, including four vice-presidents and 25 directors.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是来源于拉丁语“vice”，意为“代替”，和“president”，意为“总统”。它表示“副总裁”。在这个例句中，它表示裁员涉及普通员工和高管，包括四位副总裁和25位董事。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>lay-off (n.) - /ˌleɪ ˈɒf/ 解雇，裁员。    <p>原文例句：The affected employees included those working on the voice-based Google Assistant and the augmented reality hardware team. The central engineering organisation was also hit by lay-offs, the company said.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是来源于古英语“lecgan”，意为“放开”，和“off”，意为“离开”。它表示“解雇，裁员”。在这个例句中，它表示受影响的员工包括那些在语音助手和增强现实硬件团队工作的员工。该公司表示，核心工程组织也受到了裁员的影响。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rank-and-file (adj.) - 普通员工。    <p>原文例句：The cuts struck both rank-and-file employees and executives, including four vice-presidents and 25 directors.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由“rank”和“file”组成，表示“普通员工”。在这个例句中，它表示裁员涉及普通员工和高管，包括四位副总裁和25位董事。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The co-founders of Fitbit, James Park and Eric Friedman, are also leaving Google as part of the reorganisation, a company spokesperson confirmed. - Fitbit的联合创始人詹姆斯·帕克和埃里克·弗里德曼也将作为重组的一部分离开谷歌，一位公司发言人证实。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Fitbit的联合创始人詹姆斯·帕克和埃里克·弗里德曼也将作为重组的一部分离开谷歌，其中的主语是Fitbit的联合创始人詹姆斯·帕克和埃里克·弗里德曼，谓语是将离开谷歌。as part of the reorganisation是一个介词短语作状语，修饰离开谷歌，表示作为重组的一部分。a company spokesperson confirmed是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰离开谷歌，表示一位公司代言人证实。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语作状语 - 用以描述动作或状态的短语，由分词和其修饰语组成。    <p>原文例句：The central engineering organisation was also hit by lay-offs, the company said. - 核心工程组织也受到了裁员的影响，该公司表示。</p>    <p>语法讲解：分词短语作状语是由分词和其修饰语组成的短语，用以描述动作或状态，放在句中作状语。在这个例句中，by lay-offs是一个介词短语，修饰动词hit，表示受到了裁员的影响。the company said是一个现在分词短语，修饰动词hit，表示该公司表示。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>复合句 - 由两个或多个句子组成的句子。    <p>原文例句：Google is laying off hundreds of people working on its digital assistant, hardware and engineering teams as part of a continued effort to lower costs and focus on artificial intelligence (AI). - 作为降低成本和专注于人工智能 (AI) 的持续努力的一部分，谷歌正在裁员数百名在其数字助理、硬件和工程团队工作的员工。</p>    <p>语法讲解：复合句是由两个或多个句子组成的句子，用逗号、分号或连词连接。在这个例句中，主句是谷歌正在裁员数百名在其数字助理、硬件和工程团队工作的员工，其中的主语是谷歌，谓语是正在裁员。as part of a continued effort to lower costs and focus on artificial intelligence (AI)是一个介词短语作状语，修饰动词裁员，表示作为降低成本和专注于人工智能 (AI) 的持续努力的一部分。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The affected employees include those working on the voice-based Google Assistant and the augmented reality hardware team</li>
<li>The cuts struck both rank-and-file employees and executives, including four vice-presidents and 25 directors</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/663b61ac-615c-43fb-8726-9289f3dd1057_e5c63b15.jpg" /><figcaption>A Google logo seen during the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure><p>Alphabet’s Google is laying off hundreds of people working on its digital assistant, hardware and engineering teams as part of a continued effort to lower costs and focus on artificial intelligence (AI).</p><p>The affected employees included those working on the voice-based Google Assistant and the augmented reality hardware team. The central engineering organisation was also hit by cuts, the company said.</p><p>The reductions come as Google’s core internet search business feels the heat from the AI offerings of rivals Microsoft and ChatGPT-creator OpenAI. On calls with investors in recent months, Google executives pledged to scrutinise their operations to identify places where they can make cuts, and free up resources to invest in their biggest priorities.</p><p>“Throughout the second half of 2023, a number of our teams made changes to become more efficient and work better, and to align their resources to their biggest product priorities,” a spokesperson for the Mountain View, California-based company said in a statement. “Some teams are continuing to make these kinds of organisational changes, which include some role eliminations globally.”</p><p>Alphabet shares were little changed on Thursday, closing at US$142.08 in New York.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A statue of the Android mascot. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/e277ff08-d4f0-488c-b2be-05c62a346d28_0c42f09f.jpg" title="A statue of the Android mascot. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>A statue of the Android mascot. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>The cuts struck both rank-and-file employees and executives. Disclosures filed by Google with the state of California show that 630 workers in the state have been let go this week, including four vice-presidents and 25 directors. Employees at those levels often earn millions of dollars per year in compensation, according to a person with knowledge of the matter.</p><p>The Alphabet Workers Union, which represents some Google employees, said more than 1,000 workers have been let go so far in total.</p><p>The co-founders of Fitbit, James Park and Eric Friedman, are also leaving Google as part of the reorganisation, a company spokesperson confirmed. Google acquired the smartwatch company in 2019 for US$2.1 billion.</p><p>Workers at the search giant have been on edge since January of last year, when Alphabet said it would <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3207638/google-parent-company-alphabet-lay-12000-workers-ai-focus-intensifies" target="_self" title="">cut about 12,000 jobs</a>, more than 6 per cent of its global workforce. That sent shock waves through Silicon Valley.</p><p>The company continued to make smaller trims over the course of 2023, including lay-offs within teams focused on recruiting, news products and the Waze mapping app.</p><p>While the large round of cuts in January 2023 was telegraphed by Alphabet chief executive officer Sundar Pichai, this year’s reductions have been communicated by lower-level leaders, such as vice-presidents and human resources, according to a current employee and a former worker.</p><p>Googlers and recently laid-off employees shared information with each other about the cuts in Discord chats, hallway conversations and other social networks, two current employees told Bloomberg. A document noting which roles got cut, as well as resources for laid-off coworkers, circulated among workers on Wednesday and Thursday, one worker said.</p><p>Staffers thought the company leadership would have learned from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3208941/google-workers-stage-rallies-against-job-cuts-low-wages" target="_self" title="">the outcry that large-scale job losses provoked</a> last year, a current employee said, noting that Google is focused almost exclusively on cost-cutting now. The employee said everyone is talking about having a Plan B.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239082/microsofts-bets-generative-ai-boost-azure-cloud-business-alphabets-google-cloud-disappoints" title="">Microsoft’s AI bets lift cloud business, as Google Cloud disappoints</a></h3><p>Workers said it was difficult to get a full picture of how many jobs were affected. Google – which had about 182,000 employees as of September 30, according to regulatory filings – said more cuts could be expected throughout January as decisions are made at the department level.</p><p>The company employed 190,700 workers before the lay-offs last year, in addition to tens of thousands of contractors around the world.</p><p>One of the Google employees who lost his job this week said the first sign of trouble came when he tried to check his work email, only to find he had been logged off. He found a message delivering the news that he had lost his job in his personal email.</p><p>Over the past year, there have been several rounds of micro-lay-offs, the worker said, speaking on condition of anonymity for fear of professional repercussions. He said it has killed morale at the company and is not conducive to creating trust.</p><p>Some Googlers have come to view January as a new grim annual tradition of mass lay-offs.</p><p>While Google executives have framed the cuts as a way to refocus resources on the company’s biggest priorities, the worker who was just fired said that he and a number of his teammates who were let go were working on AI.</p><p>Amazon.com also laid off hundreds of staff in its Prime Video and studios business this week, raising questions about whether another major round of job cuts was under way in Silicon Valley.</p><p>Semafor first reported the lay-offs to the Google Assistant team, while 9to5Google first reported the reorganisation for hardware. Affected staff have begun receiving the news and will have the opportunity to apply for open positions elsewhere within Google, the company said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US bitcoin ETF trades soar to US$4.6 billion on first day after landmark SEC approval</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248152/us-bitcoin-etfs-trades-soar-us46-billion-first-day-after-landmark-sec-approval</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  The launch of spot bitcoin ETFs in the US has sparked intense competition among issuers, with fees slashed and efforts to attract investors. The move marks a significant milestone for the cryptocurrency industry, but some analysts caution that the euphoria may be premature given the broader investment community's wariness of cryptocurrencies.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Spot bitcoin ETFs debut in the US, triggering fierce market competition.</li>    <li>Theme: The emergence of spot bitcoin ETFs and their impact on the cryptocurrency industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The regulatory approval of spot bitcoin ETFs represents a watershed moment, but skepticism remains among some investors.</li>    <li>Main information: Trading volumes, fee structures, and analyst estimates for inflows; fee cuts and efforts to attract investors; mixed reactions in cryptocurrency-related stocks.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  比特币现货ETF在美国上市，引发发行机构之间的激烈竞争，纷纷削减费用并努力吸引投资者。此举标志着加密货币行业的一个重要里程碑，但一些分析师警告称，鉴于更广泛的投资界对加密货币的谨慎态度，这种欣喜若狂的情绪可能为时过早。  <ul>    <li>摘要：比特币现货ETF在美国首次亮相，引发激烈的市场竞争。</li>    <li>主题：比特币现货ETF的出现及其对加密货币行业的影响。</li>    <li>观点：比特币现货ETF获得监管部门批准是分水岭时刻，但一些投资者仍然持怀疑态度。</li>    <li>主要信息：交易量、费用结构和分析师对资金流入的估计；发行机构削减费用并努力吸引投资者的举措；与加密货币相关的股票出现喜忧参半的反应。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>watershed (adj.) - /'wɔːtəʃɛd/ 分水岭，关键时刻。    <p>原文例句：The products mark a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry that will test whether digital assets – still viewed by many professionals as risky – can gain broader acceptance as an investment.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，由water（水）和shed（分离）组成，表示“分水岭”。在这个例句中，它描述了这些产品标志着加密货币行业的一个关键时刻。</p></li>    <li>euphoria (n.) - /juː'fɔːriə/ 极乐，欣喜若狂。    <p>原文例句：Some analysts cautioned that the euphoria around the approval might be premature.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Greek，表示“欣喜若狂”。在这个例句中，它指的是一些分析师警告说，围绕着批准比特币现货ETF的欣喜若狂的情绪可能为时过早。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>bid-ask spread - 买入价差，叫卖差价。    <p>原文例句：As the ETFs began trading on Thursday, market participants were closely watching bid-ask spreads: the difference between the price for a trader to buy into an ETF and the price it can be sold.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“买入价差”，指的是交易者买入ETF的价格与可以卖出的价格之间的差额。</p></li>    <li>core asset class - 核心资产类别。    <p>原文例句：A Vanguard spokeswoman said the firm had no plans to launch its own crypto investment products, and that its focus remains on core asset classes such as stocks, bonds and cash, which it views “as the blocks of a well-balanced, long-term investment portfolio”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“核心资产类别”，指的是构成均衡、长期投资组合的基础资产类别。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers, some of whom slashed the fees for their products well below the US ETF industry’s standard even before Thursday’s launch. - 监管机构的点头点燃了发行者之间激烈的市场份额竞争，其中一些发行者甚至在周四发布之前就将产品的费用大幅削减至远低于美国 ETF 行业标准的水平。<p>句子分析：这是一个较长的句子，由多个分句组成。主句是The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers，其中的主语是The regulatory nod，谓语是sparked，宾语是intense competition for market share among the issuers。some of whom slashed the fees for their products well below the US ETF industry’s standard even before Thursday’s launch是一个定语从句，修饰先行词issuers，说明了其中一些发行者的行为。这个句子的意思是说，监管机构的批准引发了发行者之间激烈的市场份额竞争，其中一些发行者甚至在周四发布之前就将产品的费用大幅削减至远低于美国 ETF 行业标准的水平。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>比较级 - 比较两个事物或多个事物的异同。    <p>原文例句：The broader investment community still views cryptocurrencies as risky, with scandals such as the implosion of crypto exchange FTX in 2022 adding to investors’ wariness.</p>    <p>语法讲解：比较级是用来比较两个事物或多个事物的异同。比较级的构成通常是在形容词或副词的词尾加上-er，如果形容词或副词的词尾是辅音字母+辅音字母+元音字母，则在比较级词尾前加一个辅音字母e。在这个例句中，wariness是形容词wary（谨慎）的比较级，说明了投资者对加密货币的谨慎程度。</p></li>    <li>不定式 - 表示一种动作、状态或结果。    <p>原文例句：Cryptocurrency-related stocks initially climbed higher on Thursday, but ended the day lower, with bitcoin miners Riot Platforms and Marathon Digital dropping 15.8 per cent and 12.6 per cent respectively.</p>    <p>语法讲解：不定式是由to加上动词原形构成的。不定式可以表示一种动作、状态或结果。在这个例句中，不定式dropping表示比特币矿商Riot Platforms和Marathon Digital的下降。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including those from BlackRock, Grayscale and Fidelity – began trading in the US on Thursday</li>
<li>The ETF launches lifted the price of bitcoin up to its highest level since December 2021</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ba11cbce-0732-4b24-95d7-8df4f18e140b_28c230ae.jpg" /><figcaption>Representatives and guests from BlackRock rang the opening bell as bitcoin spot ETFs began trading on the Nasdaq Exchange on Thursday. Photo: Getty Images/AFP </figcaption></figure><p>US-listed bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs) saw US$4.6 billion worth of shares trade hands as of Thursday afternoon, according to LSEG data, as investors jumped into the landmark products approved by the US securities regulator on Wednesday.</p><p>The products mark a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry that will test whether digital assets – still viewed by many professionals as risky – can gain broader acceptance as an investment.</p><p>Eleven spot bitcoin ETFs – including BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust, Grayscale Bitcoin Trust and ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF, among others – began trading Thursday morning, kicking off a fierce competition for market share.</p><p>Grayscale, BlackRock and Fidelity dominated trading volumes, the LSEG data showed.</p><p>“Trading volumes have been relatively strong for new ETF products,” said Todd Rosenbluth, strategist at VettaFi. “But this is a longer race than just a single day’s trading.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/12/ae8a3757-ffff-4ff6-8d4c-962edf286621_a66cec46.jpg" title="The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF signage on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough" target="_self" title="">green light from the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)</a> for the products finally came late on Wednesday, following a decade-long tussle with the crypto industry.</p><p>Some executives called out bitcoin as a high-risk investment, and Vanguard – the largest provider of mutual funds – said it had no plans to make the new batch of spot bitcoin ETFs available on its platform to its brokerage clients.</p><p>The SEC had earlier rejected all spot bitcoin ETFs on investor protection concerns. SEC chairman Gary Gensler said in a statement on Wednesday that the approvals were not an endorsement of bitcoin, calling it a “speculative, volatile asset”.</p><p>The ETF launches lifted the price of bitcoin up to its highest level since December 2021. It was last up 0.77 per cent at US$46,303, while the price of ether, the second-largest cryptocurrency, was up 2.79 per cent at US$2597.95.</p><h3>RACE FOR MARKET SHARE</h3><p>The regulatory nod sparked intense competition for market share among the issuers, some of whom slashed the fees for their products well below the US ETF industry’s standard even before Thursday’s launch.</p><p>Fees on the new bitcoin ETFs range from 0.2 per cent to 1.5 per cent, with many firms also offering to waive fees entirely for a certain period or for a certain dollar volume of assets. After its ETF started trading, Valkyrie cut its fees a second time to 0.25 per cent and waived them for the first three months.</p><p>Grayscale was approved to convert its existing bitcoin trust into an ETF on Thursday, overnight creating the world’s largest bitcoin ETF with more than US$28 billion in assets under management.</p><p>Estimates for how much spot bitcoin ETFs could reel in vary widely. Analysts at Bernstein estimated that flows will build up gradually to cross US$10 billion in 2024, while Standard Chartered analysts this week said the ETFs could draw US$50 billion to US$100 billion this year alone. Other analysts have said inflows could be US$55 billion over five years.</p><p>As the ETFs began trading on Thursday, market participants were closely watching bid-ask spreads: the difference between the price for a trader to buy into an ETF and the price it can be sold. ETFs with narrower spreads are typically viewed as more desirable.</p><p>Trading volume, internal plumbing and the number of participants involved “are critically important to driving the spreads to a good spot”, said Jason Stoneberg, director of product strategy at Invesco, whose ETF with Galaxy Digital debuted on Thursday.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
<div class="scmp-multimedia-embed">
</div>
</div><p>Some analysts cautioned that the euphoria around the approval might be premature. The broader investment community still views cryptocurrencies as risky, with scandals such as the implosion of crypto exchange FTX in 2022 adding to investors’ wariness.</p><p>A Vanguard spokeswoman said the firm had no plans to launch its own crypto investment products, and that its focus remains on core asset classes such as stocks, bonds and cash, which it views “as the blocks of a well-balanced, long-term investment portfolio”.</p><p>Speaking at a webinar on Thursday, Sharmin Mossavar-Rahmani, head of the Investment Strategy Group and chief investment officer of wealth management at Goldman Sachs, said cryptocurrencies had no place in an investment portfolio.</p><p>“When you think about it, where is there any value to something like bitcoin?” she said. “We don’t think it is an asset class to invest in.”</p><h3>CRYPTO STOCKS GAIN</h3><p>Still, some expect the products to pave the way for even more innovative crypto ETFs, including spot ether products.</p><p>Grayscale CEO Michael Sonnenshein said in an interview Thursday that the firm plans to file for a covered call ETF in an effort to allow investors to generate income from options on its spot bitcoin product.</p><p>Cryptocurrency-related stocks initially climbed higher on Thursday, but ended the day lower, with bitcoin miners Riot Platforms and Marathon Digital dropping 15.8 per cent and 12.6 per cent respectively.</p><p>Bitcoin investor Microstrategy fell 5.2 per cent and crypto exchange Coinbase 6.7 per cent. The ProShares Bitcoin Strategy ETF, which tracks bitcoin futures, gained 0.44 per cent.</p><p>Also on Thursday, Circle Internet Financial, the company behind stablecoin USDC, said it had confidentially filed for a US initial public offering. Circle controls the issuance and governance of USDC, a cryptocurrency pegged to the US dollar.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
