# -*- mode: xml -*-
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>New refund policies from Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com spark fears of customer abuse among merchants</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247168/new-refund-policies-alibabas-taobao-and-jdcom-spark-fears-customer-abuse-among-merchants</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese e-commerce platforms such as Taobao and JD.com have introduced new "refund only" policies, allowing consumers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even if they keep it. While this aim at protecting consumer rights, it has raised concerns among some merchants about potential abuse of the policy and its impact on their operations.  <ul>    <li>Main information: Introduction of "refund only" policies by Taobao and JD.com; circumstances in which consumers can receive a refund; concerns of merchants regarding abuse and increased claims; possible impact on sellers who invest in high-quality products.</li>    <li>Theme: The potential pros and cons of the new refund policies on Chinese e-commerce platforms, including benefits for consumers and challenges for merchants.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The need to balance consumer rights with the interests of merchants; the importance of establishing clear guidelines and criteria to prevent abuse of the refund policies.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国淘宝、京东等电商平台推出了新的“先退款，再退货”政策，允许消费者在对产品不满意的情况下，即使不退回产品也可以退款。虽然此举旨在保护消费者权益，但也引发了部分商家对于政策被滥用以及对自身运营产生影响的担忧。  <ul>    <li>主要信息：淘宝、京东推出“先退款，再退货”政策；消费者可以退款的情况；商家对政策被滥用以及索赔增多表示担忧；对销售高质量产品的商家可能产生的影响。</li>    <li>主题：中国电商平台新退款政策的潜在利弊，包括对消费者的好处和对商家的挑战。</li>    <li>观点：需要在消费者权益和商家利益之间取得平衡；必须建立清晰的准则和标准，以防止退款政策被滥用。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>exploit (v.) - /ɪkˈsplɔɪt/ 利用，剥削。    <p>原文例句：Some merchants have raised concerns that consumers may look to exploit the terms of these ‘refund only’ policies, hitting their operations. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由ex-（出来）和plere（填充）组成，表示“利用，剥削”。在这个例句中，它指的是一些消费者可能试图利用这些“仅退款”政策的条款，损害其运营。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>abuse (n.) - /əˈbjuːs/ 滥用，误用。    <p>原文例句：One user with the handle “PengqiangweiVerna” posted on Weibo that the practice will “foster a group of online freeloaders”. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，由ab-（远离）和usus（使用）组成，表示“滥用，误用”。在这个例句中，它指的是微博用户“彭强威Verna”认为这种做法将“培养一群网络占便宜的人”。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rock-bottom prices - 极低的价格，最低价格。    <P>原文例句：Pinduoduo’s focus on rock-bottom prices means that the costs of the scheme are more bearable than for merchants on rival sites.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由rock-bottom（最低限度）和prices（价格）组成的，表示“极低的价格，最低价格”。在这个例句中，它表示拼多多的主要价格是最低价格，这意味着该计划的成本对于竞争网站上的商家来说更可以承受。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice was initially launched in 2021 and is seen as a key factor behind the Shanghai-based budget-shopping platform’s rise to prominence. - 拼多多的“先退款，再退货”政策首次推出于2021年，被视为这家总部位于上海的预算购物平台崛起的关键因素。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice was initially launched in 2021，其中主语是Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice，谓语是was launched，宾语是in 2021。is seen as a key factor behind the Shanghai-based budget-shopping platform’s rise to prominence是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示拼多多的“先退款，再退货”政策被视为这家总部位于上海的预算购物平台崛起的关键因素。这个句子的意思是说，拼多多的“先退款，再退货”政策首次推出于2021年，被视为这家总部位于上海的预算购物平台崛起的关键因素。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达说话人对某事的态度或看法,而不陈述事实。    <p>原文例句：The 33-year-old online shop owner, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of retribution from the platforms, said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个虚拟语气的用法，表示这位网店店主对新退款政策的看法。主句是said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products，其中said是谓语，that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products是一个宾语从句，其中could backfire和hit sellers who invest in high-quality products都是虚拟语气，表示这位网店店主认为新退款政策可能会适得其反，打击那些投资高品质产品的卖家。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba, whose company mission is “to make it easy to do business anywhere”, had a long internal debate over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo, which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去完成时的用法，表示阿里巴巴在过去某个时间点之前已经完成了内部辩论。主句是Alibaba had a long internal debate，其中had是谓语，a long internal debate是宾语。over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo是一个介词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示阿里巴巴是否要效仿竞争对手拼多多。which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰先行词Pinduoduo。在这个从句中，was是谓语，the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it是一个宾语从句，其中offer是谓语，a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it是一个宾语从句。这个句子的意思是说，阿里巴巴在过去某个时间点之前已经完成了内部辩论，内容是是否要效仿竞争对手拼多多，因为拼多多是第一家提供消费者可以不退还产品就获得退款的政策的公司。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Taobao and JD.com have introduced policies that allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it</li>
<li>Some merchants have raised concerns that consumers may look to exploit the terms of these ‘refund only’ policies, hitting their operations</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/85b29bec-f2e3-42ad-ba41-d20ec559a707_664d3160.jpg" /><figcaption>Some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse under new refund policies. Photo: SCMP</figcaption></figure><p>New “refund only” policies introduced by Chinese e-commerce players including Alibaba Group Holding’s Taobao and JD.com have sparked concern among some sellers about potential abuse of the terms, according to merchants and analysts.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com in late December introduced new policies that – in certain circumstances – allow shoppers to receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they keep it. This may occur when a consumer complains about the poor quality of a product, or about an inaccurate and misleading description on the platform. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Alibaba, whose company mission is “to make it easy to do business anywhere”, had a long internal debate over whether to follow rival Pinduoduo, which was the first to offer a policy whereby a shopper can receive a refund for a product they are unhappy with even though they do not return it.</p><p>Even though some merchants have raised concerns about potential abuse, Alibaba came down on the side of consumer rights in such a situation as merchants are ultimately dependent on buyer confidence, according to a person briefed on the discussions who asked not to be identified.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>However, since the policy went into effect last week there has been an increased number of claims under the “refund but keep the purchase” policy, according to one merchant who runs apparel shops on both Taobao and JD.com, adding that some consumers were looking to exploit the situation.</p><p>The 33-year-old online shop owner, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of retribution from the platforms, said that the new refund policy could backfire and hit sellers who invest in high-quality products, because they will bear higher costs in the event of more claims.</p><p>“This refund terms only works for merchants who sell dirt-cheap goods,” she said, adding that the policy clearly favoured consumers.</p><p>Meanwhile, some merchants took to social media platforms such as Douyin and Weibo to express anger at the potential for policy abuse.</p><p>One user with the handle “PengqiangweiVerna” posted on Weibo that the practice will “foster a group of online freeloaders”. Another Douyin user called “Xinzhouxiaohuolang” posted a dozen videos denouncing such refund requests.</p><p>Both Taobao and JD.com have said that any decisions on refund requests on their platforms will be based on multiple indicators, including the track records of both merchants and buyers, along with big data analysis to support their judgments.</p><p>A person familiar with the situation at Taobao, who asked not to be identified as they are not authorised to talk to the media, said that the platform has offered merchants an appeal option if they think they have been wronged.</p><p>Taobao and JD.com did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Wednesday.</p><p>Pinduoduo’s original “refund but keep the product” practice was initially launched in 2021 and is seen as a key factor behind the Shanghai-based budget-shopping platform’s rise to prominence.</p><p>Tang Guangyao, a 38-year-old Beijing software developer, said he has shifted from other e-commerce platforms to Pinduoduo as a primary shopping channel owing to its robust consumer protection, even though it focuses on budget prices.</p><p>But some analysts say simply following Pinduoduo’s lead may not work for rival platforms.</p><p>“This [new refund policy] isn’t very practical for platforms such as Taobao, Tmall and JD.com,” said Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangzhou-based iiMedia, pointing out that Pinduoduo’s focus on rock-bottom prices means that the costs of the scheme are more bearable than for merchants on rival sites.</p><p>“By following this [Pinduoduo] refund policy … [rival platforms] will give their merchants a dilemma,” he added.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei’s HarmonyOS to beat Apple’s IOS as the No. 2 smartphone operating system in China in 2024: TechInsights report</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  HarmonyOS，华为自研操作系统，预计今年将超越苹果iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。 华为重返5G智能手机市场，以及美国制裁后Mate 60系列的发布，是HarmonyOS采用率增长的主要推动力。 HarmonyOS表现亮眼，在智能手机操作系统全球市场中，谷歌Android和苹果iOS依然占据主导地位，但HarmonyOS将在中国市场从这两大巨头手中抢占一些份额。   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Increased HarmonyOS adoption expected with Huawei's return to 5G smartphone segment.</li>    <li>Theme: HarmonyOS, Huawei's self-developed operating system, is projected to surpass Apple's iOS, becoming the second-biggest in China.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: US sanctions and the launch of the Mate 60 series drive HarmonyOS adoption; potential impact on other smartphone makers and expansion to other devices.</li>    <li>Main information: HarmonyOS's current market position; Huawei's comeback in the 5G smartphone segment; supply challenges and recovery; plans for HarmonyOS Next and developer recruitment.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  HarmonyOS，华为自研操作系统，预计今年将超越苹果iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。华为重返5G智能手机市场，以及美国制裁后Mate 60系列的发布，是HarmonyOS采用率增长的主要推动力。HarmonyOS表现亮眼，在智能手机操作系统全球市场中，谷歌Android和苹果iOS依然占据主导地位，但HarmonyOS将在中国市场从这两大巨头手中抢占一些份额。  <ul>    <li>摘要：HarmonyOS采用率增加，主要是由于华为重返5G智能手机市场。</li>    <li>主题：HarmonyOS超越iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统。</li>    <li>观点：美国制裁和Mate 60系列发布推动了HarmonyOS采用率的增长；对其他智能手机制造商的潜在影响以及扩展到其他设备的可能性。</li>    <li>主要信息：HarmonyOS当前的市场地位；华为在5G智能手机市场的复苏；供应挑战和复苏；HarmonyOS Next的计划和开发者招募。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>handset (n.) - /ˈhændˌsɛt/ 手持式电话，话筒。    <p>原文例句：The Mate 60 Pro is a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由hand（手）和set（放置）组成，表示“手持式电话，话筒”。在这个例句中，它指的是Mate 60 Pro，即配备了先进的国产5G芯片的手持式电话，尽管美国科技制裁旨在阻止获取此类技术。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>developer (n.) - /dɪˈvɛləpər/ 开发者，研制者。    <p>原文例句：Huawei is already working with China’s major companies to develop native apps based on the system. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由develop（发展，开发）和-er（表示从事某项工作的人）构成，表示“开发者，研制者”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为正在与中国主要公司合作，基于HarmonyOS系统开发原生应用程序的开发者。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>self-developed - 自主研发的，自力更生的。    <P>原文例句：Huawei’s smartphones are all powered by HarmonyOS, its self-developed Android alternative launched in August 2019, three months after the US government added the firm to its Entity List. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由self（自我，自身）和developed（开发，研制）构成的，表示“自主研发的，自力更生的”。在这个例句中，它指的是华为手机都搭载HarmonyOS，这是华为在2019年8月推出的自主研发的Android替代品，三个月后美国政府将华为列入实体名单。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s IOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year driven by the US-sanctioned firm’s comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to a report by TechInsights. - 据TechInsights报告，华为的技术移动平台HarmonyOS预计今年将超越苹果的iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统，这得益于这家受到美国制裁的公司推出Mate 60系列手机重返市场。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂的句子，有四个分句和一个主句。主句是Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s IOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year，其中主语是Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS，谓语是is projected to surpass，宾语是Apple’s IOS。第一个分句是driven by the US-sanctioned firm’s comeback with the Mate 60 series，其中driven by是过去分词短语作状语，表示原因或理由，the US-sanctioned firm’s comeback with the Mate 60 series是名词性短语作主语，表示美国受到制裁的公司带着Mate 60系列手机重返市场。第二个分句是according to a report by TechInsights，其中according to是介词短语作状语，表示根据，a report by TechInsights是名词性短语作主语，表示TechInsights的一份报告。这个句子的意思是说，据TechInsights报告，华为的技术移动平台HarmonyOS预计今年将超越苹果的iOS，成为中国第二大操作系统，这得益于这家受到美国制裁的公司推出Mate 60系列手机重返市场。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 用于强调句子中的某个成分。    <p>原文例句：HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句型是一种特殊的句子结构，用来强调句子中的某个成分。强调句型的结构是：It is/was + 被强调的成分 + that/who + 其他成分。在这个例句中，被强调的成分是HarmonyOS Next，所以强调句的结构是：It is HarmonyOS Next that will not support Android-based apps。这个句子的意思是说，HarmonyOS Next预计将在2024年发布，它不支持基于Android的应用程序。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示假设、愿望、建议、请求等。    <p>原文例句：Huawei is expected to launch a developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next in the first quarter of 2024. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种特殊的语态，用于表示假设、愿望、建议、请求等。虚拟语气的结构是：should/could/would/may/might + 动词原形。在这个例句中，is expected to launch是虚拟语气的结构，表示华为预计将在2024年第一季度发布HarmonyOS Next的开发者预览版。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Increased HarmonyOS adoption is expected to be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment</li>
<li>TechInsights also expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/83c4b156-87f3-4acb-b3f4-8cb885281387_c0009114.jpg" /><figcaption>Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies’ mobile platform HarmonyOS is projected to surpass Apple’s IOS as the second-biggest operating system in China this year driven by the US-sanctioned firm’s comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to a report by TechInsights.</p><p>While Google’s Android and Apple’s IOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, Canadian research firm TechInsights said in a report released on Wednesday.</p><p>Increased HarmonyOS adoption will be driven by Huawei’s return to the 5G smartphone segment, which started with the surprise launch in late August of its Mate 60 Pro, a handset equipped with an advanced, home-grown 5G chip despite US tech sanctions intended to block access to such technology.</p><p>TechInsights also expects Huawei to make a solid recovery in 2024, according to the report.</p><p>Huawei’s smartphones are all powered by HarmonyOS, its self-developed Android alternative launched in August 2019, three months after the US government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">added the firm to its Entity List</a>. Under this trade blacklist, Huawei is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>On its release, the Mate 60 Pro inspired <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3233514/tech-war-huawei-helps-china-win-symbolic-victory-defying-washingtons-sanctions-headwinds-remain?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">a wave of patriotic fervour</a> among Chinese consumers, and the Shenzhen-based firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241541/huawei-has-big-problem-popular-mate-60-5g-smartphones-theres-not-enough-supply-meet-growing-demand" target="_self" title="">faced supply issues as it scrambled to crank up production to meet demand</a>.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246566/huawei-sees-9-cent-sales-growth-2023-it-bounces-back-us-sanctions-cautions-serious-challenges-ahead" title="">Huawei sees 9 per cent sales growth in 2023, boosted by Mate 60 Pro 5G comeback</a></h3><p>TechInsights expects Huawei’s supply challenge, driven by shortages of Kirin 9000s chipsets, to ease in the next few months. Huawei’s product portfolio further expanded last week when it launched new smartphone models under its mid-range Nova series.</p><p>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p><p>Huawei is expected to launch a developer preview version of HarmonyOS Next in the first quarter of 2024, and is already working with China’s major companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p><p>Last month, Chinese financial technology giant Ant Group, the fintech affiliate of South China Morning Post owner <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, said it is building a new version of mobile payment app Alipay based on HarmonyOS, after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242703/alibaba-develops-native-dingtalk-app-harmonyos-huawei-aims-end-support-android-apps?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba started development on a new version of DingTalk</a>, its workplace collaboration app, for the platform.</p><p>Other major Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> companies – including e-commerce firm <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>, video gaming giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netease?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">NetEase</a> and food delivery market leader <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> – in November already started to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241371/chinese-big-tech-firms-jdcom-netease-and-meituan-rush-hire-harmonyos-based-app-developers-huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">recruit developers to build native apps for HarmonyOS</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/mcdonalds?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">McDonald’s</a> China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees serving more than 1 billion customers each year – became <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244236/mcdonalds-china-pushes-development-native-apps-based-harmonyos-adoption-huaweis-mobile-operating?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239589/xiaomi-launches-home-grown-cross-device-system-hyperos-us-sanctioned-huawei-moves-further-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS Next</a>.</p><p>It remains to be seen whether these efforts will have a halo effect on other smartphone makers and make HarmonyOS a default operating system for not just smartphones but also laptops and cars in China, TechInsights said.</p><p>More than 700 million devices currently run on HarmonyOS, with more than 2.2 million third-party developers creating apps for the platform, according to Richard Yu Chengdong, CEO of Huawei’s consumer business group, speaking at the company’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230293/tech-war-huawei-revive-smartphone-business-back-fresh-ai-powered-operating-system-even-us-sanctions?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">annual developer conference in August</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple dominates global premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground on the back of its new 5G handsets</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Apple continued to be the world's leading vendor of premium smartphones in 2023, with a whopping 71% market share, but its dominance saw a decline compared to the previous year. This was partly attributed to Huawei's comeback in the 5G segment with its Mate 60 series and the rising popularity of Samsung's foldable phones. Despite the market challenges and a projected decline in overall smartphone shipments globally, the premium segment remained resilient and accounted for a significant portion of industry revenue.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple retains leadership in the premium smartphone market, facing competition from Huawei and Samsung.</li>    <li>Theme: Shifts in consumer buying patterns and the resilience of the premium smartphone segment amidst a declining overall market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of high-quality devices in the premium segment and the role of promotion seasons and financing options in making these devices more accessible.</li>    <li>Main information: Apple's market share decline, Huawei's resurgence, Samsung's foldable phones' success, growth in emerging markets, and increasing affordability of premium smartphones.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果公司在2023年依然是全球高端智能手机的顶级供应商，拥有71%的市场份额，但其优势地位却同比下降。这部分原因归因于华为凭借其Mate 60系列在5G领域的回归，以及三星折叠屏手机的日益普及。尽管面临市场挑战以及全球智能手机出货量预计下降，高端智能手机市场仍然保持弹性，并在行业收入中占据了很大一部分。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果在高端智能手机市场保持领先地位，面临来自华为和三星的竞争。</li>    <li>主题：消费者购买模式的变化和在整体市场下降的情况下高端智能手机市场展示的稳健性。</li>    <li>观点：高端智能手机市场的高品质设备的重要性，以及促销季和金融选项在使这些设备更实惠中所扮演的角色。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果市场份额的下降、华为的复苏、三星折叠屏手机的成功、新兴市场的发展以及高端智能手机越来越实惠。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>share (n.) - /ʃɛər/ 份额，シェア。    <p>原文例句：According to research firm Counterpoint, Apple remained the world’s top vendor of premium smartphones in 2023, with a 71 per cent market share. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词表示“份额，比例”，在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司在2023年高端智能手机市场的份额为71%。</p></li>    <li>resurgence (n.) - /rɪˈsɜːrdʒ(ə)ns/ 复兴，复苏。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei, which released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词表示“复兴，复苏”，在这个例句中，它指的是华为在2020年10月发布了第一款新的5G智能手机后，在高端智能手机市场上的复苏。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>segment (n.) - /ˈsɛɡmənt/ 部分，领域。    <p>原文例句：Apple continued to lead the smartphone industry’s premium segment in 2023, but saw its worldwide share decline mainly because of US-sanctioned Huawei Technologies’ strong 5G handset market comeback with its Mate 60 series. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词表示“部分，领域”，在这个例句中，它指的是智能手机行业的细分市场。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>projected decrease - 预计下降。    <p>原文例句：The global premium smartphone market, where handsets are priced from US$600, saw Apple remain the “undisputed leader” last year with a dominant 71 per cent share, according to the latest industry report released on Tuesday by Counterpoint Research.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由project（预测）和decrease（减少）组成，表示“预测减少”。在这个例句中，它指的是全球高端智能手机市场的预计下降。</p>    <li>consumer buying patterns - 消费者购买模式。    <p>原文例句：“There has been a shift in consumer buying patterns in the smartphone market,” Counterpoint senior analyst Varun Mishra said in the premium segment report. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由consumer（消费者）和buying patterns（购买模式）组成，表示“消费者购买模式”。在这个例句中，它指的是智能手机市场中消费者的购买模式的转变。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock - 华为Mate 60 Pro 5G智能手机于2023年9月9日在陕西省西北部首府西安市的一家电子商店展示。摄影：Shutterstock<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的陈述句，主语是Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones，谓语是are seen，宾语是on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province。这个句子的意思是说，华为Mate 60 Pro 5G智能手机于2023年9月9日在陕西省西北部首府西安市的一家电子商店展示。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 分词短语是由分词和修饰成分，表示事物不同的附加成分。分词短语可以用来修饰主语、宾语和状语，在句子中通常充当定语和状语。    <p>原文例句：According to research firm Counterpoint, Apple remained the world’s top vendor of premium smartphones in 2023, with a 71 per cent market share.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在"According to research firm Counterpoint"，"According to"是一个介词结构，"research firm Counterpoint"是一个名词短语，"According to research firm Counterpoint"是一个介词短语修饰了动词"remained"。</p></li>    <li>动词不定式 - 动词不定式是不带"to"的不定式，由动词原形加"ing"或"ed"构成。动词不定式可以作为名词、形容词和副词。    <p>原文例句：There has been a shift in consumer buying patterns in thesmartphone market,” Counterpoint senior analyst Varun Mishra said in the premium segment report.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在"There has been a shift..."，"There"是一个形式主语，"has been"是助动词，"a shift"是动名词，"in consumer buying patterns"是介词短语，"There has been a shift in consumer buying patterns"是一个完整的主语。动词不定式作为主语。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple remained the world’s top vendor of premium smartphones in 2023, with a 71 per cent market share, according to research firm Counterpoint</li>
<li>The US firm’s lead, however, declined year on year amid Huawei’s 5G comeback with its Mate 60 series and the gains made by Samsung’s foldable phones</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/64d88f21-13d4-47d7-a021-0a71facc64d7_e98ebaba.jpg" /><figcaption>Apple’s iPhone 15 Pro and Pro Max models are seen on display at a store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 22, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> continued to lead the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> industry’s premium segment in 2023, but saw its worldwide share decline mainly because of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-sanctioned</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>’ strong <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/5g/news" target="_self" title="">5G</a> handset market comeback with its Mate 60 series.</p><p>The global premium smartphone market, where handsets are priced from US$600, saw Apple remain the “undisputed leader” last year with a dominant 71 per cent share, according to the latest industry report released on Tuesday by Counterpoint Research.</p><p>Apple’s share, however, was down from 75 per cent in 2022 amid the resurgence of Huawei, which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">released its first new 5G smartphones since October 2020</a>, as well as the gains made by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/samsung-electronics" target="_self" title="">Samsung Electronics</a>’ Galaxy S23 series and its latest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foldable-phones" target="_self" title="">foldable phones</a>.</p><p>Samsung retained the global No 2 spot in the premium segment with a share of 17 per cent, compared to 16 per cent in 2022. Still, No 3 Huawei captured more new ground year on year with a 5 per cent share, up from 3 per cent in 2022, according to the Counterpoint report.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/cb3a9a4b-0ce5-45f4-91e6-798c2c4c40f0_5babf532.jpg" title="Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>Huawei Technologies’ Mate 60 Pro 5G smartphones are seen on display at an electronics store in Xian, capital of northwestern Shaanxi province, on September 9, 2023. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> last year took the fourth and fifth spots in the premium smartphone segment with a 2 per cent and 1 per cent share, respectively.</p><p>The latest market data shows the resilience of the premium segment, despite the projected decrease in the overall global smartphone market in 2023 – global handset shipments are forecast to hit their lowest level in almost a decade with a 5 per cent decline, according to an earlier Counterpoint report.</p><p>The premium segment, meanwhile, was expected to account for nearly one-fourth of global smartphone market sales and 60 per cent of the industry’s revenue in 2023. Counterpoint data shows that the so-called ultra-premium segment, where smartphones cost more than US$1,000, accounted for one-third of total premium handset sales last year.</p><p>Over the past few years, the premium segment has emerged as a growth area in the otherwise weak worldwide smartphone market. Counterpoint projected the premium segment sales share to triple to 24 per cent in 2023, compared to 6 per cent in 2016.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3246457/ranked-top-5-smartphones-2023-iphone-15-pro-max-and-google-pixel-8-pro-two-foldable-phones-and-best" title="">Top 5 smartphones of 2023, from iPhone 15 Pro Max to the best camera phone</a></h3><p>“There has been a shift in consumer buying patterns in the smartphone market,” Counterpoint senior analyst Varun Mishra said in the premium segment report. “Considering the importance a smartphone holds, consumers are willing to spend more to get a high-quality device that they can use for a longer period.”</p><p>Much of the global premium segment’s growth last year was driven by China, western Europe, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/india" target="_self" title="">India</a>, and the Middle East-and-Africa regions, according to Counterpoint.</p><p>India is already the world’s fastest-growing market for premium smartphones, the Counterpoint report said. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3217435/apple-opens-first-retail-store-india-us-tech-giant-sharpens-focus-south-asian-nation-major-market" target="_self" title="">Apple opened its first retail store in India</a> last April, underscoring the US tech titan’s increasing focus on the South Asian nation as a key sales market and alternative manufacturing hub to China.</p><p>“Owning the latest and greatest flagships has also become a status symbol for many consumers, especially in emerging markets where they are jumping directly from the mid-price band to the premium band,” Mishra said. “Further, these devices are increasingly becoming more affordable due to promotion seasons and financing options.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance’s Douyin makes instant refunds mandatory, following PDD, Taobao and JD.com amid fierce e-commerce competition</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247160/bytedances-douyin-makes-instant-refunds-mandatory-following-pdd-taobao-and-jdcom-amid-fierce-e</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  In the fierce competition of e-commerce platforms in China, Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, has made its "express refund" policy mandatory. This forces merchants to immediately return money to consumers upon request in order to compete with similar offerings on Taobao and Pinduoduo. These platforms are turning to policies known as "refund without returning the cargo" or "refund without reason" to attract more consumers.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Amid fierce competition, Douyin's mandatory "express refund" policy requires merchants to instantly return money to consumers, similar to policies on Taobao and Pinduoduo.</li>    <li>Theme: E-commerce platforms in China adopt customer-friendly policies like “refund without returning the cargo” to attract consumers.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of consumer-friendly policies in e-commerce; the impact of the mandatory refund policy on merchants.</li>    <li>Main information: Douyin's mandatory refund policy; similar policies on Taobao and Pinduoduo; increase in online retail sales in China; Alibaba's efforts to win back consumers.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  在中国电商平台的激烈竞争中，抖音作为中国版的 TikTok，已使其“极速退款”政策强制执行。为了与淘宝和拼多多上类似的优惠活动竞争，这迫使商家在收到退货请求后立即将钱款退还给消费者。这些平台正在转向“无需退货退款”或“无理由退款”等政策，以吸引更多消费者。  <ul>    <li>摘要：在激烈的竞争中，抖音强制执行的“极速退款”政策要求商家立即向消费者退款，类似于淘宝和拼多多上的政策。</li>    <li>主题：中国电商平台采用“无需退货退款”等亲消费者政策来吸引消费者。</li>    <li>观点：消费者友好政策在电子商务中的重要性；强制退款政策对商家的影响。</li>    <li>主要信息：抖音的强制退款政策；淘宝和拼多多上的类似政策；中国在线零售额的增长；阿里巴巴为赢回消费者所做的努力。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>woo (v.) - 追求，吸引。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com recently started offering refunds without returns to woo consumers away from rising budget e-commerce champion Pinduoduo.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古英语单词wōh（求爱），表示“追求，吸引”。在这个例句中，它的意思是阿里巴巴的淘宝和京东最近开始提供无理由退款服务，以吸引消费者远离新兴的预算电商巨头拼多多。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>mandatory (adj.) - 强制的，必须的。    <p>原文例句：Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok that is betting big on e-commerce, has made its “express refund” policy mandatory, forcing merchants to immediately return money to consumers upon request to compete with similar offerings on Taobao and Pinduoduo.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由manus（手）和dare（给予）组成，表示“强迫，强制”。在这个例句中，它的意思是抖音，作为在中国电子商务领域押下重注的 TikTok 的中国版本，已经将其“极速退款”政策变成强制性的，迫使商家在收到退款请求后立即向消费者退款，以与淘宝和拼多多上类似的优惠活动竞争。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>opt out of - 选择退出。    <p>原文例句：Merchants selling on the short video app Douyin can no longer opt out of the option to instantly refund up to US$211 before receiving returned goods.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由opt（选择）和out of（退出）组成，表示“选择退出”。在这个例句中，它的意思是抖音上的商家不再可以选择退出立即退款至多 211 美元的选项，即使没有收到退回的商品。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>turn off - 关闭，切断。    <p>原文例句：A recent policy update regarding the service introduced in 2021 denies merchants the option of turning it off.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由turn（转动）和off（关掉）组成，表示“关闭，切断”。在这个例句中，它的意思是最近关于 2021 年推出的这项服务的政策更新，剥夺了商家关闭该选项的权利。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Pinduoduo, owned by PDD Holdings, was the first major e-commerce site to introduce a similar refunds policy in 2021 allowing users to get their money back without returning goods found to not match merchant descriptions. - 拼多多是第一个在 2021 年推出类似退款政策的主要电子商务网站，该政策允许用户在发现商品与商家描述不符时无需退货即可拿回退款。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Pinduoduo was the first major e-commerce site to introduce a similar refunds policy，其中主语是Pinduoduo，谓语是was，宾语是the first major e-commerce site to introduce a similar refunds policy。owned by PDD Holdings是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰Pinduoduo，表示拼多多归 PDD 控股所有。in 2021 allowing users to get their money back without returning goods found to not match merchant descriptions是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示拼多多在 2021 年推出的类似退款政策的内容或方式，即允许用户在发现商品与商家描述不符时无需退货即可拿回退款。这个句子的意思是说，拼多多是第一个在 2021 年推出类似退款政策的主要电子商务网站，该政策允许用户在发现商品与商家描述不符时无需退货即可拿回退款。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作的承受者。    <p>原文例句：The platform operated by Beijing-based ByteDance, which added a shopping channel in 2019, allows users to get a refund as soon as they mail back the returned parcel, rather than when the merchant receives it.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是一种语态，表示动作的承受者。其结构是：be + 过去分词。在这个例句中，be动词是allows，过去分词是returned，表示退款是由用户获得的。这个句子的意思是说，这家位于北京的字节跳动运营的平台于 2019 年添加了一个购物渠道，该渠道允许用户在寄回退货包裹后立即获得退款，而不是在商家收到包裹后获得退款。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>强调句 - 表示强调。    <p>原文例句：This was seen as a major factor in helping Pinduoduo woo price-sensitive Chinese consumers away from competing platforms.</p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句是一种句子，用于强调句子中的某个部分。其结构是：It was/is + 被强调部分 + that/who。在这个例句中，被强调的部分是a major factor in helping Pinduoduo woo price-sensitive Chinese consumers away from competing platforms。这个句子的意思是说，这被视为帮助拼多多从竞争平台吸引对价格敏感的中国消费者的一个主要因素。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Merchants selling on the short video app Douyin can no longer opt out of the option to instantly refund up to US$211 before receiving returned goods</li>
<li>Alibaba’s Taobao and JD.com recently started offering refunds without returns to woo consumers away from rising budget e-commerce champion Pinduoduo</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/3ce8d4ad-d4c8-4569-8e73-e028869c8250_11da8613.jpg" /><figcaption>The logo of Douyin displayed next to a mobile phone displaying an e-commerce site on the app in an illustration picture taken on October 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Douyin, the Chinese version of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiktok">TikTok</a> that is betting big on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce">e-commerce</a>, has made its “express refund” policy mandatory, forcing merchants to immediately return money to consumers upon request to compete with similar offerings on Taobao and Pinduoduo.</p><p>The platform operated by Beijing-based <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance">ByteDance</a>, which added a shopping channel in 2019, allows users to get a refund as soon as they mail back the returned parcel, rather than when the merchant receives it. A recent policy update regarding the service introduced in 2021 denies merchants the option of turning it off.</p><p>E-commerce platforms are turning to policies known as “refund without returning the cargo” or “refund without reason” as part of a push to be more consumer-friendly at the expense of merchants amid intensified competition. Online retail sales of tangible goods in China increased 8.3 per cent in the first 11 months of 2023, according to the National Bureau of Statistics.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" title="">JD.com, Alibaba’s Taobao push ‘refund only’ policy to rival Pinduoduo’s strategy</a></h3><p>Budget shopping app <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo">Pinduoduo</a>, owned by PDD Holdings, was the first major e-commerce site to introduce a similar refunds policy in 2021 allowing users to get their money back without returning goods found to not match merchant descriptions. This was seen as a major factor in helping Pinduoduo woo price-sensitive Chinese consumers away from competing platforms.</p><p>The policy of allowing refunds without returns has started to gain favour as platforms look for any possible edge over rivals.</p><p>Taobao, the e-commerce platform from <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom">JD.com</a> last week rolled out their own <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating">“refund only” policies</a>, finally matching the option from Pinduoduo. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Douyin has offered refunds without returns since September.</p><p>Douyin’s new refund service is not available for customised products or non-tangible goods such as memberships. Instant refunds are also limited to 1,500 yuan (US$211).</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Alibaba has been facing a new sense of urgency to win back consumers after PDD overtook China’s e-commerce king in market capitalisation. Alibaba was valued at US$190.2 billion on the New York Stock Exchange on Tuesday, lower than PDD’s US$193.5 billion on the Nasdaq.</p><p>In December, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals">Alibaba promoted six young managers</a> to run its core e-commerce business unit in an attempt to “reignite their entrepreneurial spirit” and “secure and win their future”, according to an internal letter penned by the conglomerate’s CEO Eddie Wu Yongming, two days after he became the head of the unit.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech firms must end, says communist party newspaper after video gaming stock rout</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  The mouthpiece of the Central Party School has urged regulators to stop swaying between lax oversight and overly strict regulation of China’s Big Tech companies, arguing that such erratic moves harm the health of the country’s internet industry.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: The Study Times' opinion piece calls for more stable regulation of China's platform economy to facilitate the growth of domestic internet giants.</li>    <li>Theme: The piece emphasizes the need for balanced regulation to avoid hindering the development and competitiveness of Chinese internet companies.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The article argues that excessive regulation is detrimental to the platform economy and urges regulators to adopt a more measured approach.</li>    <li>Main information: The piece cites examples of regulatory hostility towards internet firms, such as the NPPA's draft regulation restricting spending on video games, which resulted in significant losses for Chinese gaming stocks.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中央党校机关报发文呼吁监管机构停止对平台经济忽松忽严的监管行为，认为这样会损害国内互联网产业的健康发展。  <ul>    <li>摘要：《学习时报》评论文章呼吁对中国平台经济实施更加稳定的监管，以便国内互联网巨头能够发展壮大。</li>    <li>主题：文章强调平衡监管的必要性，避免妨碍中国互联网企业的发展与竞争力。</li>    <li>观点：文章认为，过度监管不利于平台经济的发展，并呼吁监管机构采取更加有分寸的手段。</li>    <li>主要信息：文章引用了针对互联网企业的监管敌对行为的例子，例如国家新闻出版署发布的限制电子游戏支出的监管草案，导致中国游戏股遭受重大损失。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>articulate (v.) - /ɑːrtɪkjʊleɪt/ 清楚地表达。    <p>原文例句：The Cyberspace Administration of China, the country’s internet watchdog, for instance, has articulated Beijing’s demand for data security into intrusive requirements that have made it increasingly difficult and costly to comply with. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由ad-（向）和articulus（关节）组成，意为“连接，表达”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国网络空间管理局将北京对数据安全的要求明确表述为侵入性要求，使得符合要求变得越来越困难和昂贵。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>intrusion (n.) - /ɪntrˈuːʒən/ 入侵，侵入。    <p>原文例句：The Cyberspace Administration of China, the country’s internet watchdog, for instance, has articulated Beijing’s demand for data security into intrusive requirements that have made it increasingly difficult and costly to comply with. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由in-（进入）和trudere（推）组成，意为“进入，推入”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国网络空间管理局将北京对数据安全的要求明确表述为侵入性要求，使得符合要求变得越来越困难和昂贵。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：Tencent Holdings, the country’s most valuable player that once eyed being Asia’s first US$1 trillion company, fell out of the global top 10 after losing 60 per cent of its market capitalisation, while Post owner Alibaba Group Holding, which exceeded Amazon.com in market value in 2014, is now worth an eighth of the US e-commerce titan. - 腾讯控股作为中国最有价值的企业之一，曾以成为亚洲第一家市值超1万亿美元的公司为目标，但在失去60%的市值后跌出全球前10强，而邮报的所有者阿里巴巴集团控股有限公司，2014年市值超过亚马逊，现在已不及美国这家电子商务巨头的八分之一。</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示就市值而言，腾讯控股作为中国最有价值的企业之一，曾以成为亚洲第一家市值超1万亿美元的公司为目标，但在失去60%的市值后跌出全球前10强，而邮报的所有者阿里巴巴集团控股有限公司，2014年市值超过亚马逊，现在已不及美国这家电子商务巨头的八分之一。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China’s disciplinary enforcers add ‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences - 中国的纪检人员将“不良”书籍、性行为和毒品列为严重犯罪。<p>句子分析：这是一个主谓宾结构的简单句，主语是China’s disciplinary enforcers，谓语是add，宾语是‘bad’ books, sex, drugs。其中add表示添加，to表示至。这个句子的意思是说，中国的纪检人员将“不良”书籍、性行为和毒品列为严重犯罪。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The South China Morning Post reported on Tuesday that a key gaming official has left his job following the debacle, as the Chinese government tries to allay market fears. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示南华早报周二报道说，一位关键的游戏官员在惨败之后辞去了工作，因为中国政府正试图平息市场恐惧。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示虚拟、假设或愿望。    <p>原文例句：Beijing’s pursuit of market control, along with China’s economic slowdown and rising geopolitical tensions with the US, have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years. - 北京对市场控制的追求，加上中国经济放缓以及与美国的地缘政治紧张局势加剧，已使中国互联网股价在过去三年中成为表现最差的资产之一。</P>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语态，结构是：should/could/would/might/may + 动词原形。其中should表示应该，could表示能够，would表示愿意，might表示可能，may表示允许。这种语态表示对事实的假设、愿望或可能性。在这个例句中，它表示北京对市场控制的追求，加上中国经济放缓以及与美国的地缘政治紧张局势加剧，已使中国互联网股价在过去三年中成为表现最差的资产之一。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The mouthpiece of the Central Party School argued that regulators must stop the practice of swinging between extremes of lax oversight and ‘overly strict’ regulation</li>
<li>The opinion came days after the NPPA wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with draft regulation to restrict spending on video games</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/3319e698-c70a-4b75-a5c4-b17164272de6_6b557a93.jpg" /><figcaption>Tencent’s Game for Peace is seen on a mobile phone in this illustration picture taken May 13, 2019.  Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>A Chinese Communist Party newspaper has urged the country’s regulators to end their erratic moves against the platform economy, in a sign of growing concern over policy damage to the health of the country’s ailing internet titans.</p><p>A front page opinion piece published by the Study Times, the mouthpiece of the Central Party School, on Wednesday argued that regulators must stop the practice of swinging between extremes of lax oversight and “overly strict” regulation so that China’s Big Tech firms can have room to grow.</p><p>The article, which did not name any specific company or regulator, came days after the National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA) wiped out billions of dollars in value from Chinese gaming stocks with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246011/china-tighten-controls-video-gaming-industry-prompting-sell-tencent-and-neteast-shares" target="_self" title="">proposed regulation to restrict spending on video games.</a> The South China Morning Post reported on Tuesday that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247044/veteran-chinese-video-gaming-official-steps-down-wake-market-rout-linked-proposed-rule-changes" target="_self" title="">a key gaming official has left his job following the debacle,</a> as the Chinese government tries to allay market fears.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246511/chinas-disciplinary-enforcers-add-bad-books-sex-drugs-serious-offences" title="">China’s disciplinary enforcers add ‘bad’ books, sex, drugs to serious offences</a></h3><p>The draft proposal is the latest example of regulatory hostility, after Beijing’s campaign of “curbing irrational expansion of capital” in 2020 unleashed a race among different ministries and watchdogs to claim authority in checking and approving internet businesses.</p><p>A long list of Chinese ministries has been sharpening their teeth when it comes to disciplining internet firms. The Cyberspace Administration of China, the country’s internet watchdog, for instance, has articulated Beijing’s demand for data security into intrusive requirements that have made it increasingly difficult and costly to comply with.</p><p>Beijing’s pursuit of market control, along with China’s economic slowdown and rising geopolitical tensions with the US, have turned Chinese internet stocks into one of the worst-performing assets in the past three years. Tencent Holdings, the country’s most valuable player that once eyed being Asia’s first US$1 trillion company, fell out of the global top 10 after losing 60 per cent of its market capitalisation, while Post owner Alibaba Group Holding, which exceeded Amazon.com in market value in 2014, is now worth an eighth of the US e-commerce titan.</p><p>According to the Study Times opinion piece, the erratic regulatory behaviour is “a risk and a challenge” for China as its leading internet firms are left further behind their global peers in terms of competitiveness and growth potential.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/03/643c0e52-aced-4b9f-a2cf-0f56737ce2f0_bd901af2.jpg" title="People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song" width="2000" /><figcaption>People play video games in a shopping mall in Beijing, November 18, 2023. Photo: Simon Song</figcaption></figure></div><p>China must improve “cross-departmental coordination” to avoid duplicated enforcement and checks, while regulatory acts and policy adjustments must factor in “the views of all parties, especially those being regulated” to avoid interrupting normal business activities or causing unexpected risks, it said.</p><p>Chinese regulators should loosen their grip and allow “self-governance” by Chinese internet companies, it added. “It is important to respect the rationality and necessity of platform self-governance to guide and encourage the formation of self-regulatory mechanisms,” the article said.</p><p>It remains unknown whether China’s different regulators will heed the advice. Beijing’s regulatory crackdown on the internet sector officially came to an end a year ago, when the Chinese leadership said the country’s platform enterprises would be encouraged to “fully display their capabilities” in growth, job creation and international competition.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung to kick off year of AI phones with new launch this month</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247104/samsung-kick-year-ai-phones-new-launch-month</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Samsung, the world's largest smartphone manufacturer, is focusing on artificial intelligence (AI) as the key to driving sales growth in 2024. The company plans to launch its next flagship device, the Galaxy S24, on January 17, with a focus on AI capabilities. This shift comes as smartphone makers seek to differentiate their products through AI features, such as generative AI, which can generate text or visual responses to user queries. Samsung aims to capture a significant share of the market for AI-powered smartphones, estimated to reach over a billion units by the end of 2027.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Samsung emphasizes AI as the key to unlocking greater sales in the smartphone market.</li>    <li>Theme: Samsung's strategic shift towards AI-powered smartphones.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The growing importance of AI in differentiating smartphones and driving sales.</li>    <li>Main information: Samsung's plans for the Galaxy S24 launch, the potential market size for AI-powered smartphones, and the contributions of OpenAI's generative AI tools.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  三星，全球最大的智能手机制造商，正将人工智能（AI）视为2024年推动销售增长的关键。该公司计划于1月17日在加利福尼亚州圣何塞推出其下一代旗舰设备Galaxy S24，重点是人工智能功能。这种转变正值智能手机制造商寻求通过人工智能功能来区分其产品之际，例如能够对用户查询生成文本或视觉响应的生成式人工智能。三星的目标是占领人工智能智能手机市场的很大份额，据估计，到2027年底将达到超过十亿部。  <ul>    <li>摘要：三星强调人工智能是打开智能手机市场更大销量的关键。</li>    <li>主题：三星向人工智能智能手机的战略转型。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能在区分智能手机和推动销售方面日益重要。</li>    <li>主要信息：三星对Galaxy S24发布的计划、人工智能智能手机的潜在市场规模以及OpenAI的生成式人工智能工具的贡献。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>generative (adj.) - /ˈdʒɛnərətɪv/ 富有创造力的，能产生创造性成果的。    <p>原文例句：More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由generare（产生，产生）和-tive（形成，产生）组成，表示“有创造力，产生创造性成果”。在这个例句中，它指的是能够产生创造性成果的人工智能，例如能够生成文本或视觉响应的用户查询的人工智能。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>integrate (v.) - /ˈɪntɪɡreɪt/ 集成，融合。    <p>原文例句：The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices, as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由inter（之间）和gradi（走）组成，表示“使融合，使集成”。在这个例句中，它指的是将技术集成到设备中，例如将人工智能集成到智能手机中。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>promising (adj.) - /ˈprɑːmɪsɪŋ/ 有希望的，有前途的。    <p>原文例句：2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，由promettre（承诺，保证）和-ing（表示进行，延续）组成，表示“有希望的，有前途的”。在这个例句中，它指的是2024年有望成为人工智能功能占据中心位置的一年。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take centre stage - 成为中心舞台。    <p>原文例句：2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（采取），centre（中心）和stage（舞台）组成的，表示“成为中心舞台”。在这个例句中，它指的是2024年人工智能功能有望成为中心舞台。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming”. - 发布的预告片只承诺“Galaxy AI即将到来”。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是The teaser promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming”.，其中主语是The teaser，谓语是promises，宾语是that “Galaxy AI is coming”.。only that “Galaxy AI is coming”是一个由only和that “Galaxy AI is coming”组成的句子，表示“只承诺Galaxy AI即将到来”。这个句子的意思是说，发布的预告片只承诺“Galaxy AI即将到来”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示三星和其他智能手机制造商在过去的几年中一直依靠相机技术和柔性显示屏的改进脱颖而出。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>动名词 - 表示动作或状态的名词。    <p>原文例句：The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个非限定名词，结构是：动词ing。动名词可以表示动作或状态，可以作主语、宾语、表语、定语或状语。在这个例句中，它表示整合技术到设备中的过程，作主语。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out</li>
<li>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates</li>
</ul><p>The world’s most prolific smartphone maker is leaning into artificial intelligence (AI) as the key to unlocking greater sales this year.</p><p>Samsung Electronics announced it plans to launch its next flagship device – likely to be known as the Galaxy S24 – on January 17 in San Jose, California, with a live-streamed event. The teaser to the launch promises only that “Galaxy AI is coming”.</p><p>In past years, Samsung and fellow smartphone makers have relied on improvements in camera technology and flexible displays to stand out, but 2024 promises to be a year where added AI capabilities take centre stage.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3246310/huawei-launches-new-nova-smartphones-without-giving-details-chip-attention-remains-fixed-its" title="">Huawei launches new Nova smartphones without giving details on chip</a></h3><p>More than a billion smartphones with built-in generative AI are expected to be shipped by the end of 2027, according to Counterpoint Research estimates.</p><p>OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Dall-E tools, which generate text or visual responses to users’ queries, are at the forefront of a generative-AI wave that is swept across the tech industry – and helped make Nvidia a trillion-dollar company by providing the key AI-training accelerators. The next step in advancing the technology is to integrate it into devices, as US chip maker Qualcomm has touted over the past year.</p><p>“Samsung and Qualcomm are immediate leaders as current product offerings and capabilities position them as first movers,” the Counterpoint researchers wrote in December. “Similar to what it did with foldables, Samsung is likely to capture almost 50 per cent share for the next two years, followed by key Chinese OEMs like Xiaomi, Vivo, Honor and Oppo.”</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Montana appealing ruling that blocked state from barring TikTok use</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247089/montana-appealing-ruling-blocked-state-barring-tiktok-use</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  美国蒙大拿州总检察长奥斯汀·克努森（Austin Knudsen）提交了一份通知，表示该州正在向美国第九巡回上诉法院对判决提出上诉。美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊（Donald Molloy）于 11 月 30 日发布初步禁令，阻止该禁令生效，称蒙大拿州的法律“超越了州权力”。蒙大拿州周二表示，将对美国一名法官 11 月份的决定提出上诉，该法官阻止了该州对使用短视频分享应用程序 TikTok 的首次此类禁令。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: 蒙大拿州就禁止抖音一案提出上诉。</li>    <li>Theme: 蒙大拿州对 TikTok 的禁令引发法律纠纷。</li>    <li>Viewpoint: 联邦政府和州政府在应用程序监管方面的权力分歧；TikTok 在保护用户数据和国家安全方面的责任。</li>    <li>Main information: TikTok禁令被初步阻止；蒙大拿州认为该禁令符合宪法；TikTok 否认与中国政府共享用户数据；联邦政府和多个州已禁止在政府设备上使用 TikTok。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  美国蒙大拿州总检察长奥斯汀·克努森（Austin Knudsen）向法院递交了上诉通知，表示该州正在就美国第九巡回上诉法院对TikTok禁令的判决提出上诉。此前，美国地区法官唐纳德·莫洛伊（Donald Molloy）于11月30日发布了初步禁令，以阻止该禁令的生效，并表示蒙大拿州的禁令“以多种方式违反了宪法”和“超越了州权力”。TikTok和克努森的办公室对此尚未发表评论。莫洛伊法官此前表示，初步庭前陈述应在1月16日前提交。TikTok与事实核查员合作，阻止网站上的选举错误信息。去年，蒙大拿州的用户也对该州立法机构批准的禁令提起了诉讼，该禁令援引了对蒙大拿州用户个人数据和潜在中国间谍活动的担忧。在早些时候提交的法庭文件中，TikTok表示“没有，也不会与中国政府共享美国用户的数据，并已采取切实措施保护TikTok用户隐私和安全”。莫洛伊法官表示，蒙大拿州寻求行使联邦政府持有的外交政策权力，该州的行动过于全面。TikTok一直面临着国会中一些人禁止该应用程序或赋予拜登政府实施限制或禁止外国应用程序的权力的努力，但这些努力已陷入僵局。许多州和美国政府已禁止在政府设备上使用TikTok，但只有蒙大拿州试图完全禁止使用该应用程序。前总统唐纳德·特朗普在2020年试图禁止下载TikTok和中国拥有的微信，但一系列法院裁决阻止了该禁令的生效。  <ul>    <li>摘要：蒙大拿州对抖音禁令提出上诉。</li>    <li>主题：蒙大拿州对 TikTok 的禁令引发法律纠纷。</li>    <li>观点：联邦政府和州政府在应用程序监管方面的权力分歧；TikTok 在保护用户数据和国家安全方面的责任。</li>    <li>主要信息：TikTok禁令被初步阻止；蒙大拿州认为该禁令符合宪法；TikTok 否认与中国政府共享用户数据；联邦政府和多个州已禁止在政府设备上使用 TikTok。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>bar (n.) - /bɑːr/ 酒吧，阻碍，限制。    <p>原文例句：TikTok teams up with fact checkers to stop election disinformation on site</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由古法语barre（长条，棍子）演变而来，表示“长条形的东西，障碍物”。在这个例句中，它表示“酒吧”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>preliminary (adj.) - /prɪˈlɪmɪnəri/ 初步的，暂时的。    <p>原文例句：US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自拉丁语prae（以前）和limen（门槛），表示“在开始之前的，暂时的”。在这个例句中，它表示“初步的”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>violate (v.) - /ˈvaɪləˌleɪt/ 违反，侵犯。    <p>原文例句：Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government and the state’s action was too sweeping.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来自拉丁语violare（侵犯，伤害），表示“违反，侵犯”。在这个例句中，它表示“违反”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take effect - 生效，起效。    <p>原文例句：Montana’s ban had been set to take effect on January 1, but…</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由take（拿，取）和effect（效果，影响）组成，表示“生效，起效”。在这个例句中，它表示“生效”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>be due - 应该，应当。    <p>原文例句：Molloy had previously said preliminary pretrial statements were due by January 16.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由be（是，存在）和due（到期的，应得的）组成，表示“应该，应当”。在这个例句中，它表示“应该”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>TikTok has faced efforts by some in Congress to ban the app or give the Biden administration's powers to impose restrictions or bar foreign-owned apps, but those efforts have stalled.  TikTok一直面临着国会中一些人禁止该应用程序或赋予拜登政府实施限制或禁止外国应用程序的权力的努力，但这些努力已陷入僵局。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，由两个简单句“TikTok has faced efforts by some in Congress to ban the app or give the Biden administration's powers to impose restrictions or bar foreign-owned apps”和“those efforts have stalled”连接而成。第一个简单句的主语是“TikTok”，谓语是“has faced”，宾语是“efforts”。第二个简单句的主语是“those efforts”，谓语是“have stalled”。这个句子的意思是说，TikTok一直面临着国会中一些人禁止该应用程序或赋予拜登政府实施限制或禁止外国应用程序的权力的努力，但这些努力已陷入僵局。</p>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词的用法 - 分词可以作定语、状语和表语。    <p>原文例句：TikTok and Knudsen’s office did not immediately comment.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中，“comment”是一个现在分词，作状语，表示“立即”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 被动语态用于强调动作的承受者。    <p>原文例句：Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government…</p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子中，“sought”是一个过去分词，作谓语，表示“寻求”。“held”是一个过去分词，作定语，表示“被掌握的”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice that the state is appealing the ruling to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals</li>
<li>US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban, saying Montana’s law ‘oversteps state power’</li>
</ul><p>Montana said on Tuesday it was appealing a decision by a US judge in November to block the state's first-of-its kind ban on the use of short-video sharing app TikTok.</p><p>Montana Attorney General Austin Knudsen filed a notice that the state is appealing the ruling to the Ninth Circuit US Court of Appeals.</p><p>Montana’s ban had been set to take effect on January 1, but US District Judge Donald Molloy on November 30 issued a preliminary injunction to block the ban on the Chinese-owned app, saying Montana’s law “violates the Constitution in more ways than one” and “oversteps state power”.</p><p>TikTok and Knudsen’s office did not immediately comment. Molloy had previously said preliminary pretrial statements were due by January 16.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246313/taiwan-elections-tiktok-teams-fact-checkers-stop-disinformation-site" title="">TikTok teams up with fact checkers to stop election disinformation on site</a></h3><p>TikTok users in Montana also had filed suit last year to block the ban approved by the state legislature, which cited concerns about the personal data of Montana users and potential Chinese spying.</p><p>In earlier court filings, TikTok said it “has not shared, and would not share, US user data with the Chinese government, and has taken substantial measures to protect the privacy and security of TikTok users”. Molloy said Montana sought to exercise foreign policy authority held by the federal government and the state’s action was too sweeping.</p><p>TikTok has faced efforts by some in Congress to ban the app or give the Biden administration's powers to impose restrictions or bar foreign-owned apps, but those efforts have stalled.</p><p>Many states and the US government have barred TikTok on government-owned devices, but only Montana has sought to completely bar the app’s use.</p><p>Former President Donald Trump in 2020 sought to bar new downloads of TikTok and Chinese-owned WeChat, but a series of court decisions blocked the effective ban from taking effect.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple hits 7-week low after Barclays downgrade on demand concerns</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247083/apple-hits-seven-week-low-after-barclays-downgrade-demand-concerns</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Apple's shares saw a significant increase of nearly 50 percent in 2023, reaching a record high in mid-December. However, recent concerns about weakening demand, particularly for the iPhone and Mac devices, have led to a 3.6 percent drop in Apple's shares on Tuesday. Barclays downgraded the company's stock due to these concerns, making it the second brokerage to issue a "sell" rating. This has contributed to a rise in bearish recommendations for Apple, reaching the highest number in at least two years.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's share performance in 2023, recent decline due to demand concerns, and analyst recommendations.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple's stock market performance in the context of overall market trends.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Barclays' downgrade of Apple's stock highlights the shifting market sentiment towards the company.</li>    <li>Main information: Apple's share rise in 2023, holiday-quarter sales forecast below expectations, concerns about iPhone and Mac demand, and Barclays' "underweight" rating.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  苹果公司的股票在2023年上涨了近50%，并在12月中旬创下历史新高，当时科技巨头引领了市场。自去年年初以来，该公司一直在努力应对需求放缓，并预测假日季度的销售额低于华尔街的预期。周二，苹果股价下跌近3.6%，创下七周新低，此前巴克莱将这家全球最有价值公司的股票评级下调，原因是担心该公司从iPhone到Mac的设备需求在2024年仍将疲软。巴克莱是第二家给予该股票相当于“卖出”评级的经纪公司，根据LSEG的数据，该股票现在至少两年内收到的看跌建议最多。该股票占标普500指数市值权重的7%，周二大盘指数被拉低了0.56%。苹果在2023年上涨了近50%，并在12月中旬创下历史新高，当时科技巨头引领了市场。苹果公司正在加快Vision Pro的生产，目标是2月份上市。自去年年初以来，苹果一直在努力应对需求放缓，并预测假日季度的销售额低于华尔街的预期。在本土竞争对手华为技术公司复兴后，其在中国市场的表现也令人担忧。“iPhone 15一直表现不佳，我们认为iPhone 16应该也是如此，”巴克莱分析师蒂姆·朗在一份客户报告中表示，他指出中国的疲软以及发达市场的需求疲软。根据LSEG的数据，朗在苹果推荐准确度方面的评级为五星中的四星。该经纪公司还警告称，苹果的服务业务正面临越来越大的风险，该业务在美国等国家因应用商店做法而受到审查。近年来，该业务经常超过苹果硬件部门的增长，现在占公司总收入的近四分之一。苹果将在专利纠纷中对美国手表的禁令提出上诉。周二的大跌抹去了苹果公司超过1000亿美元的市值，其股价收于185.64美元。在周二之前，自2022年7月以来，伊陶BBA的“卖出”是唯一看跌苹果的评级。分析师平均将这家iPhone制造商评级为“买入”，目标价中值为200美元。该公司按其未来12个月的预期收益计算的市盈率约为28.7倍，远高于标普500指数的19.8倍。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果公司在2023年的股票表现、由于需求担忧导致的近期下跌以及分析师建议。</li>    <li>主题：苹果公司股票市场表现的整体市场趋势背景。</li>    <li>观点：巴克莱下调苹果股票评级凸显了市场对该公司的态度转变。</li>    <li>主要信息：苹果公司在2023年的股价上涨、假日季度的销售额预测低于预期、对iPhone和Mac需求的担忧以及巴克莱的“减持”评级。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>rout (n.) - /raʊt/ 大败，溃败。    <p>原文例句：The stock rout on Tuesday erased more than US$100 billion of Apple’s market capitalisation, as its shares closed at US$185.64.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语，原意为“哄闹，喧闹”，引申为“大败，溃败”。在这个例句中，它指的是周二的股市大跌，导致苹果公司的市值蒸发了超过1000亿美元，其股票收于185.64美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>scanner (n.) - /ˈskænə/ 扫描仪。    <p>原文例句：The business has come under the scanner in countries including the United States over app store practices. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语，原意为“爬行，探索”，引申为“扫描仪”。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司的服务业务在美国等国家因应用商店做法而受到审查。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li> holiday-quarter - 假日季度    <P>原文例句：Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组指的是圣诞节和新年期间的销售旺季，通常是从11月到12月。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司预测假日季度的销售额低于华尔街的预期。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech companies led the markets. </li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复句，由两个简单句组成，主句是Apple rose，宾语是从句hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech companies led the markets。 hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech companies led the markets是一个过去分词短语作状语，修饰主句Apple rose，表示苹果公司在2023年上涨了近50%，并在12月中旬创下历史新高。in a year when Big Tech companies led the markets是一个时间状语从句，修饰hitting a record high，表示在科技巨头引领市场的一年中。这个句子的意思是说，苹果公司在2023年上涨了近50%，并在12月中旬创下历史新高，当时科技巨头引领了市场。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>定语从句 - 用于修饰或限定名词或代词。    <p>原文例句：Investors are cheering Apple’s strong performance in 2023, when the company’s shares rose nearly 50 per cent. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个定语从句，由when the company’s shares rose nearly 50 per cent组成，修饰名词performance，表示投资者对苹果公司在2023年的强劲表现感到欢呼雀跃，当时该公司的股票上涨了近50%。在这个例句中，定语从句是一个时间状语从句，表示在苹果公司股票上涨近50%的时候。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>现在完成式 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Since early last year, Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成式的句子，由have been grappling with a demand slowdown组成，其中have been是助动词，grappling with a demand slowdown是现在分词。现在完成式表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示自去年年初以来，苹果公司一直在努力应对需求放缓的情况。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple’s shares rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech firms led the markets</li>
<li>The company has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates</li>
</ul><p>Apple on Tuesday fell nearly 3.6 per cent to a seven-week low after Barclays downgraded the shares of the world’s most valuable company on concerns that demand for its devices, from the iPhone to the Mac, will remain weak in 2024.</p><p>Barclays is the second brokerage to have the equivalent of a “sell” rating on the stock, which now has its most number of bearish recommendations in at least two years, according to LSEG data.</p><p>The stock accounts for a hefty 7 per cent of the S&amp;P 500’s market weight – the broader index was dragged 0.56 per cent lower on Tuesday.</p><p>Apple rose nearly 50 per cent in 2023, hitting a record high in mid-December in a year when Big Tech companies led the markets.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3245817/apple-ramps-vision-pro-production-aiming-launch-february" title="">Apple ramps up Vision Pro production, aiming for launch by February</a></h3><p>Apple has been grappling with a demand slowdown since early last year and has forecast holiday-quarter sales below Wall Street estimates. Its performance in China has also been a worry after the revival of local rival Huawei Technologies.</p><p>“The iPhone 15 has been lacklustre and we believe iPhone 16 should be the same,” Barclays analyst Tim Long said in a client note, pointing to the China weakness as well as subdued demand in developed markets.</p><p>Long is rated four out of five stars for his recommendation accuracy on Apple, according to LSEG data.</p><p>The brokerage also warned risks were mounting for Apple’s services business, which has come under the scanner in countries including the United States over app store practices.</p><p>The business has often outpaced growth in Apple’s hardware segment in recent years and now accounts for nearly a quarter of the company’s total revenue.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3246322/us-import-ban-certain-apple-watch-models-takes-effect-over-patent-clash" title="">Apple to appeal US watch ban in patent dispute</a></h3><p>The stock rout on Tuesday erased more than US$100 billion of Apple’s market capitalisation, as its shares closed at US$185.64.</p><p>Barclays downgraded the stock to “underweight” from “neutral” and trimmed its 12-month price target by US$1 to US$160. Before Tuesday, Itau BBA’s “sell” was the only bearish rating on Apple since July 2022.</p><p>Analysts, on average, rate the iPhone maker “buy”, with a median price target of US$200. The company trades at about 28.7 times its 12-month forward earnings estimates, much higher than the S&amp;P 500’s 19.8.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
