<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China smartphone brand Realme unveils new handset on sidelines of trade show as its biggest rivals stay home</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248116/ces-2024-china-smartphone-brand-realme-unveils-new-handset-sidelines-trade-show-its-biggest-rivals</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Realme, a Chinese smartphone maker, launched its new 12 Pro+ handset at an event parallel to CES, targeting young users with better zoom capabilities at a budget price. The company emphasized its commitment to young consumers, aiming to offer outstanding products across all price segments.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Realme unveils the 12 Pro+ smartphone, focusing on enhanced zoom features for young users.</li>    <li>Theme: Realme rebrands its image to appeal to young overseas consumers, prioritizing budget-friendly devices with exceptional photography capabilities.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Realme's strategic focus on catering to the needs and desires of young consumers in the global smartphone market.</li>    <li>Main information: The 12 Pro+ boasts the largest sensor in a periscope lens among smartphones globally, combined with a 3x optical zoom. Realme collaborated with watch designer Ollivier Savéo for a design inspired by Swiss watches. The company aims to double down on what young users want most in a smartphone: better photos when zooming in.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国智能手机制造商Realme在与CES平行的活动中发布了其新款12 Pro+手机，以更实惠的价格为年轻用户提供更好的变焦功能。该公司强调了对年轻消费者的承诺，旨在在所有价格范围内提供出色的产品。  <ul>    <li>摘要：Realme发布12 Pro+智能手机，专注于为年轻用户增强变焦功能。</li>    <li>主题：Realme重新打造品牌形象以吸引海外年轻消费者，优先考虑具有出色摄影功能的经济实惠的设备。</li>    <li>观点：Realme在全球智能手机市场中战略性地专注于满足年轻消费者的需求和愿望。</li>    <li>主要信息：12 Pro+拥有全球智能手机潜望式镜头中最大的传感器，结合3倍光学变焦。Realme与手表设计师Ollivier Savéo合作，设计灵感来自瑞士手表。该公司旨在加倍满足年轻用户对智能手机的最大需求：放大时获得更好的照片。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sensor (n.) - /ˈsɛnsər/ 传感器，感应器。    <p>原文例句：Realme said its latest 12 Pro+ handset has the largest sensor in any periscope lens on a smartphone sold globally. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin中的sentire（感觉），表示“能感觉到或感受到的设备或装置”。在这个例句中，它指的是12 Pro+手机的传感器，即能够感觉到或检测到光线、温度或其他物理量的装置。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>optical (adj.) - /ˈɑːptɪkəl/ 光学（的）。    <p>原文例句：…combined a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Greek中的optikos（视觉的），表示“与光或视力有关的”。在这个例句中，它指的是光学变焦镜头，即利用光学原理来改变焦距的镜头，从而实现放大或缩小的效果。</p></li>  </ul>    <ul>    <li>chipset (n.) - /ˈtʃɪpsɛt/ 芯片组。    <p>原文例句：The chipset used in the 12 Pro+ will not be made public until closer to its formal launch. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由chip（芯片）和set（组）两个词组成的，表示“一组集成电路，通常封装在一个芯片中”。在这个例句中，它指的是12 Pro+手机中使用的芯片组，即控制手机功能的集成电路组。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>periscope lens - 潜望式镜头。    <p>原文例句：The 12 Pro+ smartphone launched by Realme last year costs 2,799 yuan, or about US$400. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由periscope（潜望镜）和lens（镜头）两个词组成的，表示“潜望式镜头”，即一种使用潜望镜原理设计的镜头，可以实现更大的变焦倍数。在这个例句中，它指的是12 Pro+手机使用的潜望式镜头，能够实现3倍光学变焦。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>overseas users - 海外用户。    <p>原文例句：Realme sister brand OnePlus was also in Las Vegas, while Xiaomi, Oppo and Vivo sat out the world’s largest consumer electronics show. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由overseas（海外的）和users（用户）两个词组成的，表示“海外用户”，即居住在国外或境外的用户。在这个例句中，它指的是Realme手机的海外用户，即居住在国外或境外的Realme手机用户。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>niche market segment - 利基市场细分。    <p>原文例句：The company said it was focused on a niche market segment, where it has found success overseas at a time when global smartphone sales are slumping and China’s post-pandemic economic recovery has sputtered.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由niche（利基）和market segment（市场细分）两个词组成的，表示“利基市场细分”，即在市场细分中进一步细分出的更小的市场群体。在这个例句中，它指的是Realme手机的利基市场细分，即在智能手机市场中进一步细分出的更小的市场群体，如喜欢拍摄照片的年轻人。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Moving forward, Realme aims to double down on what it believes young users want most in a smartphone. - 展望未来，Realme致力于加倍满足年轻用户对智能手机的最大需求。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Realme aims to double down on what it believes young users want most in a smartphone，其中主语是Realme，谓语是aims to double down，宾语是what it believes young users want most in a smartphone。Moving forward是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示在未来或进展中。这个句子的意思是说，展望未来，Realme致力于加倍满足年轻用户对智能手机的最大需求。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>So the firm has combined a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones. - 因此，该公司将半英寸传感器与3倍光学变焦潜望式镜头相结合，并将其内置于其中端智能手机产品线中。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是So the firm has combined a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones，其中主语是the firm，谓语是has combined，宾语是a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens。and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones是一个现在分词短语作结果状语，表示连接两个句子之间的因果关系。这个句子的意思是说，因此，该公司将半英寸传感器与3倍光学变焦潜望式镜头相结合，并将其内置于其中端智能手机产品线中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达虚拟、假设或期望。    <p>原文例句：Realme acknowledged challenges from the pandemic, component shortages and longer replacement cycles from consumers, but the firm also touted its sales numbers – more than 200 million handsets sold since its incubation at Oppo – as “giving us confidence that we’re on to something”. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种语法结构，用来表达说话者对事实或情况的主观看法或猜测。在英语中，虚拟语气通常使用助动词would、could、should或might来表示。在这个例句中，助动词giving表示虚拟语气，表示Realme公司对自己的销售数字感到有信心。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去的某个时间或事件之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Realme, which did not reveal pricing for its latest handsets, said the chipset used in the 12 Pro+ will not be made public until closer to its formal launch. </  <ul><li>The new 12 Pro+ handset to launch at the end of January provides a better zoom lens at a budget price, as Realme caters to young overseas users</li>
<li>Realme sister brand OnePlus was also in Las Vegas, while Xiaomi, Oppo and Vivo sat out the world’s largest consumer electronics show</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/1486c8f9-79ff-40ce-9c1a-5163f3d4b7b2_2eaa662e.jpg" /><figcaption>Realme unveiled the 12 Pro+ smartphone at an event parallel to the CES trade show. The company is targeting young users with better zoom capabilities in a budget device. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> maker <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" target="_self" title="">Realme</a>, owned by mainland consumer hardware giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/2184877/meet-godfather-chinas-smartphone-industry" target="_self" title="">BBK Electronics</a> which also controls <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oppo" target="_self" title="">Oppo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/vivo" target="_self" title="">Vivo</a>, held a parallel event in Las Vegas on the sidelines of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ces" target="_self" title="">CES</a> trade show to unveil its new handset as part of a rebranding effort targeting young overseas users.</p><p>While not an official exhibitor at CES, Realme was one of only two major Chinese smartphone brands to show up in Las Vegas this week. On Wednesday, Realme introduced its 12-series smartphones at the same hotel where its sister brand, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/oneplus" target="_self" title="">OnePlus</a>, had a series of suites booked for its own presentations outside CES.</p><p>Realme said its latest 12 Pro+ handset has the largest sensor in any periscope lens on a smartphone sold globally, but pointed out that the company’s GT 5 Pro handset sold in China technically has a bigger lens.</p><p>“What sets us apart from other brands is that we are fully committed to the young generation,” Sam Cheung, senior marketing communications manager for Realme, said in his presentation during the firm’s hour-long event on the sidelines of CES 2024. “At Realme, we believe that every user at every price segment deserves an outstanding product.”</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane" class="image-inline caption" height="1506" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/714bf56a-c08f-4ee3-bc44-695f0ea16d52_68aef08b.jpg" title="Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane" width="2000" /><figcaption>Realme senior marketing communications manager Sam Cheung points out that the zoom capabilities of the firm’s new 12 Pro+ smartphone’s periscope lens are important to its young users. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure></div><p>Realme, which did not reveal pricing for its latest handsets, said the chipset used in the 12 Pro+ will not be made public until closer to its formal launch. While the new device uses a mid-tier <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/qualcomm" target="_self" title="">Qualcomm</a> processor, Realme said it collaborated with the US chip design firm on a solution to improve image-processing speed.</p><p>The 11 Pro+ smartphone launched by Realme last year costs 2,799 yuan, or about US$400.</p><p>At its event, Realme said the firm’s slogan, “Dare to leap”, has been changed to “Make it real” as part of a rebranding effort.</p><p>The company said it was focused on a niche market segment, where it has found success overseas at a time when global smartphone sales are slumping and China’s post-pandemic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chinas-economic-recovery" target="_self" title="">economic recovery</a> has sputtered.</p><p>Realme acknowledged challenges from the pandemic, component shortages and longer replacement cycles from consumers, but the firm also touted its sales numbers – more than <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments">200 million handsets sold</a> since its incubation at Oppo – as “giving us confidence that we’re on to something”.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3242898/chinas-realme-sister-brand-vivo-oppo-surges-past-200-million-smartphone-shipments" title="">China’s Realme surges past 200 million smartphone shipments</a></h3><p>Moving forward, Realme aims to double down on what it believes young users want most in a smartphone. The answer it came up with is better photos when zooming in. So the firm has combined a half-inch sensor with a 3x optical zoom periscope lens and built that in its mid-tier line of smartphones.</p><p>It also collaborated with watch designer Ollivier Savéo, who previously worked at Rolex and Piaget, among others, on a design evocative of famed Swiss watches.</p><p>At a time of rising scrutiny of all things Chinese, Realme made its latest product announcement in a country leading the charge against tech from China and where the company does not even sell smartphones.</p><p>For all the other missing Chinese brands – and the smattering of journalists and influencers who showed up to cover the Realme event – it may as well have been part of the show. Vivo and Oppo, two of China’s biggest smartphone brands, were nowhere to be found in Las Vegas, even though Realme spun out of Oppo. OnePlus, the Oppo-owned brand, had suites booked for private showings, but also had no presence on the CES exhibition floor.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>Neither <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> nor <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-blacklisted</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> were at CES.</p><p>Realme said it did not exhibit at CES because the 12 Pro+ handset has not officially launched yet. It organised a pre-briefing in Las Vegas because many of its contacts across a variety of markets would be in town for the world’s largest consumer electronics show.</p><p>While the company set a goal last year of selling in more than 100 markets over the next five years, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> is one market where it may not expand owing to the complexities of getting domestic network carrier support.</p><p>The bulk of US handset sales still happen through mobile network operators, forcing smartphone brands to strike deals to find success. OnePlus has struggled with this situation, despite the glowing reviews received by many of its devices from US tech media.</p><p>Realme said it was still trying to cooperate with a US carrier to get into the market, where 87 per cent of teenagers own an iPhone, according to a survey by investment bank Piper Sandler.</p><p>Meanwhile, Realme has been selling in parts of Europe and Latin America, which it described as an important market for the company’s upcoming 12-series handsets.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia reveals progress in China’s self-driving chip market, setting up competition with domestic players</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3248095/nvidia-reveals-progress-chinas-self-driving-chip-market-setting-competition-domestic-players</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia secures deals with Chinese EV makers, including Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR, for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system.</li>    <li>The system combines automated driving, infotainment, and parking features.</li>    <li>Competition in the Chinese autonomous driving market intensifies as local players like Huawei Technologies gain traction.</li>    <li>Nvidia maintains a strong position in China's smart-driving chip market but faces increasing pressure from Chinese competitors.</li>    <li>Chinese government's push for advanced self-driving technology boosts market growth.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>英伟达与长城汽车、理想汽车、小米和吉利旗下的极氪汽车达成合作，为其提供Drive Thor自动驾驶系统。</li>    <li>该系统集成了自动驾驶、车载信息娱乐和停车功能。</li>    <li>随着华为技术等本土企业的崛起，中国自动驾驶市场竞争日益激烈。</li>    <li>英伟达在中国智能驾驶芯片市场的主导地位依然稳固，但面临来自中国竞争对手的压力越来越大。</li>    <li>中国政府对先进自动驾驶技术的大力推动，促进了市场快速增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>deployment (n.) - /dɪˈplɔɪmənt/ 部署，配置。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia's latest move will see its Drive Thor autonomous driving system deployed in cars made by some of China's leading EV makers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于古法语desploier（展开，部署），意为“部署，配置”。在这个例句中，它指的是英伟达的Drive Thor自动驾驶系统被部署到一些中国领先的电动汽车制造商生产的汽车中。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>penetration rate - 渗透率。    <p>原文例句：In 2022, China sold about 7 million units of smart passenger vehicles equipped with assisted autonomous driving systems, which translates into a market penetration rate of 35 per cent.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由penetration（渗透）和rate（率）组成，表示“渗透率”。在这个例句中，它指的是配备辅助自动驾驶系统的智能乘用车在中国市场的渗透率，即2022年中国市场上销售的配备辅助自动驾驶系统的智能乘用车数量占总销量的比例。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 在……方面，从……角度。    <P>原文例句：Nvidia remains predominant in terms of smart-driving chips in China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示英伟达在智能驾驶芯片方面仍然占据主导地位。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>set up - 建立，设立。    <P>原文例句：Nvidia added Drive Thor – which integrates automated and assisted driving, in-vehicle infotainment, and parking in one single system – to its family of automotive system-on-a-chip solutions in September 2022.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由set（设置）和up（向上，建立）构成的，表示“建立，设立”。在这个例句中，它表示英伟达在2022年9月将Drive Thor添加到其汽车系统级芯片解决方案系列中，该系统集成了自动驾驶、辅助驾驶、车载信息娱乐和停车功能。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia said at the CES consumer electronics show in Las Vegas that Chinese EV makers, including Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR, have snapped up its Drive Thor autonomous driving system to enhance performance of their vehicles. - 英伟达在拉斯维加斯的CES消费电子展上表示，包括长城汽车、理想汽车、小米和吉利旗下的极氪汽车在内的多家中国电动汽车制造商已经抢购了英伟达的Drive Thor自动驾驶系统，以提高其车辆的性能。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Nvidia said，其中主语是Nvidia，谓语是said，宾语是that Chinese EV makers have snapped up its Drive Thor autonomous driving system to enhance performance of their vehicles。Chinese EV makers, including Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR是一个限制性定语从句，修饰Chinese EV makers，表示这些中国电动汽车制造商包括长城汽车、理想汽车、小米和吉利旗下的极氪汽车。to enhance performance of their vehicles是一个目的状语从句，修饰snapped up，表示抢购英伟达的Drive Thor自动驾驶系统是为了提高他们车辆的性能。这个句子的意思是说，英伟达在拉斯维加斯的CES消费电子展上表示，包括长城汽车、理想汽车、小米和吉利旗下的极氪汽车在内的多家中国电动汽车制造商已经抢购了英伟达的Drive Thor自动驾驶系统，以提高其车辆的性能。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表示非真实或不确定的情况。    <p>原文例句：It is unclear how the company will address the issue.</p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气是一种语气，用于表示说话人对某件事的看法或态度，而不是对事实的陈述。虚拟语气的标志是使用助动词would、should、could、might、may等，或使用动词的过去式或过去分词。在这个例句中，it is unclear how the company will address the issue是一个虚拟语气句，表示公司将如何解决这个问题尚不清楚。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 用于强调动作的承受者。<p>原文例句：The system has been integrated into a number of vehicles.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是一种语态，用于强调动作的承受者，而不是动作的执行者。被动语态的标志是使用助动词be和动词的过去分词。在这个例句中，the system has been integrated into a number of vehicles，表示系统已经被集成到许多车辆中。这个句子的意思是说，该系统已经被集成到许多车辆中。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Autonomous-driving systems have become a competitive sector as China pushes greater adoption of advanced self-driving technology</li>
<li>Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/46325582-beb7-45f2-ae5c-8a43d08517a8_f1163133.jpg" /><figcaption>Nvidia has signed up Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR for its Drive Thor autonomous driving system. Photo: EPA-EFE </figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia, the US chip maker banned by Washington from selling its most advanced semiconductors to China, has revealed solid progress in the mainland’s electric vehicle (EV) market with its self-driving technology.</p><p>Nvidia said at the CES consumer electronics show in Las Vegas that Chinese EV makers, including Great Wall Motors, Li Auto, Xiaomi, and Geely-backed ZEEKR, have snapped up its Drive Thor autonomous driving system to enhance performance of their vehicles. This sets up increased competition with local self-driving system providers such as Huawei Technologies.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3246414/huawei-and-xiaomi-launch-new-ev-models-china-reigniting-worries-about-price-wars-worlds-largest-ev" target="_self" title="">Autonomous-driving systems</a>, seen as the brains behind future cars, have become a competitive sector as China pushes greater adoption of advanced self-driving technology. Nvidia added Drive Thor – which integrates automated and assisted driving, in-vehicle infotainment, and parking in one single system – to its family of automotive system-on-a-chip solutions in September 2022.</p><p>As of June last year, Nvidia – which is unable to ship its advanced AI chips to China due to US trade sanctions – had about a 52 per cent share of the global navigate-on-autopilot (NOA) market and cooperation agreements with 25 automotive original equipment makers globally, according to data from Gasgoo Institute, a Shanghai-based research company.</p><p>“Nvidia remains predominant in terms of smart-driving chips in China,” said Brady Wang, an associate director with research firm Counterpoint. “But competition between Chinese manufacturers and foreign companies is set to intensify as they compete for a slice of the autonomous driving segment in China’s EV market.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>Chinese EV makers have been big buyers of Nvidia auto chips. For example, Nio’s flagship sedans ET5 and ES7, Li Auto’s L9 model and Xpeng’s G9 vehicle all come equipped with Nvidia’s Orin chips. Automotive chips are seen as a less sensitive area of the semiconductor market by US authorities when it comes to setting trade sanctions.</p><p>In 2022, China sold about 7 million units of smart passenger vehicles equipped with assisted autonomous driving systems, which translates into a market penetration rate of 35 per cent. In the first half of 2023, the market penetration rate rose to almost 43 per cent, according to data from China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT).</p><p>The MIIT in November issued a new policy that encourages EV makers to bring vehicles equipped with high-levels of autonomous driving to Chinese roads, in a major effort to accomplish Chinese President Xi Jinping’s vision of building a strong and modern transport network.</p><p>Thanks to policy stimulus, Chinese autonomous driving system solution providers – including Horizon Robotics and Black Sesame Technologies – have stepped up their game and are set for greater competition with the likes of Nvidia, Qualcomm, and Intel-owned MobileEye in areas such as autonomous driving chips and full-stack smart car solutions.</p><p>Nvidia topped China’s NOA computing solutions market with a share of 53 per cent in the first half of 2023, followed by smart mobility start-up Horizon Robotics with 31 per cent, and Texas Instruments with 9 per cent, according to data from the Gaogong Industry Research Institute (GGII), which tracks nascent industries in China such as EVs and batteries. Huawei and MobileEye ranked in equal 4th place with a 4 per cent market share each.</p><p>Huawei has emerged as a leading player due to its experience in auto chip design and hardware systems after it set up a smart car solution unit in 2019, the year it was added to a US trade blacklist. Under these sanctions, Huawei could not buy most US-origin semiconductors and had to rely on its own smart-driving chips.</p><p>Priot to the 2023 Shanghai Auto Show in April, Huawei launched its own home-grown smart driving platform, called advanced driving system 2.0 (ADS) and powered by a Huawei-made chipset MDC 610, according to a report by research company Counterpoint and a note in July by Kaiyuan Securities.</p><p>In November, Huawei announced it was transferring core technologies from its smart car business into a new joint venture with state-backed Changan Automobile. The <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243139/huawei-accelerates-smart-car-ambitions-invitation-four-carmakers-invest-changan-joint-venture" target="_self" title="">new venture</a>, in which Changan has a 40 per cent stake, is open to other car makers as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3235762/superior-teslas-model-s-huawei-and-chery-automobile-ev-venture-luxeed-launch-first-production-model?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">equity investors</a>.</p><p>Despite still being in the red, the firm’s car unit achieved sales of 2.1 billion yuan (US$305 million) in 2022 and 1 billion yuan in revenue in the first half of last year, according to company information.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple supplier BOE, one of the world’s top display makers, forges US$9 billion deal to build next-generation plant in southwestern China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248092/apple-supplier-boe-one-worlds-top-display-makers-forges-us9-billion-deal-build-next-generation-plant</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  BOE Technology Group, a leading display manufacturer, plans to establish a next-generation production complex in Chengdu, China, with an investment of 63 billion yuan (US$9 billion). The facility, called Gen-8.6 AMOLED, will focus on producing high-end displays for laptops and tablets, aiming to meet the soaring global demand. This project represents the largest single industrial investment in Chengdu and is expected to strengthen mainland China's lead in display manufacturing capacity.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: BOE's investment in a new display production complex in Chengdu to meet global demand for high-end displays.</li>    <li>Theme: Technological advancement and industrial development in the display industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: China's efforts to increase collaboration with private companies and restore business confidence.</li>    <li>Main information: Details of the production complex, including investment amount, production capacity, and expected completion date.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  京东方科技集团，全球领先的显示器制造商，计划在中国成都投资630亿元人民币（90亿美元）建立一个新一代生产基地。该工厂名为Gen-8.6 AMOLED，将专注于生产用于笔记本电脑和平板电脑的高端显示器，以满足全球不断增长的需求。该项目是成都最大的单笔产业投资，预计将增强中国大陆在显示器制造领域的领先地位。  <ul>    <li>摘要：京东方投资成都新显示器生产基地，以满足全球对高端显示器的需求。</li>    <li>主题：显示器行业的技术进步和产业发展。</li>    <li>观点：中国努力加强与私营企业的合作，恢复企业信心。</li>    <li>主要信息：生产基地的详细信息，包括投资金额、产能和预计完工日期。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>facility (n.) - /fəˈsɪləti/ 设备，设施。    <p>原文例句：BOE Technology Group’s new production complex for advanced displays in Chengdu, capital of southwestern Sichuan province, is expected to start mass production by the fourth quarter of 2026. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由facilis（容易）构成，意为“易于使用或操作的东西，设备，设施”。在这个例句中，它指的是京东方科技集团将在成都建立的新一代生产基地。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>bolster (v.) - /ˈboʊlstər/ 加固，加强    <p>原文例句：The deal is expected to bolster mainland China’s lead in display manufacturing capacity over the next few years.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，由bolster（枕头）构成，意为“用枕头支撑，加固，加强”。在这个例句中，它指的是这笔交易预计将在未来几年内增强中国大陆在显示器制造领域的领先地位。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。    <P>原文例句：The deal represents the largest single industrial project in terms of investment in Chengdu, the capital of southwestern Sichuan province.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），terms（条件，条款）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“按照某种标准或角度来衡量或评价”。在这个例句中，它表示这笔交易是成都最大的单笔工业投资项目。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>BOE’s so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex is expected to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets. 京东方科技集团的Gen-8.6 AMOLED生产基地预计将满足全球对用于笔记本电脑和平板电脑的高端显示器的不断增长的需求。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex is expected to meet soaring global demand，其中主语是Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex，谓语是expected to meet，宾语是soaring global demand。BOE’s so-called是一个形容词短语作定语，修饰Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex，表示这是京东方科技集团的Gen-8.6 AMOLED生产基地。for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets是一个介词短语作目的状语，表示生产基地的目的是为了满足全球对用于笔记本电脑和平板电脑的高端显示器的需求。这个句子的意思是说，京东方科技集团的Gen-8.6 AMOLED生产基地预计将满足全球对用于笔记本电脑和平板电脑的高端显示器的不断增长的需求。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Construction of the new plant is estimated to take 34 months, according to BOE, and mass production is projected to start by the fourth quarter of 2026. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it is estimated to take 34 months表示预计需要34个月的时间，start by the fourth quarter of 2026表示预计在2026年第四季度开始。这个句子的意思是说，据京东方估计，新工厂的建设预计需要34个月，预计在大规模生产将在2026年第四季度开始。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>BOE’s so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED production complex is expected to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets</li>
<li>The deal represents the largest single industrial project in terms of investment in Chengdu, the capital of southwestern Sichuan province</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/f510ed59-cdd2-46ae-9e74-0cdf88c294bd_6e2e158b.jpg" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group’s new production complex for advanced displays in Chengdu, capital of southwestern Sichuan province, is expected to start mass production by the fourth quarter of 2026. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> supplier <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/3024664/how-chinese-accountant-turned-dying-state-owned-factory-worlds-no-1?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">BOE Technology Group</a>, one of the world’s largest display makers, will set up a 63-billion yuan (US$9 billion) next-generation production complex in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chengdu" target="_self" title="">Chengdu</a>, capital of southwestern Sichuan province, that is expected to bolster mainland China’s lead in display manufacturing capacity over the next few years.</p><p>The Chengdu municipal government on Wednesday said in a statement that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/beijing" target="_self" title="">Beijing</a>-based BOE and the city’s Hi-Tech Industrial Development Zone have signed the contract to build the plant, representing the largest single industrial project in the capital in terms of investment.</p><p>BOE, which initially announced the project last December, will build its so-called Gen-8.6 AMOLED – for active-matrix organic light-emitting diode – production facility to meet soaring global demand for high-end displays used in laptops and tablets, according to the firm.</p><p>Shares of BOE in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shenzhen" target="_self" title="">Shenzhen</a> closed up 1.07 per cent to 3.76 yuan on Thursday.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1500" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/81c3e4de-5983-4500-9e40-24c9b7f0441d_edd804f5.jpg" title="BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group shows its latest flexible notebook display at this week’s CES trade show in Las Vegas, Nevada. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>The deal underscores efforts by Chinese local governments to increase collaboration with Big Tech companies in the private sector, which is in line with the mainland’s efforts to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3210306/chinas-key-private-sector-needs-continuity-stability-support-economic-recovery-doubts-remain" target="_self" title="">restore business confidence and drive economic recovery</a>.</p><p>The new BOE production facility is expected to position Chengdu as the display industry’s largest manufacturing base for advanced flexible panels.</p><p>Construction of the new plant is estimated to take 34 months, according to BOE, and mass production is projected to start by the fourth quarter of 2026. The next-generation plant is designed to produce 32,000 glass substrates – each measuring 2,290 millimetres by 2,620mm – every month.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/73fdd8a8-8b16-4d68-8c5f-e654e2a0eacf_1126e908.jpg" title="BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>BOE Technology Group previously established mainland China’s first sixth-generation, flexible OLED production line. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>Apart from accommodating larger substrates, BOE said its Gen-8.6 AMOLED production line will be able to enhance panel-cutting efficiency for mid-size displays, reduce production costs, lower power consumption and achieve an extended lifespan.</p><p>OLED displays for mobile and other information technology devices are expected to enjoy rapid expansion between 2022 and 2027, with a compound annual growth rate of 7.3 per cent, according to a recent report by Display Supply Chain Consultants (DSCC).</p><p>China is forecast to dominate global display manufacturing capacity, with a 72 per cent market share from 2026 to 2027, the DSCC report said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/gear/article/3024664/how-chinese-accountant-turned-dying-state-owned-factory-worlds-no-1" title="">How Chinese accountant turned dying factory into No 1 display maker</a></h3><p>By comparison, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>’s market shares are expected to reach 8 per cent and 17 per cent, respectively, in 2027.</p><p>The global OLED market is predicted to generate US$64 billion in revenue in 2026, driven by demand for panels used in laptops, computers monitors and tablets, according to DSCC.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei secures JD.com as HarmonyOS partner as home-grown software emerges as alternative for Apple iOS, Android in China</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248044/huawei-secures-jdcom-harmonyos-partner-home-grown-software-emerges-alternative-apple-ios-android</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  JD.com is set to develop an app for HarmonyOS Next, a mobile platform created by Huawei. Huawei's HarmonyOS aims to compete with Android and iOS in China and is projected to surpass Apple's iOS this year. HarmonyOS Next will not support Android-based apps and will feature advancements in intelligence and multi-scenario transitions.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: JD.com joins Huawei's HarmonyOS ecosystem with a new app.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's HarmonyOS gains momentum in China, challenging Android and iOS.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: HarmonyOS Next's focus on intelligence and multi-scenario support.</li>    <li>Main information: JD.com's partnership with Huawei; HarmonyOS's growth in China; HarmonyOS Next's features and launch timeline.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  京东将为 HarmonyOS Next 开发一款应用，HarmonyOS Next 是华为自主研发的移动平台。华为的 HarmonyOS 旨在在中国与 Android 和 iOS 展开竞争，预计今年将超越苹果的 iOS。HarmonyOS Next 将不支持基于 Android 的应用，并将采用智能化和多场景转换等特性。  <ul>    <li>摘要：京东加入华为 HarmonyOS 生态，打造全新应用。</li>    <li>主题：华为 HarmonyOS 在中国市场势头强劲，挑战 Android 和 iOS。</li>    <li>观点：HarmonyOS Next 专注于智能化和多场景支持。</li>    <li>主要信息：京东与华为的合作；HarmonyOS 在中国的增长；HarmonyOS Next 的特性和发布计划。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>iteration (n.) - /aɪtəˈreɪʃən/ 重复，反复。    <p>原文例句：JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform.</p>    <p>例句讲解：iteration 是 iteration 的同源词，其来源于拉丁语 iterare，原意为“重复”。在这个例句中，iteraion 指的是华为移动平台的下一个版本，即 HarmonyOS 的下一个版本。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>milestone (n.) - /ˈmaɪlstəʊn/ 里程碑，重要时刻。    <p>原文例句：Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”, Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo.</p>    <p>例句讲解：milestone 是一个合成词，由 mile 和 stone 组成，其原意为“里程碑”，引申为“重要时刻”。在这个例句中，milestone 指的是 HarmonyOS 发展过程中的一个重要时刻，即与京东的合作。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take ground - 占据优势。    <p>原文例句：While Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, according to TechInsights.</p>    <p>例句讲解：take ground 是一个短语动词，其原意为“占据优势”，引申为“取得进展”。在这个例句中，take ground 指的是华为的 HarmonyOS 在中国市场取得优势。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>comeback (n.) - /ˈkʌmbæk/ 归来，复出。    <p>原文例句：The self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative in August 2019, three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List. Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p>    <p>例句讲解：comeback 是一个合成词，由 come 和 back 组成，其原意为“归来”，引申为“复出”。在这个例句中，comeback 指的是华为在推出 HarmonyOS 后，在智能手机市场上的复出。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>native app - 原生应用。    <p>原文例句：Huawei is already working with major Chinese companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p>    <p>例句讲解：native app 是一个合成词，由 native 和 app 组成，其原意为“原生应用”，指针对特定平台或设备而开发的应用。在这个例句中，native app 指的是针对 HarmonyOS 开发的应用。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei Technologies has secured another partner to promote use of HarmonyOS, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant continues to take on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market. - 华为技术公司已获得另一家合作伙伴，以促进使用 HarmonyOS，因为这家受到美国制裁的电信设备巨头继续在中国市场上对抗谷歌的 Android 和苹果的 iOS。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个主从复合句，主句是 Huawei Technologies has secured another partner to promote use of HarmonyOS，从句是 as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant continues to take on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market。主句中的谓语是 has secured，宾语是 another partner to promote use of HarmonyOS；从句中的谓语是 continues to take on，宾语是 Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market。这个句子的意思是说，华为技术公司已获得另一家合作伙伴，以促进使用 HarmonyOS，因为这家受到美国制裁的电信设备巨头继续在中国市场上对抗谷歌的 Android 和苹果的 iOS。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>The self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative in August 2019, three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List. - 自主研发的 HarmonyOS 于 2019 年 8 月推出，作为 Android 的替代品，三个月后美国政府将华为添加到其实体清单中。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个并列复合句，并列句是 The self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative 和 three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List。并列句之间的连接词是 in August 2019。第一个并列句中的谓语是 was launched，宾语是 HarmonyOS；第二个并列句中的谓语是 added，宾语是 Huawei to its Entity List。这个句子的意思是说，自主研发的 HarmonyOS 于 2019 年 8 月推出，作为 Android 的替代品，三个月后美国政府将华为添加到其实体清单中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词作状语 - 表示动作或状态发生的时间、原因、条件等。    <p>原文例句：The self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative in August 2019, three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List. </p>    <p>语法讲解：过去分词作状语是一个由过去分词构成的状语，表示动作或状态发生的时间、原因、条件等。在这个例句中，过去分词作状语是 three months after the US government added Huawei to its Entity List，它表示 HarmonyOS 推出的时间，即在美国政府将华为添加到其实体清单的三个月后。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Huawei Technologies has secured another partner to promote use of HarmonyOS, as the US-sanctioned telecommunications equipment giant continues to take on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成时是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 过去分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则动词的过去分词。现在完成时表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，现在完成时是 has secured，它表示华为技术公司从过去的某个时间  <ul><li>JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform</li>
<li>Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of HarmonyOS, which is projected to surpass Apple’s iOS in China this year</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/5435c70a-132e-4030-86c0-5a8e160d23ce_92ca8b90.jpg" /><figcaption>A billboard advertising Huawei’s Harmony OS at the Smart China Expo in Chongqing, Sept. 4, 2023. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies has secured another partner to promote use of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3136017/will-huaweis-harmony-operating-system-end-global-duopoly-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS</a>, as the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">US-sanctioned</a> telecommunications equipment giant continues to take on Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS in the Chinese market.</p><p>Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com will build an app for HarmonyOS Next, based on the intelligence innovations in the next iteration of Huawei’s mobile platform and its ability to support transitions between multiple scenarios, Richard Yu Chengdong, chief executive of Huawei’s consumer business group, said on Wednesday.</p><p>Calling JD.com “a heavyweight partner”, Yu said the partnership marks a new milestone for HarmonyOS in a post on social media platform Weibo.</p><p>Joining with a growing number of Chinese internet companies, Huawei is pushing for wider adoption of its home-grown HarmonyOS, which is projected to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247172/huaweis-harmonyos-beat-apples-ios-no-2-smartphone-operating-system-china-2024-techinsights-report" target="_self" title="">surpass Apple’s iOS as the second-biggest operating system in China</a> this year, according to Canadian research firm TechInsights.</p><p>While Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS will continue to dominate the global smartphone operating system sector, Huawei’s self-developed HarmonyOS will take some ground from both US giants in China, driven by the firm’s smartphone comeback with the Mate 60 series, according to TechInsights.</p><p>The self-developed HarmonyOS was launched as an Android alternative in August 2019, three months after the US government <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">added Huawei to its Entity List</a>. Under this trade blacklist, the company is barred from buying software, chips and other US-origin technologies from suppliers without Washington’s approval.</p><p>HarmonyOS is also projected to reach a milestone in 2024 with the launch of HarmonyOS Next, which will not support Android-based apps.</p><p>A developer preview of HarmonyOS Next is expected to be launched in the first quarter of 2024. Huawei is already working with major Chinese companies to develop native apps based on the system.</p><p>Ant Group, the fintech affiliate of South China Morning Post owner <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, said last month that it was building a new version of mobile payment app Alipay based on HarmonyOS, after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242703/alibaba-develops-native-dingtalk-app-harmonyos-huawei-aims-end-support-android-apps?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Alibaba started development on a new version of DingTalk</a>, its workplace collaboration app.</p><p>Other major Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">internet</a> companies – including <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a>, video gaming giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/netease?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">NetEase</a> and food delivery market leader <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> – in November started to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241371/chinese-big-tech-firms-jdcom-netease-and-meituan-rush-hire-harmonyos-based-app-developers-huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">recruit developers to build native apps for HarmonyOS</a>.</p><p>McDonald’s China – with a network of more than 5,500 restaurants and over 200,000 employees – became <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244236/mcdonalds-china-pushes-development-native-apps-based-harmonyos-adoption-huaweis-mobile-operating?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">one of the first multinational food companies on the mainland to adopt</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239589/xiaomi-launches-home-grown-cross-device-system-hyperos-us-sanctioned-huawei-moves-further-googles?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">HarmonyOS Next</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Elon Musk’s X tells watchdog it has shed 1,000 ‘safety’ staff</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3248024/elon-musks-x-tells-watchdog-it-has-shed-1000-safety-staff</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Australia's eSafety Commission reports that Elon Musk's Twitter (X) has laid off over 1,000 employees responsible for combating harmful content, leading to a surge in toxicity and hate speech on the platform.</li>    <li>The commission expresses concern over the reinstatement of banned accounts and highlights the need for social media companies to prioritize user safety.</li>    <li>Australia's Online Safety Act has facilitated the collection of detailed data on X's safety staff, revealing a significant reduction in personnel dedicated to addressing trust and safety issues.</li>    <li>Commissioner Julie Inman Grant compares the situation to Volvo eliminating its safety engineers, emphasizing the detrimental impact on platform safety.</li>    <li>Australia's efforts to regulate social media companies have faced challenges, including X's disregard for a fine imposed for failing to adequately address child pornography.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>澳大利亚eSafety委员会报告称，埃隆·马斯克的Twitter（X）已经解雇了1000多名负责打击有害内容的员工，导致平台上的毒性和仇恨言论激增。</li>    <li>委员会对被禁账号的恢复表示担忧，并强调社交媒体公司需要优先考虑用户安全。</li>    <li>澳大利亚的《在线安全法》促成了对X的安全人员的详细数据收集，结果显示致力于解决信任和安全问题的人员大幅减少。</li>    <li>专员朱莉·英曼·格兰特将这种情况比作沃尔沃解雇其安全工程师，强调对平台安全产生了不利影响。</li>    <li>澳大利亚监管社交媒体公司的努力面临挑战，包括X无视因未能充分解决儿童色情内容而被处以的罚款。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>curb (v.) - /kɜːb/ 限制，遏制，约束。    <p>原文例句：Tech group with TikTok and Meta sues Ohio over law curbing children’s social media use    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，意为“束缚，限制”。在这个例句中，它指的是一项法律限制儿童使用社交媒体的尝试。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>eradicate (v.) - /ɪˈrædɪkeɪt/ 消除，根除。    <p>原文例句：You’ve got a perfect storm. You’re drastically decreasing your defences, and you’re introducing repeat offenders back onto the platform.”Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing tech companies to outline how they are tackling issues such as hate speech and child sexual abuse.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由e-（彻底），radere（刮擦，移除）和-ate（使……成为）构成，意为“彻底移除，根除”。在这个例句中，它指的是减少安全人员对平台安全的影响。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take action - 采取行动    <P>原文例句：Australia’s eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content.    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，取）和action（行为，动作）构成的，表示“采取行动”。在这个例句中，它指的是澳大利亚eSafety委员会所说的“大幅削减”和恢复数千个被禁账号导致了有害内容传播的“完美风暴”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Australia’s eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content. - 澳大利亚eSafety委员会表示，这些“大幅削减”以及数千个被禁账号的恢复为有害内容的传播创造了“完美风暴”。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Australia’s eSafety Commission said，其中主语是Australia’s eSafety Commission，谓语是said，宾语是“deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content。。these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts是一个主语从句，修饰Australia’s eSafety Commission，表示澳大利亚eSafety委员会所说的“大幅削减”和恢复数千个被禁账号。created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content.是一个结果状语从句，表示导致了有害内容传播的“完美风暴”。这个句子的意思是说，澳大利亚eSafety委员会表示，这些“大幅削减”以及数千个被禁账号的恢复为有害内容的传播创造了“完美风暴”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The regulator has in recent months zeroed in on X – formerly known as Twitter – previously saying Musk’s takeover coincided with a spike in “toxicity and hate” on the platform.    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it has zeroed in on X – formerly known as Twitter – previously saying Musk’s takeover coincided with a spike in “toxicity and hate” on the platform.表示监管机构最近几个月一直关注X（以前称为Twitter），此前曾表示马斯克的收购与平台上“毒性和仇恨”的激增相吻合。这种时态强调了监管机构对X的持续关注以及马斯克收购以来平台上“毒性和仇恨”的持续存在。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气（虚拟条件句） - 用于表达虚拟或假设的情况。    <p>原文例句：But attempts to exercise these powers have occasionally been met with indifference. In October last year, the eSafety Commission slapped X with an A$610,500 (US$388,000) fine, saying it had failed to show how it was cracking down on child pornography.    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气（虚拟条件句）用于表达虚拟或假设的情况，在从句中使用虚拟语气时，主句通常使用would或should。在这个例句中，But attempts to exercise these powers have occasionally been met with indifference.是一个虚拟条件句，主句是The regulator has in recent months zeroed in on X – formerly known as Twitter – previously saying Musk’s takeover coincided with a spike in “toxicity and hate” on the platform.。虚拟语气表示如果监管机构试图行使这些权力，可能会遇到漠不关心的情况。这种语法结构强调了监管机构行使权力时可能面临的挑战。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The eSafety Commission said the ‘deep cuts’ and reinstatement of banned accounts created a ‘perfect storm’ for the spread of harmful content</li>
<li>Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing firms to outline how they are tackling hate speech and child sexual abuse</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/194a6a33-50f8-40c7-89c1-765fdcb76853_d3339bb6.jpg" /><figcaption>In a photo illustration, the Twitter X logo is displayed on the screen of a smartphone. Photo: SOPA Images/Zuma Press/TNS</figcaption></figure><p>Elon Musk’s X has shed more than 1,000 staff globally from teams responsible for stopping abusive content online, according to new figures released Thursday by Australia’s online watchdog.</p><p>Australia’s eSafety Commission said these “deep cuts” and the reinstatement of thousands of banned accounts had created a “perfect storm” for the spread of harmful content.</p><p>The regulator has in recent months zeroed in on X – formerly known as Twitter – previously saying Musk’s takeover coincided with a spike in “toxicity and hate” on the platform.</p><p>Using Australia’s groundbreaking Online Safety Act, the eSafety Commission has obtained a detailed breakdown of software engineers, content moderators and other safety staff working at X.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247497/tech-trade-group-representing-tiktok-snapchat-and-meta-sues-ohio-over-states-new-law-limiting" title="">Tech group with TikTok and Meta sues Ohio over law curbing children’s social media use</a></h3><p>Commissioner Julie Inman Grant, a former Twitter employee, said it was the first time these figures had been made public.</p><p>They showed 1,213 specialist “trust and safety staff”, including contractors, had left X since it was acquired by Musk in October 2022.</p><p>This included 80 per cent of the software engineers focused on “trust and safety issues”, said Inman Grant.</p><p>“To take 80 per cent of these specialist engineers away, it would be like Volvo – known for its safety standards – eradicating all of their designers or engineers,” she told AFP.</p><p>“You’ve got a perfect storm. You’re drastically decreasing your defences, and you’re introducing repeat offenders back onto the platform.”</p><p>Australia has spearheaded the global push to regulate social media, forcing tech companies to outline how they are tackling issues such as hate speech and child sexual abuse.</p><p>But attempts to exercise these powers have occasionally been met with indifference. In October last year, the eSafety Commission slapped X with an A$610,500 (US$388,000) fine, saying it had failed to show how it was cracking down on child pornography.</p><p>But X ignored the deadline to pay the fine, before launching ongoing legal action to have it overturned.</p><p>X did not reply to AFP’s request for comment, instead sending an automated response that read “busy now, please check back later”.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Huawei ends US lobbying operations after years of fighting ban</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3248018/huawei-ends-us-lobbying-operations-after-years-fighting-ban</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  After lobbying for years in the US and spending tens of millions of dollars in an attempt to gain favor with US policymakers, Huawei has shut down its lobbying operations in Washington.  The company's lobbyists have departed and Huawei has ended its lobbying efforts at the Capitol. This marks the end of Huawei's long-time efforts to maintain a presence in the US market, which spanned over a decade and was hindered by Washington's warnings about espionage and the government's eventual ban on the company's products and technology access. Despite the ban, Huawei has recently released a new phone utilizing advanced technology and reported a revenue increase in 2023.   <ul>    <li>Abstract: Huawei closes its lobbying operations in Washington, signaling the end of its efforts to influence US policymakers.</li>    <li>Theme: Huawei's lobbying efforts in the US come to an end after years of trying to maintain a presence in the North American market.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The effectiveness of lobbying efforts by companies in influencing policy decisions; the impact of government actions on businesses.</li>    <li>Main information: Shutdown of Huawei's in-house lobbying operations; departure of lobbyists; Huawei's previous lobbying expenses; recent phone release and revenue growth.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  华为在美国游说多年，花费数千万美元试图赢得美国政策制定者的青睐后，如今已关闭其在华盛顿的游说业务。公司的游说者已经离开，华为也已终止其在国会山的游说努力。这标志着华为长期以来试图维持在美国市场的存在努力的结束，而这一努力跨越了十多年，并受到华盛顿有关间谍活动的警告以及政府最终禁止该公司的产品和技术获取的阻碍。尽管受到禁令，华为最近发布了一款采用先进技术的新手机，并报告称其 2023 年收入有所增长。  <ul>    <li>摘要：华为关闭其在华盛顿的游说业务，标志着其多年来试图影响美国政策制定者的努力的结束。</li>    <li>主题：华为在美国的游说努力在经过多年试图维持其在北美市场的存在后结束。</li>    <li>观点：公司游说努力对政策决策的影响力；政府行动对企业的冲击。</li>    <li>主要信息：华为内部游说业务的关闭；游说者的离开；华为先前的游说费用；最近发布的新手机和收入增长。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words：</h2>  <ul>    <li>departure (n.) - /dɪˈpɑːrtʃər/ 离开，出发。    <p>原文例句：The departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, after a years-long effort to maintain a presence in North America.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Departure是指离开或出发，是Depart的动词形式，Departure作为名词既可以表示离开，也可以表示出发。在这个例句中，它指的是华为关闭其在美国的游说业务，是华为在美国的存在努力的结束。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>lobbyist (n.) - /ˈlɑːbɪɪst/ 游说者。    <p>原文例句：Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists there – Jeff Hogg and Donald Morrissey – left in recent months, Bloomberg News found.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Lobbyist是指游说者，即受雇于公司或组织，负责向政府官员和立法者游说以影响政策和决策的人。在这个例句中，它指的是华为在美国的最后两位注册游说者，即杰夫·霍格和唐纳德·莫里西，他们在最近几个月离开了华为。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>presence (n.) - /ˈprɛzən(t)s/ 存在，出席。    <p>原文例句：The lobbyists’ recent departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, and marks a quiet end to the company’s costly, years-long effort to maintain presence in the North American market. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Presence是指存在或出席，是Present的动词形式，Presence作为名词既可以表示存在，也可以表示出席。在这个例句中，它指的是华为的存在或出席，即华为多年来一直努力维持其在北美市场的份额。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the past 10 years - 在过去的 10 年里。    <p>原文例句：The company spent more than US$13 million lobbying in the past 10 years, according to federal filings.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这句话的意思是根据联邦提交的文件，该公司在过去的 10 年中花费了超过 1300 万美元用于游说。In the past 10 years是一个时间状语，表示在过去的 10 年里。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Huawei Technologies, the Chinese wireless equipment maker that spent tens of millions of dollars trying to win over US policymakers only to eventually be blacklisted, has shuttered its in-house lobbying operations in Washington. -- 华为技术公司，这家中国无线设备制造商花费了数千万美元试图赢得美国政策制定者的青睐，但最终被列入黑名单，已关闭其在华盛顿的内部游说业务。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Huawei Technologies has shuttered its in-house lobbying operations in Washington，其中主语是Huawei Technologies，谓语是has shuttered，宾语是its in-house lobbying operations in Washington。that spent tens of millions of dollars trying to win over US policymakers only to eventually be blacklisted是一个定语从句，修饰Huawei Technologies，表示华为技术公司花费了数千万美元试图赢得美国政策制定者的青睐，但最终被列入黑名单。这个句子的意思是华为技术公司，这家中国无线设备制造商花费了数千万美元试图赢得美国政策制定者的青睐，但最终被列入黑名单，已关闭其在华盛顿的内部游说业务。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语 - 用作定语，表示事物或人的性质、特征，说明主语。    <p>原文例句：The Huawei logo is seen during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai, July 6, 2023.</p>    <p>语法讲解：seen是一个过去分词，during是一个介词，World Artificial Intelligence Conference是一个名词短语，Shanghai是一个专有名词，July 6, 2023是一个时间状语。这个过去分词短语seen during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai, July 6, 2023修饰名词The Huawei logo，表示华为的标志在2023年7月6日的世界人工智能大会期间被看到。这个句子的意思是华为的标志在2023年7月6日的世界人工智能大会期间被看到。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, after a years-long effort to maintain a presence in North America</li>
<li>At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/61065c57-e9bf-4bb0-a892-196dc21024cd_6e1ed843.jpg" /><figcaption>The Huawei logo is seen during the World Artificial Intelligence Conference in Shanghai, July 6, 2023. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Huawei Technologies, the Chinese wireless equipment maker that spent tens of millions of dollars trying to win over US policymakers only to eventually be blacklisted, has shuttered its in-house lobbying operations in Washington.</p><p>Huawei’s last two registered lobbyists there – Jeff Hogg and Donald Morrissey – left in recent months, Bloomberg News found. The Shenzhen, China-based firm did not respond to multiple requests for comment.</p><p>The lobbyists’ recent departures follow an exodus of staff from Huawei’s US operations, and marks a quiet end to the company’s costly, years-long effort to maintain presence in the North American market. The firm reached its peak by supplying small mobile firms across the US even as major carriers shunned it. Rising tensions with Beijing eventually all but banned it.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247159/apple-dominates-global-premium-smartphone-market-2023-huawei-gains-ground-back-its-new-5g-handsets" title="">Apple leads premium smartphone market in 2023, but Huawei gains ground with new 5G handsets</a></h3><p>More than a decade ago, Washington officials began warning of Huawei’s ability to embed spying capabilities in its gear, which was present in thousands of cell towers and other network equipment in the US. The company pushed back on those claims, saying its products posed no threat, but American regulators by 2022 had barred the company from selling products in the US and moved to starve it of access to cutting-edge technology.</p><p>At its height, Huawei had nine lobbying firms on its payroll and a small army of public relations representatives. Executives were known to regularly arrange briefings with congressional offices and major newsrooms. The company spent more than US$13 million lobbying in the past 10 years, according to federal filings.</p><p>In a single quarter of 2019, Huawei’s federal lobbying spending totaled US$1.8 million, a six-fold increase from the previous year. It spent US$3.6 million on lobbying in the US in 2021, according to the filings. Some of that went to glitzy parties populated by high-profile hired guns including veteran Democratic lobbyist Tony Podesta, who made US$1 million from Huawei that year, according to disclosures with the US Senate. Podesta said in a filing that his work for Huawei ended on December 30, 2022.</p><p>With a ban firmly in place and its US business scant, Huawei has little reason to keep burning through lobbying cash in Washington. “The US market isn’t a likely place for a breakthrough for Huawei in the near future,” said Chris Pereira, a former Huawei public relations executive and founder of the consultancy iMpact.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/e55aff24-0f6a-4156-9c60-9d12d7c1fc31_ac707f82.jpg" title="A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters" width="2000" /><figcaption>A customer checks a Huawei Mate 60 Pro smartphone displayed at a Huawei flagship store in Beijing, September 25, 2023. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure></div><p>Morrissey, who lobbied for both Huawei and Futurewei, confirmed in a LinkedIn message that he left the company in December. He said he is now the senior director of government affairs at the battery technology company Gotion. Hogg, who had served as Huawei’s head of government relations since 2020, left the company in November, according to his LinkedIn profile. He did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p>The company has lost outside lobbying firms as well. Imperium Global Advisors and LeMunyon Group terminated their contracts with Futurewei, Huawei’s US-based research arm, in November 2023, according to filings with the Senate. And Squire Patton Boggs, a global law firm, has not reported lobbying activity to Congress on Futurewei’s behalf since the beginning of 2023. Former US Representative Lee Terry, Republican of Nebraska, terminated his lobbying contract with Huawei at the end of 2022. according to filings with the Senate.</p><p>By October, the only firm registered as working on Huawei’s behalf was Sidley Austin, which did not respond to requests for comment.</p><p>Huawei itself has filed its own notice that it was terminating lobbying efforts at the Capitol. The company has also ceased operations at offices in Plano, Texas, Trey Smith, executive vice-president at CBRE, a real estate services firm that handles leases for the building, said in an email.</p><p>In response to Huawei’s ban, China’s government has accused the US of abusing state power to hobble Chinese companies. Huawei in recent months offered its own de facto response, producing a new phone using highly advanced technology the US has been trying to keep out of China’s hands. The company says revenue surged 9 per cent in 2023, in part thanks to the new phone.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s Taobao and Tmall Group pushes new AI tools to boost merchants’ service to consumers in first major move after leadership reshuffle</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247985/alibabas-taobao-and-tmall-group-pushes-new-ai-tools-boost-merchants-service-consumers-first-major</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  淘宝和天猫集团的AI计划旨在帮助商家提升服务质量，吸引新客户。预计到6月，所有淘宝和天猫卖家都将可以使用AI升级的客服聊天机器人店小蜜。淘宝和天猫集团的人工智能工具的应用，显示了阿里巴巴集团旗下的部门为了抵御中国电商市场日益激烈的竞争所做出的努力。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Alibaba Group's main e-commerce unit tests AI tools to enhance seller services.</li>    <li>Theme: Taobao and Tmall Group implements AI features to improve customer interaction, attract buyers, and fend off competition.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: AI technology as a response to rising competition in China's e-commerce market.</li>    <li>Main information: Introduction of the AI-powered chatbot Dianxiaomi; improved seller-consumer interaction; increased exposure for quality merchants; statistics showing the advantages of high seller ratings; plan to launch a new rating system focusing on consumer services.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  淘宝和天猫集团的人工智能倡议旨在帮助商家改善服务并吸引新客户。预计所有淘宝和天猫卖家都将在 6 月之前可以使用人工智能升级的客服聊天机器人店小蜜。淘宝和天猫集团采用人工智能工具表明阿里巴巴集团控股部门正在努力抵御中国电子商务市场日益激烈的竞争。  <ul>    <li>摘要：阿里巴巴集团主要电子商务部门测试人工智能工具以增强卖家服务。</li>    <li>主题：淘宝和天猫集团实施人工智能功能以改善客户互动，吸引买家并抵御竞争。</li>    <li>观点：人工智能技术作为应对中国电子商务市场竞争加剧的回应。</li>    <li>主要信息：推出人工智能驱动的聊天机器人店小蜜；改进卖家与消费者的互动；增加优质商家的曝光度；统计数据显示高卖家评级的优势；计划推出专注于消费者服务的新的评级系统。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>repurchase (v.) - /riːˈpɜːrtʃəs/ 回购，再购买。    <p>原文例句：The repurchase rate at five-star pet supply stores, for example, is about 127 per cent higher than those of 3-star peers.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由re-（重新）和purchase（购买）组成的，表示“再次购买”。在这个例句中，它表示五星级宠物用品商店的回购率比三星级商店高出约127%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>intervention (n.) - /ˌɪntərˈvɛnʃən/ 干预，介入。    <p>原文例句：These indicators include the “rejection rate of refund request” and “platform intervention rate”, which weigh on consumers’ purchasing decisions.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由inter-（之间）和vention（来临，发生）组成的，表示“干预，介入”。在这个例句中，它指的是平台的干预率，是消费者在做出购买决定时会考虑的因素之一。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>client-facing (adj.) - 面向客户，面向用户的。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba.com in November announced a new AI tool to help the platform’s merchants automate their client-facing operations, including writing emails, to entice more customers overseas.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由client（客户）和facing（面对的）组成，表示“面向客户，面向用户的”。在这个例句中，它描述了阿里巴巴国际站推出的新的人工智能工具，该工具可以帮助平台的商家自动化与客户相关的工作，包括写邮件，以吸引更多海外客户。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>五星级宠物用品商店的回购率比三星级商店高出约127%。 - The repurchase rate at five-star pet supply stores, for example, is about 127 per cent higher than those of 3-star peers.<p>句子分析：这是一个比较句，主句是五星级宠物用品商店的回购率比三星级商店高出约127%，其中主语是五星级宠物用品商店的回购率，谓语是高出约127%。三星级商店是比较对象，高出约127%是比较结果。这个句子的意思是说，五星级宠物用品商店的回购率比三星级商店高出约127%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示现在正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company is now beta testing artificial intelligence (AI) tools and functions for merchants on its Chinese online shopping sites.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，结构是：am/is/are + 现在分词。其中am/is/are要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态现在正在进行。在这个例句中，it is now beta testing表示这家公司现在正在测试人工智能工具和功能。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Taobao and Tmall Group’s AI initiative is geared towards helping merchants improve their services and attract new customers</li>
<li>An AI-upgraded customer service chatbot, Dianxiaomi, is expected to be available to all Taobao and Tmall sellers by June</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/a64d09cb-4f09-4901-b140-db8cdc3ed1d4_a2cf7620.jpg" /><figcaption>Taobao and Tmall Group’s adoption of artificial intelligence tools shows the Alibaba Group Holding unit’s effort to fend off increased competition in China’s e-commerce market. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>’s main <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> unit is now beta testing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">artificial intelligence</a> (AI) tools and functions for merchants on its Chinese online shopping sites, marking the first major move at the enterprise since <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245680/alibaba-names-new-taobao-and-tmall-ceo-major-move-fend-competition" target="_self" title="">a leadership reshuffle in December</a>.</p><p>The Taobao and Tmall Group (TTG) unveiled the new AI features, which are designed to improve services and attract new customers, at its “sellers’ conference” held on Tuesday in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hangzhou" target="_self" title="">Hangzhou</a>, capital of eastern Zhejiang province and home base of South China Morning Post owner Alibaba.</p><p>TTG said AI models would be employed to transform Dianxiaomi, a customer service chatbot, to enhance seller-consumer interaction. That will include tasks such as pre- and post-sales service, data analysis and other online sales activities.</p><p>The updated Dianxiaomi, which is currently undergoing tests with a select group of sellers, will be made available to all merchants by June, according to TTG. It said the accuracy rate of Dianxiaomi’s response time has so far improved to 85 per cent.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/342c70b0-1832-40c4-bff8-11fa840de980_6cb4cf92.jpg" title="The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>The Tmall app is a popular marketplace for international and major Chinese businesses to sell brand-name goods to domestic consumers. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>TTG also vowed to provide “quality merchants” more exposure to consumers, from the homepage to advertised search results, TTG announced at the event.</p><p>TTG’s adoption of AI tools shows the effort being made by the Alibaba unit to fend off increased competition from main domestic rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> and the challenge from younger platforms, such as PDD Holdings’ <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/pinduoduo" target="_self" title="">Pinduoduo</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bytedance" target="_self" title="">ByteDance</a>-owned <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3220886/tiktoks-sister-app-douyin-says-gmv-e-commerce-business-grew-80-cent-last-year" target="_self" title="">Douyin</a>.</p><p>The move comes weeks after <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245680/alibaba-names-new-taobao-and-tmall-ceo-major-move-fend-competition" target="_self" title="">Eddie Wu Yongming</a> was named the new chief executive at TTG, replacing Trudy Dai Shan. TTG subsequently <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246060/alibaba-promotes-millennials-key-e-commerce-leadership-roles-it-repositions-fend-rivals" target="_self" title="">promoted six millennial executives</a> to lead key departments.</p><p>Before TTG’s latest initiative, Alibaba’s international business-to-business wholesale marketplace <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" target="_self" title="">Alibaba.com in November announced a new AI tool</a> to help the platform’s merchants automate their client-facing operations, including writing emails, to entice more customers overseas.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3243395/alibaba-pushes-new-ai-software-tool-help-merchants-its-wholesale-platform-manage-overseas-clients" title="">Alibaba pushes new AI tool to help wholesale merchants manage overseas clients</a></h3><p>At the seller’s event in Hangzhou, TTG said internal statistics showed that five-star-rated sellers enjoy a significantly higher repurchase rate than certain 3-star stores on its platform. The repurchase rate at five-star pet supply stores, for example, is about 127 per cent higher than those of 3-star peers.</p><p>TTG on Tuesday also said it will launch a new rating system for online shops, focusing on indicators related to consumer services. These indicators include the “rejection rate of refund request” and “platform intervention rate”, which weigh on consumers’ purchasing decisions.</p><p>Late in December, both JD.com and Taobao said they will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246559/chinese-e-commerce-firms-jdcom-and-alibabas-taobao-roll-out-refund-only-policy-shoppers-heating" target="_self" title="">offer a “refund only” policy</a> so consumers can keep the goods they had bought but complained about – matching an option that budget online retailer Pinduoduo has had in place since 2021.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>US regulator SEC authorises bitcoin-spot ETFs in cryptocurrency breakthrough</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3248009/us-regulator-sec-authorises-bitcoin-spot-etfs-cryptocurrency-breakthrough</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  SEC首次批准直接投资于比特币的交易所交易基金(ETF)，标志着加密资产行业的一个里程碑。在美国监管机构最终允许投资者将其传统经纪账户中的代币敞口多样化后，比特币价格上涨了3.4%，至47,500美元。该决定是在SEC反对超过十年的反对之后做出的，SEC主席加里·詹斯勒警告投资者警惕与比特币相关的风险。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: SEC approves bitcoin ETFs, marking a milestone for the crypto industry.</li>    <li>Theme: Bitcoin ETFs are approved by the SEC, allowing investors to diversify their portfolios with crypto exposure.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The approval of bitcoin ETFs is a positive step for the crypto industry and brings it closer to the regulated world of traditional finance.</li>    <li>Main information: SEC's approval of bitcoin ETFs; skepticism from SEC Chair Gary Gensler; arguments for and against bitcoin ETFs; impact of the approval on the crypto industry.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  SEC首次批准直接投资比特币的交易所交易基金（ETF），标志着加密资产行业的一个里程碑。在美国监管机构最终允许投资者将其传统经纪账户中的代币敞口多样化后，比特币价格上涨了3.4%，至47,500美元。该决定是在SEC反对超过十年的反对之后做出的，SEC主席加里·詹斯勒警告投资者警惕与比特币相关的风险。  <ul>    <li>摘要：SEC批准比特币ETF，标志着加密货币行业的一个里程碑。</li>    <li>主题：SEC批准比特币ETF，允许投资者通过其传统经纪账户投资比特币。</li>    <li>观点：比特币ETF的批准对加密货币行业来说是积极的一步，使之更接近受监管的传统金融世界。</li>    <li>主要信息：SEC批准比特币ETF；SEC主席加里·詹斯勒的质疑；比特币ETF的支持和反对意见；批准对加密货币行业的影响。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>surveillance (n.) - /sərˈveɪləns/ 监管，监视。    <p>原文例句：Because the CME’s surveillance can assist in detecting those impacts on CME bitcoin futures prices, the exchanges’ comprehensive surveillance-sharing agreement with the CME – a US regulated market whose bitcoin futures market is consistently highly correlated to spot bitcoin, albeit not of ‘significant size’ related to spot bitcoin – can be reasonably expected to assist in surveilling for fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices in the specific context of the proposals,” the order said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语sur（在……上）和veiller（监视），意为“监视，监管”。在这个例句中，它指的是CME对比特币期货价格的监管，即CME通过监视比特币期货价格来检测欺诈和操纵行为。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>scrutiny (n.) - /ˈskruːtɪni/ 审查，检验。    <p>原文例句：It also suggests a sort of milestone of maturity for the relatively nascent industry, where skirmishes with regulators came to a climax after the collapse of Sam Bankman-Fried’s FTX empire highlighted risks lurking in the industry.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于拉丁语scrutari（仔细搜寻），意为“仔细搜寻，审查，检验”。在这个例句中，它指的是监管机构对加密货币行业的审查，即监管机构对加密货币行业进行仔细审查，以发现其中的风险。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>at the crux of - 在……的中心。    <P>原文例句：At the crux of the SEC’s previous rulings against a spot ETF was the argument that no regulated exchange was able to adequately monitor bitcoin trading in a way that would reliably detect fraud and manipulation. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由at（在），the crux（中心，核心）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“在……的中心，在……的核心”。在这个例句中，它表示SEC之前针对现货ETF的裁决的核心是，没有一个受监管的交易所能够充分监管比特币交易，以便可靠地检测欺诈和操纵行为。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>in the context of - 在……的背景下。    <P>原文例句：“Because the CME’s surveillance can assist in detecting those impacts on CME bitcoin futures prices, the exchanges’ comprehensive surveillance-sharing agreement with the CME – a US regulated market whose bitcoin futures market is consistently highly correlated to spot bitcoin, albeit not of ‘significant size’ related to spot bitcoin – can be reasonably expected to assist in surveilling for fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices in the specific context of the proposals,” the order said. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在），the context（背景，语境）和of（属于，关于）构成的，表示“在……的背景下，在……的语境中”。在这个例句中，它表示CME的监管可以帮助检测CME比特币期货价格受到的影响，交易所与CME的全面监管共享协议——一个受美国监管的市场，其比特币期货市场与现货比特币始终高度相关，尽管与现货比特币相关的“规模不大”——可以合理地预期，在提案的具体背景下，有助于监视欺诈和操纵行为和做法。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade - 批准标志着SEC罕见的让步，此前反对持续了十多年。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC，其中主语是The approvals，谓语是mark，宾语是a rare capitulation by the SEC。following opposition that lasted for more than a decade是一个现在分词短语作状语，表示在持续了十多年的反对之后。这个句子的意思是说，批准标志着SEC罕见的让步，此前反对持续了十多年。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作定语 - 用于修饰名词或代词，表示该名词或代词所指的事物或人的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个过去分词短语，由过去分词claimed和介词after构成，表示在SEC的X账户上发布的虚假帖子声称该机构已经批准了ETF之后的一天做出的决定。在这个例句中，它修饰名词decision，表示该决定是在SEC的X账户上发布的虚假帖子声称该机构已经批准了ETF之后的一天做出的。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在分词短语作状语 - 用于修饰动词、形容词或其他副词，表示动作或状态的发生时间、原因、条件、方式等。    <p>原文例句：Following opposition that lasted for more than a decade, the SEC approved bitcoin ETFs for the first time.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在分词短语，由现在分词following和介词for构成，表示在持续了十多年的反对之后。在这个例句中，它修饰动词approved，表示在持续了十多年的反对之后，SEC首次批准了比特币ETF。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The approvals mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade</li>
<li>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/df6929be-b19f-4119-85e5-a531ae26273d_52ea2e34.jpg" /><figcaption>A bitcoin is seen in an illustration picture taken in Paris, France, June 23, 2017. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>US regulators for the first time approved exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that invest directly in bitcoin, a move heralded as a landmark event for the roughly US$1.7 trillion digital-asset sector that will broaden access to the largest cryptocurrency on Wall Street and beyond.</p><p>The Securities and Exchange Commission, whose three-part mandate includes investor protection, authorised funds from industry heavyweights BlackRock, Invesco and Fidelity to smaller competitors including Valkyrie to begin trading Thursday.</p><p>The approvals also mark a rare capitulation by the SEC following opposition that lasted for more than a decade, ever since Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss first proposed a bitcoin ETF in 2013. BlackRock’s surprise application last June, followed by an appeals court ruling that called the denial of a different application “arbitrary and capricious,” triggered a blistering rally in the cryptocurrency as speculation that US regulators would finally give their blessing to the structure.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239953/hong-kongs-hashkey-launches-first-crypto-trading-app-retail-investors-gives-away-new-token" title="">Hong Kong gets first crypto trading app for retail investors</a></h3><p>“While we approved the listing and trading of certain spot bitcoin ETP shares today, we did not approve or endorse bitcoin,” SEC Chair Gary Gensler said in a statement. “Investors should remain cautious about the myriad risks associated with bitcoin and products whose value is tied to crypto.”</p><p>At the crux of the SEC’s previous rulings against a spot ETF was the argument that no regulated exchange was able to adequately monitor bitcoin trading in a way that would reliably detect fraud and manipulation. That contention was opposed by Cathie Wood’s Ark Investments, among others, which provided data showing a high correlation between cash trading and the futures contracts that trade on CME Group’s platform.</p><p>In reviewing the latest set of proposals, the SEC said it examined the correlation between spot and futures trading at a variety of time intervals and concluded prices moved in such a way that irregularities on exchanges such as Kraken and Coinbase were likely to show up in the futures.</p><p>“Because the CME’s surveillance can assist in detecting those impacts on CME bitcoin futures prices, the exchanges’ comprehensive surveillance-sharing agreement with the CME – a US regulated market whose bitcoin futures market is consistently highly correlated to spot bitcoin, albeit not of ‘significant size’ related to spot bitcoin – can be reasonably expected to assist in surveilling for fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices in the specific context of the proposals,” the order said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3246909/crypto-services-firm-linked-huobi-sees-losses-expand-40-cent-ftx-funds-still-out-reach" title="">Losses mount at Huobi-linked crypto firm while FTX funds still out of reach</a></h3><p>The decision comes a day after a false post on the SEC’s X account claimed that the agency had approved the ETFs. The regulator subsequently said that the account had been compromised, causing the price of bitcoin to fluctuate widely.</p><p>Gensler voted along side the agency’s two Republicans to back exchanges’ plans to list the products, the SEC’s website showed. The regulator’s two other Democrats voted against the proposals.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/11/9a0bebf2-048a-459e-9a2e-2dd720360177_a66cec46.jpg" title="The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>The US Securities and Exchange Commission headquarters in Washington, January 10, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Bitcoin rose about 3.4 per cent to US$47,500 following the approvals. The original cryptocurrency, which sank 64 per cent in 2022, more than doubled in 2023 in large part because of speculation that the SEC would eventually approve ETFs that will allow investors to get exposure to the token in their traditional brokerage accounts instead of one of the crypto-native start-ups that have come under increasing government scrutiny following a series of sector scandals and bankruptcies.</p><p>“The approval means that both retail and institutional investors now have the ability to diversify their portfolio with crypto exposure without worrying about the complicated issues of custody,” said Campbell Harvey, finance professor at Duke University. “The ETF makes it easy to add to your portfolio.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3246538/china-calls-tougher-crackdown-use-crypto-illegal-forex-trading" title="">China calls for tougher crackdown on use of crypto for illegal forex trading</a></h3><p>Crypto proponents have for years argued that a so-called spot fund that invests directly in bitcoin would be beneficial to investors and would help bring the industry closer to the more highly regulated world of traditional finance. It also suggests a sort of milestone of maturity for the relatively nascent industry, where skirmishes with regulators came to a climax after the collapse of Sam Bankman-Fried’s FTX empire highlighted risks lurking in the industry.</p><p>The landmark decision comes after Grayscale Investments won a key victory over the SEC. A federal appeals court had overturned the rejection of Grayscale’s application to convert its bitcoin trust into an ETF. The court called the denial “arbitrary and capricious” because the commission failed to explain its different treatment of similar products. ETFs that hold bitcoin futures were approved in 2021.</p><p>The SEC’s loss to Grayscale was one of the reasons why the SEC approved the applications, Gensler said in Tuesday’s statement.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China rich list compiler Hurun clarifies Tsinghua graduate Zhang Zetian’s ranking to quell online controversy</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247956/china-rich-list-compiler-hurun-clarifies-tsinghua-graduate-zhang-zetians-ranking-quell-online</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  Hurun Research Institute clarified that Zhang Zetian, wife of tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, is listed as the third-richest graduate of Tsinghua University on its rich list. However, netizens questioned Zhang's actual wealth, prompting the institute to explain that her 60 billion yuan net worth includes her husband's assets. The controversy highlights the growing scrutiny of personal wealth inequality in China. Tsinghua and Zhejiang universities produced the most billionaire graduates, followed by Peking, Shanghai Jiao Tong, and Wuhan universities. Notably, Zhang's marriage to Liu differs from the low-profile approach common among Chinese tech billionaires. Overall, the Hurun list covers graduates from 58 universities, including overseas institutions.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Tsinghua and Zhejiang universities produce numerous billionaire graduates; Zhang Zetian's wealth questioned, leading to clarification from Hurun.</li>    <li>Theme: Scrutiny of personal wealth in China; Unveiling the "most successful" alumni from elite universities.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: Institutions' role in shaping successful entrepreneurs; contrasting approaches to wealth and family life among Chinese tech billionaires.</li>    <li>Main information: Hurun's methodology and clarification on Zhang's wealth; controversy surrounding wealth inequality; ranking of universities with the most alumni on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  胡润研究院针对引发争议的富豪榜单对张泽天财富排名进行了澄清，表示将张泽天列为清华大学毕业生中第三大富豪，是因为她的600亿资产属于夫妻共同财产。这一事件凸显了公众对中国个人财富不平等问题的关注。清华大学和浙江大学培养的亿万富豪毕业生数量位居榜首，其次是北京大学、上海交通大学和武汉大学。值得注意的是，张泽天与刘强东的结合在注重低调的中国科技富豪中并不常见。此次胡润榜单涵盖了包括海外院校在内的58所大学的毕业生。  <ul>    <li>摘要：清华、浙大两所高校培养出众多亿万富豪；张泽天财富引质疑，胡润研究院做出澄清说明。</li>    <li>主题：中国个人财富受关注；揭秘名校“最成功的”校友。</li>    <li>观点：高校对培养成功企业家的作用；中国科技富豪对财富和家庭的不同态度。</li>    <li>主要信息：胡润研究院对张泽天财富的说明和解释；围绕贫富差距引发的争议；2023胡润中国富豪榜单上拥有最多校友的高校排名。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>netizen (n.) - /ˈnet.ɪ.zən/ 网民，上网者。    <p>原文例句：However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由net（网络）和citizen（公民）构成的，表示“网民，上网者”。在这个例句中，它指的是许多中国网民在社交媒体平台上质疑张泽天是否真的拥有如此巨大的财富。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>controversy (n.) - /ˈkɑːn.trə.vɜːrsi/ 争议，争论。    <p>原文例句：The controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由controvert（争论，辩论）构成的，表示“争议，争论”。在这个例句中，它指的是在公众对中国个人财富和收入不平等问题的关注加剧的情况下，引发了争议。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>profile (n.) - /ˈproʊ.faɪl/ 概况，简介。    <p>原文例句：Liu’s celebrity-style marriage to Zhang is also rare among Chinese tech billionaires, with many maintaining a low profile when it comes to family matters.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由pro（向前）和file（文件）构成的，表示“概况，简介”。在这个例句中，它指的是刘强东与张泽天的明星式婚姻在中国科技富豪中也很少见，许多人在家庭问题上保持低调。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>stir controversy - 引起争议。    <p>原文例句：Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.</p>    <p>例句讲解：stir controversy是一个动词词组，表示“引起争议”。在这个例句中，它指的是在将张泽天列为清华大学毕业生中第三大富豪后，胡润研究院澄清了其决定，因为这一排名在网上引起了争议。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>come from - 来自。    <p>原文例句：Robin Li Yanhong, founder, chairman and CEO of Baidu, and Xiaomi chairman and CEO Lei Jun are two of the most high-profile and richest graduates to have come from Peking University and Wuhan University, respectively, according to the list.</p>    <p>例句讲解：come from是一个动词词组，表示“来自”。在这个例句中，它指的是根据这份名单，李彦宏和雷军是分别来自北京大学和武汉大学的知名度最高、最富有的毕业生。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online. - 胡润研究院，一个由鲁伯特·胡格沃夫运营的富豪榜单编制机构，已经澄清了将其列为中国科技亿万富豪刘强东的妻子张泽天，列为清华大学毕业生中第三大富豪的决定，因为这一排名在网上引起了争议。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，由主句和一个从句组成。主句是Hurun Research Institute has clarified，其中主语是Hurun Research Institute，谓语是has clarified，宾语是不定式to list Zhang Zetian... 。从句是after the ranking stirred controversy online，其中主语是the ranking，谓语是stirred controversy，宾语是online。这个句子的意思是，胡润研究院已经澄清了将其列为清华大学毕业生中的第三大富豪的决定，因为这一排名在网上引起了争议。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，“has clarified”表示出一个已经完成的动作，并且其影响一直持续到说话的时候。这种用法叫做现在完成时，表达了动作开始于过去某个时间，并且一直持续到现在的状态。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>不定式 - 表示一种动作或状态，没有时态变化。<p>原文例句：The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.</p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个句子中，“to list Zhang Zetian”表示一种动作，即“将张泽天列为第三位”。不定式没有时态变化，它可以用作主语、宾语、表语或状语。在这个句子中，不定式用作宾语，修饰动词“has clarified”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>According to Hurun, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China</li>
<li>Zhang ranked behind Meituan founder Wang Xing and Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/22f80ee8-51eb-4f11-94d0-38c9096e305d_32c40a21.jpg" /><figcaption>JD.com chairman Richard Liu Qiangdong and wife Zhang Zetian at Princess Eugenie’s wedding. Photo: YouTube </figcaption></figure><p>The Hurun Research Institute, a rich list compiler run by Rupert Hoogewerf, has clarified its decision to list Zhang Zetian, wife of Chinese tech billionaire Richard Liu Qiangdong, as the third-richest person to have graduated from the prestigious Tsinghua University after the ranking stirred controversy online.</p><p>According to a list published by Hurun last Friday, Tsinghua University and Zhejiang University have produced the most graduates to become billionaires in China. And 30-year-old Zhang was ranked as the third-richest graduate from Tsinghua, with a net worth of 60 billion yuan (US$8.4 billion).</p><p>Zhang ranked behind 44-year-old Wang Xing, 44, founder of food delivery giant Meituan and 62-year-old Xu Hang, founder of property developer Parkland Group. However, many Chinese netizens questioned on social media platforms whether Zhang actually owns such massive wealth.</p><p>Hurun issued a statement on Monday to clarify its methodology for the ranking of rich Chinese alumni. “In the case of Tsinghua’s Zhang, her 60 billion yuan worth falls under her and [husband] Liu jointly.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3239156/chinese-tech-founders-bounce-back-huruns-2023-rich-list-number-and-overall-wealth-billionaires-drop" title="">Chinese tech billionaires move up Hurun 2023 Rich List amid internet rebound</a></h3><p>The controversy comes amid greater scrutiny of personal wealth and income inequality in China. According to a separate rich list published by Forbes in November 2023, the net worth of Liu, founder and chairman of e-commerce giant JD.com, was US$4.7 billion, ranking No. 69 in China’s top 100 rich list.</p><p>Liu’s celebrity-style marriage to Zhang is also rare among Chinese tech billionaires, with many maintaining a low profile when it comes to family matters.</p><p>The Tsinghua alumni rich list was part of a Hurun Most Successful University Alumni 2023 ranking the research firm released. Hurun defined the “most successful alumni” to include former full-time undergraduates, postgraduates and those entrepreneurs holding doctoral degrees on the Hurun China Rich List 2023.</p><p>A total of 58 universities, 45 Chinese and 13 overseas, have at least three alumni on the Hurun China Rich List 2023. Tsinghua and Zhejiang University topped the list, each with 32 alumni on the list.</p><p>Peking University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, and Wuhan University came in third, fourth and fifth with 22, 21, and 17 alumni respectively on the list.</p><p>Robin Li Yanhong, founder, chairman and CEO of Baidu, and Xiaomi chairman and CEO Lei Jun are two of the most high-profile and richest graduates to have come from Peking University and Wuhan University, respectively, according to the list.</p><p>Outside China, Stanford University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, University of California, Yale University and Harvard University from the US were the top five institutions with the most Hurun China Rich listers.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>China augmented reality start-up Rokid gets US$70 million in new funding round led by Hefei government</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247968/china-augmented-reality-start-rokid-gets-us70-million-new-funding-round-led-hefei-government</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Rokid, an augmented reality company, has secured 500 million yuan in its latest funding round, led by the municipal government of Hefei, capital of Anhui province. The investment aims to bolster Hefei's metaverse industry and promote regional development. Rokid will establish its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub, and R&D center in Hefei, tapping into the city's emerging micro-displays and metaverse ecosystem.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Hefei government's investment in Rokid supports the city's metaverse industry development.</li>    <li>Theme: Collaboration between Rokid and Hefei to advance the local metaverse industry.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The significance of government funding for tech start-ups; the mutual benefits of investment and cooperation agreements for both parties.</li>    <li>Main information: Rokid's funding amount; the establishment of Rokid's industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub, and R&D center in Hefei; Rokid's focus on cutting-edge R&D and user experience optimization.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  Rokid，一家增强现实公司，已在最新一轮融资中获得5亿元人民币，由安徽省省会合肥市政府领投。此次投资旨在支持合肥市的元宇宙产业发展，促进区域发展。Rokid将在合肥设立其产业元宇宙总部、生态中心和研发中心，依托合肥市新兴的微显示和元宇宙生态系统。    <ul>    <li>摘要：合肥政府投资Rokid支持城市元宇宙产业发展。</li>    <li>主题：Rokid与合肥合作推进当地元宇宙产业发展。</li>    <li>观点：政府资助科技初创企业的重要性；投资合作协议对双方互惠互利。</li>    <li>主要信息：Rokid融资金额；Rokid在合肥建立产业元宇宙总部、生态中心和研发中心；Rokid专注于前沿研发和用户体验优化。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>augmented reality (n.) - /ɔːɡˈmɛntid riːˈælɪti/ 增强现实，AR。    <p>原文例句：Chinese augmented reality (AR) technology firm Rokid has raised nearly half a billion yuan in its latest round of funding led by a local Chinese government, in a fresh indication of the backing from authorities for tech start-ups.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“augmented reality”是“augment（增加）”和“reality（现实）”的组合，意思是通过计算机技术将虚拟信息叠加到真实世界，从而产生一种虚实结合的感知体验。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>metaverse (n.) - /ˈmɛtəvɜːrs/ 元宇宙。    <p>原文例句：Rokid said in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor. As part of the deal, Rokid signed an investment and cooperation agreement with Hefei to advance the local metaverse industry.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“metaverse”是“meta（超越）”和“universe（宇宙）”的组合，意思是超越现实世界的虚拟世界，它是将现实世界和虚拟世界融合在一起的集合体，包括计算机技术、虚拟现实、增强现实等。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>ecosystem (n.) - /ˈiːkəʊsɪstəm/ 生态系统，生态圈。    <p>原文例句：Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and research and development (R&D) centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone, tapping into the Chinese city’s emerging ecosystem including micro-displays, the metaverse and other areas.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“ecosystem”是指由生物体及其周围环境组成的复杂系统，包括生物体与环境之间的相互作用及其相互依存关系。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>micro-displays (n.) - /ˈmaɪkrəʊ dɪˈspleɪz/ 微显示器。    <p>原文例句：Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and research and development (R&D) centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone, tapping into the Chinese city’s emerging ecosystem including micro-displays, the metaverse and other areas.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“micro-displays”是指尺寸非常小的显示器，通常用于移动设备或可穿戴设备中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>latest funding round - 最新一轮融资。    <p>原文例句：Rokid said in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“latest funding round”是指最近一次融资活动。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>cutting-edge R&D - 前沿研发。    <p>原文例句：“We are honoured to contribute to advancements in science/technology … through our innovations,” said Misa Zhu, founder and CEO of Rokid, adding that the company will focus on cutting-edge R&D and user experience optimisation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“cutting-edge R&D”是指最先进的研究与开发活动。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>“We are honoured to contribute to advancements in science/technology … through our innovations,” said Misa Zhu, founder and CEO of Rokid, adding that the company will focus on cutting-edge R&D and user experience optimisation. - Rokid的创始人兼首席执行官朱 Misa 说：“我们很荣幸能够通过我们的创新为科学/技术的发展做出贡献。”他补充说，该公司将专注于前沿研发和用户体验优化。</p>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是“We are honoured to contribute to advancements in science/technology … through our innovations”，其中主语是“We”，谓语是“are honoured to contribute”，宾语是“to advancements in science/technology … through our innovations”。“adding that the company will focus on cutting-edge R&D and user experience optimisation”是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示Rokid公司将专注于前沿研发和用户体验优化。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>There be句型 - 用于表示存在或发生。    <p>原文例句：There are plenty of reasons to use Firefox as your primary browser. </p>    <p>语法讲解：There be句型由“There be + 主语 + 其他”构成，其中主语可以是名词、代词或不定式，其他部分可以是名词词组、形容词词组或句子。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>现在完成进行时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：现在完成进行时由“have/has been + 现在分词”构成，其中have/has根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词由动词的原型加-ing构成。现在完成进行时表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Rokid said it has raised 500 million yuan in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei as a lead investor</li>
<li>Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and R&amp;D centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/f677fbfd-346b-4b28-a3ab-89b2e076e79f_2f7ce20d.jpg" /><figcaption>Rokid Glass, augmented reality glasses, at the Rokid booth during CES 2018, Las Vegas. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese augmented reality (AR) technology firm Rokid has raised nearly half a billion yuan in its latest round of funding led by a local Chinese government, in a fresh indication of the backing from authorities for tech start-ups.</p><p>Rokid said in a statement on Wednesday that it has raised 500 million yuan (US$70 million) in its latest funding round with the municipal government of Hefei, capital of central Anhui province, as a lead investor. As part of the deal, Rokid signed an investment and cooperation agreement with Hefei to advance the local metaverse industry.</p><p>Chinese authorities have increasingly stepped up as private equity investors in projects in line with local development strategies. As a quid pro quo for funding, local governments generally require these start-ups to make local investments.</p><p>Under the Hefei deal, Rokid will set up its industrial metaverse headquarters, ecosystem hub and research and development (R&amp;D) centre in Hefei’s New Station Hi-Tech Zone, tapping into the Chinese city’s emerging ecosystem including micro-displays, the metaverse and other areas.</p><p>“We are honoured to contribute to advancements in science/technology … through our innovations,” said Misa Zhu, founder and CEO of Rokid, adding that the company will focus on cutting-edge R&amp;D and user experience optimisation.</p><p>“Looking ahead, we will maintain a focus on achieving technological milestones and enriching our ecosystem to empower developers and deliver superior products that benefit consumers and enterprises globally”, Zhu said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3233933/china-wants-metaverse-firms-global-influence-and-plans-five-industrial-clusters-2025" title="">China wants up to 5 metaverse companies with ‘global influence’ by 2025</a></h3><p>Hong Fan, chairman of Hefei New Venture Investment Control, an investment vehicle under the Hefei government, added that the cooperation aligns with Rokid and the city’s efforts to drive innovation on metaverse applications and technologies.</p><p>“The cooperation between Rokid and Hefei builds on a shared vision to cultivate extended reality [XR]/metaverse industry development, ” Hong said.</p><p>XR is an overarching term that includes AR, virtual reality, and mixed reality technologies that seek to combine or mirror the physical and digital worlds to allow consumers, equipped with XR equipment, to traverse between and interact with them.</p><p>Founded in 2014, Rokid has made AR equipment for a variety of consumer, travel, and industrial uses, counting companies such as the State Grid Corporation of China and home appliance giant Midea among its clients.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Can Beethoven, Bach and Mozart help iPhone sales in China? Apple to launch classical music app on mainland amid sluggish demand for its flagship produ...</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247961/can-beethoven-bach-and-mozart-help-iphone-sales-china-apple-launch-classical-music-app-mainland-amid</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div><h2>English Summary:</h2>Apple Music Classical app to debut in mainland China, expanding digital services in the world's largest smartphone market. The app offers over five million classical music tracks and is expected to boost Apple's major digital services business in China, which generates 51% of App Store revenue. However, iPhone sales in China have been declining due to weak consumption and strong competition from Chinese smartphone brands.<ul><li>Theme: Apple Music Classical app to launch in mainland China, boosting digital services in the world's largest smartphone market.</li><li>Viewpoint: The app's potential impact on Apple's revenue in China and the challenges it faces due to declining iPhone sales.</li><li>Main information: The app's launch date, availability in East Asian markets, China's contribution to App Store revenue, iPhone sales decline, and competitors' growth.</li></ul></div><div><h2>中文总结：</h2>Apple Music古典音乐应用程序将于明年1月24日在中国大陆首次亮相，面向全球最大智能手机市场扩展数字服务，该应用程序拥有超过500万首曲库，预计将提振苹果在中国的主要数字服务业务。 然而，由于消费疲软以及中国智能手机品牌的激烈竞争，苹果在中国的 iPhone 销量一直在下降。<ul><li>主题：Apple Music古典音乐应用程序在中国大陆首次亮相，在全球最大的智能手机市场扩展数字服务。</li><li>观点：该应用程序对苹果在中国收入的潜在影响及其面临的 iPhone 销量下降的挑战。</li><li>主要信息：该应用程序的发布日期、在东亚市场的发展以及中国对 App Store 收入的贡献、iPhone 销量下降以及竞争对手的增长。</li></ul></div><div><h2>单词：</h2><ul><li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrev.ə.njuː/ 收入，收益。<p>原文例句：China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. </p><p>例句讲解：revenue意为收入、收益，是通过销售商品或提供服务而获得的货币形式的收益。在这个例句中，它指的是中国在2022年为苹果App Store生态系统创造的收入，总额为5700亿美元，占总收入的51%。</p></li></ul><ul><li>decline (n.) - /dɪˈklaɪn/ 减少，衰退。<p>原文例句：iPhone sales on the mainland were down 30 per cent year year, according to a Jefferies research note published on Sunday. </p><p>例句讲解：decline意为减少、衰退，是经济、人口、健康状况等方面下降或恶化的过程。在这个例句中，它指的是iPhone在中国的销售额与去年相比下降了30%，表明了iPhone在中国市场面临的挑战。</p></li></ul>  </div><div><h2>词组：</h2><ul><li>in terms of - 就……而言，从……方面来说。<P>原文例句：China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. </P><p>例句讲解：In term of是一个常用的词组，意为就……而言，从……方面来说。在这个例句中，In terms of Apple’s App Store ecosystem指的是从苹果App Store生态系统这个角度而言。</p></li></ul><ul><li>in comparison - 相比之下。<P>原文例句：By comparison, the United States generated US$273 billion, or almost 25 per cent, of the App Store ecosystem’s overall billings and sales in 2022. </P><p>例句讲解：In comparison是一个常用的词组，意为相比之下。在这个例句中，In comparison指的是与中国相比。它是将中国与美国在App Store生态系统中的收入进行比较，突出中国在App Store生态系统中的主导地位。</p></li></ul></div><div><h2>句子：</h2><ul><li>The Apple Music Classical app, which was launched in most markets globally in March last year, will make its mainland debut on January 24. - Apple Music古典音乐应用程序将于去年3月在全球大多数市场推出，并将于1月24日在中国大陆首次亮相。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主语是The Apple Music Classical app，谓语是will make its mainland debut on January 24，宾语是its mainland debut。其中will make its mainland debut on January 24是一个将来时态，表示这一应用程序将于1月24日在中国大陆首次亮相。</p></li></ul></div><div><h2>语法：</h2><ul><li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。<p>原文例句：China had accounted for US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of the total US$1.1 trillion in billings and sales facilitated by the App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published on Apple’s website in May last year.</p><p>语法讲解：这是一个常见的时态，结构是：had + 过去分词。其中had要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，过去分词是动词的-ed形式或不规则变化形式。这种时态表示动作或状态在过去某个时间点之前已经完成，强调动作或状态的完成性。在这个例句中，它表示中国在2022年为App Store生态系统创造的收入为5700亿美元，占总收入的51%，表明了中国在App Store生态系统中的主导地位。</p></li></ul></div>  <ul><li>The Apple Music Classical app, which was launched in most markets globally in March last year, will make its mainland debut on January 24</li>
<li>On the same date, the app will also be available in five other East Asian markets that include Hong Kong, Macau, Taiwan, Japan and South Korea</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/5bfc68e8-e24d-446d-84dd-b98d8c4fe639_56cadcbe.jpg" /><figcaption>The Apple Music Classical app’s launch in China is likely to bolster the firm’s major digital services business in the country, which is its largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apple" target="_self" title="">Apple</a> will soon make its <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/classical-music" target="_self" title="">classical music</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">app</a> available in mainland China, expanding the US tech giant’s digital services offering in the world’s largest <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> market where sales of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/iphone" target="_self" title="">iPhone</a> are seeing a deepening decline.</p><p>The Apple Music Classical app, which was launched in most markets globally in March last year, will make its mainland debut on January 24, according to the company’s online China App Store. The app – touted by Apple as the world’s largest classical music catalogue, with more than five million tracks – can now be pre-ordered by iPhone users in the country.</p><p>On the same date, the stand-alone app will also be available in five other East Asian markets that include <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hong-kong" target="_self" title="">Hong Kong</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/macau-0" target="_self" title="">Macau</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/taiwan-0" target="_self" title="">Taiwan</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan" target="_self" title="">Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a>, according to a post on Tuesday by Apple on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/twitter-x" target="_self" title="">X, formerly Twitter</a>.</p><p>The app’s launch is likely to bolster Apple’s major digital services business in China, which remains the company’s largest market in terms of App Store-related revenue.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse" class="image-inline caption" height="1330" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/8163ba04-0fe9-402a-937d-975263f7c4ad_f67d3284.jpg" title="China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse" width="2000" /><figcaption>China generated US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of total billings and sales facilitated by Apple’s App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published in May 2023. Photo: Agence France-Presse</figcaption></figure></div><p>China accounted for US$570 billion, or 51 per cent, of the total US$1.1 trillion in billings and sales facilitated by the App Store ecosystem in 2022, according to a study by consulting firm Analysis Group that was published on Apple’s website in May last year.</p><p>By comparison, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> generated US$273 billion, or almost 25 per cent, of the App Store ecosystem’s overall billings and sales in 2022. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/europe" target="_self" title="">Europe</a> accounted for US$119 billion, or 11 per cent, of that year’s total.</p><p>Whether the classical music app’s local release would somehow help lift iPhone sales on the mainland remains to be seen, as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3247712/chinas-retail-sales-weaken-year-falling-home-prices-jobs-outlook-feed-consumer-insecurity-ubs" target="_self" title="">consumption remains weak</a> across the country and Apple faces stiff competition from major Chinese smartphone rivals.</p><p>In the first week of the year, iPhone sales on the mainland were down 30 per cent year on year, according to a Jefferies research note published on Sunday. The brokerage indicated that there was “a big rise in discounts” for the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3192215/apples-iphone-14-sees-surging-pre-orders-china-enthusiastic-consumers" target="_self" title="">iPhone 14</a> and 14 Plus models, while the newer <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/gadgets/article/3235981/apple-iphone-15-review-faster-cheaper-new-standard-models-are-big-jump-over-their-predecessors" target="_self" title="">iPhone 15</a> and 15 Plus models saw “a moderate rise” in discounts.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics" title="">Apple supplier Foxconn sees sales decline in first quarter of 2024 amid weak demand</a></h3><p>Chinese smartphone vendors, with <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/honor" target="_self" title="">Honor</a> leading the pack, had “much stronger” momentum during the period, with sales delivering “flattish growth” year on year, Jefferies analysts led by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/enterprises/article/2113581/chinas-chance-lead-global-innovation-may-lie-5g-mobile-technology" target="_self" title="">Edison Lee</a> wrote in the note.</p><p>The iPhone’s total sales volume last year on the mainland was down 3 per cent from 2022, which translated to a 0.4 per cent decline in Apple’s market share, according to Jefferies. It estimated that rival Huawei saw its mainland market share in the December quarter gain 2 per cent from the previous quarter, and 6 per cent year on year.</p><p>Apple is expected to see “even higher revenue pressure” on the mainland in 2024, according to Jefferies.</p><p>Still, Apple has continued to reassure investors even though iPhone sales have been slowing. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3240278/apples-ceo-cook-sees-china-bright-spot-after-record-iphone-sales-country-despite-overall-revenue" target="_self" title="">In the firm’s earnings call in November</a>, Apple chief executive <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tim-cook" target="_self" title="">Tim Cook</a> said: “Over the long term, I view China as an incredibly important market, and I’m very optimistic about it.”</p><p>Cook made two visits to the mainland last year, meeting senior government officials, Chinese developers and Apple’s contract manufacturing partners.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Foxconn pushes into electric vehicle production near its biggest iPhone plant amid slow smartphone sales</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247941/foxconn-pushes-electric-vehicle-production-near-its-biggest-iphone-plant-amid-slow-smartphone-sales</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Foxconn, a major Apple supplier, has established a new venture in Zhengzhou, China, focusing on the electric vehicle (EV) industry.</li>    <li>The new company, Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co., will manufacture and develop car components, produce motors, and sell NEVs.</li>    <li>Foxconn's move reflects its strategic shift toward the EV sector amid declining smartphone sales.</li>    <li>The company aims to leverage its expertise in consumer electronics and its vast supply chain network to succeed in the EV market.</li>    <li>Foxconn's investment in India for Apple product manufacturing further demonstrates its global expansion strategy.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>苹果供应商富士康在中国郑州成立新合资公司，重点发展电动汽车产业。</li>    <li>新公司“富士康新能源汽车产业发展（河南）有限公司”注册资本 5 亿元人民币，经营范围涉及汽车零部件的制造和研发、电机生产、新能源汽车销售等。</li>    <li>富士康此举是其在智能手机销量下滑的背景下，战略性地向电动汽车领域转型。</li>    <li>富士康希望利用其在消费电子领域的专业知识和庞大的供应链网络，在电动汽车市场取得成功。</li>    <li>富士康在印度投资建设苹果产品制造工厂，进一步表明了其全球化扩张战略。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>venture (n.) - /ˈventʃər/ 风险事业，冒险事业。    <p>原文例句：Foxconn Technology Group has set up a new car venture in Zhengzhou city, capital of central China’s Henan province and home to the world’s largest iPhone factory, as the Apple supplier steps up its efforts in the new energy vehicle (NEV) sector amid declining smartphone sales.</p>    <p>例句讲解：venture 这个单词来源于venture （冒险、投机），意思是“冒险事业，冒险事业”。在这个例句中，它指的是富士康在郑州成立的新汽车合资公司，旨在进军电动汽车领域。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>accelerate (v.) - /əkˈselərˌeɪt/ 加速，使加速。    <p>原文例句：The world’s largest contract electronics manufacturer is accelerating its move into the automobile industry amid weakening demand for smartphones and consumer gadgets.</p>    <p>例句讲解：accelerate 这个单词来源于accelerate （加速），意思是“加速，使加速”。在这个例句中，它指的是富士康在智能手机和消费电子产品需求疲软的情况下，加快了向汽车行业的转型。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>strategic shift - 战略性转变    <P>原文例句：Foxconn's move reflects its strategic shift toward the EV sector amid declining smartphone sales.</p>    <p>例句讲解：strategic shift 这个词组的意思是“战略性转变”。在这个例句中，它指的是富士康在智能手机销量下滑的背景下，向电动汽车领域转型。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company, which was put under a tax and land use investigation in October by mainland authorities, employs 200,000 workers in its Zhengzhou manufacturing complex. - 该公司于 10 月份被大陆当局进行了税收和土地使用调查，其在郑州制造业综合体雇佣了 200,000 名工人。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单句，主句是The company employs 200,000 workers in its Zhengzhou manufacturing complex，其中主语是The company，谓语是employs，宾语是200,000 workers。which was put under a tax and land use investigation in October by mainland authorities是一个过去分词短语作定语，修饰主语，表示该公司的郑州制造业综合体于 10 月份被大陆当局进行了税收和土地使用调查。这个句子的意思是该公司于 10 月份被大陆当局进行了税收和土地使用调查，其在郑州制造业综合体雇佣了 200,000 名工人。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去分词短语作定语 - 修饰先行词，作定语。    <p>原文例句：The company, which was put under a tax and land use investigation in October by mainland authorities, employs 200,000 workers in its Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去分词短语作定语是指由过去分词构成的短语，放在先行词之后，修饰先行词，起到定语的作用。在这个例句中，“which was put under a tax and land use investigation in October by mainland authorities”是一个过去分词短语，修饰先行词The company，表示该公司于 10 月份被大陆当局进行了税收和土地使用调查。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态是由主语承受的。    <p>原文例句：Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co, was established on January 4 with a registered capital of 500 million yuan (US$70 million), according to public records in the National Enterprise Credit Information Publicity System.</p>    <p>语法讲解：被动语态是由be动词和过去分词构成的，表示动作或状态是由主语承受的。在这个例句中，was established是be动词和过去分词构成的被动语态，表示Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co,是由他人或事物建立的。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The Apple supplier has set up a new venture in Zhengzhou to sharpen its focus on the electric vehicle industry</li>
<li>The new project will involve car component manufacturing and development, motor production and car sales</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/aad49844-fb12-4001-aa76-72cbfe6b99d4_f04766b4.jpg" /><figcaption>A Foxconn building in Taipei. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/foxconn" target="_self" title="">Foxconn Technology Group</a> has set up a new car venture in Zhengzhou city, capital of central China’s Henan province and home to the world’s largest iPhone factory, as the Apple supplier steps up its efforts in the new energy vehicle (NEV) sector amid declining smartphone sales.</p><p>The new firm, named Foxconn New Energy Automobile Industry Development (Henan) Co, was established on January 4 with a registered capital of 500 million yuan (US$70 million), according to public records in the National Enterprise Credit Information Publicity System.</p><p>Its business covers car component manufacturing and development, motor production and NEV sales, among other areas.</p><p>Foxconn, known formally as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/hon-hai-precision-industry" target="_self" title="">Hon Hai Precision Industry</a>, said the new venture belongs to Foxconn Innovation Industry Development Group Co and aims to sharpen the company’s focus on the electric vehicle industry, according to a report by the Securities Times on Tuesday.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Foxconn confirmed the report, adding that the Henan subsidiary was disclosed in December 2023 to the Taiwan Stock Exchange.</p><p>The world’s largest contract electronics manufacturer is accelerating its move into the automobile industry amid weakening demand for smartphones and consumer gadgets.</p><p>The Taiwanese giant last week reported US$198.9 billion in preliminary revenue for 2023, down 7 per cent from 2022. It blamed slow market demand for its static consumer electronics product business in the fourth quarter, while <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247521/apple-supplier-foxconn-sees-revenue-decline-first-quarter-2024-amid-weak-global-consumer-electronics" target="_self" title="">expecting continuing decline in the first quarter of this year</a>.</p><p>In October, Foxconn <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3238352/apple-supplier-foxconn-build-ai-factories-using-nvidias-chips-and-software-range-applications" target="_self" title="">announced a new electric cargo van called Model N</a> and announced plans to mass produce its compact SUV Model B. Jun Seki, its chief strategy officer for electric vehicles, said the company was in touch with about 14 potential customers and saw India and Japan as promising countries for EV development.</p><p>To help push the company towards its new direction, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3218313/apple-supplier-foxconn-sets-global-business-base-iphone-city-show-commitment-china" target="_self" title="">Foxconn opened a new global business base in Zhengzhou</a> last April and reaffirmed its commitment to the Chinese market, even as the firm and other Apple suppliers move to diversify their supply chain.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/10/853102cf-b84f-499d-9b72-8c24ea357fde_a66cec46.jpg" title="A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>A Foxconn plant in Zhengzhou, Henan province. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Foxconn plans to start building new factories for smartphones and electronics goods in the cities of Zhoukou, Kaifeng and Jiyuan in Henan, according to a list of major construction projects in 2024 released last week by the provincial Development and Reform Commission.</p><p>The company, which was put under <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3239113/china-says-investigation-apple-supplier-foxconns-operations-mainland-normal-law-enforcement" target="_self" title="">a tax and land use investigation</a> in October by mainland authorities, employs 200,000 workers in its Zhengzhou manufacturing complex.</p><p>In 2022, that facility was rocked by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3200747/violence-erupts-foxconn-zhengzhou-plant-workers-protest-over-benefits-and-covid-19-controls-worlds?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">violent workers’ protests</a> and an <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3197909/coronavirus-iphone-factory-exodus-shows-how-chinas-covid-narrative-still-strikes-fear-public?module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;pgtype=article&amp;module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">exodus of tens of thousands of employees</a> that Apple CEO Tim Cook later <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3208974/apples-tim-cook-blames-supply-disruption-chinas-pandemic-controls-revenue-drop" target="_self" title="">blamed for a decline in the US company’s quarterly revenue</a>.</p><p>Separately, Foxconn plans to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3245003/foxconn-ramps-investment-giant-apple-plant-india-amid-us-china-tensions?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">invest at least US$2.6 billion in a plant</a> it is building in India to make Apple products, according to a report by Bloomberg last month.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
