<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>AIRSS</title>
<link>AIRSS_LINK</link>
<description>MY AI RSS</description>

<item>
<title>China to persist with AI development in 2024 despite rigid US chip restrictions, UBS analysts say</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247835/china-persist-ai-development-efforts-2024-despite-setbacks-rigid-us-semiconductor-restrictions-ubs</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  Despite US export controls restricting China's access to advanced semiconductors, China plans to proceed with developing large language models (LLMs) and generative AI systems. China aims to achieve progress within these constraints by utilizing domestic AI accelerator programs and optimizing computing resource usage. Nicolas Gaudois from UBS emphasizes China's resilience in overcoming setbacks and highlights the growth of China's semiconductor sector in unsanctioned segments. Randy Abrams from UBS notes the increasing market share of local semiconductor equipment suppliers and opportunities in mature application areas. The global demand for chips is expected to rise as inventory pressures ease and procurement at semiconductor foundries improves.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: China to push ahead with AI development despite US export controls.</li>    <li>Theme: China's determination to advance its AI capabilities amidst US restrictions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: China's ability to overcome challenges and its focus on domestic resources and optimization.</li>    <li>Main information: China's plans for AI development, domestic AI accelerator programs, growth in unsanctioned semiconductor segments, and rising demand for chips.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  在受到美国出口管制限制无法获得先进半导体的情况下，中国预计将继续发展大型语言模型（LLM）和生成式人工智能（AI）系统。中国将利用国内人工智能加速器项目和更经济地使用计算资源，在这些限制条件下取得进展。瑞士信贷亚太区科技研究主管 Nicolas Gaudois 强调了中国在克服挫折方面的弹性，并强调了中国半导体行业在未受制裁细分市场中的增长。瑞士信贷台湾研究主管 Randy Abrams 指出，本地半导体设备供应商的市场份额不断增加，在成熟应用领域中存在机会。随着库存压力缓解和半导体代工厂采购情况改善，全球对芯片的需求预计将增长。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国将推进人工智能发展，尽管受到美国出口管制。</li>    <li>主题：中国在面临美国限制的情况下，决心推进其人工智能能力。</li>    <li>观点：中国克服挑战的能力，以及其对国内资源和优化利用的关注。</li>    <li>主要信息：中国的人工智能发展计划、国内人工智能加速器计划、未受制裁半导体领域的增长和对芯片日益增长的需求。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>resilience (n.) - /rɪˈzɪliəns/ 弹性，韧性。    <p>原文例句：Gaudois said US export controls have blocked China’s access to Nvidia chips used for AI projects, but indicated that the mainland’s ability to overcome such setbacks must not be underestimated.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由re-（再）和salire（跳）组成，意为“恢复原来的形状”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国在面临美国出口管制时，能够克服挫折并保持前进的能力，即弹性。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Semiconductor (n.) - /ˌsemiːkənˈdʌktə/ 半导体。    <p>原文例句：UBS analysts asserted that China’s semiconductor sector has developed well in certain unsanctioned segments, showing strong market growth over the past few years.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由semi-（半）和conductor（导体）组成，意为“半导体”。在这个例句中，它指的是中国半导体行业在某些未受制裁的细分市场中发展良好，表现出强劲的市场增长。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>within those constraints - 在那些限制范围内。    <P>原文例句：China is expected to “work within those constraints and try to make progress” by tapping into domestic AI accelerator programmes and being more economical in using computing resources, said Nicolas Gaudois, head of Asia-Pacific technology research at UBS.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由within（在里面），those（那些），constraints（限制）组成，表示“在那些限制范围内”。在这个例句中，它表示中国预计将“在那些限制范围内工作并努力取得进展”。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>overcome setbacks - 克服挫折。    <p>原文例句：The country’s ability to overcome setbacks caused by US exports controls must not be underestimated, according to UBS’ Nicolas Gaudois.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由overcome（克服），setbacks（挫折）组成，表示“克服挫折”。在这个例句中，它表示中国的政府应该重视克服挫折的能力，尤其是在受到美国出口管制的影响时。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>China will press ahead this year with development of large language models (LLMs) – the technology used to train ChatGPT and similar applications – and generative artificial intelligence (AI) systems, despite restrictions imposed by the United States on the mainland’s access to advanced semiconductors, according to analysts from Swiss investment bank UBS. - 中国将在今年继续发展大型语言模型（LLM）——用于训练 ChatGPT 和类似应用程序的技术——和生成式人工智能 (AI) 系统，尽管美国对内地获取先进半导体施加了限制，瑞士投资银行 UBS 的分析师表示。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是China will press ahead this year with development of large language models (LLMs)，其中主语是China，谓语是will press ahead，宾语是development of large language models (LLMs)。despite restrictions imposed by the United States on the mainland’s access to advanced semiconductors是一个介词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示尽管美国对内地获取先进半导体施加了限制。according to analysts from Swiss investment bank UBS是一个介词短语作状语，修饰主句，表示根据瑞士投资银行 UBS 的分析师的说法。这个句子的意思是说，尽管美国对内地获取先进半导体施加了限制，中国将在今年继续发展大型语言模型（LLM）——用于训练 ChatGPT 和类似应用程序的技术——和生成式人工智能 (AI) 系统，瑞士投资银行 UBS 的分析师表示。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>主谓一致 - 主语和谓语在人称和数上要一致。    <p>原文例句：UBS analysts asserted that China’s semiconductor sector has developed well in certain unsanctioned segments, showing strong market growth over the past few years.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个主谓一致的例子，主语是UBS analysts，谓语是asserted。asserted是assert的过去分词，assert是一个不及物动词，不需要宾语。在这个例句中，UBS analysts和asserted在人称和数上都是一致的，都是第三人称单数。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：China has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种时态，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，it表示这家公司从过去的几年开始一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>China is expected to ‘work within those constraints’ while making progress via AI accelerators and more economical use of computing resources</li>
<li>The country’s ability to overcome setbacks caused by US exports controls must not be underestimated, according to UBS’ Nicolas Gaudois</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/f68371eb-a605-4c9f-afb0-20abb89d4ca9_a1137b4b.jpg" /><figcaption>A slew of sanctions imposed by the US since 2019 has forced companies across China’s vast tech supply chain to work closely together in supporting domestic artificial intelligence projects. Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>China will press ahead this year with development of <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3226942/china-create-and-implement-national-standard-large-language-models-move-regulate-ai-while-using-its" target="_self" title="">large language models</a> (LLMs) – the technology used to train <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3244420/openais-chatgpt-took-ai-world-storm-year-ago-and-china-still-playing-catch-us-piles-pressure" target="_self" title="">ChatGPT</a> and similar applications – and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/chatgpt-and-generative-ai" target="_self" title="">generative artificial intelligence</a> (AI) systems, despite restrictions imposed by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states" target="_self" title="">United States</a> on the mainland’s access to advanced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/semiconductors" target="_self" title="">semiconductors</a>, according to analysts from Swiss investment bank <a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3218263/swiss-bank-ubs-raked-us28-billion-wealthy-clients-takeover-troubled-rival-credit-suisse" target="_self" title="">UBS</a>.</p><p>China is expected to “work within those constraints and try to make progress” by tapping into domestic <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="">AI</a> accelerator programmes and being more economical in using computing resources, said Nicolas Gaudois, head of Asia-Pacific technology research at UBS, during a webinar hosted by the bank on Tuesday.</p><p>Gaudois said US export controls have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3238354/tech-war-us-ban-tailor-made-nvidia-and-intel-chips-hits-beijings-ai-ambitions" target="_self" title="">blocked China’s access to Nvidia chips used for AI projects</a>, but indicated that the mainland’s ability to overcome such setbacks must not be underestimated.</p><p>The views expressed by UBS analysts reflect how China’s semiconductor industry <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3246736/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-industry-weathers-tough-year-amid-tighter-us-sanctions" target="_self" title="">weathered last year’s escalation of Washington’s tech sanctions</a>, which restricted exports of advanced chip-making equipment and cutting-edge semiconductors for AI projects.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>The mainland’s tech sector appeared to have <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3236295/huaweis-5g-smartphone-comeback-advanced-chip-wrapped-secrecy-releases-chokehold-us-sanctions-china" target="_self" title="">overcome the chokehold of US export controls</a> last year, when <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei/news" target="_self" title="">Huawei Technologies</a> made a surprise return to the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/5g/news" target="_self" title="">5G</a> <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/smartphones" target="_self" title="">smartphone</a> market with new handsets powered by a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3233520/tech-war-top-chinese-chip-maker-smic-under-spotlight-breakthrough-5g-processor-used-huaweis-latest?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">“breakthrough” advanced made-in-China processor</a>.</p><p>It showed the lengths taken by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3012321/huawei-among-more-140-chinese-entities-us-trade-blacklist" target="_self" title="">US-blacklisted</a> company to build up its operations, following years of struggles on account of trade sanctions.</p><p>Apart from that breakthrough, UBS analysts asserted that China’s semiconductor sector has developed well in certain unsanctioned segments, showing strong market growth over the past few years.</p><p>“Restrictions from the US are very limited on mature nodes,” said Randy Abrams, head of Taiwan Research at UBS, in the same webinar on Tuesday. He pointed out that sales of these mature-node chips have not been restricted.</p><p>“We have seen China make more effort to invest in those areas,” Abrams said. “We will see steady market pickup in mature applications, such as camera image sensors, micro-controllers, analogue chips and discrete semiconductor devices for EVs.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3246736/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-industry-weathers-tough-year-amid-tighter-us-sanctions" title="">China’s semiconductor industry weathers tough year amid tighter US sanctions</a></h3><p>“In semiconductor equipment, local suppliers have built up their market share from very low single-digits into the mid- to high-single-digits,” he said. “Their gains come from supplying China semiconductor manufacturers, as they’ve added mature node capacity.”</p><p>Abrams said domestic chip-making equipment suppliers saw their market share increase to about 20 per cent on the back of demand from Chinese chip fabrication facilities. “So if we leave out the very advanced nodes, there are actually a lot of [investment] opportunities,” he said.</p><p>Global demand for chips, he said, is expected to start picking up, as soon as inventory pressures ease and procurement at semiconductor foundries improves.</p><p>A slew of sanctions imposed by the US since 2019 has also forced companies across China’s vast tech supply chain to work closely together.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">Internet</a> search giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/baidu" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>, which <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3239981/baidu-launches-paid-version-ernie-bot-chinese-firms-rush-make-money-their-generative-ai-chatbots?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">runs Ernie Bot and the Ernie LLM</a>, ordered <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3240641/us-china-tech-war-baidu-buys-ai-chips-huawei-us-restricts-nvidia-chip-exports-sources" target="_self" title="">US$61 million worth of Huawei’s 910B Ascend AI chips</a> – which the Chinese firm developed as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226981/huawei-taps-computing-power-shortage-china-touts-self-developed-ai-tech-amid-chatgpt-craze?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">an alternative to Nvidia’s A100 processor</a> – for 200 servers, according to a report in November by Reuters, which cited sources.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s DingTalk updates workplace collaboration app with new AI agent amid growing client demand</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247831/alibabas-dingtalk-updates-workplace-collaboration-app-new-ai-agent-amid-growing-client-demand</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  阿里巴巴的钉钉推出更新版本的工作协同应用，增加了AI智能助手功能，帮助用户精简和定制工作流程。该公司在杭州举行发布会宣布了这一消息，称AI智能助手功能旨在解决70多万公司客户的反馈。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Alibaba's DingTalk releases an updated version with AI agent function.</li>    <li>Theme: DingTalk's AI agent aims to streamline workflow and address user feedback.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The role of AI agents in improving productivity and user experience in workplace collaboration apps.</li>    <li>Main information: DingTalk 7.5 launch, AI agent feature, feedback from corporate clients, AI-generated content trend, low entry barriers for AI agent platform.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  在杭州举行的一次公司活动中，阿里巴巴集团控股的钉钉发布了其工作场所协同应用程序的更新版本，增加了人工智能 (AI) 代理功能，以帮助用户简化和定制他们的工作流程。这一开发正值人工智能领域的一片繁忙景象之际，中国各公司争相将类 ChatGPT 服务纳入其产品中，字节跳动旗下竞争对手飞书也采取了类似举措。阿里巴巴拥有南华早报。钉钉总裁叶军在一份声明中表示，在浙江省东部省会杭州举行的一场公司活动上宣布的钉钉 7.5 随附的 AI 代理功能旨在解决从 70 多万企业客户中收集的反馈。该公司称，这项新工具有望推动 AI 产品在行业中的更广泛采用。“随着 AI 生成的内容浪潮日益融入生产力和 [商业] 用例，AI 代理已成为 AI 应用最合适的门户，”叶军说。  <ul>    <li>摘要：阿里巴巴钉钉发布更新版本，新增AI智能助手功能。</li>    <li>主题：钉钉的AI智能助手旨在简化工作流程并解决用户反馈。</li>    <li>观点：AI智能助手在提高工作场所协同应用的生产力和用户体验中的作用。</li>    <li>主要信息：钉钉7.5发布，AI智能助手功能，企业客户反馈，AI生成内容趋势，AI智能助手平台的低进入门槛。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>streamline (v.) - /ˈstriːmlaɪn/ 简化，精简。    <p>原文例句：The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源于stream（流）和line（线），意为“使成流线型，使更有效率”。在这个例句中，它指的是AI智能助手功能旨在使工作流程更有效率。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>customization (n.) - /kʌstəmaɪˈzeɪʃən/ 定制，个性化。    <p>原文例句：The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词源于custom（习俗，习惯）和-ization（使……化），意为“定制，使适合个人需求”。在这个例句中，它指的是AI智能助手功能旨在使工作流程更适合个人需求。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>on entry - 在入口处。    <P>原文例句： Shoes and apparel giant Belle International has rolled out a customized AI agent on its DingTalk platform to track parcel shipment issues, with plans to expand the use of the agent to more cases, including stock allocation. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由on（在……上）和entry（入口，进入）构成的，表示“在入口处”。在这个例句中，它表示鞋服巨头百丽国际在其钉钉平台上推出了一个定制的AI代理，以跟踪包裹发货问题，并计划将该代理的使用范围扩展到更多案例，包括库存分配。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>take by storm - 使惊讶，震惊。    <P>原文例句：LLMs are the deep learning models, pre-trained on vast amounts of data, that underpin chatbots such as OpenAI’s ChatGPT, which took the world by storm a year ago with its ability to understand complex questions and respond with human-like text. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由take（拿，带）和storm（暴风雨）构成的，表示“使惊讶，震惊”。在这个例句中，它表示LLM是经过大量数据预训练的深度学习模型，它们是类似OpenAI的ChatGPT这样的聊天机器人的基础，ChatGPT一年前以其理解复杂问题并以类人文本进行回应的能力震惊了世界。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>At the launch of Feishu 7, ByteDance introduced an AI bot dubbed Feishu Intelligent Buddy, which can help users with daily tasks such as drafting emails, drawing up spreadsheets and summarising long reports.- 在飞书7的发布会上，字节跳动推出了一款名为飞书智能助理的AI机器人，可以帮助用户完成日常任务，如起草电子邮件、绘制电子表格和总结长篇报告。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是ByteDance introduced an AI bot dubbed Feishu Intelligent Buddy，其中主语是ByteDance，谓语是introduced，宾语是an AI bot dubbed Feishu Intelligent Buddy。At the launch of Feishu 7是一个介词短语作状语，修饰ByteDance introduced an AI bot dubbed Feishu Intelligent Buddy，表示在飞书7的发布会上。which can help users with daily tasks such as drafting emails, drawing up spreadsheets and summarising long reports是一个定语从句，修饰an AI bot dubbed Feishu Intelligent Buddy，表示这款AI机器人可以帮助用户完成日常任务，如起草电子邮件、绘制电子表格和总结长篇报告。这个句子的意思是说，在飞书7的发布会上，字节跳动推出了一款名为飞书智能助理的AI机器人，可以帮助用户完成日常任务，如起草电子邮件、绘制电子表格和总结长篇报告。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在或已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：The development comes amid a flurry of activity in the AI sector as Chinese companies rush to incorporate ChatGPT-like services into their products and after a similar move by ByteDance’s rival app Feishu. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。在这个例句中，The development comes amid a flurry of activity in the AI sector as Chinese companies rush to incorporate ChatGPT-like services into their products and after a similar move by ByteDance’s rival app Feishu.，表示一项发展正值中国公司纷纷将类似ChatGPT的服务纳入其产品的活动热潮中，以及字节跳动旗下竞争对手飞书采取类似举措之后。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>DingTalk’s AI agent function is powered by Alibaba’sTongyi Qianwen large language model</li>
<li>The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/30e71220-1a5a-4efb-b280-5bfdcfbd741d_5ecb7eee.jpg" /><figcaption>The AI agent feature was announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou. Photo: VCG via Getty Images </figcaption></figure><p>Alibaba Group Holding’s DingTalk launched an updated version of its workplace collaboration app on Tuesday with the addition of an artificial intelligence (AI) agent function to help users streamline and customise their workflow.</p><p>The development comes amid a flurry of activity in the AI sector as Chinese companies rush to incorporate ChatGPT-like services into their products and after a similar move by ByteDance’s rival app Feishu. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>The AI agent feature announced alongside DingTalk 7.5 at a corporate event held in Hangzhou, capital of eastern Zhejiang province, is designed to address feedback gleaned from more than 700,000 corporate clients, said Ye Jun, president of DingTalk, in a statement.</p><p>The new tool is expected to promote greater adoption of AI products in the industry, according to the company.</p><p>“As the tide of AI-generated content increasingly finds its way into productivity and [business] use cases, AI agents have emerged as the most suitable gateway for AI applications,” said Ye.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242571/bytedance-adds-ai-assistant-office-tool-feishu-joining-rivals-tencent-and-alibaba-workplace-chatbot" title="">ByteDance brings AI to office tool Feishu, taking on Tencent and Alibaba</a></h3><p>Ye added that DingTalk’s goal is to become an AI agent platform with low entry barriers, with the marketplace expected to grow substantially in the next three years.</p><p>As of the end of 2023, Dingtalk had over 700 million users. It also has 25 million organisations, including corporate and educational institutions that use its platform, of which 120,000 are paying clients, said Ye.</p><p>Shoes and apparel giant Belle International has rolled out a customised AI agent on its DingTalk platform to track parcel shipment issues, with plans to expand the use of the agent to more cases, including stock allocation.</p><p>DingTalk’s addition of an AI agent function, powered by the group’s Tongyi Qianwen large language model (LLM), comes after ByteDance’s Feishu made a similar push last November.</p><p>LLMs are the deep learning models, pre-trained on vast amounts of data, that underpin chatbots such as OpenAI’s ChatGPT, which took the world by storm a year ago with its ability to understand complex questions and respond with human-like text.</p><p>At the launch of Feishu 7, ByteDance introduced an AI bot dubbed Feishu Intelligent Buddy, which can help users with daily tasks such as drafting emails, drawing up spreadsheets and summarising long reports.</p><p>Feishu also announced a platform to enable its corporate clients to build and customise AI bots according to business needs, it said at the time.</p><p>After a year of hype over AI chatbots, Chinese Big Tech firms including Alibaba, ByteDance and Baidu have been rushing to build competitor products to ChatGPT, with applications spanning the finance, legal, manufacturing, retail and public sectors.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s logistics arm Cainiao offers shoppers in US grouped delivery service, cutting shipping times to five days</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247829/alibabas-logistics-arm-cainiao-offers-shoppers-us-grouped-delivery-service-cutting-shipping-times</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Chinese logistics company Cainiao has introduced a new consolidated shipping service in the US, allowing consumers to combine multiple online purchases from different platforms and deliver them in as little as five days by air or at a reduced cost by sea.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Cainiao's consolidated shipping service simplifies cross-border deliveries for Chinese consumers in the US, offering faster and cost-effective options.</li>    <li>Theme: Cainiao's expansion of its services to cater to the needs of Chinese consumers in the US and support e-commerce growth.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The growing demand for cross-border e-commerce and the importance of efficient logistics solutions for overseas consumers.</li>    <li>Main information: Cainiao's consolidated shipping service, covering both air and sea routes, provides faster delivery times and cost savings; the service is initially targeting Chinese consumers in the US; Cainiao plans to raise $1 billion through a listing in Hong Kong.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  中国物流公司菜鸟在美国推出了一项新的综合运输服务，允许消费者将来自不同平台的多个网上购物订单合并，并通过空运在五天内交货，或通过海运以更低的成本交货。  <ul>    <li>摘要：菜鸟的综合运输服务简化了中国消费者在美国的跨境交货，提供了更快、更具成本效益的选择。</li>    <li>主题：菜鸟扩展服务以满足中国消费者在美国的需求并支持电子商务增长。</li>    <li>观点：对跨境电子商务需求的增长以及海外消费者对高效物流解决方案的需求。</li>    <li>主要信息：菜鸟的综合运输服务，涵盖空运和海运，提供更快的交货时间和节省成本；该服务最初针对美国中国消费者；菜鸟计划通过在香港上市筹集 10 亿美元。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>consolidated (adj.) - /kənˈsɑːlɪdeɪtɪd/ 合并的，统一的。    <p>原文例句：The so-called “consolidated shipping” service, covering both air and sea transport routes, will collect multiple online shopping orders placed by users on various platforms in a warehouse before shipping them from China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由con-（共同）和solidus（坚固）组成，意为“使坚固，使统一”。在这个例句中，它指的是一种综合运输服务，将用户在不同平台上下的多个在线购物订单收集到一个仓库，然后从中国发货。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>parcel (n.) - /ˈpɑːrsəl/ 包裹，包裹物。    <p>原文例句：If the parcel is sent via air, delivery times may be reduced five days after the items are sent out from the warehouse. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，由par（通过）和cel（this）组成，意为“通过这个传递的东西”。在这个例句中，它指的是一个包裹，如果通过空运发送，包裹的交货时间可能会在从仓库发出后五天内减少。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrevənjuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：In the third quarter of 2023, Best’s global businesses achieved revenue of US$37.7 million, contributing to 12.4 per cent of the total.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old French，由revenir（回来）和nue（新）组成，意为“重新开始，重新获得”。在这个例句中，它指的是收入，即通过商业活动获得的收益，在这个例子中，Best在2023年第三季度的全球业务收入为3770万美元，占总收入的12.4%。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>cross-border e-commerce - 跨境电子商务。    <p>原文例句：Cainiao has its eye on the overseas market, and recorded more than 1.5 billion cross-border e-commerce parcel deliveries in its recent financial year to March, making it one of the world’s top logistics services providers, according to its prospectus.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由cross-border（跨境）和e-commerce（电子商务）组成，意为“跨境电子商务”。在这个例句中，它指的是一种通过互联网进行的跨国界商品交易活动，通常涉及消费者和企业之间的商品交易。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>subject to market conditions - 取决于市场状况。    <p>原文例句：Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to a Post report in September that cited people familiar with the situation.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由subject to（取决于）和market conditions（市场状况）组成，意为“取决于市场状况”。在这个例句中，它指的是菜鸟的筹资目标取决于市场状况，即市场状况将影响菜鸟能够筹集到的资金数量。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The company has been making iPhones and other products in India for several years, including the latest iPhone 15. - 该公司一直在印度生产 iPhone 和其他产品数年，包括最新的 iPhone 15。<p>句子分析：这是一个现在完成进行时态的句子，主语是The company，谓语是has been making，其中has been是be动词的现在完成时态，making是动词make的-ing形式。这个句子表示该公司的动作或状态从过去的某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个句子中，它表示该公司一直在印度生产iPhone和其他产品，直到现在仍在进行，并且包括最新的iPhone 15。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>助动词will的用法 - 表示将来时态。    <p>原文例句：Cainiao said the cross-border shipping service would mainly help Chinese consumers and students in the US who tend to buy lots of goods on Chinese e-commerce sites.</p>    <p>语法讲解：will是助动词，用在动词前面，表示将来时态。在肯定句中，will与动词原形连用；在否定句和疑问句中，will与动词原形的否定式连用。在这个例句中，will与动词help连用，表示菜鸟所说的跨境运输服务将主要帮助那些经常在中国电商网站上购买大量商品的中国消费者和学生。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Cainiao said cross-border shipping service would mainly help Chinese consumers in US who tend to buy lots of goods on Chinese sites</li>
<li>The so-called ‘consolidated shipping’ service covers both air and sea transport routes</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/8c90f6e8-359a-4cee-bbfa-62226abce761_8e97fde8.jpg" /><figcaption>The so-called ‘consolidated shipping’ service covers both air and sea transport routes. Photo: Handout  </figcaption></figure><p>Cainiao, Alibaba Group Holding’s logistics unit, will open a new service for consumers in the US to allow them to package several items they have bought together, cutting delivery times to as little as five days.</p><p>Cainiao said in a statement on Tuesday that the cross-border shipping service would mainly help Chinese consumers and students in the US who tend to buy lots of goods on Chinese e-commerce sites. As of 2020, there were roughly 60 million Chinese living outside the country, according to a report by Huaqiao University.</p><p>If the parcel is sent via air, delivery times may be reduced five days after the items are sent out from the warehouse. If by sea, the new service may cut the cost to as low as 12 yuan (US$1.7), depending on the size of the parcel, according to the statement.</p><p>The new overseas service comes ahead of Cainiao’s planned US$1 billion listing in Hong Kong. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247710/alibabas-aliexpress-pdd-owned-temu-face-supply-chain-challenges-south-korea-amid-rapid-business" title="">Alibaba’s AliExpress, PDD-owned Temu face supply chain challenges in South Korea</a></h3><p>The so-called “consolidated shipping” service, covering both air and sea transport routes, will collect multiple online shopping orders placed by users on various platforms in a warehouse before shipping them from China.</p><p>Prior to its US expansion, Cainiao provided consolidated shipping to shoppers in other markets outside mainland China, including Hong Kong, Singapore and Australia.</p><p>In November, Cainiao and Alibaba were part of a consortium that made a US$57 million offer to buy Chinese logistics company Best. Best is a major courier in China and has a presence in Southeast Asia. In the third quarter of 2023, Best’s global businesses achieved revenue of US$37.7 million, contributing to 12.4 per cent of the total.</p><p>Cainiao has its eye on the overseas market, and recorded more than 1.5 billion cross-border e-commerce parcel deliveries in its recent financial year to March, making it one of the world’s top logistics services providers, according to its prospectus.</p><p>Cainiao aims to raise at least US$1 billion, subject to market conditions, according to a Post report in September that cited people familiar with the situation. The listing is part of a group-wide restructuring of Alibaba, as the e-commerce titan seeks to free up decision- making amid increased competition.</p><p>Established in 2013, Cainiao serves as the logistics backbone of Alibaba’s e-commerce empire, handling more than 4 million cross-border parcels on a daily basis in 2023. Alibaba announced it would spin off Cainiao in the restructuring announced in March.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>CES 2024: China TV makers Hisense and TCL promote AI, live sports at US show</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247808/ces-2024-china-tv-makers-hisense-and-tcl-promote-ai-live-sports-us-show</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Chinese television manufacturers Hisense and TCL showcased their latest product lineups at CES 2024, emphasizing AI (Artificial Intelligence) and smart home integration.</li>    <li>Both brands positioned themselves as leading Chinese contenders in the US television market, highlighting their in-house technology production and supply chain capabilities.</li>    <li>Mini-LED technology and affordable high-quality TVs were major talking points, with Hisense offering mini-LEDs integrated into all its models.</li>    <li>AI-powered image processing and enhancement featured prominently, with both Hisense and TCL utilizing AI chips to optimize picture quality based on content type.</li>    <li>Beyond TVs, TCL and Hisense also showcased augmented reality (AR) glasses and virtual reality (VR) headsets.</li>    <li>Hisense highlighted its foray into the automotive sector, developing AR displays for car windshields and aiming to connect home appliances with car infotainment systems.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>中国电视制造商海信和TCL在2024年国际消费类电子产品展览会（CES）上展示了他们的最新产品阵容，强调人工智能 (AI) 和智能家居集成。</li>    <li>这两个品牌都将自己定位为美国电视市场领先的中国竞争者，突出它们的内部技术生产和供应链能力。</li>    <li>Mini-LED 技术和价格实惠的高质量电视是主要卖点，海信提供集成到所有型号中的 Mini-LED。</li>    <li>人工智能驱动的图像处理和增强功能尤为突出，海信和 TCL 都利用人工智能芯片根据内容类型优化图像质量。</li>    <li>除了电视外，TCL 和海信还展示了增强现实 (AR) 眼镜和虚拟现实 (VR) 头显。</li>    <li>海信重点介绍了其进军汽车行业，为汽车挡风玻璃开发 AR 显示器，并旨在将家用电器与汽车信息娱乐系统连接起来。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>supply chain (n.) - 供应链。    <p>原文例句：The companies emphasised their ability to produce much of their technology in-house and how they are branching out into areas like AR.</p>    <p>例句讲解：供应链是指从原材料采购到产品销售的整个链条，包括生产、运输、仓储、配送等各个环节。在这个例句中，它指的是这两家公司能够在自己内部生产大部分的技术，并且正在将业务扩展到诸如增强现实（AR）等领域。</p></li>    <li>emphasis (n.) - 强调，重点。    <p>原文例句：Both companies offered competing narratives, presenting themselves as the biggest Chinese brands in the US television space.</p>    <p>例句讲解：强调是指特别突出或重视某件事或某一方面。在这个例句中，它指的是这两家公司在介绍自己时都强调自己是美国电视领域最大的中国品牌。</p></li>    <li>integrate (v.) - 集成，整合。    <p>原文例句：Hisense said that mini LEDs – which cram more LEDs into a display to offer a greater range of contrast and image quality – are now integrated into all its models, including one for under US$500.</p>    <p>例句讲解：集成是指将几个独立的部分或系统组合成一个整体。在这个例句中，它指的是海信表示，mini LED（一种将更多 LED 集成到显示器中以提供更大范围的对比度和图像质量的 LED）现在集成到其所有型号中，包括一款售价低于 500 美元的型号。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>state-of-the-art (adj.) - 最先进的，最新的。    <p>原文例句：Hisense unveiled its latest line-ups at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday, with an emphasis on artificial intelligence (AI) and making screens the centre of the home, while pushing into new areas like cars.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由 state（状态）和 art（艺术）构成的，表示“最先进的，最新的”。在这个例句中，它描述了海信在 2024 年拉斯维加斯 CES 上推出的最新产品阵容，重点是人工智能 (AI) 和将屏幕作为家庭的中心，同时进军汽车等新领域。</p></li>    <li>expand into (v.) - 扩展到，进军。    <p>原文例句：Both companies offered competing narratives, presenting themselves as the biggest Chinese brands in the US television space.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由 expand（扩展）和 into（到）构成的，表示“扩展到，进军”。在这个例句中，它描述了两家公司在介绍自己时都强调自己是美国电视领域最大的中国品牌。</p></li>    <li>enhance picture quality (v.) - 增强图片质量。    <p>原文例句：Hisense highlighted the ability of its AI chips to enhance picture quality by identifying whether the video is coming from streaming, cable or another source.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由 enhance（增强）和 picture quality（图片质量）构成的，表示“增强图片质量”。在这个例句中，它描述了海信突出显示其人工智能芯片通过识别视频是来自流媒体、有线电视还是其他来源来增强图像质量的能力。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The companies emphasised their ability to produce much of their technology in-house and how they are branching out into areas like AR. - 这两家公司强调了他们能够在内部生产大部分技术的能力，以及他们如何进军增强现实等领域。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The companies emphasised their ability to produce much of their technology in-house，其中主语是The companies，谓语是emphasised，宾语是their ability to produce much of their technology in-house。how they are branching out into areas like AR是一个宾语从句，其中主语是they，谓语是are branching out，宾语是into areas like AR。这个句子的意思是说，这两家公司强调了他们能够在内部生产大部分技术的能力，以及他们如何进军增强现实等领域。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词短语 - 由分词和其修饰语组成的短语。    <p>原文例句：With an emphasis on artificial intelligence (AI) and making screens the centre of the home, while pushing into new areas like cars.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个分词短语，由分词making和其修饰语With an emphasis on artificial intelligence (AI) and和the centre of the home组成的。这个短语作状语，修饰主句while pushing into new areas like cars，表示在强调人工智能（AI）和将屏幕作为家庭的中心的同时，也进军汽车等新领域。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The two biggest Chinese TV brands offered competing narratives about their global stature and AI processing capabilities</li>
<li>The companies emphasised their ability to produce much of their technology in-house and how they are branching out into areas like AR</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/d720b3c6-868e-43ae-b6f8-e7b08d7057b0_128316fa.jpg" /><figcaption>Hisense USA president David Gold on stage at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday. Photo: Matt Haldane</figcaption></figure><p>Chinese television set makers Hisense and TCL unveiled their latest line-ups at CES 2024 in Las Vegas on Monday, with an emphasis on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence">artificial intelligence (AI)</a> and making screens the centre of the home, while pushing into new areas like cars.</p><p>Both companies offered competing narratives, presenting themselves as the biggest Chinese brands in the US television space. They also boasted about their supply chain prowess and the ability to manufacture leading technologies in-house.</p><p>David Gold, president of Hisense USA, said the company’s ability to produce displays and even its own AI chipsets without third parties is something that sets it apart.</p><p>“When you think about global players, I think we are one of less than a handful of companies that have everything that it takes to be able to truly provide a smart home solution,” Gold said after the Hisense presentation. “We have all the ingredients, all the components. There are very few companies out there that can do the same.”</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>The flagship product from Hisense this year is its new 110-inch ULED X television with a brightness of 10,000 nits and 40,000 backlight zones.</p><p>Not to be outdone, TCL announced what it said is the world’s largest mini-LED TV at 115 inches. TCL referred to itself as a “great global power” with 32 research and development centres and 43 manufacturing sites around the world.</p><p>Mini LEDs featured prominently in the presentations of both Hisense and TCL, as they each presented their brands as the best option for finding this tech in TVs that cost just a few hundred dollars, rather than thousands.</p><p>Hisense said that mini LEDs – which cram more LEDs into a display to offer a greater range of contrast and image quality – are now integrated into all its models, including one for under US$500.</p><p>Hisense also introduced its new so-called laser TVs, which are projectors combined with an ambient-light-rejecting screen. The company said its newest 8K Sonic Laser TV is the “world’s largest sound-emitting screen”, offering a sound bar-like experience built into the projector. It is also offering a new Rollable Laser TV, which is exactly what it sounds like: a projector screen that rolls up and disappears, offering a cleaner look at home when not in use.</p><p>Both companies used sports to draw attention to their new TVs. As more viewers switch to streaming, the focus on live television has largely fallen to sports, a major reason households remain subscribed to cable and satellite TV packages.</p><p>TCL leaned into this heavily, inviting sportscasters including Charissa Thompson and former National Football League player Charles Woodson on stage for nearly the entire duration of the presentation.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1331" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/e0266ca3-3156-4fd7-af77-61200f190c62_3aeb65d0.jpg" title="Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Stefan Streit, chief marketing officer of TCL Communication, introduces the RayNeo X2 Lite smart glasses at CES 2024 in Las Vegas, January 8, 2024. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>Hisense highlighted the ability of its AI chips to enhance picture quality by identifying whether the video is coming from streaming, cable or another source.</p><p>“[Our AI is] about recognising what content it is, the quality, the factor in which it’s being displayed – whether it’s streaming, cable, DVDs, Blu-ray – and finding the way to enhance that picture quality,” Gold said. “Usually you put in one setting and never change it again. What we’re trying to do with AI is automatically detect, ‘Oh, now you’re watching football, let’s move to a sport setting’.”</p><p>Seemingly omnipresent at CES 2024, AI was mentioned repeatedly during both presentations, as it has been by rivals like Samsung and LG.</p><p>TCL talked of enhancing access to its AI processing with three levels of its AIPQ processors, which include “pro” and “ultra” versions. The AI processors are now offered in its cheaper S Class series.</p><p>While TVs are typically the highlight for these events from the Chinese display giants, they are also chasing other trends in the industry. TCL mentioned the latest version of the RayNeo X2 smart glasses, which can display images on the lenses to do things like offer real-time text translation. TCL incubated RayNeo.</p><p>The company also highlighted its newest smartphones and tablets with an emphasis on its Nxtpaper display, which is meant to be easier on the eyes like e-reader displays.</p><p>Hisense is working on its own augmented reality (AR) glasses and a virtual reality headset, but both are just prototypes for now.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE" class="image-inline caption" height="1229" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/5dbb9d8d-418e-45e8-ade6-ea407301ebfc_dc8aec28.jpg" title="Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE" width="2000" /><figcaption>Hisense US president David Gold speaks during a presentation at CES 2024, January 8, 2024. Photo: EPA-EFE</figcaption></figure></div><p>It has also followed many of its Chinese peers – like <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/xiaomi">Xiaomi</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei">Huawei Technologies</a> – into the auto sector. It is working on bringing its projector technology into cars to, among other things, turn the windscreen into an AR display. The company said this enhances safety because drivers do not need to take their eyes off the road when getting information like navigation.</p><p>“If you’re on the road and your smart refrigerator can tell you, ‘hey, you’re out of eggs; so on your way home, stop by and pick up some eggs,’ that’s the idea that we’re going for,” Gold said.</p><p>Many tech firms are betting on cars as the next big area of growth. As leaders in electric vehicles, Chinese companies are benefiting from the trend. Carmakers <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/li-auto">Li Auto</a>, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/great-wall-motors" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/topics/great-wall-motors">Great Wall Motor</a>, Zeekr and Xiaomi will all <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector" target="_self" title="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector">use Nvidia’s Drive tech</a> for autonomous driving, the chip firm announced on Monday.</p><p>Samsung and Sony also discussed their own partnerships with carmakers in their presentations on Monday. Sony has partnered with Honda on its Afeela joint venture, while Samsung is partnering with Hyundai to bring its SmartThings platform to cars.</p><p>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>JD.com’s on-demand delivery unit, Dada Nexus, loses 46 per cent of US stock value overnight amid internal inquiry into potential fraud</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247804/jdcoms-demand-delivery-unit-dada-nexus-loses-46-cent-us-stock-value-overnight-amid-internal-inquiry</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Shanghai-based Dada Nexus, an on-demand delivery firm affiliated with JD.com, disclosed questionable revenue and costs amounting to US$140 million in its books during the first three quarters of 2023.</li>    <li>The internal audit revealed overstated revenue from online advertising and marketing services and operational costs.</li>    <li>Dada Nexus's stock value dropped by 46% in New York following the news, further eroding investor confidence in Chinese tech stocks.</li>    <li>Xin Lijun, Dada Nexus's chairman, resigned in December 2023, and Chen Zhaoming, the chief financial officer, also stepped down.</li>    <li>The company reported the potential fraud case to local police and is working with third-party agencies to conduct an independent review.</li>    <li>Dada Nexus's operations include JD Daojia, JD.com's on-demand retail platform, and Dada Now, which works with brick-and-mortar retailers to fulfill and deliver online orders.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Chinese Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>总部位于上海的京东到家关联企业达达集团，在2023年前三季度账目中发现10亿元的可疑收入和成本。</li>    <li>内部审计揭示了在线广告和营销服务收入以及运营成本的夸大。</li>    <li>达达集团的股票价值在纽约下跌46%，进一步侵蚀了投资者对中国科技股的信心。</li>    <li>达达集团董事长新利军于2023年12月辞职，首席财务官陈照明也已离职。</li>    <li>该公司已向当地警方报案，并正与第三方机构合作进行独立审查。</li>    <li>达达集团的业务包括京东到家、京东的按需零售平台和达达快送，后者与实体零售商合作，以履行和交付在线订单。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>nexus (n.) - /ˈneksəs/ 联系，连接。    <p>原文例句：Dada Nexus, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin，由nectere（连接）衍生而来，表示“连接，联系”。在这个例句中，它指的是达达集团，一家经营京东到家和达达快送的按需配送公司。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>overstate (v.) - /ˌoʊvərˈsteɪt/ 夸大，夸饰。    <p>原文例句：While the amount that is subject of the inquiry makes up just about a third of Dada’s total revenue in the September quarter, a potential fraud in the company’s books could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese internet stocks. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词是由over（超过，高于）和state（状态，陈述）构成的，表示“夸大，夸饰”。在这个例句中，它指的是达达集团可能夸大了其在2023年9月季度的收入，这可能会进一步损害投资者对中国互联网股票的信心。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>internal audit - 内部审计。    <p>原文例句：A routine internal audit at Dada found US$140 million worth of questionable revenue and costs in the firm’s books for the first three quarters of 2023. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“内部审计”，即由公司内部人员对公司的财务状况、经营情况等进行审查和评价。在这个例句中，达达集团进行了一次内部审计，发现2023年前三季度账目中有10亿元的可疑收入和成本。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>potential case of fraud - 潜在的欺诈案件。    <p>原文例句：Shanghai-based Dada has reported the potential case of fraud to police, according to local media. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示“潜在的欺诈案件”，即可能存在的欺诈行为。在这个例句中，上海达达集团已向警方报案，称其内部审计发现潜在的欺诈案件。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>On-demand delivery firm Dada Nexus lost 46 per cent of its stock value in New York on Monday, following an inquiry into “suspicious” data during an internal audit, dealing a fresh blow to confidence in China’s tech stocks. - 按需配送公司达达集团周一在纽约股市下跌46%，此前该公司在内部审计期间对“可疑”数据进行调查，这给中国科技股的信心带来了新的打击。<p>句子分析：这是一个长句，主句是Dada Nexus lost 46 per cent of its stock value in New York on Monday，其中主语是Dada Nexus，谓语是lost，宾语是46 per cent of its stock value。following an inquiry into “suspicious” data during an internal audit是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰Dada Nexus lost 46 per cent of its stock value in New York on Monday，表示这一事件发生在内部审计期间对“可疑”数据进行调查之后。dealing a fresh blow to confidence in China’s tech stocks是一个现在分词短语作状语，修饰Dada Nexus lost 46 per cent of its stock value in New York on Monday，表示这一事件导致中国科技股的信心受到新的打击。这个句子的意思是说，按需配送公司达达集团周一在纽约股市下跌46%，此前该公司在内部审计期间对“可疑”数据进行调查，这给中国科技股的信心带来了新的打击。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>副词修饰形容词 - 副词可以修饰形容词，使形容词的程度或范围更加明确。    <p>原文例句：JD Daojia operates in more than 1,700 counties, districts and cities across mainland China, while Dada Now does business in 2,700 domestic locations. </p>    <p>语法讲解：在这个例句中，副词more than修饰了形容词1,700，表示京东到家在中国大陆的1,700多个县、区和城市运营。副词domestic修饰了形容词2,700，表示达达快送在中国大陆的2,700个城市开展业务。这些副词使形容词的程度和范围更加明确，使读者对京东到家和达达快送的运营范围有了更清晰的了解。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>A routine internal audit at Dada found US$140 million worth of questionable revenue and costs in the firm’s books for the first three quarters of 2023</li>
<li>Shanghai-based Dada has reported the potential case of fraud to police, according to local media</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/c047f84e-6340-412a-9bce-843911227d91_14f4c464.jpg" /><figcaption>A potential case of fraud at JD.com-affiliated, on-demand delivery firm Dada Nexus could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese tech stocks. Image: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>An on-demand delivery firm affiliated with Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/jdcom" target="_self" title="">JD.com</a> lost 46 per cent of its stock value in New York on Monday, following an inquiry into “suspicious” data during an internal audit, dealing a fresh blow to confidence in China’s tech stocks.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3195587/jdcoms-logistics-arm-pushes-ahead-unmanned-robotic-grocery-deliveries" target="_self" title="">Dada Nexus</a>, which operates JD Daojia and Dada Now, found 1 billion yuan (US$140 million) worth of questionable revenue and costs in its books for the first three quarters of 2023 during a routine internal audit, according to its corporate filing. Parent JD.com’s share price tumbled 3 per cent on Tuesday in Hong Kong.</p><p>Nasdaq-listed Dada said an estimated 500 million yuan of online advertising and marketing service revenue plus another 500 million yuan of operations and support costs for the first three quarters of 2023 may have been overstated.</p><p>While the amount that is subject of the inquiry makes up just about a third of Dada’s total revenue in the September quarter, a potential fraud in the company’s books could further undermine investor confidence in Chinese <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/internet" target="_self" title="">internet</a> stocks.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/933378cf-3ccc-42bf-a060-3d2efc2145c7_55c83460.jpg" title="Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg" width="2000" /><figcaption>Dada Nexus chairman Xin Lijun stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” on December 19, 2023. That came more than a month after he was removed as chief executive of JD Retail in November. Photo: Bloomberg</figcaption></figure></div><p>The investigation at Dada comes nearly a month since the company’s chairman, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3241791/chinese-e-commerce-giant-jdcom-removes-veteran-executive-retail-ceo-after-brutal-singles-day-price" target="_self" title="">Xin Liju</a>n, stepped down from his post “for personal reasons” effective on December 19. In that same corporate announcement of management changes at Dada, Chen Zhaoming resigned as the firm’s chief financial officer.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a>-based Dada, according to a report by Chinese news outlet The Paper, has reported the potential fraud case to local police.</p><p>A JD.com representative referred the South China Morning Post to Dada’s US filing and declined to provide further details. Dada did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Tuesday.</p><p>Dada had earlier said it was working with third-party agencies, including an accounting company and a law firm, to conduct an independent review of the case.</p><p>In separate filings with regulators, both JD.com and Dada said they are committed to maintaining high corporate-governance standards and internal controls.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246715/chinese-e-commerce-giant-jdcom-wins-antitrust-lawsuit-against-alibaba-which-was-ordered-beijing" title="">Chinese e-commerce giant JD.com wins antitrust lawsuit against Alibaba</a></h3><p>Founded in Shanghai in 2014, Dada runs two core businesses: parent JD.com’s on-demand retail platform JD Daojia and its own Dada Now. Both these operations work with bricks-and-mortar retailers and merchants on fulfilment, including delivery of online orders to consumers in under roughly an hour.</p><p>JD Daojia operates in more than 1,700 counties, districts and cities across mainland China, while Dada Now does business in 2,700 domestic locations.</p><p>In November, Dada reported that total third-quarter revenue rose 20.4 per cent year on year to 2.9 billion yuan.</p><p>On-demand delivery is a hotly contested field on the mainland, where Dada competes against the likes of food delivery giant <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/meituan" target="_self" title="">Meituan</a> and JD.com rival <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a>, which owns the Post.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>ByteDance confirms talks with Tencent, other potential buyers over sale of video game operations</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247766/bytedance-confirms-talks-tencent-other-potential-buyers-over-sale-video-game-operations</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  ByteDance, the owner of TikTok and Douyin, reportedly attempted to lower the valuation of its gaming studios after investing heavily in game development. The sale of various titles and shutting down some unreleased projects occurred due to failed returns from past gaming-related expenses. Although ByteDance confirmed negotiations with Tencent, no agreement has been reached yet. The purpose of the restructuring is to focus on long-term growth amidst the company's tremendous success with its short video platforms. Despite spending billions on gaming studios, revenue from this sector made up less than 1% of their total income in the first half of 2023. ByteDance's founder wasn't a gaming enthusiast and the head of their gaming unit had a strategy and consulting background rather than a gaming background. Slow development and lack of progress prompted the decision to restructure the gaming division and focus on long-term growth.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: ByteDance's failed gaming investments lead to restructuring and sale of studios.</li>    <li>Theme: Despite the success of TikTok and Douyin, ByteDance struggles to make profits from its gaming ventures.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: ByteDance's attempts to make a deal reflect the challenges of generating revenue from gaming investments, and the growing emphasis on strategic growth in the company.</li>    <li>Main information: Lowering valuation of gaming studios; sale of unreleased titles; restructuring of gaming unit; ByteDance's past gaming expenses and returns; lack of progress in the gaming division.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  字节跳动，即抖音和今日头条的所有者，据报道，在大量投资游戏开发之后，试图降低其游戏工作室的估值。由于先前与游戏相关的支出未能产生回报，该公司出售了几个游戏作品，并且关闭了一些未发布项目。尽管字节跳动证实了与腾讯的谈判，但双方尚未达成协议。进行重组的目的是专注于长期增长，尽管公司旗下的短视频平台取得了巨大成功。尽管在游戏工作室花费了数十亿美元，但游戏部门在 2023 年上半年的收入只占其总收入的不到 1%。字节跳动的创始人并不是一个游戏发烧友，而其游戏部门的负责人具有战略和咨询背景，而不是游戏背景。缓慢的开发和缺乏进展促使公司决定重组游戏部门，专注于长期增长。  <ul>    <li>摘要：字节跳动游戏投资失败，导致工作室重组和出售。</li>    <li>主题：字节跳动虽然在抖音和今日头条上大获成功，但其游戏业务一直难以盈利。</li>    <li>观点：字节跳动试图达成交易，反映了从游戏投资中获取收入的挑战性，以及公司日益重视战略增长。</li>    <li>主要信息：降低游戏工作室估值；出售未发行游戏作品；重组游戏部门；字节跳动先前游戏支出及其回报；游戏部门缺乏进展。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - 营业收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：Tencent Holdings, the world’s biggest gaming company by revenue.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Revenue是指公司的销售收入和相关的营业收入，是公司财务报表中的重要项目，也是衡量公司经营业绩的重要指标。在这个例句中，它表示腾讯控股是全球最大的游戏公司，以收入计算。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>valuation (n.) - 估值，评价。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance was lowering the valuation of its video gaming studios to try and make a deal.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Valuation是指对资产或公司的价值进行评估，以确定其价值。在这个例句中，它表示字节跳动正在降低其视频游戏工作室的估值，试图达成交易。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>restructure (v.) - 重组，调整。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance said at the time that it decided to “restructure its gaming business” and “make adjustments to focus on long-term strategic growth areas”.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Restructure是指对组织或公司的结构进行调整，以提高效率或适应 changing circumstances。在这个例句中，它表示字节跳动当时表示决定“重组其游戏业务”并“调整以专注于长期战略增长领域”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>make a deal - 达成交易，达成协议。    <P>原文例句：ByteDance was lowering the valuation of its gaming studios to try and make a deal. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示通过谈判或协商，达成交易或协议。在这个例句中，它表示字节跳动正在降低其视频游戏工作室的估值，试图达成交易。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>long-term strategic growth areas - 长期战略增长领域。    <P>原文例句：ByteDance said at the time that it decided to “make adjustments to focus on long-term strategic growth areas”. </P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组表示在制定长期战略规划时，企业或组织重点关注的领域，以实现可持续发展和竞争优势。在这个例句中，它表示字节跳动决定“调整以专注于长期战略增长领域”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>ByteDance founder Zhang Yiming, who stepped down as chairman and CEO in 2021, was never a video gaming enthusiast before dipping his toe in the market. - 字节跳动创始人张一鸣，在 2021 年卸任董事长兼首席执行官之前，在涉足游戏市场之前一直都不是电子游戏爱好者。<p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Zhang Yiming was never a video gaming enthusiast before dipping his toe in the market，其中主语是Zhang Yiming，谓语是was，宾语是a video gaming enthusiast，状语是before dipping his toe in the market。who stepped down as chairman and CEO in 2021是一个现在分词短语作定语，修饰Zhang Yiming，表示张一鸣在 2021 年卸任董事长兼首席执行官。这个句子的意思是说，字节跳动创始人张一鸣，在 2021 年卸任董事长兼首席执行官之前一直都不是电子游戏爱好者。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去的某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance founder Zhang Yiming, who stepped down as chairman and CEO in 2021, was never a video gaming enthusiast before dipping his toe in the market.</p>    <p>语法讲解：过去完成时态结构是：had + 过去分词。它表示在过去的某个时间点之前已经完成的动作或状态。在这个例句中，had stepped down 表示在涉足游戏市场之前，张一鸣已经卸任董事长兼首席执行官。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 用于表达假设、愿望、可能性或不确定性。    <p>原文例句：ByteDance also started lay-offs at its games unit, which employs nearly 2,000 people, although the exact number of affected employees was not clear. </p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气在从句中使用，以表达假设、愿望、可能性或不确定性。它通常用were来代替was，用had been来代替had，用would来代替will。在这个例句中，although the exact number of affected employees was not clear是一个让步状语从句，其中用了虚拟语气，表示尽管受影响的员工的确切数量尚不清楚，但字节跳动也开始在其游戏部门裁员。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Local media reported that ByteDance was lowering the valuation of its gaming studios to try and make a deal after spending more than US$14 million developing titles</li>
<li>Despite its huge success with short video app TikTok and its Chinese version Douyin, ByteDance has failed to achieve returns from its gaming investments</li>
</ul><p>TikTok owner ByteDance has confirmed that it is in talks with multiple potential buyers for its video game operations, including Tencent Holdings, the world’s biggest gaming company by revenue.</p><p>The confirmation from a ByteDance representative on Tuesday came after local media outlet LatePost reported that the company's gaming unit Nuverse was in negotiations with Tencent regarding the disposal of its operations. According to the report, ByteDance was lowering the valuation of its video gaming studios to try and make a deal after spending more than 100 million yuan (US$14 million) developing various titles.</p><p>The representative said that the company has not reached an agreement with Tencent.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3242972/tiktok-owner-bytedance-retreats-video-gaming-cuts-main-studio-amid-stagnating-market-dominated" target="_self" title="">In November, the South China Morning Post reported</a> that the Beijing-based company told employees that it would shut down most game projects that had not been released online, and sell rights to at least two of its titles – the anime-style role-playing game <em>Crystal of Atlan</em> and sci-fi survival game <em>Earth: Revival.</em></p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247123/chinas-erratic-regulatory-moves-against-big-tech-firms-must-end-says-communist-party-newspaper-after" title="">China’s erratic regulatory moves against Big Tech must end, party paper says</a></h3><p>ByteDance also started lay-offs at its games unit, which employs nearly 2,000 people, although the exact number of affected employees was not clear. Some workers who want to remain at ByteDance could be allowed to transfer to other teams, the Post reported.</p><p>A ByteDance representative said at the time that it decided to “restructure its gaming business” and “make adjustments to focus on long-term strategic growth areas”.</p><p>Despite its huge success with short video app TikTok and its Chinese version Douyin, ByteDance has failed to achieve returns from its video gaming investments. The company spent around 30 billion yuan on video game acquisitions and investments involving more than 20 studios between 2019 and 2022, according to local media outlet DingjiaoOne.</p><p>“While the company made US$54 billion in the first half of 2023, less than 1 per cent of that came from their video games business,” said Lisa Hanson, chief executive of gaming industry consultancy Niko Partners.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Crystal of Atlan, the action role-playing game developed by ByteDance’s Nuverse studio, is up for sale. Photo: Handout" class="image-inline caption" height="1037" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/1b444be4-f8e0-4989-bcc0-6ad82a22dc7a_d4f55384.jpg" title="Crystal of Atlan, the action role-playing game developed by ByteDance’s Nuverse studio, is up for sale. Photo: Handout" width="2000" /><figcaption>Crystal of Atlan, the action role-playing game developed by ByteDance’s Nuverse studio, is up for sale. Photo: Handout</figcaption></figure></div><p>ByteDance founder Zhang Yiming, who stepped down as chairman and CEO in 2021, was never a video gaming enthusiast before dipping his toe in the market.</p><p>Yan Shou, head of ByteDance’s video gaming unit, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3246294/after-tiktok-owner-bytedance-cuts-fat-focus-fundamentals-social-commerce-challenges-and-us-election" target="_self" title="">spent most of his career in strategic investments</a> and hired several people with a consulting and strategy background to help him run the unit, the Post reported.</p><p>Zhang had grown impatient with the slow development, complaining in 2022 about the lack of progress at the gaming division during a video call with executives, saying that its Moonton studio had not grown despite doubling its headcount, tech media outlet The Information reported in December. Reuters reported a month earlier that ByteDance was in talks to sell Moonton.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia rolls out new chips, claims leadership of &#39;AI PC&#39; race</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247752/nvidia-rolls-out-new-chips-claims-leadership-ai-pc-race</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia unveils new AI-powered computer chips, claiming they are more secure and responsive than internet-based AI.</li>    <li>The GeForce RTX 4080 Super graphics chip offers a significant performance boost for AI software like Stable Diffusion XL.</li>    <li>Nvidia emphasizes the advantage of running AI software on personal computers rather than relying on remote services.</li>    <li>The new chips are expected to drive demand for AI-capable laptops and desktops among gamers, designers, and other users.</li>    <li>Nvidia's stock price surged after the announcement, reaching a record high and pushing the company's market value above $1 trillion.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文翻译：</h2>  <ul>    <li>英伟达发布新型人工智能芯片，宣称其安全性与响应速度优于基于互联网的人工智能。</li>    <li>GeForce RTX 4080 Super 图形芯片为 AI 软件（如 Stable Diffusion XL）提供了显著的性能提升。</li>    <li>英伟达强调了在个人电脑上运行人工智能软件的优势，而非依赖于远程服务。</li>    <li>新芯片有望带动游戏玩家、设计师和其他用户对支持人工智能的笔记本电脑和台式机提出需求。</li>    <li>英伟达的股价在公布后大幅上涨，创下历史新高，并推动公司市值突破1万亿美元。（一万亿的后面是美元）</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>lure (v.) - /lʊər/ 吸引，诱惑。    <p>原文例句：The PC makers are desperate to lure cash-strapped young consumers to replace their old computers. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Middle English，意为“引诱，诱惑”。在这个例句中，它描述了PC制造商急切地希望吸引囊中羞涩的年轻消费者来更换他们旧的电脑。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>stoutly (adv.) - /staʊtli/ 坚决地，坚定地。    <p>原文例句：The PC makers stoutly denied that their machines were vulnerable to such an attack. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English，意为“强壮的，坚固的”。在这个例句中，它描述了PC制造商坚决否认他们的机器容易受到此类攻击。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>turn over - 轮流做，轮换，轮到。    <p>原文例句：All the other people had turned over and gone back to sleep. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由turn（转动，翻转）和over（完成，结束）构成的，表示“轮流做，轮换，轮到”。在这个例句中，它描述了其他人轮流翻身并回到睡梦中。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>A spokesman, quoted by the China Securities Journal, attributed this to high expectations of the company’s new AI products. - 一位发言人被中国证券报引用称这是由于公众对公司的全新人工智能产品的巨大期望。</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个被动态句，其中A spokesman是句子的主语，attributed this to high expectations of the company’s new AI products是句子的谓语，其中attributed是谓语动词，this是宾语，to high expectations of the company’s new AI products是介词短语作原因状语，表示“对公司全新人工智能产品的巨大期望”。这个句子说的是，一位发言人将此归因于公众对公司全新人工智能产品的巨大期望。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>"So...that"句型 - 表示结果或目的。    <p>原文例句：I do this so that I can help more people find the information they need. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个包含so...that的复合句，表示结果或目的。结构是：so + 形容词或副词 + that + 子句。其中so相当于如此，形容词或副词用于强调，that引导子句，子句表示结果或目的。在这个例句中，so是如此，that引导的子句表示结果，即如此帮助更多的人找到他们需要的信息。这个句子的意思是说，我这样做是为了帮助更多的人找到他们需要的信息。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 在某些情况下，表示想象或愿望。    <p>原文例句：In Ireland, last year, you could do whatever you wanted and you didn’t have to wash your hands. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一种语气，用于表示说话者对事实或情况的猜测、想象或愿望。结构是：助动词（could、would、should、might等）+ 主语 + 动词原形。在这个例句中，助动词是could，主语是you，动词原形是do，表示说话者对过去在爱尔兰可以做任何想做的事情并不必洗手的情况的想象或猜测。这个句子的意思是说，在爱尔兰，去年，你可以做任何你想做的事情，而不必洗手。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Intel and AMD have already touted AI PCs as a new era for the industry, arguing that AI software is more secure and responsive on the PC than over the internet</li>
<li>The new GeForce RTX 4080 Super&nbsp;can run Stable Diffusion XL image generation software 1.7 times faster than the equivalent model from the previous generation</li>
</ul><p>Nvidia, whose chip technology dominates in data centres used to create artificial intelligence (AI) software, announced new products to help the personal computer industry lure consumers with “AI PCs”.</p><p>Nvidia unveiled three new desktop graphics chips with extra components that will let gamers, designers and other computer users make better use of AI on their personal machines, without having to rely on remote services accessed over the internet. The chips, updated versions of existing offerings, will be offered at a “great new price”, the company said on Monday in a presentation at the CES trade show in Las Vegas.</p><p>The company's major rivals, Intel and Advanced Micro Devices, have already touted what they say is a new era for the industry: AI PCs. The companies argue that AI software is more secure and responsive when it is run on the PCs themselves rather than over the internet.</p><p>Nvidia now claims its graphics chips are the best engines to power the new types of laptops and desktops.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector" title="">Nvidia expands its reach in China’s electric vehicle sector</a></h3><p>The new GeForce RTX 4080 Super will get more processing cores and faster memory. It can run Stable Diffusion XL image generation software 1.7 times faster than the equivalent model from the previous generation of Nvidia technology, the company said. The new chip will also power games with ray tracing – building an image by calculating the path of individual rays of light – at 4K resolution.</p><p>The product is scheduled to go on sale from January 31 for US$999. The company also unveiled an RTX 4070 Ti Super for US$799 and a 4070 Super for US$599, which will be available later this month.</p><p>Paired with new software and optimisations of AI models that Nvidia is also releasing, the products will offer an “order-of-magnitude” improvement over machines that are powered by Intel chips, according to Justin Walker, an Nvidia vice-president.</p><p>Nvidia’s stock rose as much as 5 per cent in New York trading on Monday, taking it back above US$500 a share to a record high. The stock more than tripled last year, giving the company a market value of more than US$1 trillion.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>After a spike in sales during the pandemic, PC shipments have fallen steeply, leaving makers and component suppliers burdened with inventory and little growth. Nvidia has avoided the worst of the PC plunge by owning the market for accelerator chips used to create AI software in data centres. The explosion in demand for that more expensive type of chip has pushed Nvidia’s market value past US$1 trillion, making it the most valuable company in the history of the semiconductor industry.</p><p>For chip makers in general, though, the majority of the volume they ship still goes into PCs. They are searching for a way to persuade laptop owners and corporate buyers to upgrade their equipment and have begun touting AI capabilities as a reason for new purchases.</p><p>Nvidia said the new chips will provide more realistic gaming with high-definition images enhanced by AI, which will also generate improved dialogue by in-game characters. In another example, the products will provide more responsive tools for image-editing software from companies such as Adobe. There are currently 500 applications that are tuned to work better with AI and Nvidia’s RTX technology, the company said.</p><p>Separately, Nvidia said the capabilities of its new products will not trigger rules put in place by the US government to limit the export of AI-related chips to China. The top-of-the-line GTX 4090 already fell afoul of those restrictions, requiring Nvidia to produce a less-capable version for that market.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Apple’s Vision Pro headset launches next month, as US tech giant seeks to expand mixed-reality market</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247747/apples-vision-pro-headset-launches-next-month-company-seeks-expand-mixed-reality-market</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  On January 19, Apple will begin taking pre-orders for its highly priced Vision Pro virtual-reality headset, a cutting-edge device that blurs the line between the physical and digital worlds. With a starting price of US$3,500, the headset is compatible with over a million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad, ensuring a diverse app ecosystem. However, the substantial cost and requirement for a store visit for a proper fitting are potential obstacles to widespread adoption. Apple's strategy aims to introduce more affordable versions in the future, paving the way for broader market penetration.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Apple's Vision Pro headset combines virtual and real worlds, offering a wide range of apps and controlled eye and hand interactions.</li>    <li>Theme: Apple enters the virtual-reality market with the high-end Vision Pro headset, targeting a broader audience beyond gamers and tech enthusiasts.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The headset's high price and requirement for store fitting may limit initial sales, despite its sophisticated technology and compatibility with iPhone and iPad apps.</li>    <li>Main information: Pre-orders start January 19; headset compatible with over a million apps; in-store fitting required; plans for future affordable versions and inclusion of 3D video capabilities in iPhones.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  1月19日，苹果将开始接受其高昂的Vision Pro虚拟现实头盔的预购，这是一款模糊物理和数字世界界限的尖端设备。这款售价3500美元起的头盔与一百万多款专为iPhone和iPad设计的应用程序兼容，确保了应用程序生态系统的多样性。然而，高昂的成本和需要到店进行适当的配件是广泛采用的潜在障碍。苹果的战略是未来推出更实惠的版本，为更广泛的市场渗透铺平道路。  <ul>    <li>摘要：苹果公司的Vision Pro头盔结合了虚拟和现实世界，提供了广泛的应用程序和受控的眼睛和手部交互。</li>    <li>主题：苹果公司带着高端的Vision Pro头盔进入虚拟现实市场，目标是超越游戏玩家和技术爱好者的更广泛的受众。</li>    <li>观点：尽管这款头盔采用了先进的技术，并与iPhone和iPad应用程序兼容，但其昂贵的价格和需要在商店进行配件可能会限制最初的销售。</li>    <li>主要信息：1月19日开始预订；耳机兼容一百多万个应用程序；需要在商店里试穿；计划推出未来更实惠的版本，并在iPhone中加入3D视频功能。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>unveiled (v.) - /ʌnˈveɪld/ 解开，揭开，公开。    <p>原文例句：Apple unveiled the sleek US$3,500 goggles at a software conference held at its Cupertino, California, headquarters eight months ago. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由un-（不是）和veil（面纱）组成，表示“揭开，公开”，通常用于正式或新颖的事情首次被展示或披露时。在这个例句中，它表示苹果公司八个月前在其位于加利福尼亚州库比蒂诺的总部举行的软件发布会上，公布了售价3500美元的时尚护目镜。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>virtual-reality (n.) - /ˈvɜːrtʃuːəl riˈælɪti/ 虚拟现实，虚拟实境。    <p>原文例句：Apple’s high-priced headset for toggling between the real and digital world will be available in its stores beginning February 2. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词由virtual（虚拟的）和reality（现实）组成，表示“虚拟现实”，是指使用计算机技术创造出一种虚拟的世界，使人有亲临其境的感觉。在这个例句中，它指的是苹果公司将从2月2日起在其商店销售一款高价头戴式虚拟现实设备，使人们能够在现实世界和数字世界之间切换。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>for years - 多年来，很多年。    <p>原文例句：Facebook owner Meta Platforms and other companies have been making virtual-reality headsets for years with limited success. </p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由for（为了，对于）和years（年）组成，表示“很多年，多年来”的意思。在这个例句中，它指的是Facebook所有者Meta公司和其他公司多年来一直在制造虚拟现实头戴式设备，但并没有取得很大的成功。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Apple unveils the sleek US$3,500 goggles at a software conference held at its Cupertino, California, headquarters eight months ago. - 八个月前，苹果公司在其位于加利福尼亚州库比蒂诺的总部举行的一场软件发布会上公布了售价3500美元的时尚护目镜。<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的过去时态的句子，主语是Apple，谓语是unveils，宾语是the sleek US$3,500 goggles。at a software conference held at its Cupertino, California, headquarters eight months ago是一个过去分词短语作状语，表示八个月前在位于加利福尼亚州库比蒂诺的总部举行的一场软件发布会上。这个句子的意思是说，八个月前，苹果公司在其位于加利福尼亚州库比蒂诺的总部举行的一场软件发布会上公布了售价3500美元的时尚护目镜。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>被动语态 - 表示动作或状态的承受者或接受者。    <p>原文例句：Its price tag probably means relatively few unit sales during its first year on the market. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子使用了被动语态，其中probably means是谓语，而relatively few unit sales是承受动作或状态的宾语。句子中的few unit sales是指相对较少的销量，而relatively则是表示相对的程度，on the market是指在市场上。这个句子的意思是说，这个产品的价格可能会意味着在其上市的第一年里，销量相对较少。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>过去完成时 - 表示在过去的某个时间或动作之前已经完成的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这个句子使用了过去完成时，其中with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023是谓语，而Apple CEO Tim Cook则是承受动作或状态的宾语。句子中的Apple CEO Tim Cook是指苹果公司首席执行官蒂姆·库克，而with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023则是表示在2023年6月5日苹果全球开发者大会上戴着Vision Pro虚拟现实头戴式设备。这个句子的意思是说，苹果公司首席执行官蒂姆·库克在2023年6月5日苹果全球开发者大会上戴着Vision Pro虚拟现实头戴式设备。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad, with pre-orders beginning January 19</li>
<li>Industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far</li>
</ul><p>Apple’s high-priced headset for toggling between the real and digital world will be available in its stores beginning February 2, launching the trendsetting company’s push to broaden the appeal of what so far has been a niche technology.</p><p>Apple unveiled the sleek US$3,500 goggles at a software conference held at its Cupertino, California, headquarters eight months ago – an event that was designed to encourage developers to make apps tailored for a device that projects users into three-dimensional simulations of reality.</p><p>Apple’s announcement coincides with the annual CES trade show in Las Vegas, where the company has long been conspicuously absent.</p><p>Apple says the goggles’ operating system will be compatible with more than 1 million apps designed for the iPhone and iPad. Pre-orders begin January 19, but buyers will have to go to a store to be properly fitted for the goggles, which are controlled with the eyes and a few simple hand gestures.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3247367/qualcomm-unveils-chip-mixed-reality-compete-apples-vision-pro" title="">Qualcomm unveils chip for mixed reality to compete with Apple’s Vision Pro</a></h3><p>Although Facebook owner Meta Platforms and other companies have been making virtual-reality headsets for years with limited success, many industry analysts believe Apple has the potential to expand the technology’s audience beyond the video gamers and mostly tech nerds that have embraced it so far.</p><p>The Vision Pro already has got largely enthusiastic reviews among the media who were able to test it in tightly controlled demonstrations monitored by Apple, but the device’s price tag probably means relatively few unit sales during its first year on the market.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" class="image-inline caption" height="1271" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/c20a30fc-1af5-4a7c-af6e-4132fe5d819a_b9343cec.jpg" title="Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS" width="2000" /><figcaption>Apple CEO Tim Cook with the Vision Pro virtual reality headset during Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference, June 5, 2023. Photo: AFP/Getty Images/TNS</figcaption></figure></div><p>Even so, Apple’s first new product since its smartwatch debuted a decade ago could set the stage for the introduction of more affordable versions for a broader audience. Right now, the Vision Pro will cost seven times more than Meta’s latest virtual-reality headset, the Quest 3.</p><p>In a sign that Apple is expecting the Vision Pro to pave the way to a bigger market, the company included the ability to take 3D videos that can be viewed through the goggles on its latest premium iPhones, the 15 Pro and 15 Pro Max. These videos are so realistic that the people and other images in them appear to be right in front of the viewer watching them.</p><p>Apple is looking for ways to juice its sales after suffering a slight decline in revenue during its last fiscal year ended September. Apple still raked in US$383 billion in sales, with the iPhone accounting for more than half that amount.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Samsung profit tumbles 35% as chip weakness persists</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247740/samsung-profit-tumbles-35-chip-weakness-persists</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Samsung Electronics recorded its sixth consecutive quarter of declining operating profit, reflecting weak global demand for consumer electronics.</li>    <li>The company's operating income dropped by 35% to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), against analysts' estimates of 3.7 trillion won.</li>    <li>Despite the downturn, Samsung plans to aggressively expand its capacity in high-density memory chips, targeting a 2.5-fold increase by 2024.</li>    <li>The company remains optimistic that the long-depressed memory market will recover in 2024, driven by advancements in artificial intelligence and data center construction.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>三星电子连续第六个季度营业利润下降，反映出全球消费电子需求疲软。</li>    <li>该公司的营业收入下降35%，至2.8万亿韩元（21亿美元），而分析师的平均估计为3.7万亿韩元。</li>    <li>尽管出现下滑，三星计划积极扩大其高密度存储芯片的产能，目标是在2024年增长2.5倍。</li>    <li>该公司仍然乐观地认为，长期低迷的内存市场将在2024年复苏，这将受到人工智能和数据中心建设的推动。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>sluggish (adj.) - /ˈslʌɡɪʃ/ 迟缓的，不活跃的。    <p>原文例句：Demand for smartphones and the memory chips that power modern electronics remains sluggish given economic uncertainty.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Old English的“sleac”，意思是“懒惰的、迟缓的”。在这个例句中，它描述了智能手机和现代电子产品所需的内存芯片的需求仍然缓慢，反映了经济的不确定性。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>accelerator (n.) - /ækˈsɛlərˌeɪtər/ 加速器。    <p>原文例句：HBM, an advanced chip that handles data more quickly, works with hardware such as Nvidia’s accelerators to speed up data processing for intensive tasks like training AI models.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于Latin的“accelerare”，意思是“加快，加速”。在这个例句中，它指的是一种先进的芯片，可以更快地处理数据，与英伟达的加速器等硬件配合使用，可以加速处理密集型任务，如训练人工智能模型。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>deployment (n.) - /dɪˈplɔɪmənt/ 部署，配置。    <p>原文例句：“Prices are not rising that fast and the demand from certain sectors is not that strong.”</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个单词来源于“deploy”，意思是“部署，配置”。在这个例句中，它描述了价格没有上升那么快，并且来自某些部门的需求并不那么强劲。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>catch up with - 赶上，追上。    <p>原文例句：Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由catch（抓住）和up with（跟上）组成的，表示“赶上，追上”。在这个例句中，它表示三星现在致力于在快速发展的高密度存储芯片领域赶上竞争对手SK海力士。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>running out of steam - 失去动力，失去势头。    <p>原文例句：At a time investors worry Apple’s iPhone 15 may be running out of steam mere months after launch.</p>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由run out（用完）和steam（蒸汽）构成的，比喻地表示“失去动力，失去势头”。在这个例句中，它描述了在投资者担心苹果的iPhone 15可能在发布后几个月内失去动力的时候。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES - 科技巨头阿里巴巴和字节跳动引领中国企业重返CES。    <p>句子分析：这是一个复合句，主句是Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES，其中主语是Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance，谓语是lead，宾语是China’s return to CES。这是一个简单句，主语是Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance，谓语是lead，宾语是China’s return to CES。lead China’s return to CES是一个复合宾语，其中China’s return to CES是一个名词短语，作宾语，lead是一个动词，作谓语。lead China’s return to CES这个复合宾语的意思是“引领中国企业重返CES”。这个句子的意思是说，科技巨头阿里巴巴和字节跳动引领中国企业重返CES。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>强调句型 - 表示强调。    <p>原文例句：The company will release a full earnings report, with divisional breakdowns, on January 31.</p>    <p>语法讲解：强调句型通常使用there be句型或倒装句型。在这个例句中，使用的是there be句型，其中主语是The company，谓语是will release，宾语是a full earnings report, with divisional breakdowns。there be句型表示强调，强调主语The company将发布一个完整的收益报告，其中包含部门细分。这个句子的意思是说，该公司将于1月31日发布一份完整的收益报告，其中包含部门细分。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>虚拟语气 - 表示虚拟或假定的情况。    <p>原文例句：“I think this shows that the rebound is slower than we all thought,” said Tom Kang, research director at Counterpoint Technology.</p>    <p>语法讲解：虚拟语气通常使用would、should、could、might、may等情态动词。在这个例句中，使用的是would，表示虚拟或假定的情况，即汤姆·康认为这次反弹比我们想象的要慢。这个句子的意思是说，康特波因特技术研究所的研究总监汤姆·康说：“我认为这表明反弹速度比我们想象的要慢。”</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>South Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates</li>
<li>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024</li>
</ul><p>Samsung Electronics posted its sixth straight quarter of declining operating profit, reflecting stubbornly weak demand for consumer electronics globally.</p><p>South Korea’s largest company reported a 35 per cent fall in operating income to 2.8 trillion won (US$2.1 billion), versus the 3.7 trillion won average of analysts’ estimates. Revenue came to 67 trillion won, compared with projections for 70.31 trillion won.</p><p>The results underscore how demand for smartphones and the memory chips that power modern electronics remains sluggish given economic uncertainty.</p><p>In December, rival Micron Technology delivered a better-than-projected revenue outlook that suggested data centre construction may make up for the lukewarm computing and mobile devices markets.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247657/ces-2024-chinese-tech-giants-alibaba-bytedance-lead-chinas-return-premier-consumer-electronics-show" title="">Tech giants Alibaba, ByteDance lead China’s return to CES</a></h3><p>“I think this shows that the rebound is slower than we all thought,” said Tom Kang, research director at Counterpoint Technology. “Prices are not rising that fast and the demand from certain sectors is not that strong.”</p><p>Samsung in October predicted the long-depressed US$160 billion memory market will bounce back gradually in 2024, driven by a boom in artificial intelligence (AI) development. Prices should start climbing out of troughs around the latter part of 2023, executives said at the time.</p><p>The company will release a full earnings report, with divisional breakdowns, on January 31.</p><p>Samsung now aims to catch up with rival SK Hynix in the burgeoning field of high-density memory chips, where it plans to increase capacity by 2.5 times in 2024. HBM, an advanced chip that handles data more quickly, works with hardware such as Nvidia’s accelerators to speed up data processing for intensive tasks like training AI models.</p><p>Samsung is also counting on a new line-up of devices and foldable smartphones to drive growth in 2024. The Korean tech conglomerate is preparing to unveil its latest gadgets in the US later this month, at a time investors worry Apple’s iPhone 15 may be running out of steam mere months after launch.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alibaba’s AliExpress, PDD-owned Temu face supply chain challenges in South Korea amid rapid business expansion</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3247710/alibabas-aliexpress-pdd-owned-temu-face-supply-chain-challenges-south-korea-amid-rapid-business</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English Summary：</h2>  <ul>    <li>AliExpress and Temu, two Chinese e-commerce giants, have experienced rapid growth in South Korea but face challenges such as slow delivery and poor product quality.</li>    <li>Korean consumers are cautious about using Chinese platforms due to long delivery times and unstable product quality.</li>    <li>AliExpress and Temu have taken steps to improve supply chain efficiency, including launching new services and expanding warehouse capacity.</li>    <li>Despite these efforts, Korean consumers remain concerned about counterfeit products and prefer local online retail sites for daily necessities and fashion items.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  <ul>    <li>两家中国电子商务巨头AliExpress和Temu在韩国快速增长，但同时也面临着配送缓慢、产品质量不稳定等问题。</li>    <li>由于配送时间长，产品质量不稳定，韩国消费者对使用中国平台持谨慎态度。</li>    <li>AliExpress和Temu采取了措施提高供应链效率，包括推出新的服务和扩大仓库容量。</li>    <li>尽管如此，韩国消费者仍然担心假冒产品，并更喜欢使用本地在线零售网站购买日用品和时尚物品。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>gadget (n.) - /ˈɡædʒɪt/ 小物件，小器具。    <p>原文例句：Alibaba Group Holding and PDD, two of the largest e-commerce companies in China, have been aggressively expanding their foothold in South Korea, offering prices as low as US$1 for some small gadgets on their overseas shopping platforms AliExpress and Temu, respectively. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Gadget是一个中性词，通常指一些新奇或有趣的小物件或小器具。在这个例句中，它指的是阿里巴巴和拼多多在海外购物平台AliExpress和Temu上销售的一些小物件，价格低至1美元。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>revenue (n.) - /ˈrɛvəˌnjuː/ 收入，收益。    <p>原文例句：South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. </p>    <p>例句讲解：Revenue是一个中性词，通常指通过销售商品或提供服务而获得的收入或收益。在这个例句中，它指的是根据在线数据库ECDB的报告，韩国被列为全球第四大电子商务市场，预计2023年的收入将达到1398亿美元。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>take steps - 采取措施。    <p>原文例句：AliExpress and Temu have taken steps to improve supply chain efficiency, including launching new services and expanding warehouse capacity.</p>    <p>例句讲解：Take steps是一个常用短语，表示采取措施或行动。在这个例句中，它指的是AliExpress和Temu采取了措施提高供应链效率，包括推出新的服务和扩大仓库容量。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Some consumers in Korea remain cautious about replacing local online retail sites, such as Coupang and Gmarket, owing to the Chinese platforms’ supply chain problems that include long delivery time and unstable product quality. - 一些韩国消费者对更换本地在线零售网站（如Coupang和Gmarket）持谨慎态度，因为中国平台存在供应链问题，包括交货时间长且产品质量不稳定。<p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是Some consumers remain cautious about replacing local online retail sites，其中主语是Some consumers，谓语是remain cautious，宾语是replacing local online retail sites。owing to the Chinese platforms’ supply chain problems that include long delivery time and unstable product quality是一个现在分词短语作原因状语，表示导致消费者谨慎更换本地在线零售网站的原因，即中国平台存在供应链问题，包括交货时间长且产品质量不稳定。这个句子的意思是说，一些韩国消费者对更换本地在线零售网站持谨慎态度，因为中国平台存在供应链问题，包括交货时间长且产品质量不稳定。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词结构 - 现在分词和过去分词。    <p>原文例句：South Korea has become one of the major battlefields for Alibaba and PDD, as both count on overseas markets to maintain their business momentum amid sluggish user growth and weak spending in their home market. </p>    <p>语法讲解：分词结构包括现在分词和过去分词，表示动作或状态。现在分词表示进行或持续的动作，过去分词表示完成或被动的动作。在这个例句中，count on overseas markets是现在分词短语作原因状语，表示阿里巴巴和拼多多依赖海外市场来维持业务增长。maintain their business momentum是现在分词短语作目的状语，表示阿里巴巴和拼多多维持业务增长的目的。sluggish user growth and weak spending是过去分词短语作原因状语，表示用户增长缓慢和支出疲软导致阿里巴巴和拼多多的业务增长疲软。这个句子的意思是说，韩国已成为阿里巴巴和拼多多的主要战场，因为两家公司都依赖海外市场来维持业务增长，而国内市场用户增长缓慢、支出疲软。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Despite their popularity, AliExpress and Temu lag behind the competition in South Korea in terms of fast delivery and product quality assurance</li>
<li>Korean consumers find that proliferation of copycat merchandise is a major problem for Chinese online shopping platforms</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/429e5290-226a-46f7-b76d-3c56e51b65b3_f7ecc5a8.jpg" /><figcaption>Online retail platforms AliExpress and Temu ranked as the two fastest-growing apps in South Korea in 2023, according to market research firm WiseApp. Photos: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p><strong>This article was first published by The Korea Times in a partnership with the South China Morning Post.</strong></p><p>China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/ecommerce" target="_self" title="">e-commerce</a> giants are now the fastest-growing online platforms for Korean shoppers, but they are still grappling with problems of long delivery time and unstable product quality, according to consumers and retail industry officials.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/alibaba" target="_self" title="">Alibaba Group Holding</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3243140/discount-e-commerce-giant-pdd-nearly-doubles-quarterly-revenue-closing-alibaba-meituan-also-chalks" target="_self" title="">PDD</a>, two of the largest e-commerce companies in China, have been aggressively expanding their foothold in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea" target="_self" title="">South Korea</a>, offering prices as low as US$1 for some small gadgets on their overseas shopping platforms <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3213632/alibabas-aliexpress-steps-investment-spain-and-south-korea-chinas-e-commerce-players-look-growth" target="_self" title="">AliExpress</a> and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3244193/chinese-budget-e-commerce-app-temu-snatching-business-us-dollar-stores-ahead-lucrative-holiday" target="_self" title="">Temu</a>, respectively. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p><p>Launched in South Korea in 2018, AliExpress saw its monthly active users surpass 7 million as of last November, nearly doubling the number recorded a year earlier, according to mobile market research firm WiseApp. Temu, which started Korean operations in July, averages 3.5 million users per month. WiseApp ranked the two Chinese platforms as the fastest-growing <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/apps" target="_self" title="">apps</a> in Korea in 2023.</p><p>But on the flip side, some consumers in Korea remain cautious about replacing local online retail sites, such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/start-ups/article/2174243/softbank-doubles-down-korean-online-retailer-coupang-us2-billion" target="_self" title="">Coupang</a> and Gmarket, owing to the Chinese platforms’ supply chain problems that include long delivery time and unstable product quality.</p><div class="image-inline-container"><figure><img alt="South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock" class="image-inline caption" height="1333" src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/a4611340-1803-40fa-8f74-caa324044017_1126e908.jpg" title="South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock" width="2000" /><figcaption>South Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, according to a report from online database ECDB. Photo: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></div><p>Lawrence Woo, a 38-year-old office worker in Seoul, started using AliExpress a year ago after he was lured by the platform’s low prices. Woo found, for example, a laptop stand on AliExpress that costs 30,000 won (US$23) and comes with free shipping, which was a deal around 50 per cent cheaper than those offered by local retail sites.</p><p>Still, Woo said he was confused about the delivery time of merchandise he bought on AliExpress. For instance, it took AliExpress two months to deliver a smartphone camera protector film that he bought last autumn.</p><p>“The delivery time is too long,” Woo said. “I tried to cancel the order, but the customer service was not working.”</p><p>On Temu, product shipping times would range from six to 20 days, according to the Chinese budget shopping app’s website.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3108619/south-korea-some-couriers-are-paying-same-day-deliveries-their" title="">In South Korea, couriers crack under the weight of same-day deliveries</a></h3><p>By comparison, Korean e-commerce giant Coupang is capable of shortening delivery times to within a day through its signature Rocket Delivery service.</p><p>Both AliExpress and Temu work with domestic logistics service providers such as CJ Logistics Corp, the oldest and largest parcel delivery firm in South Korea.</p><p>“It depends on [these companies’] supply chain,” said Zhuang Shuai, founder and chief analyst at Chinese market consultancy Bailian. “For instance, whether the sellers are local merchants or Chinese merchants, and whether the platforms have their own warehouses.”</p><p>Zhuang indicated that Chinese shopping platforms face both policy and cultural barriers in their overseas expansion. “Just like how <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/amazon" target="_self" title="">Amazon</a> did not succeed in China, it is also not easy for Chinese companies to operate overseas,” he said.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3235863/alibabas-cainiao-and-aliexpress-start-5-day-global-delivery-service-consumers-uk-spain-netherlands" title="">Alibaba’s Cainiao and AliExpress start ‘5-day global delivery’ service</a></h3><p>Despite those challenges, both AliExpress and Temu have pushed initiatives to improve supply chain efficiency in South Korea.</p><p>The Alibaba unit last March launched a new service called AliExpress Choice that aims to provide Korean consumers with “delivery guarantees and more affordable prices”, touting up to a “three-day delivery window”. AliExpress also expanded the capacity of its warehouses in Weihai and Yantai, two cities in eastern Shandong province, which is close to the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/korean-peninsula-0" target="_self" title="">Korean peninsula</a>.</p><p>Long-time AliExpress user Lee Ye-seul, a 35-year-old resident of Seoul, said the platform’s delivery speed has improved, pointing out that some products she recently ordered arrived within four days of her online purchase. Still, she lamented another major problem: copycat designs widely seen on Chinese e-commerce platforms.</p><p>Lee indicated that there were many merchants on AliExpress selling smartphone cases designed with characters from popular Korean or Japanese brands, such as <a href="https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/article/3131357/hello-kitty-story-how-sanrio-went-silk-sandals-global-superstar" target="_self" title="">Sanrio</a>. “It’s hard to tell if the product you’re buying is plagiarised or an original design,” she said.</p><p>Echoing Lee’s view on copycat merchandise, office worker Woo said it was tough to determine the authenticity of branded products on Chinese shopping platforms. He suggested that these platforms set up a “patrol system” to punish counterfeiters.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3243361/how-temu-shopping-app-targeting-us-consumers-helped-latecomer-pdd-catch-alibaba-market-value" title="">How Temu, an app for US shoppers, helped PDD catch up with Alibaba in market value</a></h3><p>Products bought from AliExpress are “unknowingly circulating” on Korean second-hand sales sites as counterfeits, according to Kang Hyoung-goo, a professor of finance at Hanyang University in Seoul.</p><p>“It is a stumbling block to expanding global outreach through K-fashion exports,” Kang said.</p><p>South Korea has become one of the major battlefields for Alibaba and PDD, as both count on overseas markets to maintain their business momentum amid sluggish user growth and weak spending in their home market.</p><p>Korea was ranked as the world’s fourth-largest e-commerce market with a projected revenue of US$139.8 billion in 2023, followed by Japan, according to a report from online database ECDB.</p><p>Although Chinese platforms have paved the way for many Korean consumers to gain direct access to China-made goods at extremely low prices, Woo and Lee both indicated that these online marketplaces would not become their prime destinations for shopping.</p><p>“I will keep using such platforms, but I’d rather turn to Coupang or Naver Shopping for daily necessities or fashion items,” Woo said.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nvidia expands its reach in China’s electric vehicle sector</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3247723/nvidia-expands-its-reach-chinas-electric-vehicle-sector</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  Four Chinese electric vehicle brands, Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr, and Xiaomi's EV unit, announced at CES that they will use Nvidia's DRIVE technology to power automated driving systems. This move underscores Nvidia's commitment to expanding in China despite Washington's stricter export controls. While China's rising EV brands present a key market for Nvidia's automotive technology business, both Nvidia and its US rivals encounter challenges in balancing market demands and complying with US export regulations.    <ul>    <li>Abstract: Chinese car brands adopt Nvidia's DRIVE technology for automated driving despite US export control challenges.</li>    <li>Theme: The demand for powerful chips in China's automotive industry and Nvidia's strategies to navigate US export restrictions.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of striking a balance between market opportunities and geopolitical factors in international technology trade.</li>    <li>Main information: Four Chinese brands using Nvidia's DRIVE technology; Nvidia's efforts to expand in China; challenges in meeting demands amidst export control regulations.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  四家中国电动汽车品牌——理想汽车、长城汽车、极氪和小米汽车，宣布将在其自动驾驶系统中采用英伟达的DRIVE技术。这突显了英伟达致力于在中国扩张的决心，尽管华盛顿收紧了对中国的出口管制。虽然中国崛起的电动汽车品牌为英伟达的汽车技术业务提供了一个关键市场，但英伟达及其美国竞争对手在平衡市场需求和遵守美国出口法规方面都面临着挑战。  <ul>    <li>摘要：中国汽车品牌采用英伟达DRIVE技术实现自动驾驶，尽管面临美国出口管制挑战。</li>    <li>主题：中国汽车行业对强大芯片的需求以及英伟达应对美国出口限制的策略。</li>    <li>观点：在国际技术贸易中，在市场机遇和地缘政治因素之间寻求平衡的重要性。</li>    <li>主要信息：使用英伟达DRIVE技术的四家中国品牌；英伟达在中国扩张的努力；在出口管制法规下满足需求的挑战。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>underscoring (v.) - /ˌʌndəˈskɔːrɪŋ/ 强调，突出。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia said four Chinese electric vehicle brands will use its technology as the brains for automated driving systems, underscoring the US chip maker’s determination to expand in China despite Washington’s tighter export rules.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Underscore”源自拉丁语“sub”（在……之下）和“scribere”（书写），意为“写在字下面”。在这个例句中，“underscoring”表示强调或突出。它强调了英伟达致力于在中国扩张的决心，尽管华盛顿收紧了对中国的出口管制。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>demands (n.) - /dɪˈmændz/ 需求，要求。   <p>原文例句：Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Demand”源自古法语“demander”（要求），意为“请求、要求”。在这个例句中，“demands”表示客户对产品的需求。它强调了中国客户对强大芯片的需求，以及英伟达及其美国竞争对手在满足这些需求的同时遵守美国出口管制的挑战。</p></li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>in compliance with - 遵守，符合。    <P>原文例句：Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组是由in（在……里面），compliance（遵守，符合）和with（与……一起）构成的，表示“遵守，符合”。在这个例句中，它表示Nvidia及其美国竞争对手在满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求的同时，遵守美国对先进半导体出口的更严格控制。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Nvidia and its US rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China. - 英伟达及其美国竞争对手面临着满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求的挑战，同时还要遵守美国对先进半导体出口更严格的控制。<p>句子分析：这是一个并列复合句，主句是Nvidia and its US rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips和Nvidia and its US rivals face challenges remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China。其中主语分别是Nvidia and its US rivals和Nvidia and its US rivals，谓语分别是face challenges meeting demands和face challenges remaining in compliance。虽然，while是一个连词，连接了两个主句，表示并列关系。在这个例句中，它表示英伟达及其美国竞争对手面临着满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求的挑战，同时还要遵守美国对先进半导体出口更严格的控制。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在进行时 - 表示正在进行的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在进行时态，结构是：be + 现在分词。其中be要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态正在进行。在这个例句中，它表示英伟达及其美国竞争对手正在面临满足中国客户对强大芯片的需求的挑战，同时还要遵守美国对先进半导体出口更严格的控制。</p></li>  </ul>   <ul>    <li>比较级 - 表示两个或多个事物或情况之间的差异。    <p>原文例句：Chinese carmakers are racing each other to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays and automated driving functions. </p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个比较级，结构是：形容词或副词的比较级形式。比较级表示两个或多个事物或情况之间的差异。在这个例句中，它表示中国汽车制造商正在竞相推出更先进的车载信息娱乐显示屏和自动驾驶功能。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday</li>
<li>Nvidia and US rivals face challenges meeting China’s demands for powerful chips, while complying with US controls on semiconductor exports to China</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/ca10cd80-a417-41ba-821c-f909879abb0a_5739d5f7.jpg" /><figcaption>A Nvidia logo at the company’s headquarters in Taipei, Taiwan. Photo: Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Nvidia said four Chinese electric vehicle brands will use its technology as the brains for automated driving systems, underscoring the US chip maker’s determination to expand in China despite Washington’s tighter export rules.</p><p>Chinese carmakers Li Auto, Great Wall Motor, Zeekr and the new EV unit of Chinese telecommunications company Xiaomi will use Nvidia’s DRIVE technology to power automated driving, Nvidia said on Monday at the CES technology conference in Las Vegas.</p><p>China’s rising EV brands are a key market for Nvidia’s automotive technology business. Chinese carmakers are racing each other to launch more advanced in-vehicle infotainment displays and automated driving functions. That has created a growth opportunity for Nvidia, Intel, Qualcomm and other semiconductor manufacturers.</p><p>Nvidia and its US-based rivals face challenges meeting demands from Chinese customers for powerful chips, while remaining in compliance with tighter US controls on exports of advanced semiconductors to China.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3245507/chinese-non-tech-firms-have-also-been-scrambling-buy-nvidia-gpus-landscape-designer-reveals-order" title="">Non-tech Chinese firms tout orders of Nvidia chips, winning stock boosts</a></h3><p>In related CES announcements, Nvidia said it is working with advertising giant WPP, Lotus and six other companies to develop more advanced online shopping tools. Using Nvidia technology, carmakers and dealers hope to create online shopping sites with three dimensional graphics and more lifelike graphics, said Danny Shapiro, Nvidia’s vice-president for automotive.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tencent’s Pony Ma says 2021 WeChat photo privacy controversy was ‘misunderstanding’ that was fixed with update</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3247704/tencents-pony-ma-says-2021-wechat-photo-privacy-controversy-was-misunderstanding-was-fixed-update</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary:</h2>  In 2021, Pony Ma Huateng, the founder and CEO of Tencent, responded to a user privacy issue regarding WeChat's accessing of user photo galleries without authorization, clarifying that it was a misunderstanding caused by image cache acceleration. Despite reassurances of the issue being fixed, the incident sparked widespread privacy concerns among WeChat users.  <ul>    <li>Abstract: WeChat photo issue in 2021 caused privacy concerns despite Tencent's clarification.</li>    <li>Theme: Tencent CEO's explanation of the WeChat photo issue as a "misunderstanding" due to image cache acceleration.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The importance of user privacy in the context of social media platforms and the scrutiny faced by tech companies regarding data handling.</li>    <li>Main information: Ma's explanation of the issue; implementation of a new programming interface to resolve the lag; Tencent's initial statement about optimizing the photo sending process; and the introduction of stricter data protection laws in China.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  2021年，腾讯创始人兼首席执行官马化腾对微信在未经授权的情况下访问用户相册的用户隐私问题做出了回应，他澄清说这是一个由图片缓存加速造成的误解。尽管保证了这个问题已经得到解决，但这起事件在微信用户中引起了广泛的隐私担忧。  <ul>    <li>摘要：尽管腾讯澄清，2021 年微信照片问题引发了隐私担忧。</li>    <li>主题：腾讯首席执行官将微信照片问题解释为“误解”，原因是图片缓存加速。</li>    <li>观点：在社交媒体平台背景下的用户隐私及其重要性，以及科技公司在数据处理方面面临的审查。</li>    <li>主要信息：马化腾对该问题的解释；实施新的编程接口以解决滞后；腾讯关于优化照片发送过程的初始声明；在中国引入了更严格的数据保护法。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Words:</h2>  <ul>    <li>sparks (v.) - /spɑːrk/ 引起，激发。    <p>原文例句：The 2021 WeChat photo issue sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time despite reassurances that the glitch had been fixed.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“sparks”在这里被用作及物动词，意为“引起，激发，点燃”。在这个句子中，“sparks widespread privacy concerns”的意思是“引发了广泛的隐私担忧”。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>routine (adj.) - /ruːˈtiːn/ 例行公事，常规的。    <p>原文例句：The influencer also said in 2021 that Tencent’s QQ messaging app and Taobao, Alibaba Group Holding’s top online shopping marketplace with roughly 900 million MAUs, had also been found routinely accessing user photos.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“routinely”在这里被用作形容词，意为“例行公事的，常规的，习惯性的”。在这个句子中，“routinely accessing user photos”的意思是“例行访问用户照片”。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Phrases:</h2>  <ul>    <li>in the context of - 在……的背景下。    <P>原文例句：The importance of user privacy in the context of social media platforms and the scrutiny faced by tech companies regarding data handling.</P>    <p>例句讲解：这个词组由in（在……里面），the context of（背景，语境）和of（属于，关于）构成，表示“在……的背景下”。在这个例句中，它表示在社交媒体平台的背景下。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Sentences:</h2>  <ul>    <li>That year, a tech influencer found that WeChat, China’s largest social media app with 1.3 billion monthly active users (MAUs), was frequently accessing user photo galleries even when not in use, which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time.</li>    <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是That year, a tech influencer found that WeChat...which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time，其中主语是That year, a tech influencer，谓语是found，宾语是that WeChat...。which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time是一个非限制性定语从句，修饰先行词WeChat，表示的就是微信这个动作引发了广泛的隐私担忧。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>Grammar:</h2>  <ul>    <li>Present perfect tense - 表示从过去某个时间点开始一直延续到现在的动作或状态。    <p>原文例句：Pony Ma Huateng, founder, chairman and CEO of Tencent Holdings, has described a 2021 privacy controversy sparked by a photo issue with its all-purpose super app WeChat as a “misunderstanding”, according to a local media report.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时态的句子，表示从2021年开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。结构是：has/have + 过去分词。在这个句子中，has是助动词，described是过去分词，表示马化腾从2021年开始一直到现在把2021年微信照片问题引起的隐私争议描述为“误解”。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>Ma described the issue as ‘a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images’</li>
<li>The 2021 WeChat photo issue sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time despite reassurances that the glitch had been fixed</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/09/daec20ec-0fa7-42e0-ad58-197447fdda39_11d7714e.jpg" /><figcaption>Ma described the WeChat issue as “a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images”. Photo: Shutterstock </figcaption></figure><p>Pony Ma Huateng, founder, chairman and CEO of Tencent Holdings, has described a 2021 privacy controversy sparked by a photo issue with its all-purpose super app WeChat as a “misunderstanding”, according to a local media report.</p><p>That year, a tech influencer found that WeChat, China’s largest social media app with 1.3 billion monthly active users (MAUs), was <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3151762/tencents-wechat-stop-routine-scans-photos-after-tech-influencer" target="_self" title="">frequently accessing user photo galleries even when not in use</a>, which sparked widespread privacy concerns at the time.</p><p>Ma described the issue as “a misunderstanding caused by cache acceleration of images”, according to a report by Chinese media outlet Yicai on Monday.</p><p>He said the matter was solved by the roll-out of a new application programming interface within the operating system to fix the lag.</p><p>Tencent said at the time that the app was looking for new images to make it “faster and smoother for users to send photos”, and it only accessed the gallery when authorised by the user. The company also said it would cancel the scanning in a new version of the app.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>Yicai picked up Ma’s comments from CSDNnews, a tech news outlet run by the Chinese Software Developer Network.</p><p>Ma told CSDNnews in a private WeChat message last Friday that this “old incident” in 2021 had been fixed, according to a screenshot shared by the outlet.</p><p>Tencent did not immediately respond to a request for comment by the Post on Monday.</p><p>China has introduced <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3147040/what-chinas-new-data-laws-are-and-their-impact-big-tech?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">new laws in recent years</a> that tighten scrutiny over how tech companies handle personal data.</p><p>The Data Security Law and the Personal Information Protection Law, some of the world’s toughest data protection laws, went into effect in 2021 with strict penalties for the unauthorised collection, processing, storage and use of data generated in the country.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3245623/chinas-finance-influencers-face-stricter-rules-tencents-live-streaming-channels-beijing-moves-shore" title="">China’s finance live streamers face stricter rules on Tencent</a></h3><p>Tencent faced intense scrutiny in 2021 when tech influencer Hackl0us said on social media platform Weibo that the app periodically accessed user photos while running in the background.</p><p>The activity was discovered using Apple’s “Record App Activity” feature on its iOS 15 operating system at that time.</p><p>The influencer also said in 2021 that Tencent’s QQ messaging app and Taobao, Alibaba Group Holding’s top online shopping marketplace with roughly 900 million MAUs, had also been found routinely accessing user photos. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tightening noose: Hong Kong joins EU, US, South Korea and Singapore in tightening crypto rules, report says</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247684/hong-kong-joins-eu-us-south-korea-and-singapore-tightening-crypto-regulations-2023-report-says</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>English summary:</h2>  In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the European Union, South Korea, Singapore, and the United States, strengthened cryptocurrency regulations. This move came in response to a series of meltdowns in the crypto market, leading to increased scrutiny and consumer protection measures. Governments worldwide are aiming to establish a more stable and regulated landscape for the volatile cryptocurrency sector.<ul>    <li>17 jurisdictions tightened cryptocurrency regulations in 2023.</li>    <li>80% of those jurisdictions focused on consumer protection measures.</li>    <li>Major events like the collapse of FTX and TerraUSD prompted these regulatory changes.</li>    <li>Hong Kong, Singapore, and South Korea also ramped up their regulatory efforts.</li>    <li>The United States' House Financial Services Committee proposed bills for a federal regulatory framework.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>中文总结：</h2>  2023年，包括中国香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币监管。此举是对加密货币市场一系列崩溃做出的回应，导致了对加密货币市场监管的加强和消费者保护措施的增加。世界各国政府都致力于为波动的加密货币行业建立一个更加稳定和受监管的环境。  <ul>    <li>17个司法管辖区在2023年收紧了加密货币监管。</li>    <li>80%的司法管辖区重点关注消费者保护措施。</li>    <li>FTX和TerraUSD的崩盘等重大事件促使了这些监管变化。</li>    <li>中国香港、新加坡和韩国也加大了监管力度。</li>    <li>美国众议院金融服务委员会提出了建立联邦监管框架的法案。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Scrutiny (n): 仔细检查，审查。    <p>原文例句：Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Scrutiny”是指仔细检查或审查。在这个句子中，它表示各国政府在过去一年中加强了对加密货币的审查。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Volatile (adj): 波动的，不稳定的。    <p>原文例句：In the volatile sector.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Volatile”是指波动或不稳定。在这个句子中，它表示加密货币行业是一个波动或不稳定的行业。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Rout (n): 溃败，崩溃。    <p>原文例句：a market rout that wiped out trillions of dollars in value.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Rout”是指溃败或崩溃。在这个句子中，它表示一场导致数万亿美元价值被抹去的市场溃败。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>Tighten regulations: 收紧法规    <p>原文例句：17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, tightened cryptocurrency regulations.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Tighten regulations”是指收紧法规。在这个句子中，它表示包括中国香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币法规。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>Consumer protection measures: 消费者保护措施。    <p>原文例句：Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures.</p>    <p>例句讲解：“Consumer protection measures”是指消费者保护措施。在这个句子中，它表示几乎一半收紧加密货币法规的司法管辖区都增加了消费者保护措施。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the United States, tightened cryptocurrency regulations.<p>句子分析：这是一个简单的句子，主语是“17 jurisdictions”，谓语是“tightened cryptocurrency regulations”。介词短语“including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the United States”是主语的定语，表示收紧加密货币法规的17个司法管辖区包括中国香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国。这个句子的意思是，2023年，包括中国香港、欧盟、韩国、新加坡和美国在内的17个司法管辖区收紧了加密货币法规。</p></li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>分词结构。    <p>原文例句：Those strengthening protection accounted for 80 per cent of the 21 jurisdictions studied by the firm.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个分词结构，分词是“strengthening”，它修饰主语“Those”，表示那些加强保护的司法管辖区。这个句子的意思是，那些加强保护的司法管辖区占该公司研究的21个司法管辖区的80%。</p></li>  </ul>  <ul>    <li>被动语态。    <p>原文例句：In 2022, the collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms, including the stablecoin TerraUSD and exchange FTX, led to a market rout that wiped out trillions of dollars in value.</p>    <p>语法讲解：这是一个被动语态的句子，谓语动词“led”是被动的，主语是“the collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms”。这个句子的意思是，2022年，包括稳定币TerraUSD和交易所FTX在内的几家主要加密货币平台的崩盘导致了一场市场溃败，导致数万亿美元的价值被抹去。</p></li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US, tightened cryptocurrency regulations</li>
<li>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures, according to TRM Labs</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/70965061-8587-4332-9ba0-361c7665e6c9_67fe6e02.jpg" /><figcaption>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the EU, South Korea, Singapore, and the US tightened cryptocurrency regulations. Photo: Bloomberg </figcaption></figure><p>Governments around the world have increased their scrutiny of cryptocurrencies in the past year following a series of meltdowns, with many strengthening consumer protection in the volatile sector.</p><p>In 2023, 17 jurisdictions including Hong Kong, the European Union, South Korea, Singapore, and the United States, tightened cryptocurrency regulations, according to a report published on Monday by blockchain analytics firm TRM Labs.</p><p>Those strengthening protection accounted for 80 per cent of the 21 jurisdictions studied by the firm, with the latter representing 70 per cent of global exposure to cryptocurrencies, said TRM Labs.</p><p>In 2022, the collapse of several major cryptocurrency platforms, including the stablecoin TerraUSD and exchange FTX, led to a market rout that wiped out trillions of dollars in value.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" title="">Hong Kong to push retail access to spot cryptocurrency exchange-traded funds</a></h3><p>While 2023 began with the crypto ecosystem “reeling from the collapse of FTX”, the subsequent 12 months “saw an extraordinary boom in regulation across the globe”, the report says.</p><p>Among prominent moves, the European Union’s Markets in Crypto Assets Regulation came into force in June last year, and Hong Kong’s new licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges went live, the firm noted.</p><div class="scmp-code-block methode-html-wrapper">
</div><p>Singapore, which the report described as “an early adopter of crypto regulation”, in November last year issued a set of rules aimed at curbing retail speculation in cryptocurrencies, and finalised its rules for stablecoins.</p><p>Meanwhile, South Korea and Australia also increased scrutiny of the cryptocurrency sector last year, the report says.</p><p>In the US, the Securities and Exchange Commission ramped up its enforcement actions against crypto firms in 2023, and the House Financial Services Committee also advanced bills last July aimed at creating a federal regulatory framework for the crypto market, with specific attention to stablecoins.</p><p>Almost half of the jurisdictions that tightened crypto regulations in 2023 increased consumer protection measures, according to TRM Labs.</p><p>It also noted that international organisations, including the G20, the Financial Action Task Force, the Financial Stability Board, International Monetary Fund, and the International Organization of Securities Commissions, all laid out global frameworks and policy recommendations for regulating cryptocurrencies.</p><p>Hong Kong, which in October 2022 announced a major initiative to support the virtual asset sector with the goal of becoming a global hub for such businesses, has implemented a mandatory licensing regime for centralised crypto exchanges that allow them to accept retail investors.</p><p>Eleven companies have so far submitted applications for the licence in the city, including OKX, one of the largest exchanges by trading volume.</p><p>In December, the Asian financial hub also <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246415/hong-kong-regulators-propose-tougher-rules-sale-stablecoins-retail-investors?module=hard_link&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">proposed rules for stablecoin issuers</a>, which would ban companies without a licence from selling stablecoins to Hong Kong’s retail investors through regulated channels, or from actively marketing their tokens to the city.</p><p>The rules have been deemed as “extremely challenging” for stablecoin issuers, potentially deterring operators of the world’s biggest stablecoins, such as Tether and USDC, from entering the city, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246692/hong-kongs-proposed-stablecoin-rules-would-be-extremely-challenging-global-issuers-tether-and-usdc" target="_self" title="">experts told the Post last month</a>.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Shanghai explainer on taxation of digital currency transaction drives speculation on potential easing of China’s crypto ban</title>
<link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3247683/shanghai-explainer-taxation-digital-currency-transaction-drives-speculation-potential-easing-chinas</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <div>  <h2>Summary：</h2>  上海市税务局发布文章解释数字货币交易征税问题，引发当地加密货币爱好者猜测中国可能放松对加密货币的严厉禁令。但随后，上海市税务局从其官方微信公众号删除了这篇文章。中国业内专家指出，这篇文章并不暗示中国政府将改变对加密货币的政策，而只是针对虚拟游戏中的虚拟货币的税收问题。中国多年来一直严厉打击与加密货币相关的活动，以维护金融稳定。  <ul>    <li>Abstract: Shanghai tax authority's article on taxing digital currency transactions sparks speculation about potential easing of China's crypto ban; the article's deletion raises doubts.</li>    <li>Theme: China's stance on cryptocurrencies and the recent developments in the country's approach to digital asset regulation.</li>    <li>Viewpoint: The implications of the Shanghai tax authority's article and its subsequent deletion on China's crypto policy; the need for regulatory oversight of virtual asset-related income in China.</li>    <li>Main information: Shanghai tax authority's article explaining taxation of digital currency transactions; deletion of the article from the official WeChat account; mainland legal experts' interpretation; China's crackdown on crypto-related activities.</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>总结：</h2>  上海市税务局发布文章解释数字货币交易征税问题，引发当地加密货币爱好者猜测中国可能放松对加密货币的严厉禁令。但随后，上海市税务局从其官方微信公众号删除了这篇文章。中国业内专家指出，这篇文章并不暗示中国政府将改变对加密货币的政策，而只是针对虚拟游戏中的虚拟货币的税收问题。中国多年来一直严厉打击与加密货币相关的活动，以维护金融稳定。  <ul>    <li>摘要：上海税务局关于对数字货币交易征税的文章引发了人们猜测中国可能放松对加密货币的禁令；该文章被删除后引起了人们的怀疑。</li>    <li>主题：中国对加密货币的立场以及该国最近在数字资产监管方面的发展。</li>    <li>观点：上海税务局文章及其随后删除对中国加密政策的影响；中国需要对虚拟资产相关收入进行监管。</li>    <li>主要信息：上海税务局的文章解释了对数字货币交易的征税；从官方微信公众号中删除了该文章；中国法律专家的解读；中国对与加密货币相关的活动的打击。</li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>单词：</h2>  <ul>    <li>legitimacy (n.) - /lɪˈdʒɪtɪməsi/ 合法性，正当性。      <p>原文例句：That prompted some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies. </p>      <p>例句讲解：这个单词由legitim（合法，正当）和-acy（状态）组成，表示“合法性，正当性”。在这个例句中，它指加密货币的合法性和正当性，即当局开始认可加密货币的合法性和正当性。</p>    </li>    <li>draconian (adj.) - /drəˈkəʊniən/ 残酷的，严厉的。      <p>原文例句：China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks.</p>      <p>例句讲解：这个单词源自古希腊立法家德拉科（Draco），他制定了非常严厉的法律，因此draconian的意思是“残忍的，严厉的”。在这个例句中，它指中国对加密货币相关活动的严厉打击，即中国多年来一直以金融稳定风险为由，加大了对所有与加密货币相关的活动的打击力度。</p>    </li>  </ul>  </div><div>  <h2>词组：</h2>  <ul>    <li>citing financial stability risks - 援引金融稳定风险      <p>原文例句：China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks.</p>      <p>例句讲解：这个词组由citing（援引）和financial stability risks（金融稳定风险）组成，表示“援引金融稳定风险”。在这个句子中，it表示中国政府以金融稳定风险为由，对加密货币相关活动进行严厉打击。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>句子：</h2>  <ul>    <li>The explainer, “Common Misunderstandings Regarding Personal Income Tax on Business Income and Categorised Income”, became widely circulated on Sunday after it was published on WeChat by the Shanghai tax service on Thursday. - 解释器“关于个人所得税中经营所得和分类所得的常见误区”在上海税务局周四在微信上发布后，于周日被广泛传播。      <p>句子分析：这是一个复杂句，主句是The explainer became widely circulated on Sunday，其中主语是The explainer，谓语是became widely circulated，宾语是on Sunday。after it was published on WeChat by the Shanghai tax service on Thursday是一个时间状语从句，表示这一消息是在上海税务局周四在微信上发布后。这是一个被动语态的句子，主语The explainer是动作承受者，谓语became widely circulated是过去式，表示这一消息在周日被广泛传播。这个句子的意思是说，这一消息在上海税务局周四在微信上发布后，于周日被广泛传播。</p>    </li>  </ul></div><div>  <h2>语法：</h2>  <ul>    <li>现在完成时 - 表示从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在的动作或状态。      <p>原文例句：China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks.</p>      <p>语法讲解：这是一个现在完成时的句子，结构是：have/has + been + 现在分词。其中have/has要根据主语的人称和数进行变化，been是be的过去分词，现在分词是动词的-ing形式。这种时态表示动作或状态从过去某个时间开始一直持续到现在，强调动作或状态的持续性和未完成性。在这个例句中，它表示中国多年来一直以金融稳定风险为由，加大了对所有与加密货币相关的活动的打击力度，即中国政府从过去的几年开始一直持续到现在，以金融稳定风险为由，对加密货币相关活动进行严厉打击。</p>    </li>  </ul></div>  <ul><li>The explainer became widely circulated on Sunday after some local crypto enthusiasts suggested that it acknowledged cryptocurrencies’ legitimacy</li>
<li>The Shanghai Municipal Tax Service has since deleted the article from its public WeChat account</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2024/01/08/dd38a0bb-3bd5-4e5f-aee4-d25bc7d830f4_a5b28db7.jpg" /><figcaption>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure><p>An online article posted by the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/shanghai" target="_self" title="">Shanghai</a> Municipal Tax Service, explaining levies imposed on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/digital-currencies" target="_self" title="">digital currency</a> transactions in China, has fanned speculation among local cryptocurrency enthusiasts that it signals a potential relaxation of the country’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3208481/chinese-economist-calls-review-rigid-cryptocurrency-ban-digital-yuan-fails-take?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">draconian ban on crypto operations</a>.</p><p>The explainer, “Common Misunderstandings Regarding Personal Income Tax on Business Income and Categorised Income”, became widely circulated on Sunday after it was published on <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/wechat" target="_self" title="">WeChat</a> by the Shanghai tax service on Thursday. It cited a 2008 statement by the State Taxation Administration (STA).</p><p>That prompted some crypto-themed online content creators on the mainland to suggest that taxing such transactions show authorities are starting to acknowledge the legitimacy of cryptocurrencies. The Shanghai tax service subsequently deleted the explainer on Sunday from its public WeChat account.</p><p>The wide attention received by the Shanghai tax service’s explainer reflects the lingering hope among Chinese crypto circles that the country’s rigid ban on cryptocurrencies would be reviewed amid Beijing’s drive to expand adoption of the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/topics/china-digital-currency/news" target="_self" title="">digital yuan</a>.</p><div class="methode-html-wrapper oembed-wrapper">
</div><p>China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology last month announced plans to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3245895/beijing-draft-national-web3-development-plan-authorities-maintain-draconian-cryptocurrency-ban" target="_self" title="">draft a national Web3 development plan</a> to suit the country’s needs, although it did not specifically mention cryptocurrencies.</p><p>Mainland legal experts, however, pointed out that the Shanghai tax service’s explainer does not suggest any potential change in the country’s cryptocurrency policy.</p><p>The published article is not an official policy document, and the STA statement it cited concerns virtual tokens used in <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/video-gaming" target="_self" title="">video games</a>, according to Guo Zhihao, a partner at Beijing-based Yingke Law Firm, in an article he posted on WeChat on Sunday.</p><p>The explainer had indicated that individuals who obtain virtual currencies from other players through online transactions and generate revenue by selling them at a higher price must pay income tax on such earnings. The Shanghai tax agency’s article detailed taxation in four scenarios, including loans obtained by individual investors from their investee companies and online monetary gifts.</p><h3><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3208481/chinese-economist-calls-review-rigid-cryptocurrency-ban-digital-yuan-fails-take" title="">Chinese economist calls for review of rigid crypto ban amid slow e-CNY adoption</a></h3><p>China over the years has ramped up its crackdown on all activities related to cryptocurrencies, citing financial stability risks. It maintains that stance even though it <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3216894/chinese-officials-pledge-support-hong-kongs-tech-web3-ambitions-digital-economy-summit?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_self" title="">supports Hong Kong’s ambitions to become a major hub for virtual assets</a>, including cryptocurrencies.</p><p>While there is no official sign from Beijing about changing its position on cryptocurrencies, local crypto circles expect increased regulatory oversight on the taxation of virtual asset-related income on the mainland.</p><p>China has denied legal-tender status for cryptocurrencies, but has not opposed its attribution as property or commodity, according to an article published on Friday by Jin Jianzhi of the Shanghai Mankun Law Firm. The lawyer said the government can levy taxes on relevant transactions under the law.</p><p>The global cryptocurrency market, meanwhile, appears to be slowly recovering from a prolonged slump last year. <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/bitcoin" target="_self" title="">Bitcoin</a> prices gained more than 150 per cent from a year earlier on the back of expectations that the US Securities and Exchange Commission will soon approve <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3246308/hong-kong-prepares-retail-access-spot-cryptocurrency-exchange-traded-funds-boosting-citys-virtual" target="_self" title="">bitcoin exchange-traded funds</a>, which would make these virtual assets more attractive to mainstream investors.</p> ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
